<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>whiteboard &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/whiteboard/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why (and How) I Model</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/introductionarchitecturedesign/why-and-how-i-model/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/introductionarchitecturedesign/why-and-how-i-model/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 09:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Introduction to Architecture and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[constraints]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whiteboard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/10/why-and-how-i-model/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over my years in (and before) IT, I've seen long projects, failed projects, confused projects, wildly successful projects, and even fun projects that ended far differently than we expected. The consistent take-away for me is that I am a big picture type of person, and that understanding that big, abstract picture cuts out a lot of wasted time sprinting down the wrong paths.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over my years in (and before) IT, I&#8217;ve seen long projects, failed projects, confused projects, wildly successful projects, and even fun projects that ended far differently than we expected. The consistent take-away for me is that I am a big picture type of person, and that understanding that big, abstract picture cuts out a lot of wasted time sprinting down the wrong paths.</p>
<div style="font-size: .8em; color: #666666; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/modeling/sprint.jpg" alt="Don't Sprint Blindly" /><br />
Don&#8217;t Sprint Blindly&#8230;<br />(care of <a href="http://www.dmitriev.com/blog/2009-04-14/wrong-sprint-burndown/">dmitriev.com</a>)
</div>
<p>Creating a model forces me to refine a concept down to it&#8217;s simplest elements, forces me to face the unknowns that my mind has so casually been skipping over. When done well, a model communicates a clear idea and replaces not only the thousands words required to explain it, but the 9000 I would have wasted getting there.</p>
<p>I model to think through processes, question my assumptions, and provide guidance towards a solution. While it probably looks like something I threw together in about ten minutes, there are actually a lot of processes going on behind the scenes.</p>
<h2>Purpose &#8211; What are We Drawing?</h2>
<div style="float: right; font-size: .8em; color: #666666; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/modeling/dostuff.jpg" title="Do Stuff!" /><br />
No Goal? Here&#8217;s a Diagram.
</div>
<p>As with all things, a diagram should have a goal. A model that isn&#8217;t trying to communicate an idea is filler for a report no one is going to read anyway. A goal should be concise and limited to a single subject or perspective:</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em;">
<li>The data flow from the end customer to our master data system</li>
<li>An order-to-cash business process</li>
<li>The functional architecture of a software application</li>
<li>A graphic representation of our current state</li>
</ul>
<p>Mess around with too many factors and at the end of the day a mess is all you&#8217;ll  have:</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em;">
<li>The physical network topology combined with the disaster recovery plan and data flows between the systems</li>
<li>The application architecture with defined user work flows and user experience elements</li>
</ul>
<p>Or to translate: gobbledygook.</p>
<h2>Constraint &#8211; Less is More</h2>
<p>A goal provides me with my first constraint, and constraints are good. Defining constraints will keep my model simpler and consistent, which means the end message will be clearer. At the same time, a well-defined set of constraints will encourage creativity, providing a better end product.</p>
<p>Often my constraints will include things like not allowing connections to cross, only using a very simple set of shapes, restricting myself to only a few shades of color, or setting time limits. I&#8217;ll define the perspective I want to use with my goal, whether it will be a topological map, a flow, or just a set of connected shapes. </p>
<p>This keeps me focused instead of playing with the entire palette of colors, shapes, and page sizes available in my favorite software tools.</p>
<h2>Content &#8211; Work on a Temporary Surface</h2>
<p>Even with constraints and a goal, I still don&#8217;t know exactly where I will end up or what I will learn along the way, so I start on the whiteboard. With a whiteboard I can start diagramming out the pieces I know, add in new items or resolve question marks as I run into them, and easily combine and rearrange my thoughts. Some of my constraints will be ineffective at this stage, but natural constraints (like the number of markers I have and the board size) will replace them in helping my creativity and thought processes.</p>
<p>This stage is also where I figure out my wording. Because it&#8217;s so easy to see the big picture (heh) on my whiteboard, I also get a good feel for when words are too specific, not specific enough, or possibly just not quite the right word for what I am trying to communicate. Instead of focusing on getting all the boxes lined up, I can focus on using clear and consistent terminology that will help support the final model rather than detract from it.</p>
<h2>Medium &#8211; Where is it Going?</h2>
<div style="float: left; font-size: .8em; color: #666666; text-align: center; margin: 2em 1em 1em 1em">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/trent/2004_11_05_04_sm.jpg" title="Content needs context" /><br />
Content needs Context
</div>
<p>As I make the transition from whiteboard to diagramming software, the last piece of the equation is to consider the medium I am going to use to communicate the model. A standalone diagram may put higher priority on further simplicity of shapes and colors, where a presentation model may put lower priority on text and higher priority on subtleties for deeper conversation. </p>
<p>Will there need to be a legend? Is font-size 8 going to be a waste of time or readable font? If I use subtle shades of color will it all print the same color or show up in gloriously rendered imagery on a 12 foot display? Will adding a cartoon get a chuckle in a presentation or a frown in an executive review? Can I include a picture of my cat?</p>
<p>The context the diagram will be communicating in will determine the last set of constraints.</p>
<h2>Terminology &#8211; The Wrong Word Invalidates the Model</h2>
<div style="float: right; font-size: .8em; color: #666666; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/modeling/van-venn-diagram.jpg" title="'Van' Diagram" /><br />
Using the right terminology, <br />thanks <a href="http://www.lolcaption.com/random-funny/what-is-a-van-diagram-you-ask-well-let-me-show-you/">lolcaption.com</a>
</div>
<p>General wording may have been roughed in on the whiteboard and some really good words may have been chosen, but these now need to be examined in light of the future medium as well as the audience. In many cases, using a word out of context can distract my audience or even negate the model&#8217;s message entirely.</p>
<p>That being said, endless anxiety over perfection is nowhere near as good as a cool beer at the end of a work day, so we need to strike a balance between working through the night and achieving good enough. So I&#8217;ll be careful, in general, when using customer terminology and try to be pragmatic in my search for the perfect name for the third box from the left.</p>
<h2>Composition &#8211; Additional Layers of Meaning</h2>
<p>The last stage of the model, having transferred it from whiteboard to software and applied corrections to terminology, is to add some depth that supports the initial concept. </p>
<p>Colors, re-arranging layout to alter proximity, fonts, and even line thicknesses are all tools I use to add subtle depth to a model. If I am planning on presenting the model, I can start the discussion on the general message of the model and dive into these subtleties as the discussion progresses. A thicker line between two systems can communicate greater bandwidth or a more secure transport layer. A common shading of colors between multiple objects communicates a relationship or similarity. As with the stages before, I try to use constraint. Applying the whole palette and a different shape for each object may seem fun, but it&#8217;s going to communicate confusion (and possibly a desire for medication).</p>
<p>While working with the composition, I will also create temporary versions to play with drastically different layouts or shapes. This gives me a fresh look at a concept that has undoubtedly been on my whiteboard for days, giving me an opportunity to catch last minute holes or simply provide alternative layout options.</p>
<h2>Sounds Like a Lot of Work&#8230;</h2>
<p>There are different levels of work involved in modeling. In some cases even finding the time to stop doing and try to draw an idea may seem like a waste. </p>
<div style="float: right; font-size: .8em; color: #666666; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/modeling/lookbothways.jpg" title="No Need To Look Ahead" /><br />
Not looking ahead?<br />Diagram for that too&#8230;
</div>
<div style="font-size: .8em; margin: 1em;  padding: 1em;">
How do I judge when it is worth spending the time?</p>
<p><strong>5 Minutes:</strong> If it only takes five minutes to draw a fast diagram of what I am intending to do, then that 5 minutes didn&#8217;t cost much and I can move forward with confidence.</p>
<p><strong>30 Minutes:</strong> If it takes 30 minutes, I&#8217;ve erased and redrawn half of it, and the person I am explaining it to is still arguing with me, then it&#8217;s time to draw a model. </p>
<p><strong>3 Hours:</strong> If it takes 3 hours, we end with more questions than we started with, half the questions have the potential for refocusing the project, and we&#8217;re still trying to figure out what to call this thing&#8230;yeah, it&#8217;s definitely time to get a handle on what we&#8217;re spending time on.
</div>
<p>Jumping right into any project when we can&#8217;t draw a high level summary means we&#8217;re spending time and resources on something we can&#8217;t adequately define. It doesn&#8217;t matter how fast we&#8217;re moving if we&#8217;re spending that time running in random directions and ignoring cross-traffic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/introductionarchitecturedesign/why-and-how-i-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating a Conceptual Data Model</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/creating-a-conceptual-data-model/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/creating-a-conceptual-data-model/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 11:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conceptual model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whiteboard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/08/creating-a-conceptual-data-model/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are three types of data models: Conceptual, Logical, and Physical. The conceptual model provides a high-level view of the data, defining the general entities and entity relationships using the language of the business or organization. The logical model adds attributes to these entities, providing a technology-agnostic foundation for a database design. The physical model assigns table names, column names, and data types to the entities and attributes defined in the prior models. Defining the data model in distinct layers helps us manage the complexity of design and focus as we refine our understanding of the problem space.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are three types of data models: Conceptual, Logical, and Physical. The conceptual model provides a high-level view of the data, defining the general entities and entity relationships using the language of the business or organization. The logical model adds attributes to these entities, providing a technology-agnostic foundation for a database design. The physical model assigns table names, column names, and data types to the entities and attributes defined in the prior models. Defining the data model in distinct layers helps us manage the complexity of design and focus as we refine our understanding of the problem space.</p>
<div style="background-color: #ffffcc; border: 2px solid #cccccc; padding: .5em; margin: .5em .5em 1em .5em;">This topic is a sub-set of my presentation later this week at Baton Rouge, <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/28/eventhome.aspx">SQL Saturday #28</a>. If you are planning on being in the area I urge you to sign up, there are going to be a wide range of speakers presenting on SQL and .Net development topics and so far it sounds like we have over 500 attendees (read: networking opportunities). My slides are posted up on <a href="http://tiernok.com/presentation.php">my website</a>.</div>
<h2>Building the Conceptual Model</h2>
<p>My approach is to start with the business drivers for the data and progress through external materials, technical inputs, and an analysis phase. Whether we are in a university environment, software development house, manufacturing company or non-profit organization, there is generally one key business driver. That driver has a business owner, technical or non-technical, and it is there that I prefer to start. Conversations with the business owner will often include less than specific terms and examples of competing services or existing data stores (think excel and MS Access) in the organization. Factors like maintainability, reliability, scalability, and so on will be mentioned in some cases, so we will want to document these if they come up. This provides the raw materials we need to build our data model.</p>
<h3>What is the purpose of [fill in the blank]?</h3>
<div style="text-align: center; color: #666666; float: right; margin: 1em;"><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/-0iJqUji9TzP6kINPqkyqw"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/conceptual/dogcatdinner.jpg" alt="Context and expectations are key" title="Context and expectations are key" style="width: 260px" /></a><br />Context and expectations are key<br />Unnamed Picture on <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/-0iJqUji9TzP6kINPqkyqw" title="See original on Picasa">Picasa</a></div>
<p>Start with the purpose of the project or initiative. As the business owner describes the purpose of the project, we collect the nouns and specific terms they use and how those words are related. A notepad can be sufficient but a small recorder is probably the best tool (especially if your memory and handwriting are less than stellar). The terms we collect during this conversation generally fall into three buckets: initial entities to populate a rough model with, attributes that may need to be analyzed in later steps, and existing materials/systems/projects/people to follow up with. In this step I often find it easier to deal with non-technical people, as a technical person will sometimes communicate the design they have started in their head rather than the original business case.</p>
<h3>What does the business do?</h3>
<p>It may not always be necessary to ask the business this (hopefully if you work there you already know the answer), but at a minimum it should be written somewhere near your other notes. The business provides context for the data and drives the relative importance of different terms and entities. It&#8217;s important to remember that one company&#8217;s definition of &#8220;customer&#8221; could be entirely different from another company&#8217;s. Knowing the context helps us determine how important the terms from the prior conversation are and the wide variety of contexts is the reason there isn&#8217;t one world-wide standard for the &#8220;Customer&#8221; entity.</p>
<div style="text-align: center; color: #666666; float: left; margin: 1em;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/miranda_jc/3406275289/"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/conceptual/sneakycat.png" alt="Evaluate outside influences" title="Evaluate outside influences" /></a><br />Outside influences can sneak up<br />Sneaky Cat on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/miranda_jc/3406275289/" title="See original on Flickr">Flickr</a></div>
<h3>About those other materials&#8230;</h3>
<p>Any additional materials, products, or people referenced in that first conversation need to be tracked down. Materials will expose a much more detailed list of potential data fields then you will hear in a conversation, competing products or products priced out of the organizations range will provide additional terminology and purpose, while other people will provide both a sounding board for the assumptions so far and a source of secondary translations and assumptions. The important part is that we all started with the same base story (the initial business owner) before getting this far, as that frames these conversations and investigations. And yes, I really want to use the word <em>context</em> again.</p>
<h3>What&#8217;s sneaking up on us?</h3>
<p>The last source of information we want to address is projects that are starting in the near future, strategic initiatives, and similar surprises waiting only a few weeks down the road. Going back to the business to ask about planned projects in the near future can often uncover additional information that will be critical to the model. Changes in business direction, assumptions of geographic growth or acquisitions, and even projects that are intended to tie into this data source can all mean the difference between a completed model and a redo of the modeling effort.</p>
<h3>Put it all together&#8230;</h3>
<p>So by now we should be able to put it all together, right? Well, maybe. Probably not.</p>
<p>Now that we have all of those raw inputs, all of those conversations, all of those identified terms and topics we need to start trying to fit it all into a cohesive structure. So as we start drawing pieces (and usually I am drawing all along) we are going to run into more questions, we are going to have moments where we stare dumbfounded at our whiteboards, and there will be a number of odd moments of clarity (generally in the shower or coffee line). </p>
<div style="text-align: center; color: #666666; float: right; margin: 0em 1em;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mcnutcase/2229434187/"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/conceptual/catbasket.jpg" alt="Turn the problem sideways" title="Turn the problem sideways" /></a><br />Turn the problem sideways<br />Cat in Basket on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mcnutcase/2229434187/" title="See original on Flickr">Flickr</a></div>
<p>This last step incorporates the &#8220;Analysis&#8221; phase that I mentioned above. This is where we look at all of the potential attributes we have collected (you kept a list to make the logical phase easier, right?) and consider them from multiple different directions.</p>
<p>As we look through our list of entities and potential attributes, we want to question them on the dimensions of time, availability, location/person, and categorization:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do we need to track the value as it changes over time?</li>
<li>Do we need to provide a mechanism to enter future values?</li>
<li>Do these values get deleted, flagged as inactive, or &#8230;?</li>
<li>Do different variations of the value exist based on Location? Language? Currency? Person viewing the data?</li>
<li>Can entities be re-categorized (ie, relationships changed)?</li>
<li>Can relationships/categorizations be duplicated? Many-to-Many? Time sensitive?</li>
</ul>
<p>These questions can often spark the creation of new entities or extra information to consider in later modeling efforts. This extra analysis (and the rigor with which we gathered information) is what brings everything together and, in my mind, is where our expertise and experience should shine. </p>
<h3>And Done-ish</h3>
<p>There will be a time when you have to call it done (for now). I probably spend the most time on the conceptual model because the clearer and better a fit it is, the easier it is to come back and start attaching attributes and to communicate amongst the business and other technical personnel. But even so, perfect is the enemy of good, so we want to reach good and call it a day.</p>
<h2>The Finished Conceptual Model</h2>
<p>At the point we call it &#8220;Finished [for now]&#8221;, we will have one or more diagrams that display the different entities and relationships, using business terms. We will also have a whole slew of notes on what those terms meant, other terms that were mentioned during the exploration (potential attributes, technical requirements, etc), and a partially worn out whiteboard. These our our deliverables from the conceptual modeling process and provide the foundation for our next steps.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/creating-a-conceptual-data-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
