<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>videos &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/videos/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Watch all the Tech·Ed North America 2011 SQL Server videos</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/watch-all-the-tech-ed-north-america-2011-sql-server-videos/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/watch-all-the-tech-ed-north-america-2011-sql-server-videos/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server denali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/05/watch-all-the-tech-ed-north-america-2011-sql-server-videos/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you missed Tech·Ed North America 2011, I have compiled a list of all the SQL Server videos for you.

Each one links directly to the video, have fun watching it all

Microsoft SQL Server Code-Named "Denali" AlwaysOn Series,Part 1: Introducing the&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you missed Tech·Ed North America 2011, I have compiled a list of all the SQL Server videos for you.</p>
<p>Each one links directly to the video, have fun watching it all</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI302">Microsoft SQL Server Code-Named &#8220;Denali&#8221; AlwaysOn Series,Part 1: Introducing the Next Generation High Availability Solution</a></strong><br />
Santosh Balasubramanian Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI302 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 1:15PM to 2:30PM<br />
In this session we talk about the new high availability solution that is being introduced in SQL Server code-named &#8220;Denali&#8221;. The session provides an overview of AlwaysOn and introduces the key new features and capabilities that will help businesses achieve the high availability SLA for mission…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI403">Building Scalable Database Solutions Using Microsoft SQL Azure Database Federations</a></strong><br />
Cihan Biyikoglu Database &amp; Business Intelligence 400 &#8211; Expert DBI403 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 3:00PM to 4:15PM</p>
<p>SQL Azure provides an information platform that you can easily provision,configure and use to power your cloud applications. In this session we explore the patterns and practices that help you develop and deploy applications that can exploit the full power of the elastic,highly available,and…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI207">Using Knowledge to Cleanse Data with Data Quality Services</a></strong><br />
Elad Ziklik Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI207 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 3:00PM to 4:15PM</p>
<p>SQL Server Data Quality Services (DQS) is a Knowledge-Driven Data Quality product aimed at the data stewards and IT professionals who seek to improve the quality of their business data. In this session,we describe the concept and main principles behind Data Quality Services from Microsoft,and demo…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI205">Top 10 Reasons to Upgrade to Microsoft SQL Server 2008/R2 Reporting Services</a></strong><br />
Teo Lachev Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI205 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 3:00PM to 4:15PM</p>
<p>Rich in demos,this session presents top reasons to upgrade to Microsoft SQL Server 2008 and SQL Server 2008 R2 versions of Reporting Services. Use this information to convince your boss that it&#8217;s time to upgrade and remove past limitations. If you already use these versions,you might discover…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI318">The T-SQL Cookbook: What&#8217;s Cool in Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 and New in SQL Server Code-Named &#8220;Denali&#8221;</a></strong><br />
Tobias Ternstrom Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI318 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 3:00PM to 4:15PM</p>
<p>In this session we walk through the new T-SQL-related features that are being delivered in the next version of SQL Server. We show off some cool demos as well as describe the use-cases that these language extensions enable.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI316">Microsoft SQL Server Beyond Relational Landscape: Current and Future</a></strong><br />
Michael Rys Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI316 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 4:45PM to 6:00PM</p>
<p>Many database applications today need to manage not only tabular relational data,but documents,images,objects such as spatial objects etc. In fact,80% or more of the data produced and stored are so-called unstructured documents and are often not stored in the database,but often need to be managed in…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI210">Getting Started with Cloud Business Intelligence</a></strong><br />
Pej Javaheri, Tharun Tharian Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI210 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 4:45PM to 6:00PM</p>
<p>The cloud has many possibilities and advantages for your Business Intelligence deployments,enhancing and even simplifying your on-premises environments. In this demo-packed session,we go over the capabilities available to you in Windows Azure to help you deploy,execute and enhance your Business…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/OSP205">Creating Self-Service Analytic BI Applications with Microsoft SharePoint 2010</a></strong><br />
Peter Myers Database &amp; Business Intelligence, Office &amp; SharePoint 200 &#8211; Intermediate OSP205 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 4:45PM to 6:00PM</p>
<p>SharePoint 2010 is the premier BI portal solution. In this session learn how business users can be empowered to create self-service analytic applications by harnessing the power of SharePoint. Topics cover an introduction to the Chart and Status List Web Parts and the three SharePoint service…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI307">Automating Database Migration to Microsoft SQL Server</a></strong><br />
Welly Lee Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI307 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 4:45PM to 6:00PM</p>
<p>Does your organization have Oracle,Sybase,MySQL or Access databases that you like to migrate to SQL Server or SQL Azure? Do you know that Microsoft offers a free tool to automate database migration? In this demo-heavy session,we examine how SQL Server Migration Assistant (SSMA) migrates other…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI330">Can Your BI Solution Scale?</a></strong><br />
Teo Lachev Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI330 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 4:45PM to 6:00PM</p>
<p>Your Business Intelligence solution is ready for prime-time but will it perform well? Join this session to learn techniques for testing the performance and scalability of Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) and Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS).</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI209">A Lap around Microsoft Business Intelligence</a></strong><br />
Pej Javaheri, Herain Oberoi Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI209 Day 1 May 16, 2011 from 1:15PM to 2:30PM</p>
<p>Familiar with the database functionality of Microsoft SQL Server or the collaboration functionality of Microsoft SharePoint,but have not had the chance to explore the broad and integrated Business Intelligence capabilities offered by across these products and Microsoft Excel? This session provides…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI204">Managing Master Data with MDS and Microsoft Excel</a></strong><br />
John McAllister Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI204 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 8:30AM to 9:45AM</p>
<p>Master Data Services (MDS) was released in Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 and enables organizations to do a better job of managing key data assets. In the next release of SQL Server,it will be even easier to manage data by using Excel as the user interface. In this session we cover the basics of MDS…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI206">What&#8217;s New in Microsoft SQL Server Code-Named &#8220;Denali&#8221; for SQL Server Analysis Services and PowerPivot</a></strong><br />
T.K. Anand, Ashvini Sharma Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI206 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 10:15AM to 11:30AM</p>
<p>In Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2,we introduced PowerPivot which is a self-service Business Intelligence experience that enables information workers to build,share and collaborate on their personal and team BI applications within the familiar environment of Excel and SharePoint. In SQL Server…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI208">Abundantly &#8220;Crescent&#8221;: Demos Galore</a></strong><br />
Sean Boon, Carolyn Chau, Sabrena McBride Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI208 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 3:15PM to 4:30PM</p>
<p>What is Microsoft project code-named &#8220;Crescent&#8221; really capable of? How can it address the needs of your business? This session covers a variety of demonstrations against REAL DATA,across various industry verticals,to enable you to see what&#8217;s possible when deploying this new technology. If you like…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI211">What’s New in Microsoft SQL Server Code-Named “Denali” for Reporting Services</a></strong><br />
Carolyn Chau Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI211 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 1:30PM to 2:45PM</p>
<p>Microsoft SQL Server code-named “Denali” introduces many new features and enhancements for both IT professionals and business users. This session provides an end-to-end introduction and demonstrations of all the new capabilities specific to Reporting Services including SharePoint…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI303">Microsoft StreamInsight: Introduction to Complex Event Processing with SQL Server 2008 R2 StreamInsight</a></strong><br />
Torsten Grabs Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI303 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 5:00PM to 6:15PM</p>
<p>Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 introduces StreamInsight,a comprehensive platform for building event-driven applications. While typical relational database applications are query-driven,event-driven applications are characterized by continuously arriving new data,continuous processing of the incoming…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI304">What&#8217;s New in Manageability for Microsoft SQL Server Code-Named &#8220;Denali&#8221;</a></strong><br />
Denny Cherry Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI304 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 1:30PM to 2:45PM</p>
<p>Microsoft SQL Server &#8220;Denali&#8221; has many new features and enhancements. With a focus on manageability,this session tours new features including Contained Databases,Distributed Replay Utility,User Defined Roles,SQL Management Studio enhancements,and PowerShell. The session is demo-intensive and…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI309">High Availability and Disaster Recovery Customer Panel: Architectures and Lessons Learned</a></strong><br />
Thomas Grohser, Prem Mehra, Sanjay Mishra, Ayad Shammout, David Smith, Michael Steineke Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI309 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 3:15PM to 4:30PM</p>
<p>This session covers real-life customer deployment scenarios to achieve high availability (99.99+) and disaster recovery (regional and distant),lessons learned,and associated best practices. The content is not merely coverage of available functions and features of Microsoft SQL Server,but based on…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI312">Columnstore Indexes Unveiled</a></strong><br />
Eric Hanson Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI312 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 8:30AM to 9:45AM</p>
<p>This talk describes a new data warehouse SQL query acceleration feature in Microsoft SQL Server code-named &#8220;Denali&#8221; based on a new type of index called the columnstore. This new index,combined with enhanced query processing features,improves data warehouse query performance by hundreds to thousands…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI313">Microsoft SQL Azure Advanced Administration: Backup,Restore and Database Management Strategies for Cloud Databases</a></strong><br />
David Robinson Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI313 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 5:00PM to 6:15PM</p>
<p>The cornerstone of any enterprise application is the ability to backup and restore data. In this session we focus on the various options available to application developers and administrators of SQL Azure applications for archiving and recovering database data. We look at the various scenarios in…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI323">Using Cloud (Microsoft SQL Azure) and PowerPivot to Deliver Data and Self-Service BI at Microsoft</a></strong><br />
Harinarayan Paramasivan, Diana Putnam, Sanjay Soni Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI323 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 1:30PM to 2:45PM</p>
<p>See a live demo of how Microsoft IT is distributing terabytes of data from the Enterprise Data Warehouse to various business and IT groups at Microsoft using SQL Azure cloud and on-premise platform. Learn about Data Services Layer (DSL) which is a distribution platform that provides a single…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI329">Killer Real-World PowerPivot Examples</a></strong><br />
Grant Paisley, Daniel Yu Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI329 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 5:00PM to 6:15PM</p>
<p>This session is jam packed with amazing PowerPivot report examples. This is *the* session to attend if you want to get the most out of PowerPivot visualizations. Essentially we look at multiple PowerPivot reports from different clients (Education,Retail,Banking,Airline) and show a variety of…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI332">All Up Data Warehouse: From SMP to Parallel Data Warehouse</a></strong><br />
Dandy Weyn Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI332 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 10:15AM to 11:30AM</p>
<p>Microsoft Data Warehousing brings you a solid offering that provides the right data warehousing solution for customer needs and workloads. In this session,learn about Reference Architectures using Fast Track Data Warehouse 3.0 and appliance-based implementations including Microsoft SQL Server…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI335">Advanced Business Intelligence Solutions Using Microsoft Excel + Excel Services</a></strong><br />
Kevin Fan, Manpratap Suri Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI335 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 10:15AM to 11:30AM</p>
<p>Learn how you can utilize the power of Excel and Excel Services BI features to easily create a compelling BI solution using the tools you already know.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI402">Performance Tuning and Optimization in Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 and SQL Server Code-Named &#8220;Denali&#8221;</a></strong><br />
Adam Machanic, Mike Wachal Database &amp; Business Intelligence 400 &#8211; Expert DBI402 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 3:15PM to 4:30PM</p>
<p>Understanding when to search for performance problems and how to tune your queries to correct them is one of the most persistent questions that face DBAs. Join Adam and Mike to explore a methodology for discovering and improving performance problems. Along the way you&#8217;ll see examples that take…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI407">Best Practices for Building Tier 1 Enterprise Business Intelligence Solutions with Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services</a></strong><br />
Adam Jorgensen Database &amp; Business Intelligence 400 &#8211; Expert DBI407 Day 2 May 17, 2011 from 8:30AM to 9:45AM</p>
<p>The purpose of this session is to highlight issues,best practices and lessons learned from a select group of SQL Server Enterprise customers. Some example of the customer projects we cover in this session: AdCenter and their 6TB SSAS environment: two 3TB OLAP cubes,XBox Live and their planned…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI201">BI Power Hour</a></strong><br />
Pej Javaheri, Carolyn Chau, Manpratap Suri, Allan Folting, Matt Masson, Julie Strauss Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI201 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 5:00PM to 6:15PM</p>
<p>The legacy continues. The Microsoft Business Intelligence team is excited to once again present the BI PowerHour. In this entertaining session,we dazzle you with new demonstrations that expose the lighter side of Business Intelligence exposing the flexibility and power of the Microsoft BI Platform.…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI203">Introducing the Next Generation Design Tools for Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services</a></strong><br />
Julie Strauss Database &amp; Business Intelligence 200 &#8211; Intermediate DBI203 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 10:15AM to 11:30AM</p>
<p>Microsoft SQL Server code-named “Denali” brings the simplicity and power of the PowerPivot technologies to corporate BI,and at the same time drives forward the PowerPivot self-service capabilities that we introduced in SQL Server 2008 R2. We give you a tour of building corporate BI Semantic Models…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI301">Microsoft SQL Server Reference Architecture and Appliances</a></strong><br />
D. Britton Johnston, Bernardo Zamora Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI301 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 5:00PM to 6:15PM</p>
<p>Learn what are the current and future SQL Server Appliances and References Architectures that allow customers to deploy OLTP,DW,BI and Database consolidation solutions in a very short time,with all the components configured and optimized. These appliances include all the Hardware,Software and…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI308">Fast Track Data Warehouse Version 3.0 New Features and Best Practices</a></strong><br />
Michael Bassett, Anjan Das, Jim Hautala Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI308 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 1:30PM to 2:45PM</p>
<p>This session depicts some of the new features and architecture changes present in version 3.0 of SQL Server Fast Track Data Warehousing. Best practices derived from HP&#8217;s extensive joint testing with Microsoft during the development of its current Fast Track reference architectures are also detailed.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI314">Microsoft SQL Azure Performance Considerations and Troubleshooting</a></strong><br />
Henry Zhang Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI314 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 1:30PM to 2:45PM</p>
<p>Become an expert on SQL Azure by learning how to best utilize the cloud database platform to your advantage. We show you the unique performance considerations to keep in mind when architecting your SQL Azure application. Learn the inside tips and tricks to quickly identify performance…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI315">Microsoft SQL Server in Virtualization and Private Cloud</a></strong><br />
Guy Bowerman, Darmadi Komo Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI315 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 10:15AM to 11:30AM</p>
<p>Come and learn how SQL Server fits into your company&#8217;s strategy on virtualization and private cloud. We talk talk about SQL Server feautures that are relevant in virtualization and private cloud deployment,why Hyper-V is better for SQL Server virtualization,the upcoming HP Database Consolidation…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI317">What’s New in Microsoft SQL Server Code-Named “Denali” for SQL Server Integration Services</a></strong><br />
Matt Masson Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI317 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 3:15PM to 4:30PM</p>
<p>This session shows off the new features of Microsoft SQL Server Integration Services in SQL Server code-named “Denali”. Using customer scenarios,we demonstrate the migration process and highlight the benefits of the new SSIS server architecture. We cover the many improvements made to increase…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI320">Upsizing and Modernizing with the Microsoft BI Stack and Fast Track Data Warehouse</a></strong><br />
Kevin Cornett, Ilan Wajsman Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI320 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 8:30AM to 9:45AM</p>
<p>In 2010,Stein Mart deployed a Microsoft SQL Server Fast Track Data Warehouse and launched an aggressive effort to become an information-based culture leveraging the Microsoft Business Intelligence stack. This session provides a detailed description of the infrastructure as it existed before and…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI325">End-to-End PerformancePoint Services</a></strong><br />
Peter Myers Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI325 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 3:15PM to 4:30PM</p>
<p>PerformancePoint Services 2010 (PPS) is the next generation performance management application from Microsoft. It delivers a design environment targeted at power users for creating and deploying sophisticated Key Performance Indicator (KPI),scorecard,report and dashboard definitions. The session…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI328">Integrating Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services with Microsoft SharePoint Technologies</a></strong><br />
Prash Shirolkar Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI328 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 1:30PM to 2:45PM</p>
<p>Deep dive into how and why to integrate SQL Server code-named “Denali” Reporting Services (SSRS) with SharePoint 2010,including an overview of the new claims-aware shared service architecture,IT experience,performance enhancements,and end user functionality.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI331">Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services Design Challenges</a></strong><br />
Peter Myers Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI331 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 8:30AM to 9:45AM</p>
<p>Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services allows developers to produces cubes which,when designed well,can deliver intuitive,feature-rich and highly-performant data models. In many ways they are a key component to delivering Business Intelligence within the enterprise. To be clear,this session…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI334">Let’s Get Visual: The Art of Report Design</a></strong><br />
Paul Turley Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI334 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 3:15PM to 4:30PM</p>
<p>Do your users have the same old,mundane table reports they’ve been using for decades? Stop living in the past and make your reports pop. Learn to use design patterns,best practices and visuals that pack more usable information into fewer,more usable reports. Use Reporting Services and other…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI336">Innovative Storage and Data Management Strategies to Power Your Microsoft Enterprise Applications</a></strong><br />
Alex Jauch, Robert Quimbey Database &amp; Business Intelligence 300 &#8211; Advanced DBI336 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 1:30PM to 2:45PM</p>
<p>In this session,hear about innovative storage and data management strategies that are being used by leading organizations around the world to build highly efficient,flexible and reliable IT infrastructure to support their business-critical enterprise software including Microsoft Exchange…</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI404">Microsoft SQL Server Code-Named &#8220;Denali&#8221; AlwaysOn Series,Part 2: Building a Mission-Critical High Availability Solution Using AlwaysOn</a></strong><br />
Justin Erickson Database &amp; Business Intelligence 400 &#8211; Expert DBI404 Day 3 May 18, 2011 from 8:30AM to 9:45AM</p>
<p>In this session we walk you through the steps to deploy a high availability solution using AlwaysOn. This is a demo-heavy presentation and the experts from the product development team walk you through a high availability solution architecture and deployment,explain key architectural concepts and…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/watch-all-the-tech-ed-north-america-2011-sql-server-videos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Collection of SQL Server Videos on Channel 9</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/new-collection-of-sql-server/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/new-collection-of-sql-server/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[denali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/03/new-collection-of-sql-server/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are 13 new videos on channel 9 posted about SQL Server.  The non-marketing videos (by engineering PMs) give customers peek into the goals and visions why certain SQL Server features were decided and implemented. Below is a list with a little blurb&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are 13 new videos on channel 9 posted about SQL Server.  The non-marketing videos (by engineering PMs) give customers peek into the goals and visions why certain SQL Server features were decided and implemented. Below is a list with a little blurb what the video is about.</p>
<p>They have the following formats available</p>
<p>High Quality WMV (PC, XBox, MCE)<br />
MP3 (Audio only)<br />
Medium Quality WMV (Lo-band, Mobile)<br />
High Quality MP4 (iPad, WP7)<br />
MP4 (iPod, Zune HD)</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/Upgrade-Your-Database">Upgrade Your Database</a></strong><br />
Joe Yong<br />
Learn improvements/enhancements on upgrade experience for SQL Server from Joe Yong, Senior Program Manager from SQL Server China Research &amp; Development Manageability team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Data-Programmability-Tools">Data Programmability Tools </a></strong><br />
Krzysztof Kozielczyk<br />
Learn about the vision of database programmability tools for SQL Server &#8220;Denali&#8221; from Krzysztof Kozielczyk, Program Manager from SQL Server Programmability team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Appliance">SQL Server appliance</a></strong><br />
Britt Johnston<br />
Learn the upcoming SQL Server appliances from Britt Johnston, Principal Group Manager from SQL Server Appliance Engineering team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/Parallel-Data-Warehouse">Parallel Data Warehouse</a></strong><br />
Dandy Weyn<br />
Learn massive parallel architecture of SQL Server Parallel Data Warehouse from Dandy Weyn, Senior Technical Product Manager from SQL Server marketing team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Virtualization">SQL Server virtualization</a></strong><br />
Guy Bowerman<br />
Learn how decisions were made for SQL Server virtualization from Guy Bowerman, Senior Program Manager from SQL Server Engine team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Security">SQL Server security</a></strong><br />
Il-Sung Lee<br />
Learn security &amp; compliance features for SQL Server from Il-Sung Lee, Senior Program Manager from SQL Server Engine Security team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-AlwaysOn">SQL Server AlwaysOn</a></strong><br />
Justin Erickson<br />
Learn about AlwaysOn &#8211; HA/DR improvements/enhancements for SQL Server from Justin Erickson, Senior Program Manager from SQL Server Engine team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Backup-Compression">SQL Server backup compression</a></strong><br />
Kevin Farlee<br />
Learn about the choices made for SQL Server backup compression from Kevin Farlee, Senior Program Manager from SQL Server Storage Engine team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Integration-Services">SQL Server Integration Services</a></strong><br />
Kevin McGuire<br />
Learn improvements/enhancements on SQL Server &#8220;Denali&#8221; Integration Services from Kevin McGuire, Principal Architect from SQL Server Integration Services team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Non-Relational">SQL Server Non-Relational</a></strong><br />
Michael Rys<br />
Learn improvements/enhancements on SQL Server non-relational features from Michael Rys, Principal Program Manager from SQL Server Engine team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-CLR">SQL Server CLR</a></strong><br />
RobAnn Mateja<br />
Learn improvements/enhancements on CLR for SQL Server from RobAnn Mateja, Senior Program Manager from SQL Server Engine team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Data-Compression">SQL Server Data Compression</a></strong><br />
Sunil Agarwal<br />
Learn data compression for SQL Server from Sunil Agarwal, Principal Program Manager from SQL Server Engine Storage team.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/SQL-Server-Manageability">SQL Server Manageability</a></strong><br />
Vinod Jagannathan<br />
Learn manageability vision for SQL Server from Vinod Jagannathan, Senior Program Manager from SQL Server Manageability team.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/new-collection-of-sql-server/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
