<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sql friday &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/sql-friday/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 18</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-19/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-19/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 12:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/04/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-19/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: Backup Log with Truncate_Only Brent Ozar (without Hulk hands) explains in a video why backup log with truncate_only is a dangerous command with serious consequences. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlserverpedia.com/blog/sql-server-management/backup-log-with-truncate_only/">Backup Log with Truncate_Only</a></strong><br />
Brent Ozar (without Hulk hands) explains in a video why backup log with truncate_only is a dangerous command with serious consequences. Learn why this might not be the best way to free up drive space on your SQL Server.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.sqlskills.com/BLOGS/PAUL/post/Weekly-survey-does-size-really-matter-or-is-it-what-you-do-with-it.aspx">does size really matter &#8211; or is it what you do with it?</a></strong><br />
Paul Randal has a survey on his website: &#8220;I&#8217;m interested in the physical layout of your databases. I&#8217;ve got four surveys, for a variety of database sizes. Please vote multiple times in each survey, as you see fit&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andrew_kelly/archive/2009/04/10/how-dirty-are-your-reads.aspx">How Dirty are your Reads?</a></strong><br />
Andrew Kelly asks: &#8220;are dirty reads overused or even abused” by the average shop these days?&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/louis_davidson/archive/2009/04/12/requirements-vs-architecture.aspx">Requirements vs Architecture</a></strong><br />
Louis Davidson has a nice post, he asks: &#8220;Can you turn off the “Get ‘er done” part of your mind when you are doing requirements, or do you find that you really really want to start building software well before you really understand the entire problem?&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/aaron_bertrand/archive/2009/04/15/sql-server-2008-sp1-cumulative-update-1-is-available.aspx">SQL Server 2008 SP1 Cumulative Update 1 is available!</a></strong><br />
Aaron Bertrand tells us that if you were among those who installed CU4 for SQL Server 2008, then installed SP1, you may not know that you lost some of the fixes that came with CU4</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SqlInTheWild/~3/mP2NcDDRCVw/">Developers vs DBAs</a></strong><br />
Gail writes: &#8220;I was listening to a podcast on nHibernate this morning. Most of it was very good, but there was one section that absolutly made me see red.</p>
<p>The guest on the show was asked how the DBAs felt about the use of nHibernate for a new app on an existing (old) database. The reply essentially was &#8216;We haven&#8217;t told them and we’re not going to tell them.'&#8221;</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 17</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-18/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-18/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 13:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/04/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-18/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show, the Good Friday edition. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: Updated Errors may occur after configuring Analysis Services to use Kerberos authentication on Advanced Encryption Standard Aware Operating Systems The PSS [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show, the Good Friday edition.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/04/03/errors-may-occur-after-configuring-analysis-services-to-use-kerberos-authentication-on-advanced-encryption-standard-aware-operating-systems.aspx">Updated Errors may occur after configuring Analysis Services to use Kerberos authentication on Advanced Encryption Standard Aware Operating Systems</a></strong><br />
The  PSS SQL Server Engineers explain what causes this, here is just a part of the post</p>
<blockquote><p>The Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services support team has seen an increasing number of issues involving errors when attempting to execute queries against or deploy databases to instances of Analysis Services 2005 and Analysis Services 2008 that are configured for Kerberos authentication and running on Windows 2008 Server or Windows Vista. This note provides information regarding the errors that have been reported and investigated.</p>
<p>What we&#8217;ve found is that when a client application is running on an operating system that is Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) aware (i.e. Windows Vista and Windows 2008 Server) and connects to an Analysis Services server that is running on an operating system that is AES aware then one of the following error return values or error messages may surface.</p>
<p>0X80090302<br />
SEC_E_NOT_SUPPORTED<br />
The requested Function is not supported</p>
<p>0x8009030f<br />
SEC_E_MESSAGE_ALTERED<br />
The message or signature supplied for verification has been altered</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BrentOzar-SqlServerDba/~3/OGJVyaL6OF8/">Free SQL Server DBA Training Videos</a></strong><br />
Brent Ozar shows us some links to <strong>SQL Server DBA Tutorial Podcasts</strong> and also <strong>Free Online SQL Server Training Events</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/04/08/the-3-things-you-need-to-know-to-install-sql-2005-on-windows-2008-cluster.aspx">The 3 Things you Need to Know to Install SQL 2005 on Windows 2008 Cluster</a></strong><br />
The PSS SQL Server Engineers explain what we need to know to install SQL Server 2005 on a Windows 2008 Cluster</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SqlFool/~3/Xlk6dqsXROM/">Page Splitting &amp; Rollbacks</a></strong><br />
Michelle Ufford shows us that when you have a lot of rollbacks you could have page splits and not be aware of it</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/04/09/sql-server-2008-sp1-and-cumulative-updates-explained.aspx">SQL Server 2008 SP1 and Cumulative Updates Explained</a></strong><br />
Does SQL Server 2008 SP1 contain the hotfixes that were included in Cumulative Update 4? good question, the PSS SQL Server Engineers explain that SQL Server 2008 SP1 does contain some fixes in CU4 for SQL Server 2008 RTM. There is a table in the post so make sure that you take a look</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-18/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 16</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-17/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-17/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 15:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/04/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-17/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. I skipped last week because of some mysterious reason. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: The death of datetime? Bart Duncan explains why you should almost always use DateTimeOffset instead of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
I skipped last week because of some mysterious reason. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/bartd/archive/2009/03/31/the-death-of-datetime.aspx">The death of datetime?</a></strong><br />
Bart Duncan explains why you should almost always use DateTimeOffset instead of Datetime</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic/archive/2009/03/30/who-is-active-v8-40-now-with-delta-power.aspx">Who is Active? v8.40 &#8211; Now With Delta Power!</a></strong><br />
Adam Machanic has updated his Who is Active with a huge number of changes, fixes, and enhancements</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BrentOzar-SqlServerDba/~3/iMGDbC6nyLE/">SQL Server DBA Interview: Kendal Van Dyke</a></strong><br />
Brent Ozar interviews Kendal Van Dyke about SQL, RAID, Blogging etc</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/03/30/sqldumper-unable-to-generate-mdmp-files-in-sql-server-2008-failover-clusters.aspx">SQLDumper unable to generate mdmp files in SQL Server 2008 Failover clusters</a></strong><br />
SQLDumper utility is used by various components of the product to generate and save diagnostic information in the form of mini-dump and other log files. You will normally find the output files [with extension .mdmp, .txt and .log] created by sqldumper.exe in the LOG folder of the specific instance for the Database Engine.<br />
If you have  SQL Server 2008 failover cluster installations you might be having a problem that prevents these important files from getting created </p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblogcasts.com/blogs/tonyrogerson/archive/2009/04/01/sql-server-technical-rollup-lots-of-useful-documents-news-events-and-new-kb-articles.aspx">SQL Server Technical Rollup &#8211; Lots of Useful Documents, News, Events and New KB articles</a></strong><br />
Tony Rogerson has compiled a nice list of useful documents, news, events and new KB articles</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-17/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 15</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-16/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-16/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 21:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/03/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-16/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: A DBA utility database in every SQL Server instance? Linchi Shea writes: I was reading Louis Davidson’s post earlier today, and what he said below [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/linchi_shea/archive/2009/03/16/a-dba-utility-database-in-every-sql-server-instance.aspx">A DBA utility database in every SQL Server instance?</a></strong><br />
Linchi Shea writes: I was reading Louis Davidson’s post earlier today, and what he said below caught my attention:</p>
<blockquote><p>I am a big believer in having the database be as self contained as possible, so I try to put [maintenance] objects and such in the database, typically in a schema named utility.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is different from what I typically do, and got me wondering how people out there managing their maintenance objects. I typically store all the maintenance objects in a dedicated database on every SQL Server instance across the enterprise</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/03/17/sql-server-what-is-a-cold-dirty-or-clean-buffer.aspx"><br />
SQL Server: What is a COLD, DIRTY or CLEAN Buffer?</a></strong><br />
What is clean buffer? What is cold buffer cache? The PSS SQL Server Engineers explain the difference</p>
<p><strong><br />
<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/alexander_kuznetsov/archive/2009/03/17/set-based-calculation-of-products-of-several-numbers.aspx">Set based calculation of products of several numbers</a></strong><br />
Alexander Kuznetsov shows us how we can use use SUM to calculate the sum of several numbers, but you cannot directly use set-based logic to calculate a product. Yet there is a very simple trick – you can use EXP(SUM(LOG(…))) and get a product of several numbers without a loop</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-16/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 14</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-15/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-15/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 17:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/03/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-15/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: SQL Server 2008 Auditing Resources Lara Rubbelke points us to some good SQL Server 2008 Auditing Resources Spatial Indexes in SP1, almost no hints required [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/lara_rubbelke/archive/2009/03/07/sql-server-2008-auditing-resources.aspx">SQL Server 2008 Auditing Resources</a></strong><br />
Lara Rubbelke points us to some good SQL Server 2008 Auditing Resources</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.sqlskills.com/BLOGS/BOBB/post.aspx?id=27658d6b-b6dc-47d4-8fcb-9540e7b94f0c">Spatial Indexes in SP1, almost no hints required</a></strong><br />
Bob Beauchemin is letting us know that with SQL Server 2008 Service pack 1 Spatial Indexes require almost no hints at all</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/alexander_kuznetsov/archive/2009/03/08/summarizing-previous-posts-about-defensive-database-programming.aspx">Summarizing previous posts about defensive database programming</a></strong><br />
Alexander Kuznetsov summarizes his previous posts about defensive database programming and also gives you all the links to the previous posts</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/03/09/how-to-use-computed-columns-to-improve-query-performance.aspx">How to use computed columns to improve query performance</a></strong><br />
The PSS SQL Server Engineers  show you how you can use computed columns to improve query performance</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/tibor_karaszi/archive/2009/03/09/do-you-have-instant-file-initialization.aspx">Do you have Instant File Initialization?</a></strong><br />
Tibor Karaszi explains what Instant File Initialization is and why it matters</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/arnie_rowland/archive/2009/03/09/is-it-time-for-sql-server-to-have-isolated-transactions.aspx">Is it time for SQL Server to have Isolated Transactions?</a></strong><br />
Arnie Rowland suggests that there is a need for a completely ‘Isolated Transaction’. That is, a transaction that can be started in the midst of a ‘regular’ transaction (parent), and that will be durable regardless of the outcome of the parent transaction. Using this ‘Isolated Transaction’, once a commit occurs, even a rollback of the parent transaction will not undo the saved work. The activity log is properly persisted and durable.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/louis_davidson/archive/2009/03/13/granting-rights-to-all-objects-in-a-database.aspx">Granting rights to all objects in a database</a></strong><br />
Louis Davidson shows us a cool way to grant rights to all objects in a database</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-15/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 14</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-14/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-14/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2009 15:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/03/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-14/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: How To Get High Quality Information About Query Performance Elisabeth Redei shows us how you can use the profiler, dynamic management views and SQLNexus to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/elisabeth_redei/archive/2009/03/01/how-to-get-high-quality-information-about-query-performance.aspx">How To Get High Quality Information About Query Performance</a></strong><br />
Elisabeth Redei shows us how you can use the profiler, dynamic management views and SQLNexus to get high quality information about your query performance</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/03/03/how-it-works-almost-everything-you-wanted-to-know-about-the-sql-server-2005-2008-performance-counter-collection-components.aspx">How It Works: Almost Everything You Wanted To Know About The SQL Server (2005, 2008) Performance Counter Collection Components</a></strong><br />
The PSS SQL Server Engineers have a post about how the Performance Counter Collection Components work</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/03/04/sparse-file-errors-1450-or-665-due-to-file-fragmentation-fixes-and-workarounds.aspx">Sparse File Errors: 1450 or 665 due to file fragmentation: Fixes and Workarounds</a></strong><br />
The PSS SQL Server Engineers have a blogpost showing you what they fixed in regards to Sparse File Errors: 1450 or 665 due to file fragmentation</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheHobt/~3/AehfIxdP4uc/sql-server-and-null-values-revisited.html">SQL Server And NULL Values, Revisited</a></strong><br />
Do you love or do you hate NULLs, Are you scared of NULLs? Aaron Alton has a nice post about NULLs&#8230;.and don&#8217;t be scared of NULLs</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://itknowledgeexchange.techtarget.com/sql-server/steps-to-troubleshoot-connections-to-your-sql-server/">Steps to Troubleshoot Connections to your SQL Server</a></strong>Denny Cherry outlines some thoubleshooting steps that people should take in order to find out what the problem is with connecting to SQL Server.</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-14/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 13</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-13/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-13/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 12:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-13/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: Is CHECKDB A Necessity? I&#8217;m often asked by professionals whether CheckDB is still recommended on SQL2k8. SQL is calculating a checksum to avoid physical page [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/02/20/sql-server-is-checkdb-a-necessity.aspx">Is CHECKDB A Necessity?</a></strong><br />
I&#8217;m often asked by professionals whether CheckDB is still recommended on SQL2k8.  SQL is calculating a checksum to avoid physical page corruption since 2k5. However in my experience (starting with SQL 7.0) I’ve never been able to clearly say that CheckDB is not necessary .. Does anyone have a good advice? Read the post to find out the answer</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/joe_chang/archive/2009/02/21/run-time-execution-plan-options.aspx">Run-time Execution Plan Options</a></strong><br />
Joe Chang made a post and hes sks &#8220;What are the top core SQL Server engine performance issues today, after all the improvements that have gone into 2005 and 2008? (I am excluding matters beyond the power of Microsoft, like eliminating bad developers.)&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheHobt/~3/yC00L4Ps7o0/enabling-data-compression-by-default-in.html">Enabling Data Compression By Default in a SQL Server 2008 Database</a></strong><br />
Aaron Alton show us how you could have every table in your database have data compression on by default. Of course he also warns you that this is not necessarily  a good thing</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/paul_nielsen/archive/2009/02/24/sql-in-the-cloud.aspx">SQL in the Cloud</a></strong>  and <strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/denis_gobo/archive/2009/02/25/12206.aspx">SQL Server In The Cloud Vaporware Or Inevitable?</a></strong><br />
Two links dealing with SQL Server in the cloud and if it will happen, see also our poll here: <strong><a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=17&amp;t=4736">Poll: Your Database in The Cloud?</a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheHobt/~3/HuP8wH5GltI/always-test-your-assertions-calendar.html">Always Test Your Assertions – Calendar Tables vs. Table Valued Functions</a></strong><br />
Aaron Alton shows us performance differences between Calendar Tables and Table Valued Functions</p>
<p>And this week we have a bonus link, it is not SQL Server but MySQL, a very interesting post</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://bret.appspot.com/entry/how-friendfeed-uses-mysql">How FriendFeed uses MySQL to store schema-less data</a></strong><br />
Bret Taylor writes: We use MySQL for storing all of the data in FriendFeed. Our database has grown a lot as our user base has grown. We now store over 250 million entries and a bunch of other data, from comments and &#8220;likes&#8221; to friend lists.</p>
<p>As our database has grown, we have tried to iteratively deal with the scaling issues that come with rapid growth. We did the typical things, like using read slaves and memcache to increase read throughput and sharding our database to improve write throughput. However, as we grew, scaling our existing features to accomodate more traffic turned out to be much less of an issue than adding new features.</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-13/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 12</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-12/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-12/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 13:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-12/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for another episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: Understanding backups and log-related Trace Flags in SQL Server 2000/2005 and 2008 Kimberly Tripp is giving a play by play from 2000 to 2005/2008 to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for another episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.sqlskills.com/BLOGS/KIMBERLY/post/Understanding-the-Transaction-log.aspx">Understanding backups and log-related Trace Flags in SQL Server 2000/2005 and 2008</a></strong><br />
Kimberly Tripp is giving a play by play from 2000 to 2005/2008 to discuss the differences and what&#8217;s changed and why those changes were significant. The biggest changes were between 2000 and 2005.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/louis_davidson/archive/2009/02/16/business-rule-enforcement.aspx">Business Rule Enforcement</a></strong><br />
Louis Davidson explains how to enforce business rules and what the difficulty is</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jonathan_kehayias/archive/2009/02/17/linq-to-sql-the-ongoing-developer-dba-debate.aspx">LINQ to SQL: The ongoing Developer/DBA debate</a></strong><br />
Jonathan Kehayias shows us what he thinks of LINQ to SQL</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic/archive/2009/02/18/who-is-active-v7-30.aspx">Who is Active? v7.30</a></strong><br />
Adam Machanic has released the latest version of his <em>Who is Active</em> script. Who is Active? is a comprehensive DMV-based monitoring script, designed to tell you at a glance what processes are active on your SQL Server and what they&#8217;re up to. It has a number of optional features so that you can get results quickly, or monitor deeply, depending on your needs when you happen to be using the script. </p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.karaszi.com/SQLServer/util_sp_indexinfo.asp">Sp_indexinfo has been updated</a></strong><br />
Tibor Karaszi has updated his Sp_indexinfo procedure<br />
This procedure will give you the following info:</p>
<ul>
<li>What indexes exists for a particular table or for each table in the database</li>
<li>Clustered, non-clustered or heap</li>
<li>Columns in the index</li>
<li>Included columns in the index</li>
<li>Unique or nonunique</li>
<li>Number rows in the table</li>
<li>Space usage</li>
<li>How frequently the indexes has been used</li>
<li>Any obvious indexes I should add?</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SqlFool/~3/J2HQOSyRsf8/">Digging Around in SQL Internals &#8211; View Page Data</a></strong><br />
Michelle Ufford wrote a post about using DBCC Page and sys.system_internals_allocation_units to view page data</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/02/19/how-to-copy-dts-2000-packages-between-servers-and-from-sql-2000-to-sql-2005-and-sql-2008.aspx">How to copy DTS 2000 packages between servers (and from SQL 2000 to SQL 2005 and SQL 2008)</a></strong></p>
<p>The PSS SQL Server Engineers show us how to migrate SQL Server 2000 DTS packages to a SQL 2005 Server without upgrading them, thus leaving them as legacy DTS 2000 packages within SQL 2005</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SqlInTheWild/~3/rv7z9KDR6kQ/">Estimated and Actual execution plan revisited</a></strong><br />
Gail Shaw explains why the terms ‘estimated execution plan’ and ‘actual execution plan’ are perhaps a little bit misleading.</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-12/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 11</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-11/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-11/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 17:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-11/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here we are with another mesmerizing episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land: All indexes are unique Gail Shaw tells us about the uniquefier which makes indexes unique Performance impact: a large number of virtual [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here we are with another mesmerizing episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlinthewild.co.za/index.php/2009/02/09/all-indexes-are-unique/">All indexes are unique</a></strong><br />
Gail Shaw tells us about the uniquefier which makes indexes unique</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/linchi_shea/archive/2009/02/09/performance-impact-a-large-number-of-virtual-log-files-part-i.aspx">Performance impact: a large number of virtual log files – Part I</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/linchi_shea/archive/2009/02/12/performance-impact-a-large-number-of-virtual-log-files-part-ii.aspx">Performance impact: a large number of virtual log files – Part II</a></strong><br />
Linchi Shea&#8217;s two part post explores two questions<br />
   1. Is a large number of VLFs in a transaction log still a significant performance factor in SQL Server 2008?<br />
   2. Does a large number of VLFs have an adversely impact on application-related operations such as INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE?</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jonathan_kehayias/archive/2009/02/09/released-sql-server-2008-extended-events-manager-build-1-0-3-114-stable.aspx">Released: SQL Server 2008 Extended Events Manager</a></strong><br />
Jonathan Kehayias writes: This started out as a pet project in August 2008 when I decided that if I was ever going to get good use out of Extended Events in SQL Server 2008, I needed to be able to see the layout of the metadata graphically.  What started out as a simple TreeView that displayed the MetaData in a sensible (at least to me) manner slowly began to transform into a complete application that could build and manage Extended Event Sessions as well. </p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheHobt/~3/v-RnN0rVeJo/bit-vs-char1-in-sql-server.html">Bit vs. Char(1) in SQL Server</a></strong><br />
Aaron Alton shows us some reasons why bits rock, and I agree with him</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/SqlFool/~3/4iOti0-0PaQ/">Estimating Rows per Page</a></strong><br />
Michelle Ufford shows us some code which we can use to estimate rows per page</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/psssql/archive/2009/02/11/how-it-works-file-stream-compression-with-backup-restore.aspx">How It Works: File Stream Compression with Backup/Restore</a></strong><br />
The PSS SQL Server Engineers show how File Stream Compression compression works with Backup/Restor</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week Episode 10</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-10/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-10/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 09:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql friday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-10/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here we are with another fascinating episode of the SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week show. I can&#8217;t believe it is week 10 already, if I continue like this I will be retired soon&#8230;..or just tired without the re prefix. Here is what I found interesting this past week in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here we are with another fascinating episode of the <strong>SQL Friday, The Best SQL Server Links Of The Past Week</strong> show. I can&#8217;t believe it is week 10 already, if I continue like this I will be retired soon&#8230;..or just tired without the re prefix.<br />
Here is what I found interesting this past week in SQL Land:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.straightpathsql.com/blog/2009/1/31/shrinking-is-a-popular-topic.html">Shrinking is a popular topic&#8230;</a></strong><br />
Mike explains some concepts about shrinking and the transaction log</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/linchi_shea/archive/2009/01/31/string-comparison-binary-vs-dictionary.aspx">String comparison: binary vs. dictionary</a></strong><br />
Linchi Shea writes: t is well known that you get better performance if you compare two strings in a binary collation than in a dictionary collation. But is the performance difference significant enough to warrant the use of an explicit COLLATE clause in the string comparison expression?</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/allen_white/archive/2009/02/01/get-a-quick-review-of-sql-server-information.aspx">Get a Quick Review of SQL Server Information</a></strong><br />
Allen White shows us how you can use PowerShell and SMO to get some information about your SQL Servers</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/greg_low/archive/2009/02/02/much-ado-about-logins-and-sids.aspx">Much ado about logins and SIDs</a></strong><br />
Greg Low explains what you have to do to SQL Server logins that need to be moved between servers</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://itknowledgeexchange.techtarget.com/sql-server/back-to-basics-clustered-vs-nonclustered-indexes-whats-the-difference/">Back To Basics: Clustered vs NonClustered Indexes; what’s the difference?</a></strong><br />
Denny Cherry highlights some differences between Clustered and  NonClustered Indexes</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://thehobt.blogspot.com/2009/02/what-heck-is-sql-server-hobt-anyway.html">What the heck is a SQL Server HOBT, anyway?</a></strong><br />
Aaron Alton explains what a HOBT aka Heap Or B-Tree is, so we are not talking about hobbits</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlfool.com/2009/02/bitwise-operations/">T-SQL Bitwise Operations</a></strong><br />
Having written about this myself a while back here: http://sqlblog.com/blogs/denis_gobo/archive/2007/05/29/test.aspx<br />
It was nice to see that Michelle Ufford did a nice job of explaining Bitwise Operations in T-SQL</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/denis_gobo/archive/2009/02/05/11743.aspx">Some Simple Code To Show The Difference Between Newid And Newsequentialid</a></strong><br />
Someone who thinks he is me  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> wrote a post showing why NEWID() is Evil</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://sqlinthewild.co.za/index.php/2009/02/06/index-columns-selectivity-and-inequality-predicates/">Index columns, selectivity and inequality predicates</a></strong><br />
Gail Shaw shows us how how selectivity and index column order affect inequality predicates.</p>
<p></p>
<p>That is it for this week, I will tag the weekly posts with <strong>SQL Friday</strong> in case you want to see the whole archive in the future</p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-friday-the-best-sql-server-links-of-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
