<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>review &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/review/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 11:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization cookbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After my review of Tableau Dashboard Cookbook, I read another book about Tableau, namely Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook by Ashutosh Nandeshwar. The book is published by Packt but I am relieved to say this time there were no significant editing issues. In fact it is quite well written and as far as I could tell [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">After my review of <a href="/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/">Tableau Dashboard Cookbook</a>, I read another book about Tableau, namely <a href="http://amzn.to/1RzPjkU">Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook</a> by Ashutosh Nandeshwar. The book is published by Packt but I am relieved to say this time there were no significant editing issues. In fact it is quite well written and as far as I could tell there were no spelling mistakes or typos (yeah those things can really bug me out when reading a book).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The book promises “Over 70 recipes for creating visual stories with your data using Tableau”. That sounds like a lot and it is, because the book (the actual content, not counting preface, indexes …) is about 150 pages long. In other words, a little over 2 pages per recipe. In fact, I actually counted them (I have apparently nothing better to do). There are 74 recipes spread out over 147 pages, so 1.986 pages per recipe. Those are not long recipes. Some other numbers: the shortest recipe is 2 bullet points. It’s about adding a wildcard filter on a worksheet, but it actually builds upon a previous recipe, so it doesn’t count. The following scatter plot (created with Tableau of course) gives an overview of the various lengths of the recipes encountered in the book:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2898" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png" alt="scatterplot" width="500" height="598" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png 573w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot-250x300.png 250w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are quite a few very short recipes, which can easily be verified with a histogram:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2897" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png" alt="histogram" width="500" height="521" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png 725w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram-288x300.png 288w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">As you can notice, the distribution is a little bit skewed to the left (sorry for the sarcasm). Recipes with a length of 6 or shorter make up over 50% of the book. More statistics can be deduced from this box and whisker plot:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2899" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png" alt="boxwhiskerplot" width="800" height="146" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What is my point in all this (aside from me giving the opportunity to myself to exercise creating some charts in Tableau)? The point is that this book is short and the recipes are too basic. 74 recipes in 150 pages, clearly the choice for quantity over quality has been made. It would have been much better if the bulk of those recipes were bundled into a few recipes who were longer but also more complex and challenging. Now most of the recipes just scratch the surface of a feature and never go into any depth. They are the equivalent of a recipe for boiling potatoes:</p>
<ol style="text-align: justify">
<li>Peel potatoes.</li>
<li>Throw them in boiling water.</li>
<li>Wait for 10 to 20 minutes, depending on type of potatoes.</li>
<li>Bon appétit.</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: justify">Maybe in another chapter you get a recipe for cooking vegetables and in another for grilling meat, but you don’t get instructions to cook a lovely meal with all of the ingredients (and now I’m hungry…). There are three chapter dealing with almost the same basic stuff: creating visualizations with one measure, creating visualizations with two measures and finally creating visualizations with multiple measures. Those should be combined in one single chapter with just a couple of interesting recipes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Another issue is that the author sometimes doesn’t bother to give more information on how the resulting visualization should be interpreted (from time to time the resulting visualization looks nice, but is rubbish from a business perspective becomes it doesn’t really give useful insights). Anyway, this is just a detail. The author does include a lot of links to reference material however, which is certainly a big plus. He also gives some good advice about the different types of charts, for example what the downsides are of pie charts and stacked area charts and how to avoid them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The book is way too basic and this because of the overly simplistic recipes. Get this book only if you are an absolute beginner in Tableau and have never read anything about this tool or if you are an absolute novice in data visualizations tools. In my opinion, the <a href="/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/">Tableau Dashboard Cookbook</a> by Jen Stirrup offers considerable more depth (despite the editing issues) and you’ll learn more tricks than in this book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thinking with Data by Max Shron</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 11:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[o'reilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2445</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DISCLAIMER I recently enrolled myself in the O’Reilly Blogger Review program, which basically allows me to get one O’Reilly eBook for free per month so I can review it on my blog. This works in both ways of course: I get free eBooks while they’re still hot from the press (figuratively speaking of course) and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify"><b>DISCLAIMER</b></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I recently enrolled myself in the O’Reilly Blogger Review program, which basically allows me to get one O’Reilly eBook for free per month so I can review it on my blog. This works in both ways of course: I get free eBooks while they’re still hot from the press (figuratively speaking of course) and the books get some extra coverage on social media. A nice bonus is that Microsoft Press books are also published through O’Reilly, so it is possible I can get my hands early on new SQL Server books.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">They do encourage you to do honest reviews, so don’t expect every review to go like “OMG this is the bestest most awesomesauce book I have ever read!”. It might though if it is an actual great book, but if it isn’t, I will surely mention it in the review.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><b>THINKING WITH DATA</b></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The first book I got my hands on is <i>Thinking with Data – How to Turn Information into Insigths</i> by Max Shron. In this book, Max describes a framework and methodology on how to approach data science projects. Instead of diving straight into a project by applying your favorite tools and techniques on a giving data set, the author explains it is more useful and productive to stop and think a while about the <i>why </i>before the <i>how</i>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920029182.do"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2447" alt="thinkingwithdata" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/thinkingwithdata.gif" width="180" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The first chapters explain how to set the scope – context, need, vision and outcome – and show you how to refine the scope even further, using for example scaffolding. Then you get an introduction on how to construct arguments, using claims, evidence, justifications and rebuttals. Using other fields like philosophy and mathematics, patterns of reasoning are explained (the most interesting chapter in my opinion), followed by a deep-dive into causality. The final chapter puts it all together by two elaborate case studies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Personally I liked this book. Although it is focused on data science projects, there are plenty nuggets of wisdom that can be ported to the realm of business intelligence. The book isn’t too long – a mere 93 pages – which makes it easily digestible. If the book would have been longer, it might get a bit boring to read. The author has a pleasant writing style and uses examples throughout the book. Without the examples, the concepts would have been much harder to grasp. I would recommend this book to anyone who works with data professionally. It will help you to structure your thoughts before diving into the next project.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Star Schema The Complete Reference – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/star-schema-the-complete-reference-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/star-schema-the-complete-reference-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 15:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dimensional modelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star schema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I finished my first book of this year and here’s the review! After I finished the newest edition of Ralph Kimball’s Data Warehouse Toolkit, a senior colleague of mine recommended the book Star Schema The Complete Reference by Christopher Adamson. To be honest, I had never heard about it. But was I wrong: this book [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">I finished my first book of this year and here’s the review! After I finished the newest edition of Ralph Kimball’s Data Warehouse Toolkit, a senior colleague of mine recommended the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Star-Schema-The-Complete-Reference/dp/0071744320">Star Schema The Complete Reference</a> by Christopher Adamson. To be honest, I had never heard about it. But was I wrong: this book is an absolute must read for every data warehouse professional who takes himself/herself seriously. The book is extremely well written and it explains the concepts of star schemas (hence the title of course) very thoroughly with great detailed examples. I would even go as far by proclaiming that I like this book better than the “Toolkit”. If I had to choose only one book to take with me on new projects, it would be this one.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">One of the strengths of this book is that it is vendor independent and also architecture independent. The book begins by introducing how dimensional modelling is used in the methodologies used by Inmon and Kimball and it debunks quite a few myths that exist about both methodologies. It also explains the concept of stand-alone data marts and which advantages and especially which disadvantages this technique has. Throughout the book, the author explains how the different methodologies can have an impact on how certain concepts are implemented.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Another great piece was the explanation of drilling-across and the importance of it for cross analysis of different process. While reading Kimball’s book, I didn’t pick up the significance of this, but because of the attention Christopher gives to conformed dimensions – a whole chapter – I could really put it in perspective. The different types of conformity are well explained and are illustrated with clear examples. The book also gives different ways of drilling across and provides a few code samples.</p>
<p><a href="http://amzn.to/1fJVq5q"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2317 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/bookcover-241x300.jpg" alt="bookcover" width="241" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/bookcover-241x300.jpg 241w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/bookcover.jpg 322w" sizes="(max-width: 241px) 100vw, 241px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are the usual chapters that you expect from a book like this: dimension design, slowly changing attributes, snowflaking, different kinds of fact tables et cetera. But there is the occasional deep dive: multi-valued dimensions/ attributes and how they relate to bridge tables, type-specific stars, recursive hierarchies and so on. He even explains how to handle all these exotic features when there are slowly changing attributes, but unfortunately he doesn’t back it up with detailed examples. It’s the only weak point of the book, but making the book too detailed would perhaps make it too long and harder to read. And hopefully we never have to implement a slowly changing many to many relationship.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are also some chapters on performance enhancements, such as derived tables and aggregates. These solutions might become somewhat obsolete in the past years thanks to hardware advancements and the introduction of columnar and in-memory databases, but since not every company has Enterprise edition these tools might still be very useful.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The last three chapters are more about how to design the ETL, how to work with BI tools and how to document models. Personally I found those less interesting, but there’s still some value in it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><b>Conclusion</b></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It’s a great book about designing data warehouses using star schemas. Buy it, read it and take it with you on every data warehouse project you encounter. You won’t regret it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/star-schema-the-complete-reference-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services Blueprints – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/reporting-services-blueprints/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/reporting-services-blueprints/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blueprints]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reporting services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/12/reporting-services-blueprints/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ 

Recently Packt Publishing released the book SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services Blueprints authored by Marlon Ribunal (blog&#124;twitter) and Mickey Stuewe (blog&#124;twitter). My former colleague Valentino was the technical reviewer for this piece – he wrote&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image_block"><a href="http://www.packtpub.com/sql-server-2012-reporting-services-blueprints/book?utm_source=mention.com&amp;utm_medium=link&amp;utm_campaign=book_mention.com"><br /><img style="float: left; margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SSRS_blueprints/ssrsblueprints.png?mtime=1386846154" alt="" width="231" height="284" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently <a href="https://www.packtpub.com/">Packt Publishing</a> released the book <a href="http://www.packtpub.com/sql-server-2012-reporting-services-blueprints/book?utm_source=mention.com&amp;utm_medium=link&amp;utm_campaign=book_mention.com">SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services Blueprints</a> authored by Marlon Ribunal (<a href="http://marlonribunal.com/sql-server-express-reporting-data-solutions/">blog</a>|<a href="https://twitter.com/MarlonRibunal">twitter</a>) and Mickey Stuewe (<a href="http://mickeystuewe.com/">blog</a>|<a href="https://twitter.com/SQLMickey">twitter</a>). My former colleague Valentino was the technical reviewer for this piece – he wrote about it <a href="http://blog.hoegaerden.be/2013/11/17/book-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-blueprints/">here</a> – so I was very interested in getting my hands on this book. Luckily Packt was kind enough to provide me with a copy so I could write a review.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-align: justify;">The book itself is advertised as a </span><em>step-by-step, task-driven tutorial</em><span style="text-align: justify;">, a hands-on book with some real-life blueprints which doesn’t waste time with boring introductions and technical obscurities. In my opinion, the book achieves this goal quite well. At no point I had the feeling I was reading dry technical documentation, but rather practical easy-explained tips on how to use Reporting Services. I also have to admit the reviewers really did a great job: the text reads fluently and I believe I didn’t find any spelling mistakes or typos, which are pet peeve of mine (I do hope I didn’t make any myself in this blog post). The book is aimed at people new to Reporting Services, so hardcore BI professionals won’t get much out of it, but I have to admit I learned a few nuggets here and there.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The book tells the journey of John Kirkland, an <em>awesome accidental DBA</em> for Red Speed Bicycle LLC, a company remarkably similar to AdventureWorks, who also happens to become an <em>accidental</em> report developer. Using this story makes the book relatable and more uplifting than most technical books. The first 4 chapters guide John through the basics of creating reports: how to create data sources and data sets, how to use parameters (with a good piece on multivalued parameters), how to format reports, how to use the different actions (learned something about document maps here) and finally how to implement charts. These chapters are the most valuable for beginners of SSRS and they cover a lot of the basic reporting needs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The fifth chapter goes into detail about location based reporting and shows how you can use maps in SSRS. The sixth chapter is quite an important one and deals with Analysis Services as data source for the reports. The first sections of this chapter deal with some administrative issues of SSAS, such as for example setting the firewall and finding the correct port. Personally I found this information superfluous and I would have liked more details on how to create reports on top of SSAS. For example, how to create a report using a parent-child hierarchy, how to use distinct count over a many-2-many dimension and so on. I get it from the point of view from John, the hero of the book who is a DBA and might like all that technical information about SSAS, but maybe an additional appendix would have been better. If you’re going technical though, why not include more technical deep-dives into managing the SSRS server instead of SSAS?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Chapter 7 deals with deployments and everything that comes after: subscriptions, caching, snapshots et cetera. One minor downside is that it only explains deployment from Visual Studio. There’s no explanation on alternatives with scripting. Chapter 8 – the final chapter &#8211; is a bit of the “garbage” chapter, as it covers multiple subjects: SharePoint integration, Power View and Power Pivot. What disappointed me most is the very short introduction to Power View which has no screenshots at all. I repeat: no screenshots at all. Power View is Microsoft’s answer to competitors like QlickView and it is has beautiful, rich and interactive graphics, it’s easy to use and it makes SSRS look pretty bland and boring. But no screenshots. As Power View is officially part of Reporting Services (although it resides in Office and SharePoint) and is another reporting/visualization tool, I’d rather have a full chapter on Power View and less info on the SSAS DBA and the geo reporting stuff.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The book closes with two appendixes: a short one on SSRS best practices and one on using replication to create a separate reporting database.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I really enjoyed the book and I will recommend it to people new to Reporting Services to get up to speed quickly with this tool. It has great examples that you can follow along using provided code snippets. The only downside – but this is my personal opinion – is the lack of Power View goodness. Don’t let this stop you though on adding this title to your library!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/reporting-services-blueprints/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of Pro SQL Server 2008 Relational Database Design and Implementation</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/review-of-pro-sql-server-2008-relational/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/review-of-pro-sql-server-2008-relational/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 17:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[database design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/review-of-pro-sql-server-2008-relational/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good database design is extremely important if you want to have a database that performs well and is easily modifiable. How many times did you have to go back and change countless lines of code because your database was not normalized and it was not easy to add another payment type to the existing database? [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good database design is extremely important if you want to have a database that performs well and is easily modifiable.<br />
How many times did you have to go back and change countless lines of code because your database was not normalized and it was not easy to add another payment type to the existing database?</p>
<p>This is where <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/143020866X/002-3562882-4309664?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creativeASIN=143020866X">Pro SQL Server 2008 Relational Database Design and Implementation</a>  comes in; in the first couple of chapters you are taught how to design a database in a normal form. Most books that deal with database design are dry and boring; you need to read a chapter several times to digest the information leaving you with a headache. Not this book, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/143020866X/002-3562882-4309664?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creativeASIN=143020866X">Pro SQL Server 2008 Relational Database Design and Implementation</a>  makes this almost fun, the author goes through the phases of database design in a fun way which is understandable to the common man</p>
<p>After the design is done and you have your database you will be shown how you can protect the integrity of your data. Remember nothing in the database is as important as to make sure the data is correct, if you have bad data then you might as well have no data at all. This book will show you how to protect the integrity of your data by using constraints and triggers</p>
<p>There is a whole chapter of some good tips and tricks, patterns and query techniques. I think that you will find out you can solve a whole lot of business problems with a numbers table much faster than if you had to do it without</p>
<p>Security is a big topic these days, look on the internet, ever week you here horror stories how some data was stolen or otherwise compromised. Fear not there one whole chapter about securing access to your valuable data</p>
<p>Table structure and indexing is also covered, how are tables stored internally, the differences between clustered and non clustered indexes. These are very important concepts to understand; there are plenty of stories of people who designed a database and it worked flawless when they tested it. Once they loaded it up with real data in the real world it became painfully slow, by then they had to spend countless hours trying to refactor that mess. This book will prevent these kind of things</p>
<p>Coding for concurrency is also covered. This is also a very important concept. Explained are the different isolation levels, the difference between optimistic and pessimistic locking and best practices</p>
<p>Each chapter has a summary and a best practices chapter. This is very handy because you can quickly get an overview of the whole chapter in a page or two.</p>
<p>I highly recommend this book to anyone who wants to learn or get better at designing databases. Having a bad database design is like building a house on a weak foundation; sooner or later you will pay for it and you will have to tear parts down to fix that faulty foundation.</p>
<p>When it comes to database design and SQL Server I have no doubt in my mind that this is the book to get. This is the third version of the book I have read and I am pleased to see that every edition is a little better than the previous one.</p>
<p>Download chapter 1 here: http://www.apress.com/book/downloadfile/4090 to get a &#8216;feel&#8217; for the book</p>
<p>Amazon link here: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/143020866X/002-3562882-4309664?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creativeASIN=143020866X">Pro SQL Server 2008 Relational Database Design and Implementation</a></p>
<p>If you are interested in some more info about the author then check out the interview I did a while back: <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DataDesign/interview-with-louis-davidson-author-of-">Interview With Louis Davidson Author of Pro SQL Server 2008 Relational Database Design and Implementation</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/review-of-pro-sql-server-2008-relational/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of MCTS Self-Paced Training Kit (Exam 70-502): Microsoft .NET Framework 3.5 Windows Presentation Foundation</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 15:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.net 3.5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows presentation foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Review of MCTS Self-Paced Training Kit (Exam 70-502): Microsoft .NET Framework 3.5 Windows Presentation Foundation Written by Matthew A. Stoecker This book has 524 pages The reason I read exam preparation books is to learn things about the product which you would otherwise learn the hard way, you might have introduced bugs because you didn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Review of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735625662?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creativeASIN=0735625662">MCTS Self-Paced Training Kit (Exam 70-502): Microsoft .NET Framework 3.5 Windows Presentation Foundation</a> </strong></p>
<p>Written by Matthew A. Stoecker<br />
This book has 524 pages</p>
<p>The reason I read exam preparation books is to learn things about the product which you would otherwise learn the hard way, you might have introduced bugs because you didn&#8217;t know why certain things worked the way they did. Taking the preparation exams in the book is also another good way to see if you have actually mastered the material inside the book. This book is organized in 10 chapters. If you have done Windows Forms programming then you will have no problem following the material in the book, it is written in a clear and concise matter and source code is in C# and VB. </p>
<p>Here is what is covered in each chapter.</p>
<p>Chapter one explains the different kinds of WPF apps that you can develop and when you should chose one over the other.<br />
Chapter two is about Evens, Event Handling, Commands and Application Settings.<br />
Chapter three is all about building the user interface.<br />
Chapter four is about content, this includes images and binary resources.<br />
Chapter five is about data binding including ADO.NET and XML.<br />
Chapter six is about data validation and conversion, this includes implementing IValueConverter.<br />
Chapter seven is all about Styles and Animation. This chapter is where the fun of WPF programming is. You will learn about using triggers, animations, styles and understanding Property Value Precedence.<br />
Chapter eighth is all about customizing the User Interface.<br />
Chapter nine deals with Resources, Localization and Documents.<br />
Chapter ten will teach you how to deploy and application including using a windows installer or ClickOnce</p>
<p>After you are done with this book you will be able to create a Windows Presentation Foundation application from start to finish including deployment. You will also learn that you can do things in code or in XAML and that the end result is the same. I highly recommend this book for any person who has done at least 6 months of Windows Forms. Windows Presentation Foundation is the natural evolution of Windows Forms and this book will help you master the cool stuff and let you know about pitfalls. You will learn that all your Windows Forms knowledge is still relevant, you will also learn that WPF is so much more than Windows Forms. The graphics features and multimedia integration alone will make you stay up until the early morning to create that cool app to show to your boss.</p>
<p>One thing I would recommend is to read this book twice, reading things the second time around will make it very clear why things are done a certain way</p>
<p>This book is a must if you want to pass the 70-502 exam or if you want to learn about Windows Presentation Foundation</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of Inside Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Query Tuning and Optimization</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/review-of-inside-microsoft-sql-server-20/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/review-of-inside-microsoft-sql-server-20/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 02:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[databases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/02/review-of-inside-microsoft-sql-server-20/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SQL performance tuning is probably one of those things you can do to really make a HUGE difference in performance. Let’s put this in perspective: take a typical application, if you can improve the performance by 100% then you really made a huge improvement. You can improve a SQL query by 1000% with 2 lines [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SQL performance tuning is probably one of those things you can do to really make a HUGE difference in performance. Let’s put this in perspective: take a typical application, if you can improve the performance by 100% then you really made a huge improvement. You can improve a SQL query by 1000% with 2 lines of code (sometimes all you have to do is take away a % sign). If you can make a query sargable so that the optimizer can do an index seek instead of an index scan your query might go from 12 seconds to 200 milliseconds. Now try doing that in an application, even if you change all the string concatenation to use a stringbuilder instead of creating new strings all the time you will not get such a drastic performance improvement. I am sure you get the point by now, let’s talk about the book. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735621969/102-5735017-0910517?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creativeASIN=0735621969">Inside Microsoft SQL Server 2005: Query Tuning and Optimization</a> is part 4 of the Inside Microsoft SQL Server 2005 series, it is written by Kalen Delaney and five other authors. There are 6 chapters in this book</p>
<p></p>
<p>1 A Performance Troubleshooting Methodology<br />
This chapter explains some typical things that affect performance and also gives a troubleshooting overview</p>
<p>2 Tracing and Profiling<br />
This chapter explains how to use the profiler and how to analyze traces. SQL Server’s built-in traces are also covered</p>
<p>3 Query Execution<br />
This chapter gives a query processing and execution overview. It explains how to read plans and goes into a lot of detail about analyzing plans</p>
<p>4 Troubleshooting Query Performance<br />
This chapter explains how to detect problems in plans, how to improve queries and some best practices</p>
<p>5 Plan Caching and Recompilation<br />
This chapter goes into detail about plan caching and recompilation and how to troubleshoot plan cache issues</p>
<p>6 Concurrency Problems<br />
The final chapter deals with concurrency (locking, blocking and deadlocking)</p>
<p>This is an excellent book for an intermediate/advanced developer. There is so much new stuff in SQL Server 2005 compared to 2000 to help you with tuning queries that you probably want to read each chapter several times. The Dynamic Management Views are a big help and this book shows you how to use them. Some other cool stuff in this book is the discussion of internal tables, undocumented DBCC commands and undocumented trace flags to discover information which could help you determine much faster what the cause of a performance problem might be. Some pages are packed with so much information that you need to pause for a second and process all that info (I have read some pages two to three times in a row). You will also find out that there are more joins besides left, full and outer. Page 137 for example has a nice table with the three Physical Join Operators: Nested Loop Join, Hash Join and Merge Join. This table lists the characteristics for each of these joins.</p>
<p></p>
<p>If you are an intermediate to advanced developer then I highly recommend this book. </p>
<p></p>
<p>I have interviewed Kalen a while back about this book and you can find that interview here:  <a href="http://sqlservercode.blogspot.com/2007/10/interview-with-kalen-delaney-about.html">Interview With Kalen Delaney About Inside Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Query Tuning and Optimization</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/review-of-inside-microsoft-sql-server-20/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
