<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>jython &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/jython/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Django 1.0 Released</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/django-1-0-released/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/django-1-0-released/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 00:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[django]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jython]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[python]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/django-1-0-released/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes it is true, Django 1.0 has been released today. Here is a part of the announcement: No, you&#8217;re not hallucinating, it&#8217;s really here. Around three years ago, Adrian, Simon, Wilson and I released some code to the world. Our plan was to hack quietly on it for a bit, release a solid 1.0 release, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes it is true, Django 1.0 has been released today. Here is a part of the announcement:</p>
<blockquote><p>No, you&#8217;re not hallucinating, it&#8217;s really here.</p>
<p>Around three years ago, Adrian, Simon, Wilson and I released some code to the world. Our plan was to hack quietly on it for a bit, release a solid 1.0 release, and then really get the ball rolling.</p>
<p>Well.</p>
<p>What happened, of course, was that an amazing community sprung up literally overnight — our IRC channel had over a hundred people in it the day after release, and it’s never been that “empty” since.</p>
<p>I really can’t stress enough how amazing our community of users and developers are. About half of the code that’s gone into Django over the past three years has been contributed by someone other than a core committer. Since our last stable release, we’ve made over 4,000 code commits, fixed more than 2,000 bugs, and edited, added, or removed around 350,000 lines of code. We’ve also added 40,000 lines of new documentation, and greatly improved what was already there.</p>
<p>Django 1.0 represents a the largest milestone in Django’s development to date: a web framework that a group of perfectionists can truly be proud of. Without this amazing community, though, it would have never happened.</p></blockquote>
<p>Read the release notes here: http://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/releases/1.0/</p>
<p>Download Django 1.0 here http://www.djangoproject.com/download/</p>
<p>And of course congratulations to the team  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/django-1-0-released/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
