<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Microsoft Word &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/desktopdev/microsoft-word/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Keyboarding in Word</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/vbaformsoffice/keyboarding-in-word/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/vbaformsoffice/keyboarding-in-word/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[chopstik]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VBA for Microsoft Office Products]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/02/keyboarding-in-word/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now that I have moved back over to the not-so-technical side, I find that I am having to relearn things that I probably knew a long time before but have forgotten. As I have pointed out to my friends before, I don't care so much about what tools I use s&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now that I have moved back over to the not-so-technical side, I find that I am having to relearn things that I probably knew a long time before but have forgotten. As I have pointed out to my friends before, I don&#8217;t care so much about what tools I use so long as the job gets done. However, since I don&#8217;t have ready access to dev tools at this job (since I&#8217;m not a developer in this role), I have to go back to more common office tools. It&#8217;s not a bad thing, mind you, just something that I have to do and there are ups and downs to it.</p>
<p>I was recently asked to go manually update a bunch of Word documents with specific formatting. I hate to do things manually so naturally I sought out a way to make it go faster. Because of the formatting issues of the docs, a macro was not the most efficient method. However, I recalled that I could set my own keyboard shortcuts &#8211; woohoo! In MS Word 2007, it&#8217;s actually pretty straightforward. First, click on the Office button in the top left corner. This will provide the base-level menu list. </p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev/WordKeyboard1.JPG?mtime=1330380437"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev/WordKeyboard1.JPG?mtime=1330380437" width="429" height="477" /></a></div>
<p>On this menu list, click on the &#8220;Word Options&#8221; button at the bottom right of the menu list. On the list on the left-hand side, click on &#8220;Customize&#8221;. You will then see the following:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev/WordKeyboard2.JPG?mtime=1330351484"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev/WordKeyboard2.JPG?mtime=1330351484" width="840" height="685" /></a></div>
<p>At the bottom, click on &#8220;Customize&#8221; next to &#8220;Keyboard shortcuts:&#8221; in order to view all of the menu items and to enable the creation/modification of keyboard shortcuts. That will bring up the option to customize any keyboard commands. Below, you can see that I&#8217;ve updated the Highlight to use the default setting (Alt-Ctrl-H) which I found didn&#8217;t work as I wanted and the Alt-Q that I added and which is easier for me to use. The same, obviously, can be done for any changes that you may also wish to make.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev/WordKeyboard3.JPG?mtime=1330351825"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev/WordKeyboard3.JPG?mtime=1330351825" width="574" height="441" /></a></div>
<p>It is little shortcuts like these that create efficiencies and, at the end of the day, shorten the time I need to do things manually and enable me to accomplish more. Hopefully this will point the way to doing the same for you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/vbaformsoffice/keyboarding-in-word/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
