<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>internet explorer &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/internet-explorer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>First Look at IE 10</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/first-look-at-ie-10/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/first-look-at-ie-10/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AJAX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XHTML and CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mix 11]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/04/first-look-at-ie-10/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Channel 9 has made available a video on their site about Internet Explorer 10, I have embedded the video here



Here is what they say on the channel 9 site

Just when you were expecting to hear more about IE9 on this opening day of Mix '11, and t&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Channel 9 has made available a video on their site about Internet Explorer 10, I have embedded the video here</p>
<p><iframe style="height: 288px; width: 512px; " src="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/First-Look-Internet-Exploer-10-Platform-Preview/player?w=512&amp;h=288" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Here is what they say on the channel 9 site</p>
<blockquote><p>Just when you were expecting to hear more about IE9 on this opening day of Mix &#8217;11, and today we&#8217;ll be talking about the IE10 Platform Preview. IE10 builds on IE9 with support for even more standards like CSS3 gradients, multi-column, and grid layouts. In this video Rob Mauceri walks us through some of the new features of IE10 including an example of flowing of content in multi-column layouts.</p></blockquote>
<p>
Here is Dean Hachamovitch, corporate vice president in charge of the Internet Explorer team at Microsoft wearing a shirt with the IE 10 logo during the IE keynote ate Mix 11 today.<br />
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5613176833/" title="IE10 preview released"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5143/5613176833_d7febf783d.jpg" width="337" height="307" alt="IE10 preview released" /></a></p>
<p>Developers can download the Internet Explorer 10 Platform Preview at http://www.IETestDrive.com/ and provide direct feedback through new code refreshes approximately every 12 weeks.</p>
<p>I wonder if they are going to do a more aggressive release schedule like the Chrome browser. Anything is better than the waiting period between IE6 and IE7, that was insane.</p>
<p>Make sure to check it out here: http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/First-Look-Internet-Exploer-10-Platform-Preview</p>
<p>Also make sure to check out Mix 11 here http://live.visitmix.com/ for the keynotes over the next 3 days</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/first-look-at-ie-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Has FireFox lost its Mojo, are FireFox user jumping ship to Chrome?</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 11:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/05/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have been using Chrome for over a year now and have been very happy with it. Yesterday version 5 was released, you can get it here: http://www.google.com/chrome I decided to look at some stats for this site and compared April of this year to April of last year. The image below has this information. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have been using Chrome for over a year now and have been very happy with it. Yesterday version 5 was released, you can get it here: http://www.google.com/chrome</p>
<p>I decided to look at some stats for this site and compared April of this year to April of last year. The image below has this information.</p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/WebDev//BrowserPercentage.PNG" alt="" title="" width="592" height="756" /></p>
<p>As you can see FireFox lost about 10% while Chrome gained 9% and Safari gained almost 1%. So what is going on, are the early adapters switching to Chrome from FireFox? Take a look at the <a href="http://marketshare.hitslink.com/browser-market-share.aspx?qprid=1">NetMarket stats</a></p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/WebDev//stats.PNG" alt="" title="" width="750" height="242" /></p>
<p>FireFox had 24.72% of all bowser traffic in November, in April it had 24.59%, FireFox didn&#8217;t gain anything in the last 6 months.</p>
<p>So what is going on? When Internet Explorer 6 was the dominant browser it was very easy for FireFox to grab market share. Internet Explorer 6 was a mess, Internet Explorer 8 is better but still not as good as either FireFox or Chrome in my opinion.</p>
<p>So what will happen to FireFox will they ever pass 25% or is this a downward spiral and within a year Chrome will have that 25% and FireFox will be at 15% or so? With all the new stuff like the Google&#8217;s App Store that Google is adding to Chrome its usage will have to grow fast.</p>
<p>What browser do you use and did you try Chrome and if so did you like it?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Internet Explorer 9 available for a test drive</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/internet-explorer-9-available-for-a-test/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/internet-explorer-9-available-for-a-test/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AJAX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XHTML and CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[html 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web standards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/03/internet-explorer-9-available-for-a-test/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Internet Explorer 9 is available for a test drive Microsoft detailed its support for a number of HTML5 specifications, including CSS3, Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG), XHTML parsing, and the video and audio tags using industry-standard (H.264/MPEG4 and MP3/AAC) codecs, among others. In addition, Microsoft demonstrated a new JavaScript engine that uses the multiple cores of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/WebDev//IE9.PNG" alt="" title="" width="361" height="76" /></p>
<p>Internet Explorer 9 is available for a test drive</p>
<p>Microsoft detailed its support for a number of HTML5 specifications, including CSS3, Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG), XHTML parsing, and the video and audio tags using industry-standard (H.264/MPEG4 and MP3/AAC) codecs, among others. In addition, Microsoft demonstrated a new JavaScript engine that uses the multiple cores of today’s modern chips to effectively manage computing resources and improve Web performance. By combining increased interoperability with a new JavaScript engine and Direct 2D technology, Internet Explorer 9 enables Web developers to provide users with richer experiences that render more quickly and consistently.</p>
<p>The new IE 9 script engine is codenamed &#8220;Chakra&#8221;<br />
Internet Explorer 9  focuses  on three key themes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Best interoperable HTML5</li>
<li>Hardware Accelerated Graphics</li>
<li>High Performance Browser</li>
</ul>
<p>There are a bunch of HTML 5 demos available, below is the list of these demos<br />
Border Radius<br />
CSS3 Selectors<br />
DOM Events<br />
DOM Style<br />
HTML5 T-Shirt Designer</p>
<p>
<h2>Webkit SunSpider JavaScript Benchmark Results</h2>
<p>If you look at the SunSpider results in the image below, you can see that IE 9 is much faster than IE 8.</p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/WebDev//SunSpiderResults.png" alt="" title="" width="736" height="520" /></p>
<p>Microsoft also announced increased support of client development through the jQuery JavaScript Library</p>
<p>As part of Microsoft’s broad engagement with open source communities, Corporate Vice President Scott Guthrie today announced that Microsoft is investing resources to contribute to the development of the jQuery JavaScript Library to help improve the development process of standards-based Web applications. Microsoft will also work to provide better interoperability between ASP.NET and the jQuery JavaScript Library by enhancing ASP.NET so .NET developers can better incorporate jQuery capabilities. In addition, Microsoft will actively promote and distribute versions of the jQuery JavaScript Library by packaging it with popular products such as Microsoft Visual Studio 2010 and ASP.NET MVC 2. As a first step, Microsoft will contribute a templating engine to the jQuery JavaScript Library Team to simplify Web applications.</p>
<p>You can take Internet Explorer 9  for a test drive here<br />
http://ie.microsoft.com/testdrive/</p>
<p>If you want more info then take a look at the press release that went out earlier: http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/press/2010/mar10/03-16MIX10Day2PR.mspx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/internet-explorer-9-available-for-a-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Banish IE6? Not As Easy As You Think</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 12:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 7]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/05/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You have all seen sites that popup messages telling you that your IE6 browser is insecure and that you should upgrade to IE7/8, FireFox or Chrome. The reason for this is of course that IE6 is a terrible browser to develop against; nobody wants to spend half their time putting in CSS hacks so that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You have all seen sites that popup messages telling you that your IE6 browser is insecure and that you should upgrade to IE7/8, FireFox or Chrome. The reason for this is of course that IE6 is a terrible browser to develop against; nobody wants to spend half their time putting in CSS hacks so that their webpage looks halfway decent. Some sites like <a href="http://37signals.blogs.com/products/2008/07/basecamp-phasin.html">37signals decided to dump IE6</a> completely </p>
<p>So here is the problem with this, most companies I interact with won’t let you run as an administrator and you cannot install a single thing. Yeah you can download another browser but you can’t install it. Most of these companies also have windows update disabled on the machines, updates are pushed through LANDesk. A new browser is not part of these update pushes. Just imagine that you call help desk to ask them to install a new browser on your machine. Most probably you will get an answer that IE6 is the corporate standard and that it is the browser you have to use.</p>
<p>Of course some companies developed internal apps that use ActiveX and will only work on IE6, this is another reason that IE6 will not go away any time soon.</p>
<p>On our site IE6 still commands about 30% usage of total IE usage. Here is the breakdown for the last 10 months</p>
<pre>Aug 2008 30.06%
Sep 2008 31.14%
Oct 2008 30.10%
Nov 2008 28.62%
Dec 2008 28.95%
Jan 2009 29.74%
Feb 2009 30.38%
Mar 2009 29.73%
Apr 2009 25.90%
May 2009 24.76%</pre>
<p>As you can see it was around 30% until April and then it dropped. This drop is probably because of the introduction of IE8 in April at Mix09</p>
<p>Here is all IE for May</p>
<pre>IE7 57.73%	
IE6 24.76%	
IE8 17.51%</pre>
<p>As you can see IE8 is closing in on IE6 fast, it is however also taking market share away from IE7</p>
<p>It will be interesting to see how many people will upgrade to Windows 7 this year, so far XP is still king For the month of May 2009 XP traffic was 68.24% of all windows machines on our site</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Internet Explorer 8 Release Candidate 1 Available For Download</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/internet-explorer-8-release-candidate-1/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/internet-explorer-8-release-candidate-1/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 18:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[release candidate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/01/internet-explorer-8-release-candidate-1/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On Monday, January 26 at 12pm PT, Internet Explorer 8 Release Candidate 1 (RC1) will be released to tech and consumer enthusiasts in a total of 25 languages. Users should visit www.microsoft.com/ie8 IT Professionals should visit http://technet.microsoft.com/ie Developers should visit http://msdn.microsoft.com/ie Since Beta 2, you’ll note some of the changes in RC1 include the following: [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Monday, January 26 at 12pm PT, Internet Explorer 8 Release Candidate 1 (RC1) will be released to tech and consumer enthusiasts in a total of 25 languages.</p>
<p>Users should visit www.microsoft.com/ie8</p>
<p>IT Professionals should visit http://technet.microsoft.com/ie</p>
<p>Developers should visit http://msdn.microsoft.com/ie</p>
<p>Since Beta 2, you’ll note some of the changes in RC1 include the following:</p>
<p><strong>ClickJacking protection</strong>.  The SmartScreen Filter now includes the ability to help detect and prevent “ClickJacking” which is a malicious technique of tricking web users into revealing confidential information or taking control of their computer.</p>
<p><strong>InPrivate™</strong>. Helps to protect user’s data and privacy from being retained “locally” on a PC. InPrivate Browsing and InPrivate Filtering can now be used independently.</p>
<p><strong>Performance improvements</strong>. Reduces the time that users must wait when starting the browser, opening a “new tab”, or loading a page.</p>
<p><strong>User interface and experience updates</strong>. There have been several user interface changes to help ensure a better user experience.</p>
<p>Internet Explorer 8 RC1 will be available in 25 languages including: Arabic, Chinese (Traditional, Simplified and Hong Kong), Czech, Danish, Dutch, English, Finnish, French, German, Greek, Hebrew, Hungarian, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Norwegian, Portuguese (Brazil and Portugal), Polish, Russian, Spanish, Turkish and Swedish</p>
<p>For some additional information on running IE8 RC1 on Windows 7 beta, please check out the following link:  http://blogs.msdn.com/ie/archive/2009/01/10/ie8-in-windows-7-beta.aspx</p>
<p>I still think that InPrivate should have been named PornMode  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/internet-explorer-8-release-candidate-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
