<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>data visualization &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/data-visualization/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Overview of the data visualization books by Stephen Few</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/overview-stephen-few/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/overview-stephen-few/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 12:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stephen few]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3337</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I recently finished the book Now You See It: Simple Visualization Techniques for Quantitative Analysis by Stephen Few of Perceptual Edge. Stephen Few is a data visualization guru and his books about designed visualizations has changed my career in BI and how I develop reports and dashboards. Few currently has three books published (with a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">I recently finished the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Now-You-See-Visualization-Quantitative/dp/0970601980/ref=la_B001H6IQ5M_1_3?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1428393017&amp;sr=1-3">Now You See It: Simple Visualization Techniques for Quantitative Analysis</a> by Stephen Few of <a href="http://www.perceptualedge.com/">Perceptual Edge</a>. Stephen Few is a data visualization guru and his books about designed visualizations has changed my career in BI and how I develop reports and dashboards. Few currently has three books published (with <a href="http://www.perceptualedge.com/blog/?p=1749">a fourth on its way</a>):</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify">
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Show-Me-Numbers-Designing-Enlighten/dp/0970601972/ref=la_B001H6IQ5M_1_2?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1428393017&amp;sr=1-2">Show Me the Numbers: Designing Tables and Graphs to Enlighten</a>, which has already 2 editions.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Information-Dashboard-Design-At---Glance/dp/1938377001/ref=la_B001H6IQ5M_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1428393017&amp;sr=1-1">Information Dashboard Design</a>, which also has 2 published editions.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Now-You-See-Visualization-Quantitative/dp/0970601980/ref=la_B001H6IQ5M_1_3?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1428393017&amp;sr=1-3">Now You See It: Simple Visualization Techniques for Quantitative Analysis</a></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify">I’m a huge fan of Few’s work and this blog post is meant as an introduction to his different titles, so people know what to expect when they read one of his books. I’ll review each of them in the order that I’ve read them (which actually has no specific meaning).</p>
<h1 style="text-align: justify">Information Dashboard Design</h1>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://amzn.to/1SnBSj9"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/dashboard-150x150.jpg" alt="dashboard" width="150" height="150" /></a>This book really opened my eyes regarding data visualization best practices. I read the first edition, of which you can find my review <a href="/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/data-visualization-book-review/">here</a>. I ordered the second edition the day it came out; the book is that good.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">As the title says, this book explains how to design dashboards efficiently. It introduces you to the principles of visual perception and how you can use those to make better dashboards. It also gives plenty examples of bad and good dashboard design.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Even though its focus is on dashboards, a lot of the design principles are true for regular reports and visualizations as well. I could apply them immediately at my job when creating SSRS reports.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: justify">Show me the Numbers</h1>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://amzn.to/1Oejusx"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/showmethenumbers-150x150.jpg" alt="showmethenumbers" width="150" height="150" /></a>After reading <em>Information Dashboard Design</em>, I thought: “Great, now I know how to design dashboards and charts, but what about tables?” This book is the answer to that question. It gives a full overview on how to design data visualizations, be it tables or graphs. There are even some exercises in the book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This makes the book more complete than <em>Information Dashboard Design</em>. There is in fact quite some considerable overlap between the two books. If you want to buy only one book about data visualization, I recommend this one. If you are interested in dashboards only and how multiple graphs can interact on one page, then get the other book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are also some interesting appendices to this book, such as adjusting for inflation and how to create some chart types in Excel.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: justify">Now you see it</h1>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://amzn.to/1OejBUY"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/nowyouseeit-150x150.jpg" alt="nowyouseeit" width="150" height="150" /></a>The final book is a bit more different. While the other two books focus more on how to create data visualizations, this book goes into more detail on what you should do with those visualizations and why purpose they can serve.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This book is meant for people using visualizations for analytic purposes. It describes what characteristics analysts should have, what kind of analytical interaction and navigation there is and how analytical software should support it. Very interesting to read, because even 6 years after this book has been published, not a single software product supports all of those features.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It also describes analytical techniques such as using reference lines, reducing overplotting and using trellises. The book then talks about patterns and then details all the different types of relationships: time-series, ranking, deviation, distribution, correlation and multivariate analysis. Most of the time examples were made using Excel, Tableau or Spotfire.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">All in all a very interesting book to read. I definitely recommend it for people who have to analyze data as part of their job.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/overview-stephen-few/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tableau Dashboard Cookbook by Jen Stirrup</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 08:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DISCLAIMER I received this book through the O’Reilly blogger review program, which I already mentioned in the review of Thinking With Data. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself. TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">DISCLAIMER</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I received this book through the <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/reviews/">O’Reilly blogger review program</a>, which I already mentioned in the review of <a href="/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/">Thinking With Data</a>. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard of Jen Stirrup (<a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/jenstirrup">twitter</a>): she currently holds the PASS board seat for Europe, she has spoken at dozens of different events and has won the PASSion award in 2012. I have watched her speak at the SQL Server Days in Belgium a few times before and this year she will deliver <a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/precon/#jen">a full precon about Power BI and R</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s say I was a little bit excited when I heard she wrote<a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781782177906.do"> a book about Tableau</a>. I had no experience whatsoever with Tableau, but I had seen some demos and visualizations so I was anxious to try out the product. I got myself the book and I downloaded the free trial of <a href="http://www.tableausoftware.com/products/desktop">Tableau Desktop 8.2</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em>Note:</em> the trial is only 10 days, so if you want to finish the entire book in that time period, you better reserve some quality reading time for yourself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2816" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif" alt="tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover" width="180" height="222" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s start with the good stuff. Personally I loved this book and the main reason is because it is very hands-on: there are a lot of examples (or recipes if you follow the cookbook doctrine) that guide you step-by-step through the features of Tableau. For readers inexperienced with Tableau – such as myself – this is a great way to discover the product without being overwhelmed by its many features. Each recipe starts with a short introduction – not too long so it doesn’t get tedious – and then dives directly into the action. At the end there is a small recap of what you just did and how it works and there are optionally some pointers to further references. The book is limited on theory but overloaded with practicalities, which was very appealing to me. I felt I learned a great deal about Tableau by reading this book, but I also realized I just learned the basic functionalities of the product. That’s why this book may not be suited for already advanced users of Tableau; they may not find a lot of new information in this book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">A small disadvantage is that this book is (in theory) already outdated because it deals with Tableau 8.1, while the 8.2 version has just been released. However, I didn’t experience much difficulties over this. The only obvious difference is the import of multiple files, where there is now a much more graphical and easier to use interface to join tables together.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Personally I found that this book is best read from front to back, as the recipes in a single chapter often depend on each other: you start with a blank worksheet and in each recipe you build on top of the other until you end with a working dashboard at the end of the chapter. Also, sometimes chapters depend on the finished dashboard of the previous chapter. This makes it a bit harder to just jump to a chapter in the book and do some recipes. Luckily you can download finished worksheets from the publishers’ website.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What I found a little bit disappointing was the section in the final chapter about R, called <em>Wrapping up with R – dashboards as a tool</em>. I have been toying with the R language lately and I expected to see some cool stuff there. But there was only an introduction on how to install R with a package called Rserve and how to set-up a connection from within Tableau to Rserver. That’s it. No demonstration on how to actually use R with Tableau. I would have liked some more material over there, or maybe something in an addendum. An idea perhaps for a second edition? Anyway, this book is not about R but about Tableau <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Now on to the bad stuff. Quite early on in the book – somewhere in chapter 2 – it became very clear that this book was badly edited. There are no spelling or grammar mistakes – not that I know of – but sometimes screenshots are switched or even wrong. One time a recipe – which is essentially a bulleted list of action points – jumped to the end while skipping a few steps. Sometimes when following the recipe step-by-step, you achieve a different result than what is displayed in a screenshot. Most of the time you can work around those issues by using your mind a bit and by comparing with (hopefully correct) screenshots. It can get annoying after a while, but it didn’t stop me from reading the book (unlike some delicate little flowers who wrote some reviews on Amazon) because there is still very great content inside it. But you would think that with 4 reviewers, 3 proofreaders and 10 (!) editors mistakes like these would have been avoided. I have contacted the author and she told me that the mistakes have been reported and should appear on the Errata page.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">All in all, I recommend this book to people new to Tableau. They will definitely learn enough by this book to take their first steps with Tableau. A job well done by the author, but shame on you Packt Publishing for all those mistakes. Fire those editors please.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">UPDATE: the author (Jen Stirup) has placed <a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/2014/07/packt-tableau-dashboard-cookbook-errata.html">errata about chapter 2 on her blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ITPROceed &#8211; Slide Deck and demo materials</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssrs/itproceed-slide-deck-and-demo-materials/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssrs/itproceed-slide-deck-and-demo-materials/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 07:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Excel Reporting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[itproceed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2744</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ITPROceed 2014 is now a thing of the past, but is has been an awesome &#8211; and free! &#8211; event. A very big thank you and &#8220;well done&#8221; to the organizers. It has been a great gathering of the #sqlfamily, with superb sessions about Azure, restoring databases with PowerShell, Hekaton (yes yes In-Memory OLTP), Administration [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">ITPROceed 2014 is now a thing of the past, but is has been an awesome &#8211; and free! &#8211; event. A very big thank you and &#8220;well done&#8221; to the organizers. It has been a great gathering of the #sqlfamily, with superb sessions about Azure, restoring databases with PowerShell, Hekaton (yes yes In-Memory OLTP), Administration Intelligence (a new buzzword for marketing?), a glimpse into the new APS (Analytics Platform System, a blend of PDW and Hadoop that will knock your socks off) and of course my own session about data visualization.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">My session went pretty well: I had time left at the end and every demo went really OK (so sacrificing a virgin to the demo gods really does help, in case you are wondering). You can find the presentation at <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/KoenVerbeeck/get-more-out-of-your-data-visualizations">SlideShare</a> and you can download the demo code (SSRS report project and Excel worksheet) <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/ITPROceed_DataViz_Demos.rar">here</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">See you at the SQLServerDays and at ITPROceed 2015!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/itproceed_003.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2612" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/itproceed_003.png" alt="itproceed_003" width="340" height="62" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/itproceed_003.png 340w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/itproceed_003-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 340px) 100vw, 340px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssrs/itproceed-slide-deck-and-demo-materials/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speaking at ITPROceed</title>
		<link>/index.php/uncategorized/speaking-at-itproceed/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/uncategorized/speaking-at-itproceed/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 11:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[itproceed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reporting services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2611</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m delighted to announce I will be giving a session at ITPROceed, a new event in Belgium for the IT Professional. From their website: ITPROceed is a joint effort between the ITProfessional User Groups with the strong support of Microsoft to bring you the best on the Cloud OS, System Center, SQL, Office 365, Windows [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m delighted to announce I will be giving a session at <a href="http://www.itproceed.be/">ITPROceed</a>, a new event in Belgium for the IT Professional. From their website:</p>
<blockquote><p>ITPROceed is a joint effort between the ITProfessional User Groups with the strong support of Microsoft to bring you the best on the Cloud OS, System Center, SQL, Office 365, Windows 8, Unified Communications, Lync, Azure and SharePoint.</p></blockquote>
<p>My session is titled <em>Get More Out Of Your Data Visualizations</em>. The abstract is short and simple:</p>
<p><em>With data you can tell important and compelling stories, if done right. In this session, we will review a few guidelines on how to create communicative visualizations and how this can be implemented in Excel and Reporting Services.<br />
Because SSRS is often underestimated, we&#8217;ll finish off with some eye-catchers.</em></p>
<p>There are other excellent sessions about SQL Server and Business Intelligence, so make sure to check out the <a href="http://www.itproceed.be/agenda">agenda</a>!<br />
Tickets are almost sold out, so you better hurry!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.itproceed.be/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2612" alt="itproceed_003" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/itproceed_003.png" width="340" height="62" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/itproceed_003.png 340w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/itproceed_003-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 340px) 100vw, 340px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/uncategorized/speaking-at-itproceed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Visualization – Book Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/data-visualization-book-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/data-visualization-book-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/07/data-visualization-book-review/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To prepare myself for my session Data Visualization Tips &#38; Tricks, I read a few books. In this blog post, I’ll give a short review for each one of them.
Information Dashboard Design
This book, written by Stephen Few, was the first one I read. And&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">To prepare myself for my session <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/business-intelligence-1/data-visualization-tips-tricks">Data Visualization Tips &amp; Tricks</a>, I read a few books. In this blog post, I’ll give a short review for each one of them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Information Dashboard Design</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://amzn.to/1J0ZLfO"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/DataVizBookReview/informationdashboarddesign.png?mtime=1372771566" alt="" width="186" height="219" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify">This book, written by <a href="http://www.perceptualedge.com/blog/">Stephen Few</a>, was the first one I read. And it was a fascinating read! I went through the book in one long haul. It’s very well written and the design of the book is very well done. A big plus is that the printed version of the book is in color.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><span style="text-align: justify">The essence of the book is on how to design dashboards properly. In the first chapter, you obviously get an introduction and a few examples of poorly designed dashboards. In the second chapter, Stephen defines the concept of a dashboard and the different variations that exist. For example: how does an operational dashboard look like in contrast with an analytical dashboard. The third chapter goes into detail about what you should not do when designing a dashboard by presenting 13 common mistakes. Chapter 4, one of the most interesting chapters delves into visual perception and explains what you can do to draw attention to certain parts of a dashboard. This involves a wee bit of psychology and worth knowing when designing dashboards.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Chapter 5 demonstrates the principle of eloquence through simplicity, or in other words: keep it simple stupid. It talks about how to reduce the “noise” in a dashboard so that only the important aspects remain. Chapter 6 gives an overview of available chart/display types and presents the bullet graph – invented by Stephen himself – which is a very efficient display medium. Chapter 7 talks about usability of your dashboards and chapter 8 brings it all together. In this final chapter Stephen gives a few examples of how to design a few command dashboards according to his vision. Here he also gives yet another few examples of very bad designed dashboards to illustrate his points.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I absolutely recommend this book to anyone who considers reading about data visualization in general. Every self-respecting BI professional should have read this book. The only criticism I can come up with is that the book focuses a lot on “the bad”, or how not to do things. Perhaps a little bit more focus on how to design properly would have been welcome. But overall, a very great book. In August 2013 <a href="http://www.perceptualedge.com/blog/?p=1656">a second edition of the book</a> should launch, and I definitely will keep my eye on that one.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Data Visualization: a successful design process</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://amzn.to/1TD1cUR"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/DataVizBookReview/datavisualizationprocess.png?mtime=1372771564" alt="" width="178" height="219" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify">The second book I read was written by Andy Kirk (<a href="http://www.visualisingdata.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/visualisingdata">twitter</a>), who also gives training classes about data visualization. In contrast with the previous book, this one talks about the design approach on how to create visualizations. In other words, it describes a project-based methodology on how to tackle the process of creating a visualization. This might make the book a bit more “dry” to read, but that doesn’t make it less interesting.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><span style="text-align: justify">The first chapter deals about the context of data visualizations and serves as a general introduction. Chapter 2 talks about setting the scope – or intent – of your visualization project and the different roles that exist in such a project. The 3</span><sup>rd</sup><span style="text-align: justify"> chapter is about finding the right story (editorial focus) and explains the importance of preparing your data. Chapter 4 delves into various design choices, such as choosing the right visualization method and goes for example into detail about color usage. This chapter has quite some similarities with some chapters of Stephen Few’s book. Chapter 5 gives a very extensive overview of different chart/visualization types. The final part, chapter 6, touches the concept of evaluating data visualizations and gives a whole bunch of links to designing tools, resources about data visualization et cetera.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It was a nice book to read and because of the process-based approach of the book it’s something completely different then <em>Information Dashboard Design</em>. So it is very well worth the effort to read both books. My main criticism about this book is that it is not in color, which is a pity since it’s about data visualization. Some examples were not clear as you could not make any distinction between the colors. Perhaps the e-book version is in color, but I haven’t been able to look into that one, so it is probably worth checking out the e-book instead of the printed version.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Say it with Charts</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://amzn.to/1M6gzDc"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/DataVizBookReview/SayItWithCharts.jpg?mtime=1372771569" alt="" width="172" height="224" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify">During the dry-run of my data visualization session a BI manager of my company recommended me this book. It’s written by Gene Zelazny, a consultant by McKinsey. It is quite an old book, initially written in 1985 and already in its fourth edition! However, it still talks about some universal concepts of data visualization which still hold firm today. As with the other two books, there are not a lot of pages so you’ll breeze through it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><span style="text-align: justify">The book is divided 4 large sections. The first section introduces you to charts. First it gives an example of a guy giving a presentation and of course doing everything wrong. It presents you with 5 basic chart types – pie chart, bar chart, column chart, line chart and dot chart – which are according to the book the only ones you’ll ever need. A bit short-sighted, but probably due to the age of the book. With all the designer tools and computing power we have nowadays, there are certainly more chart types available which are also efficient in its communication.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The second section gives 80 examples of every possible combination of those 5 basic charts. This is very good introduction to people new to charts and it is also a good source for inspiration. The third section talks about concepts and metaphors and is in my opinion worthless. It’s over 60 pages full of outdated sketches. For example on how to use arrows to symbolize process or interrelationships. Basically a lot of PowerPoint/Visio/Clip Art objects. This section was written in a time with no Internet so I get the idea, giving the people some inspiration, but it should’ve been thrown out in later editions. The last edition was published in 2001 and surely there was already some digital revolution going on. Speaking of, the last section goes into detail about the wonders that this revolution has given us. It was added in the latest edition and it is the only one in color. It talks about how computers simplify the development of visualizations and what powerful/beautiful creations can be made with all this new technology. However, it is already 12 years old and it looks – again – very outdated and to be honest, ugly as well. There are a few design errors which the other two books warn about. This section is in serious need of an update. It even talks about animation and gives examples, which is a bit pointless in a written medium such as a book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Is this a bad book? No. Skipping the last two sections and focusing only on the first two, you got yourself a very nice introduction to charts. A very quick one as well, as this reduces the book to a mere 128 pages. There are also some exercises in this book (get out your pencil) to get you started about thinking how to use charts. Conclusion: still worth the read, even if it is just to laugh with the old technology J.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/data-visualization-book-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Visualization Tips &#038; Tricks  &#8211; Slides</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/data-visualization-tips-tricks-slides/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/data-visualization-tips-tricks-slides/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/06/data-visualization-tips-tricks-slides/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The slides of my data visualization session are now available for download.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Last week my colleague Valentino and I did a session on <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/business-intelligence-1/data-visualization-tips-tricks">Data Visualisation Tips &amp; Tricks</a> at the Belgian <a href="http://www.communityday.be/">Community Day</a>. At the beginning of the session there were only a handful of people in the room but luckily we quickly realized the keynote was running over time. So after the keynote speaker finally wrapped up his talk, our audience steadily grow to about 60 people which exceeded our expectations. Valentino’s demos didn’t fail, I didn’t fall of the stage and I heard good feedback, so we’re safe to say our session was a bit of a success.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Anyway, I posted the slides on <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/KoenVerbeeck/data-visualization-tips-tricks-23479927">Slideshare</a> and you can also download the code for the demos of Valentino on <a href="http://blog.hoegaerden.be/2013/06/21/community-day-data-visualization-tips-tricks-download/">his blog</a>. To everyone who showed up at our session: thanks for being such a great audience. ‘till next time!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/ComDayBe2013/long.png?mtime=1370952579"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ComDayBe2013/long.png?mtime=1370952579" alt="" width="600" height="90" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/data-visualization-tips-tricks-slides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Visualization Tips &#038; Tricks at Community Day 2013</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssrs/data-visualization-tips-tricks/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssrs/data-visualization-tips-tricks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[user group]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/06/data-visualization-tips-tricks/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In exactly one week I’ll be giving a session with my colleague Valentino Vranken (blog &#124; twitter) at the Belgian Community Day. We’ll be talking about Data Visualization. I’ll be talking about the tips: how do you need to visualize your data without the&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">In exactly one week I’ll be giving a session with my colleague Valentino Vranken (<a href="http://blog.hoegaerden.be/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/ValentinoV42">twitter</a>) at the <a href="http://www.communityday.be/">Belgian Community Day</a>. We’ll be talking about Data Visualization. I’ll be talking about the <em>tips</em>: how do you need to visualize your data without the audience scratching their eyes out because of the ugly colors you used? Why would or wouldn’t you use pie charts? And what’s the difference between an analytical dashboard and an operational dashboard? You can find answers on such question in this session.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Valentino will be talking about the <em>tricks</em>: little bits of wisdom on how to get things done in Reporting Services. We did the dry-run of the session yesterday and I definitely learned something from his part, so be sure to check it out!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Community Day is on the 20<sup>th</sup> of June in the city of Mechelen. It combines the various user groups of Belgium (and some of the Netherlands) and gives you an astonishing 5 track agenda with over 30 sessions! So get yourself registered, come on over and get your learning cap on!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.communityday.be/"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ComDayBe2013/long.png?mtime=1370952579" alt="" width="600" height="90" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssrs/data-visualization-tips-tricks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
