<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>How to Learn and Get Answers &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/itstudents/learngetanswers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Where to find advanced SQL Server Training (in Belgium)</title>
		<link>/index.php/itstudents/learngetanswers/where-to-find-advanced-sql/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itstudents/learngetanswers/where-to-find-advanced-sql/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 08:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Axel Achten (axel8s)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How to Learn and Get Answers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belgium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/05/where-to-find-advanced-sql/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In response of my previous post about being sure you sign up for the correct training, I got the question where you could find training for more experienced DBA's, for a reasonable price and not involving self-study. As I'm living in Belgium, I only can&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In response of my <a href="/index.php/ITStudents/LearnGetAnswers/choosing-the-right-training">previous post</a> about being sure you sign up for the correct training, I got the question where you could find training for more experienced DBA&#8217;s, for a reasonable price and not involving self-study. As I&#8217;m living in Belgium, I only can answer this question for my region. But I think you can use the same approach for other countries and regions.<br />
First of all it&#8217;s true, the basic implementing and maintaining courses are so popular that they are regularly scheduled. When you browse the <a href="http://learning.microsoft.com/Manager/Catalog.aspx?qry=SQL+Server+2012&amp;nav=trainingtype%3aClassroom+Training&amp;btn=1">Microsoft Training Catalog</a> you&#8217;ll find some other available trainings, it&#8217;s possible to call a training center and ask to schedule the training but keep in mind they need at least 2-3 students before they will start the training.<br />
Another possibility is walk-in trainings. It&#8217;s something new: you can book a walk-in training and make an appointment whenever you want during a couple of months. The idea is you get a PC with a recording of the training and a PC to do the exercises. So you can come and follow the training at your own pace and when you have time for it. It&#8217;s a pity that there are no SQL Server trainings available for the moment but we are working on it. </p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://www.oak3.be/oak3/walkinCalendar.jsp"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/FindTrain1.jpg?mtime=1337766271" width="152" height="108" /></a></div>
<p>Second place to check is your local <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/belux/nl/newsletters/">Microsoft website</a>. Sign-up for the newsletters and check the events they are announcing. The events they organize are not always very technical but can give you a head start when it comes to new products and releases. Check <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/nicktrog/archive/2012/04/06/register-for-a-free-sql-server-2012-training.aspx">this blog</a> where they announce some sessions about some new features in SQL Server 2012.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="https://msevents.microsoft.com/cui/EventDetail.aspx?culture=en-US&amp;EventID=1032505931&amp;IO=EyEgX%2fLgmnoaz0j6vViSeA%3d%3d"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/FindTrain2.png?mtime=1337766284" width="135" height="137" /></a></div>
<p>They also organize the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/belux/techdays/2012/Home.aspx">TechDays</a> every year where they have a lot of sessions about different Microsoft Technologies. Make sure you check the agenda and see if there are sessions you&#8217;re interested in. On the other hand it&#8217;s also a place where you can meet the local MEET members and ask your questions. More in-depth sessions but also for more money, you have the yearly TechEd week.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://europe.msteched.com/"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/FindTrain3.jpg?mtime=1337766307" width="180" height="390" /></a></div>
<p>Also don&#8217;t forget to sign up for the local SQL Server User group (<a href="http://sqlug.be/">site</a>|<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/sqlug">twitter</a>). They organize sessions during the year about different SQL Server subjects. Also once a year they have their own <a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/">SQL Server Days</a>, 2 days with 3 SQL Server tracks full of sessions for almost no money. Together with other User groups they also organize every year a <a href="http://www.communityday.be/">Community Day</a>. Again just check if you find the sessions interesting or just go and meet the experts at the different user group booths.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://www.communityday.be/cd/tabid/36/Default.aspx"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/FindTrain4.png?mtime=1337766326" width="600" height="90" /></a></div>
<p>If you have more budget and are allowed to go abroad, keep an eye on <a href="http://www.sqlpass.org/">Pass</a> or <a href="http://sqlbits.com/">SQLBits</a> they also organize events in Europe with top international speakers.<br />
And last but not least. Instead of the money for a 5-day training and your wage, you can hire a consultant for at least 2 days who can come over, answer all your questions, audit your environment and coach you on how and WHY you should make some changes to your environment.<br />
I&#8217;m sure there are a lot of other options to learn more about SQL Server. But this will get you started.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itstudents/learngetanswers/where-to-find-advanced-sql/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Choosing the right training for you</title>
		<link>/index.php/itstudents/learngetanswers/choosing-the-right-training/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itstudents/learngetanswers/choosing-the-right-training/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 10:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Axel Achten (axel8s)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How to Learn and Get Answers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/05/choosing-the-right-training/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a post I wanted to write for a while but I just didn't want my students to think I was visioning them. So if you are one of my students, no it's not about you but I have to write this because almost every class I teach I have a student who does&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a post I wanted to write for a while but I just didn&#8217;t want my students to think I was visioning them. So if you are one of my students, no it&#8217;s not about you but I have to write this because almost every class I teach I have a student who does not meet the prerequisites, is too experienced or had other expectations of the course.<br />
When teaching at a Microsoft Learning Partner Center I usually use the standard Microsoft Official Curriculum courses so there is plenty information about them on the internet.
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/elycefeliz/3262326159/"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/ChooseTrain1.jpg?mtime=1337691082" width="647" height="584" /></a></div>
<p>First there is the Partner Centers&#8217; website where you can book the training, they all list the official numbers and most of them have also the complete description. Otherwise you can check the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/learning/en/us/default.aspx">Microsoft Learning site</a>. Fill in the course number and make sure you read the Course Details and Prerequisites! If you don&#8217;t match the prerequisites for let&#8217;s say 60% and don&#8217;t think <i>&#8220;hmm interesting&#8221;</i> for 75% of the chapters, maybe this is not the ideal training for you.</p>
<p>What happens when you&#8217;re in the &#8220;wrong training&#8221;?<br />
Well it depends, if you don&#8217;t meet the prerequisites, you&#8217;ll lose interest, get bored, and miss some essential information so you completely can&#8217;t follow anymore,&#8230; You just wasted you&#8217;re time and money. The same happens when you already have too much knowledge. It&#8217;s good that you have some working experience before you come follow a course. But if you work for 5 years with the previous release you shouldn&#8217;t follow the complete basic course of the next release. You will get the same result.<br />
On the other hand you will also ask a lot of questions, because you don&#8217;t know how to get the exercises to work or because you can ask all the exceptions you ran into the last 5 years to the teachers. In both scenario&#8217;s you will annoy you&#8217;re co-students for slowing down they&#8217;re training experience, taking too much teacher time and so on.<br />
As a teacher I don&#8217;t mind getting all these extra questions, beginner or advanced. But I have to make sure that the majority of the class gets what they paid for so at some point I might have to disappoint you.</p>
<p>So if you&#8217;re going to take a training, make sure you look up the available information and if you&#8217;re still in doubt. Just mail or call the Education Center. They&#8217;re happy to help you find the training that meets your expectations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itstudents/learngetanswers/choosing-the-right-training/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Picking a science fair project</title>
		<link>/index.php/itstudents/assignments/picking-a-science-fair-project/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itstudents/assignments/picking-a-science-fair-project/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 10:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Mastros (gmmastros)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Assignments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to Learn and Get Answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/11/picking-a-science-fair-project/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When school started this year, my 7th grade daughter was informed that she is expected to complete a science fair project.  I plan on convincing her to post her final report as a blog on this site, but it’s not scheduled to be completed for a couple mor&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When school started this year, my 7th grade daughter was informed that she is expected to complete a science fair project.  I plan on convincing her to post her final report as a blog on this site, but it’s not scheduled to be completed for a couple more months.  I plan on writing a series of blogs outlining the steps involved from a parents&#8217; perspective.  </p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITStudents/albert_einstein_256515.jpg" alt="" title="" width="256" height="500" /></div>
<p><strong>Step 1: Picking the project.</strong></p>
<p>During dinner one night, my daughter informed us that she needed to present 6 science fair project ideas to her teacher the next day, but she couldn’t think of anything.  Several ideas were presented but none were acceptable. After the meal was over and the plates were clean, we turned to google for some help.  I was expecting google to present some interesting ideas, but was surprised at how many there are.  Our first google search was &#8220;7th grade science fair project ideas&#8221;.  There were so many ideas to choose from.</p>
<p>When helping your child present ideas to the teacher, it’s important that each idea is acceptable to you, the parent.  I’m reminded of Sunday morning breakfasts when my daughter was younger.  I didn’t ask &#8220;What would you like for breakfast?&#8221;  Instead, I would ask, &#8220;Would you like pancakes, eggs, or oatmeal?&#8221; By restricting the choices to those that I think are appropriate, I was guaranteed to get an acceptable answer.  The science fair project is no exception.</p>
<p><strong>Safety</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m glad that my daughter was expected to present ideas to the teacher.  This is an important safety measure that shouldn&#8217;t be overlooked because it is easy for a seemingly interesting &amp; safe project idea to become dangerous or malicious.  The teacher is the filter, the guardian, the safety net.  Any project involving an animal is immediately rejected, don&#8217;t even bother presenting it.  If your project involves dangerous chemicals, it is likely to be rejected also.  Trust the teachers decision.</p>
<p><strong>Fun and interesting</strong></p>
<p>The project idea is the single most important decision made.  The teacher will help make sure the project is safe, but it&#8217;s your job to make sure the project is fun, interesting, and appropriate for your child.  As your child is making this decision, you should constantly be asking, is this interesting to you?  Is this something you&#8217;ll enjoy doing.  Most science fair projects require a lot of time.  If your child is going to be miserable during this time, so will you.  </p>
<p><strong>Cost</strong></p>
<p>Another consideration when picking a science fair project is cost.  Some projects can be done without incurring any costs, some are low cost, and others can be expensive.  As a parent, you should have a clear understanding about the costs you are willing incur.  Some projects may initially seems like there is a low cost associated with it, only to find hidden expenses once you get in to a later phase of the project.  For example, if the science fair project is about the freshness of bread stored various ways, all you may need is a single loaf of sliced bread and perhaps a Ziploc bag, cellophane wrapping, etc… These are materials you probably already have in your home, and the expense is likely to be quite small and reasonable.  Other projects have hidden costs that may surprise you.  For example, &#8220;Does the bounciness of a golf ball relate to its ability to be hit a long distance?&#8221;  For this project, you will need to purchase a variety of golf balls and measure it bounciness.  More importantly, you’ll need a method to consistently hit each ball so that it is exactly the same strength and angle.  Building such a device may include hidden expenses.</p>
<p><strong>Time</strong></p>
<p>Lastly, you should consider the amount of time and level of effort that will be involved in your child’s project.  Some projects will be easy to prepare for and conduct.  For example, &#8220;testing the effect of music volume on your ability to remember&#8221;.  All you’ll really need for this is to prepare a test and get a music source, preferably with head phones.  Other projects may require more preparation time.  Also realize that it&#8217;s not just preparation time that could be significant.  It may take a long time to conduct the experiment too.  For example, &#8220;Fish growth as a result of tank size&#8221;.  This experiment may take several months to complete.</p>
<p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<p>At first glance, picking a science fair project may seem simple, but it&#8217;s not.  It may be the most important decision you can make.  Guiding your child is important in order to assure an acceptable project is picked.  Remember these factors when picking a science fair project: safety, fun, cost, and time commitments.  Determine what is acceptable for you and your family and then let your child pick from several acceptable ideas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itstudents/assignments/picking-a-science-fair-project/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
