<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>apache &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/apache-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Is your Apache Server Status wide open for the world to see?</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/2003server/is-your-apache-server-status/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/2003server/is-your-apache-server-status/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2003 Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/03/is-your-apache-server-status/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Apache web server comes with something called Apache Module mod_status installed

From the Apache site: http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.0/mod/mod_status.html
The Status module allows a server administrator to find out how well their server is perf&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Apache web server comes with something called Apache Module mod_status installed</p>
<p>From the Apache site: http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.0/mod/mod_status.html</p>
<blockquote><p>The Status module allows a server administrator to find out how well their server is performing. A HTML page is presented that gives the current server statistics in an easily readable form. If required this page can be made to automatically refresh (given a compatible browser). Another page gives a simple machine-readable list of the current server state.</p>
<p>The details given are:</p>
<p>The number of worker serving requests<br />
The number of idle worker<br />
The status of each worker, the number of requests that worker has performed and the total number of bytes served by the worker (*)<br />
A total number of accesses and byte count served (*)<br />
The time the server was started/restarted and the time it has been running for<br />
Averages giving the number of requests per second, the number of bytes served per second and the average number of bytes per request (*)<br />
The current percentage CPU used by each worker and in total by Apache (*)<br />
The current hosts and requests being processed (*)</p></blockquote>
<p>If you go to a site that uses the Apache web server, you can get interesting info if you add server-status after the domain name</p>
<p>If you go to http://apache.org/server-status, you will get the following</p>
<p>Server Version: Apache/2.4.1 (Unix) OpenSSL/1.0.0g<br />
Server Built: Mar 3 2012 19:35:24<br />
Current Time: Friday, 23-Mar-2012 00:20:33 UTC<br />
Restart Time: Tuesday, 20-Mar-2012 16:36:59 UTC<br />
Parent Server Config. Generation: 4<br />
Parent Server MPM Generation: 3<br />
Server uptime: 2 days 7 hours 43 minutes 34 seconds<br />
Total accesses: 41598844 &#8211; Total Traffic: 571.4 GB<br />
CPU Usage: u1734.41 s1457.05 cu0 cs0 &#8211; 1.59% CPU load<br />
207 requests/sec &#8211; 2.9 MB/second &#8211; 14.4 kB/request<br />
24 requests currently being processed, 616 idle workers</p>
<p>This will be followed by a list of IP addresses and pages that were served.</p>
<p>This can potentially be dangerous, it doesn&#8217;t long to write a program that will crawl the web and checking if it gets anything back when hitting domains with server-status appended</p>
<p>Several high traffic site have this enabled, just hit http://www.washingtonpost.com/ or http://boston.com/ and add server-status</p>
<p>What do you think, is this a problem or meh? I think it could be a problem, attackers now can now if you have an unpatched version of Apache running and they can take advantage of that.</p>
<p><strong>Edit</strong><br />
And it seems that washingtonpost.com disabled it. As of this morning you see this instead</p>
<p><em>Forbidden</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t have permission to access /server-status on this server.</p>
<p>Apache Server at failover.washingtonpost.com Port 80</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/2003server/is-your-apache-server-status/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Second Caching, Brilliant Or Insane?</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/one-second-caching-brilliant-or-insane/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/one-second-caching-brilliant-or-insane/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[database]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/one-second-caching-brilliant-or-insane/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Let's say you get 1000 hits per second on your website's home page, you want the users to feel that the site is as real time as possible without overloading your database. These hits on your site display some data from the database and are mostly reads;&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s say you get 1000 hits per second on your website&#8217;s home page, you want the users to feel that the site is as real time as possible without overloading your database. These hits on your site display some data from the database and are mostly reads; for every 10 reads there is one write. </p>
<p>Yes you can cache it for 1 minute and the database won&#8217;t be hit that much. By doing this it will look like your site doesn&#8217;t update so often. Now what will happen if you do a 1 second cache? You will eliminate most of the reads and your site will still look like it is updating real time. If a user hits F5/CTRL + R every couple of seconds he will see new content. Does this make sense? I am interested in your opinion.</p>
<p>[edit]I am talking about database results caching here. For example take a page like the new submission page on digg,  a lot of stuff gets submitted every second, a lot more gets read of course. If you cache this for one second you eliminate a lot of the reads[/edit]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/one-second-caching-brilliant-or-insane/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
