<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>seo &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/seo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What Does a Web Developer Need To Know</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/uidevelopment/what-does-a-web-developer/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/uidevelopment/what-does-a-web-developer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 09:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AJAX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Server Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UI Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XHTML and CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asp.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[css]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[html]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jsp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[table layout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[w3c]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/06/what-does-a-web-developer/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What is a web developer? Recently I was involved in a discussion about the skills a web developer is expected to have and how interesting it has been to watch common bad practices (like table layout and SQL injection) continue to spread. So in the nature of Denis's What does a SQL Server developer need to know? post, I present the web developer breakdown.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What is a web developer? Recently I was involved in a discussion about the skills a web developer is expected to have and how interesting it has been to watch common bad practices (like table layout and SQL injection) continue to spread. So in the nature of Denis&#8217;s <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBProgramming/MSSQLServer/what-does-a-sql-server" title="Read Denis's post">What does a SQL Server developer need to know?</a> post, I present the web developer breakdown.</p>
<h2>What Level Am I?</h2>
<p>Rather than try and attach years of experience to this scale, I&#8217;m going to present a list of major areas and skills, questions, or topics in each area. I&#8217;ve tried to capture whether I feel a skill is required to be an Intermediate or Advanced web developer. </p>
<p>I put this list together based on my own experience, 20-30 web developer interview lists, and some feedback from others.</p>
<p>Beginner: Knows some of the items on the list<br />
Intermediate: Knows most intermediate items and some advanced<br />
Advanced: Knows almost everything on the list</p>
<style>
.oneshottable { border: 1px solid #444444; border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; margin-bottom: 12px; }
.oneshottable th { background-color: #444444; color: white; text-transform: uppercase; font-weight: bold; padding: 4px;font-size: 90%; }
.oneshottable td{ padding: 1px 2px; min-width: 20px; border-bottom: 1px solid #999999; font-size: 80%;}
.oneshottable td.summary:first-child{ text-align: left; font-weight: normal; padding: 3px;}
.oneshottable td:first-child{ text-align: center; font-weight: bold }
</style>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">HTML</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">The ability to produce clean, valid, maintainable HTML is critical for a web developer. Current standards include HTML 4.01 (1999), XHTML 1 (2000), and the beginning of HTML 5 (2011)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>The effect of doctypes, can code a mostly valid site without looking up the rules</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>The effect of content-types and how to set or debug them</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows (and use) all of these without looking them up:  html, head, title, meta, script, style, link, body, a, strong, em, ul, ol, li, table, tr, th, td, h1-5, input, select, option, img, p, span, div, pre, textarea</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>And most of these: dl/dt/dd, thead, tbody, tfoot, abbr, acronym, applet, object, blockquote, iframe, label, map, optgroup, sup, sub, base, fieldset</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can name/explain at least 15 of the new HTML5 tags</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows the escapes for &amp;, &lt;, &gt;, &copy;, ASCII characters (though you may have to look up the character code)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can explain how HTTP works (headers, redirects, header requests, clientside caching)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows how to link to a position in a page</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">CSS</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Cascading Style Sheets are used to describe the way an HTML documented should be presented. CSS 1 was released in 1996 and the latest published recommendation is CSS 3. </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Difference between display inline, block, and inline-block and what the default value is for div, span, a, b</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Difference between position static, relative, fixed, absolute</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>What z-index is and how to use it</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>How z-index is calculated by individual browsers</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Difference between padding and margin</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Difference between display: none and visibility: hidden</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Purpose and use of &#8220;media&#8221;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Able to describe and calculate specificity</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows at least a few attribute selectors</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can describe pseudo-classes and know many without looking them up</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Javascript</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Javascript has become the defacto scripting language for web browsers, one of only a few ways to create client-side interactions consistently across available browsers. JavaScript was first shipped in 1995 as part of the Netscape browser.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>How to write a basic function, inline event handler, and a non-inline event handler (raw or w/ a package)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can write one or or more methods to make an AJAX call with reference material</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can write one or or more methods to make an AJAX call without reference material</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows at least one framework (jQuery, Prototype, YUI, Dojo, MooTools, …)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can create classes (function or literal)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Knows and can use prototype (little &#8216;p&#8217;, not the framework)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can dynamically find and add elements to the page using DOM or a framework (without looking it up)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Tools</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Along with standard languages, there are numerous tools available to help validate, evaluate, and improve existing websites. Similar to a spell-checking tool in a word processing application, these tools can help us catch errors and oversights in our websites.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can name at least one site, application, or organization that has an HTML validation tool</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can name at least one site, application, or organization that has an CSS validation tool</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can name at least one site, application, or organization that has an SEO scoring tool</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can name at least one site, application, or organization that has an Accessibility evaluation tool</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Server-Side Programming</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">The shift to dynamic, server-generated websites in the mid-to-late 90&#8217;s was responsible for shifting the focus of the web from document retrieval to interactivity, commerce, and services.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows at least 2 server-side technologies &#8211; Perl, PHP, ASP 3, JSP, Java Servlets, CFM, ASP.Net (WebPages, Web Forms, MVC), Ruby on Rails, Python (WSGI, CGI, mod_python), etc</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Knows more than 4 of the above list</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can explain difference between stateful and stateless development</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can explain how sessions work</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can explain how cookies work</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Difference between GET and POST and how known languages present this information</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Pros and cons of client-side vs server-side validation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Understands the basics of (SOAP) web services, how to implement them, and how they work</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Data</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Most web applications have some form of data store behind them. Several forms of storage and caching mechanisms exist and being able to build a basic system often requires at least a basic level of knowledge in these areas.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can build databases, define queries, and debug on at least one major RDBMS</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Knows basics for normalization and can create a basic data model to describe their database</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can work with at least one NoSQL database or data cache</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Can write match and search regular expressions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can write match and search regular expressions without a reference in more than one language</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Web Server</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Using a server-side technology to generate HTML generally requires a web server. The two largest install bases are Microsoft IIS 7.5 and Apache 2.2.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Understands the basics of how the web server (Apache or IIS) works and can create a new site</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can explain URL rewriting and implement on at least one system</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Performance</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Tuning a website to run in an optimal fashion can sometimes be the difference between paying for a single server or multiple servers, between a responsive site and one that fails under load. </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Understands and can implement data caching</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Understands and can implement page caching</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can use one or more page performance or load testing tools</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Tools/methods and purpose of minification of JS and CSS</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Understands and uses CDNs when possible</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Testing</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">As the technology behind the web has developed, tools to help automate some of the repetition involved in testing websites has likewise evolved.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can use one or more automated tools for interface testing</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Security</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">As recent news stories have reminded us, security is an ongoing requirement for websites. Understanding the basics of security can help us build security in from day one rather than trying to squeeze it in at the end.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>SQL Injection &#8211; what it is, how to prevent it</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Cross site scripting &#8211; what it is, how to prevent it</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Cross Site Request Forgery &#8211; what it is, how to prevent it</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Understand hashing, salting, and importance of storing critical information in hashed or encrypted formats</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Cookies &#8211; Understand session hijacking and dangers of storing user information or identification</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Design Principles</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Being able to implement common design patterns without restoring to hacks is an important part of being a web developer (as opposed to a hobbiest). While it may prove impossible to build a site without some form of hack, hacks should not be the only tool in the toolbox.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Table Layout &#8211; what it is, why it&#8217;s bad (at least three reasons)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can implement multi-column fixed, fluid, and elastic layouts without reference material</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Table Layout &#8211; and why using CSS for table layout (display: table, table-cell, etc) is not bad</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can explain and implement fixed, fluid (liquid), and elastic layouts</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Can implement multi-column fixed, fluid, and elastic layouts without reference material</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Meta</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">Metadata (data about data) is critical to helping people and search engines find resources in our sites and applications.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows purpose of description, keyword tags</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Knows purpose of robots.txt file</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Knows purpose and can implement sitemap.xml file</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>You know the basics for SEO</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>You&#8217;ve implemented some form of browser analytics</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>Microformats </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>You know what WCAG is and how to test conformance</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A</td>
<td>You know what semantic markup is</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="oneshottable">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Disqualifiers/Limiters</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" class="summary">These are topics I consider to be critical to advancement. They reflect common misunderstandings or bad practices that an experienced web developer has to grow past in order to advance their skillset.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>B</td>
<td>Backbutton doesn&#8217;t work w/ your sites, would prefer to disable it altogether</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>B</td>
<td>You protect images from download by implementing right click intercepts, layering transparent images in top, etc</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>I</td>
<td>Implement performance tuning without before/after measurements</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>B</td>
<td>Table layout</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><em>Note: Disqualifiers indicate that you won&#8217;t progress past [B]eginner or [I]ntermediate levels until you stop doing them and understand why doing them was a bad idea</em></p>
<h2>What&#8217;s Missing</h2>
<p>There are several things that were intentionally left out of this list. Some were hard to quantity in a general manner, others I was unsure how relevant they were. And I&#8217;m sure people will be kind enough to add additional oversights and revisions below.</p>
<p>Missing Categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Level of knowledge with server-side languages</li>
<li>Project management skills</li>
<li>Documentation and Modeling skills</li>
<li>Design and Graphics skills</li>
<li>Application Lifecycle Management &#8211; Source Control, Deployment, etc</li>
</ul>
<p>Extra items that didn&#8217;t make it in:</p>
<ul>
<li>Can implement RSS and ATOM feeds</li>
<li>Can implement a web farm</li>
<li>Implemented single-signon (openID, SAML, etc)</li>
<li>Knows how to implement XML data islands (still relevant?)</li>
<li>Knows how to create DTDs and/or XSDs</li>
<li>Can write regular expressions without a reference</li>
<li>Knows relevant tools for Yahoo (SiteExplorer), Google, Bing for managing site information</li>
<li>Schema.org &#8211; it belongs in the Meta category but I didn&#8217;t know what level of skill, knowledge, or adoption I should include considering it&#8217;s newness and several other factors</li>
</ul>
<p>There is also the fact that we often get caught up maintaining or even adding on to a site that violates many of the skills and standards you see in this list. This doesn&#8217;t prevent us from writing good, clean, semantic sites the rest of the time and being forced to write poor code does not make on inherently less skilled.</p>
<h2>A Brief Digression, or Why an App Dev is Not a Web Dev</h2>
<p>At one point web development was seen as less exciting and far less complex than application development. It is still seen as extremely similar to application development, so much so that it is quite normal to hire a good or great application developer and expect them to be a good or great web developer. </p>
<p>Unfortunately it doesn&#8217;t quite work that way, as web development has grown extremely complex since the first dynamic sites started showing up in the late 90&#8217;s. Doubly unfortunately, web development is based on a stateless model instead of the stateful one most application developers are used to, uses a fluid layout instead of the grid layout, and sneaks a lot of extra communications and caching into the mix. This is a series of paradigm shifts not unlike the one between procedural, object oriented, and functional programming.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/uidevelopment/what-does-a-web-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Quick Beginners Look at SEO</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/quick-beginners-look-at-seo/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/quick-beginners-look-at-seo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 10:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[links]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/03/quick-beginners-look-at-seo/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As technical people in a field that is expanding daily, we all run into areas that we know poorly, or haven&#8217;t been able to refresh our knowledge on this decade. For me, and I&#8217;m sure many of you, SEO is one of those topics that fell by the wayside. Sure, I remember circa-1998 tips on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As technical people in a field that is expanding daily, we all run into areas that we know poorly, or haven&#8217;t been able to refresh our knowledge on this decade. For me, and I&#8217;m sure many of you, SEO is one of those topics that fell by the wayside. Sure, I remember circa-1998 tips on getting the search engines to rank your site more highly, such as making sure my meta tags are filled in, using terms frequently that you want to attach to your key search values, even trying to keep the content-to-crap ratio as high as possible. But no one is paying me high dollar to come improve their site rankings, so it is obvious I was missing a few steps. </p>
<h2>The New Site, v1</h2>
<p>Every few years I throw away my website and re-invent it. This time I had decided to create an extended professional profile with a secondary goal of bringing together my online handle (Tarwn) and my real name (Eli Weinstock-Herman). That link wasn&#8217;t completely missing, but it was tenuous and this was the first time I purposefully set out to link the technical postings and articles under my handle to my real name. Eighteen hours gave me a site that I felt was a step better than my previous one..and the crushing realization that I had no idea how to capture my personal brand and be the number one search result for my own name(s). Google was listing me (<a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=tarwn" title="Google results for Tarwn">Both</a> of <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=eli+weinstock-herman" title="Google results for Eli Weinstock-Herman">me</a>) on the front page, but for older content that no longer existed and my profile on many other sites. Bing didn&#8217;t even have links to an old version of my site for one of my names. Ask and Yahoo? Similar stores, there were links and many of them were me, but my site was not in a prominent position. Luckily both my names are unique enough that I was really only competing with myself, albeit myself on much higher dollar, professional sites.</p>
<p>Time to hit the books.</p>
<h2>Instant Knowledge&#8230;</h2>
<p>I won&#8217;t lead you down all the blind alleys, scams, and occasionally clueless articles I ran into. Instead I&#8217;ll leave you with a few key links that stood out during my beginners education.</p>
<dl>
<dt><a href="http://www.seomoz.org/article/search-ranking-factors" title="read the Article">Search Ranking Factors</a></dt>
<dd>A high level list of SEO factors, listed by importance with additional feedback from SEO experts on each answer.</dd>
<dt><a href="http://www.webconfs.com/15-minute-seo.php" title="Read the Article">15 Minute SEO</a></dt>
<dd>I don&#8217;t know how up to date this article is, but wow. Everything you need to know, nicely packaged in one humongous table. After reading through this table (and various articles when I googled common terms), I immediately started rethinking my content. </dd>
<dt><a href="http://tool.motoricerca.info/robots-checker.phtml" title="To the Checker!">Robots File Checker</a></dt>
<dd>A little web form tool to test a potential robots file and make sure it is formatted correctly.</dd>
<dt><a href="http://woorank.com/" title="Visit the WooRank site">WooRank</a></dt>
<dd>WooRank is a tool that calculates a ranking for your site based on common SEO factors, performance, and existing links. Every red light gave me one more topic to learn about.</dd>
<dt><a href-"http://www.seounique.com/blog/anchor-text-optimization/" title="Read the Article">Anchor Text Optimization</a></dt>
<dd>As I continued to fine tune, I ran into an article that focused entirely on link text optimization. Many sites pointed out the importance of backlinks, but this was the first that went in depth on selecting appropriate text and content for those links.</dd>
<dt><a href="http://www.traffictravis.com/" title="Visit the TrafficTravis site">Traffic Travis</a></dt>
<dd>Traffic Travis is a set of tools that allows you to analyze your website, keyword usage, search indices, and several more key indicators that hep you track whether changes you are making are improving or degrading your position. The tools have a free version, with more extensive abilities available with the premium version.</dd>
<dt><a href="http://google.com/analytics" title="Visit Google Analytics">Google Analytics</a></dt>
<dd>In order to try and get a handle on outstanding issues, I added my site to Google Analytics and watched it daily. I tweaked my (until then missing) robots file to keep the search engines pointed at the pages I wanted them on, instead of the ones they had somehow found, and watched the traffic each day to see what was getting picked up.</dd>
</dl>
<div style="background-color: #eeeeee; padding: 1em; font-style: italic">Note: if you visit my site&#8217;s <a href="http://tiernok.com/" title="Tarwn's About Site page">About page</a>, you will notice a simple graphic on the right side that shows time for ongoing development. Each of these bars (after the first few) were driven from the Analytics and Ranking tools, as I continue to expand the site, attempt to engage my target keywords, and capture existing search engine topics that previously linked to me.</div>
<p></p>
<h2>The Results, so Far</h2>
<p>After less than 10 hours invested in both learning from the links and tools above, and applying that knowledge to my site, I achieved the top position in Google for both &#8220;Tarwn&#8221; and &#8220;Eli Weinstock-Herman&#8221;. I do have to admit I feel a little bad, though, as I have apparently also started edging into the results of someone named <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=eli+page" title="Try the google search">&#8220;Eli Page&#8221;</a> by complete accident. Bing has me listed for 3 and 4 currently, which is great considering I started on page two with one of my names. Yahoo has gracefully given me top spots for both names, once again just barely nudging my LinkedIn profile down to second place. </p>
<p>Unfortunately there were no quick secrets to what I did (and continue to do). I read and re-read the articles I found from searching terms on the 15-minute article, use the tools above every few days to continue to tweak and change values, and read up on every suggestion I see mentioned in the WooRank results. Considering my low traffic rate (by design) and the purpose of my site (help people learn more about me), I would consider my result to be a success. I did not intend to become an expert in the magic of SEO, just a basic practitioner. I not only achieved the result I wanted, I also am continuing to practice those skills and have learned enough to speak intelligently (and filter out basic scams) the next time someone wants to sell me SEO services. I may not be an expert, but at least now I could listen to one and understand the language.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/quick-beginners-look-at-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
