<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">IT Professionals &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-03-09T12:50:36Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/" />
	<id>/index.php/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/category/itprofessionals/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple NuGet Methods for VS2017 + MSBuild 15 in TeamCity]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/multiple-nuget-methods-for-vs2017-msbuild-15-in-teamcity/" />
		<id>/?p=8697</id>
		<updated>2017-07-19T18:06:25Z</updated>
		<published>2017-07-19T18:06:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Software and Configuration Management" /><category scheme="/" term="nuget" /><category scheme="/" term="teamcity" /><category scheme="/" term="Visual Studio 2017" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[ASP.Net Projects and NuGet have been a moving target the last couple years. I have an ASP.Net Core project (.Net Framework) with several class libraries and had to work through a number of problems to get NuGet Restore working on a TeamCity CI server. Hopefully this will help someone else along the way. It turns [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/multiple-nuget-methods-for-vs2017-msbuild-15-in-teamcity/"><![CDATA[<p>ASP.Net Projects and NuGet have been a moving target the last couple years. I have an ASP.Net Core project (.Net Framework) with several class libraries and had to work through a number of problems to get NuGet Restore working on a TeamCity CI server. Hopefully this will help someone else along the way. </p>
<p>It turns out I have 3 situations:</p>
<ul>
<li>ASP.Net Core uses the new <a href="http://blog.nuget.org/20170316/NuGet-now-fully-integrated-into-MSBuild.html">PackageReference</a> for packages instead of packages.json</li>
<li>Other C# Projects still use the packages.json method for packages</li>
<li>Solution packages (great for tooling) are (still) not supported after VS 2013 (<a href="https://github.com/NuGet/Home/issues/522">NuGet #522</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>(the last couple years also saw the ill-fated project.json, which isn&#8217;t represented here and may or may not be covered by one of these methods)</p>
<p>The software versions I am working with are:</p>
<ul>
<li>TeamCity 2017.1</li>
<li>NuGet 4.1.0</li>
<li>Visual Studio 2017 Community</li>
<li>MS Build Tools 2017 (MSBuild 15)</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;ve outlined the issues I ran into and the individual Build Steps I used to workaround them.</p>
<h2>Some of the issues</h2>
<p><b>Issue #1: Restoring packages.json + PackageReference</b></p>
<p>NuGet Restore is built into MSBuild 15 (<code>msbuild /t:restore</code>) to support the new PackageReference case. Supposedly NuGet.exe 4+ supports this out of the box, but I was unable to make this work (<a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/nuget/consume-packages/package-restore">NuGet Package Restore</a>):</p>
<blockquote><p>
<code>msbuild /t:restore</code> 	Nuget 4.x+ and MSBuild 15.1+ with package references in project files only. nuget restore and dotnet restore both use this command for applicable projects. See NuGet pack and restore as MSBuild targets- restore target.
</p></blockquote>
<p>It is possible to <a href="http://blog.nuget.org/20170316/NuGet-now-fully-integrated-into-MSBuild.html#what-about-other-project-types-that-are-not-net-core">use PackageReference with other project types</a>, but you have to know to turn this on from the beginning. There is no migration option to change tracks with later. </p>
<p><b>Issue #2: MSBuild install location has moved</b><br />
MSBuild installs to a new folder with 2017 (<code>C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft Visual Studio\2017\BuildTools\MSBuild</code>), which means for a while my NuGet Restore commands were defaulting to MSBuild 14. The <code>-MsBuildPath</code> parameter let&#8217;s you provide a path to a specific install, so we can at MSBuild 15 via it&#8217;s new path. </p>
<p><b>Issue #3: Regular Package.json files plus Solution Package.son File</b></p>
<p>When we run it against a <code>*.sln</code> file, NuGet.exe will find and run against each project&#8217;s <code>package.json</code> file. Alternatively, you can also point NuGet.exe directly at a package.json file to install that specific file, which is a workaround for the no longer support solution packages. There is not an option (that I could find) to combine these into a single call.</p>
<p><b>Issue #4: TeamCity only supports NuGet Restore of *.sln files</b></p>
<p>TeamCity restricts the built-in NuGet Restore command to only run against files that end in &#8220;.sln&#8221;. A separate flaw in this restriction was <a href="https://blog.jetbrains.com/teamcity/2013/08/nuget-package-restore-with-teamcity/#comment-177428">pointed out to JetBrains in 2015</a>, but has not been fixed as of TeamCity 2017.1.</p>
<p>This restriction prevents me from doing a clean NuGet Restore of my solution-level packages.json from issue #3.</p>
<h2>The Fixes</h2>
<p>I ended up using 3 Build Steps to do NuGet restores in TeamCity for this one ASP.Net Core deployment.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8699" style="width: 882px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/TeamCityNuGetRestorePost.png" alt="TeamCity NuGet Restore Steps" width="872" height="239" class="size-full wp-image-8699" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/TeamCityNuGetRestorePost.png 872w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/TeamCityNuGetRestorePost-300x82.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/TeamCityNuGetRestorePost-768x210.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 872px) 100vw, 872px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">TeamCity NuGet Restore Steps</p></div><br />
<b>1. Restore from package.json files</b></p>
<p>I used the built-in Nuget Installer with the Restore option and the name of my solution file. I added an extra command line parameter to point it at MSBuild 15:<br />
<code>-MsBuildPath "C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft Visual Studio\2017\BuildTools\MSBuild\15.0\Bin"</code>.</p>
<p><b>2. Restore from PackageReferences</b></p>
<p>For PackageReference, I used the MSBuild task in TeamCity with my Solution file as the Build file path and a target of &#8220;Restore&#8221; (same as running <code>msbuild /t:Restore</code>).</p>
<p><b>3. Restore Solution-level packages</b></p>
<p>A solution-level packages file is useful for solution-level build and deploy tools that aren&#8217;t needed locally. Because TeamCity has an artifical constraint on only accepting *.sln files, I solved this with a <code>Command Line</code> runner type with the following script:</p>
<p><code>%teamcity.tool.NuGet.CommandLine.DEFAULT%\\tools\\nuget.exe restore Deployment/packages.config -PackagesDirectory packages</code></p>
<p>Deployment/packages.config is my solution-level packages file. The TeamCity variable resolves to the path of my default NuGet installation, which is 4.1.0 in this case.</p>
<h2>Final Words</h2>
<p>This experience was roughly 3-5 times longer than I expected, given the number of ASP.Net deployments, TeamCity setups, and so on I&#8217;ve done over the years. The playing field feels littered with half-baked solutions that not only break backwards compatibility, but break compatibility across projects in the same solution using vanilla Visual Studio project templates. </p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/multiple-nuget-methods-for-vs2017-msbuild-15-in-teamcity/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/multiple-nuget-methods-for-vs2017-msbuild-15-in-teamcity/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>damber</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Software Development Survey 2017]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/webdev/software-development-survey-2017/" />
		<id>/?p=8651</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T19:28:11Z</updated>
		<published>2017-05-31T17:10:36Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="All Blogs" /><category scheme="/" term="Architecture, Design and Strategy" /><category scheme="/" term="Data Management" /><category scheme="/" term="Designing Multi-Application Solutions" /><category scheme="/" term="Designing Software" /><category scheme="/" term="Enterprise Architecture" /><category scheme="/" term="Enterprise Developer" /><category scheme="/" term="Enterprise Development" /><category scheme="/" term="IT Professionals" /><category scheme="/" term="Management" /><category scheme="/" term="Web Developer" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[&#160; So, you’re a developer? or an architect? or maybe even a technical delivery manager? Great 🙂 I need you! I’m currently doing some research for an upcoming book, and for a new software product, and who better to ask than those that are building and delivering software solutions each and every day? So I’d like [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/webdev/software-development-survey-2017/"><![CDATA[<p class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8652" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/shutterstock_374219557-small-1024x683.jpg" alt="Person having a bright idea" width="800" height="533" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/shutterstock_374219557-small-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/shutterstock_374219557-small-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/shutterstock_374219557-small-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/shutterstock_374219557-small.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p id="f163" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure">So, you’re a developer? or an architect? or maybe even a technical delivery manager?</p>
<p id="654c" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">Great <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p id="e525" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">I need you!</p>
<p id="4ba4" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">I’m currently doing some research for an upcoming book, and for a new software product, and who better to ask than those that are building and delivering software solutions each and every day?</p>
<p id="4b38" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">So I’d like you to share the wisdom of your experience, by filling in a survey that will take you about 10–15 minutes to complete, about your experiences with designing, building, running and managing software. Start-ups and Enterprises both welcome.</p>
<p id="5c00" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">There is a prize draw for an Amazon Echo, which you can opt into, as a thank-you for taking the time.</p>
<p id="8b54" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">So, if you design, build or manage software on a regular basis, I would like to hear from you…</p>
<p id="3ecf" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">Do you think you can help?</p>
<p id="1415" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing"><a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://enterprisecore.io/page/making-systems-work-survey-2017" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://enterprisecore.io/page/making-systems-work-survey-2017</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/webdev/software-development-survey-2017/#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/webdev/software-development-survey-2017/feed/atom/" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Catch my keynote at Chicago Code Camp 2017!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/" />
		<id>/?p=8628</id>
		<updated>2017-03-28T20:37:55Z</updated>
		<published>2017-03-28T20:37:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a notebook for my Ideas, and Dreams, and Goals. Here&#8217;s one of my Ideas. I watched a very inspiring keynote at That Conference, and I decided I wanted to be the person at the front of the room, giving a keynote, inspiring the audience. Achievement unlocked: on Saturday, April 29, 2017, I&#8217;ll be [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8631" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook-225x300.jpg" alt="notebook" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook.jpg 1512w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a></p>
<p>I have a notebook for my Ideas, and Dreams, and Goals.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s one of my Ideas.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8632" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal-225x300.jpg" alt="goal" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal.jpg 1512w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a></p>
<p>I watched a very inspiring keynote at <a href="https://www.thatconference.com/">That Conference</a>, and I decided I wanted to be the person at the front of the room, giving a keynote, inspiring the audience.</p>
<p>Achievement unlocked: on Saturday, April 29, 2017, I&#8217;ll be the keynote speaker at <a href="https://www.chicagocodecamp.com/">Chicago Code Camp 2017</a>! This event, in its ninth year, is a free, volunteer-run, day-long conference in downtown Chicago. There&#8217;s a huge list of technical sessions, ranging from React to Machine Learning to Docker.</p>
<p>My keynote is &#8220;Busy is a Four Letter Word&#8221;. I&#8217;m tired of asking people, &#8220;How are you?&#8221; only to hear, &#8220;I&#8217;m so busy.&#8221; What I want to hear is, &#8220;I&#8217;m learning a new skill or language&#8221;, or &#8220;I recently had this great adventure&#8221;, or &#8220;I&#8217;m content with my life.&#8221; How do we, as over-worked, over-scheduled, over-tired people get to that state? I&#8217;m going to share what I&#8217;ve learned about how to be less busy &#8211; how to say no, how to set a priority, and how to enjoy being bored again!</p>
<p>Register today to attend this free event and get a great day of technical training!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/#comments" thr:count="4"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/feed/atom/" thr:count="4"/>
		<thr:total>4</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[You Are Responsible for Telling Your Story]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/" />
		<id>/?p=5006</id>
		<updated>2017-01-27T02:11:08Z</updated>
		<published>2017-01-27T13:00:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="IT Professionals" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I’m writing this, it’s January, and I see a steady stream of “working on my annual review” tweets. You want something. (We all do.) It could be a raise or a promotion at your current job, a new job, or a board position at a non-profit you love. How do you get that something? [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/"><![CDATA[<p>As I’m writing this, it’s January, and I see a steady stream of “working on my annual review” tweets.</p>
<p>You want something. (We all do.) It could be a raise or a promotion at your current job, a new job, or a board position at a non-profit you love. How do you get that something? You tell people what you’ve already accomplished, and why you deserve more.</p>
<h3>Why <em>you</em> need to be the one to tell your story</h3>
<p>What you need to keep in mind, always, is that you are the only one that knows what you have done. Projects you’ve completed, milestones you’ve reached, and goals you’ve conquered haven’t been noticed by everyone. Your manager can’t know everything (and probably doesn’t write down everything she does know). Your team members are too busy taking care of their own work to notice. Your customers are happy you’ve done the work, but don’t know what went into it. No one else is keeping a list of your accomplishments.</p>
<p>You are in charge of telling your story.</p>
<h3>How do I tell my story?</h3>
<p>The first step is to make a list of what you’ve accomplished. <strong>Be specific</strong>. Write down as many details as you can remember. Dig through emails to find more information. Look through notes you kept about a project. Read documentation you wrote.</p>
<p>Now, pull out the main points.</p>
<p>Then, tell the story.</p>
<p>Let’s travel back to middle school English class. Every story has five parts: exposition, rising action, climax, falling action, resolution.  Your story should have the same.</p>
<p>Exposition is where you set the stage. What is the background of the project or task you were working on? Was it an internal or external request? Was it something you’d done before and were optimizing, or a new task you had to learn?</p>
<p>Rising action is where you can list what went into planning and executing the project. What resources did you need to gather, and how did you do so? What new skills did you learn?</p>
<p>At the climax, you’ve accomplished the goal. Brag about it. Did you meet deadlines, stay within budget, surpass expectations? List these things! This can be hard. It takes a lot of effort to put yourself front and center. Remember your end goal, what it is you want. Without talking about what you’ve done, you can’t get to that goal.</p>
<p>Falling action is also very important – after the main part of the project, what impact did it have? Have you gotten compliments on the work? Add those. If you can add specific impact, such as hours or money saved by a process, do so!</p>
<p>Resolution is where you let people know why it’s important to you. Did you learn something fascinating? Did you accomplish a major goal? Did you free up time to be able to do something else?</p>
<p>Segue this into what you want. You’re clearly making the case for something – that raise, promotion, or new position. Another thing to remember, which could be a blog post of its own, is that you don’t get what you don’t ask for. This is why we tell our story – so we can get what we want <em>and</em> need.</p>
<h3>When to tell your story</h3>
<p>Writing your story about your accomplishments isn’t something you should be doing just once a year, in January, when your annual review is due. It should be a regular part of your professional development process.</p>
<p>If you haven’t put together a list of your accomplishments for six months or more, open up a document and start writing, right now.</p>
<p>Today is also a great day to start keeping notes for your future story. It can be in a format as simple as a notebook where you take notes every day or week. I love using OneNote. You could use a Word document. Use whatever format works for you.</p>
<p>Don’t wait until the end of the year to update it. If you have to, put an appointment on your calendar or a task on your list at least every month to update this.</p>
<p>In order to get what you want, you have to prove why you deserve it. Write your story so you can get it.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/#comments" thr:count="3"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/feed/atom/" thr:count="3"/>
		<thr:total>3</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[A Communications Hack for Helpful Ideas]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/helpful-developers-and-angry-coworkers/" />
		<id>/?p=4711</id>
		<updated>2016-11-03T17:55:39Z</updated>
		<published>2016-11-03T17:51:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="IT Professionals" /><category scheme="/" term="communication" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You&#8217;re taking a break from the two week project and bump into Joe at the coffee machine. He&#8217;s a little frazzled and starts telling you about this little task he took on Monday that is kicking his butt. While he&#8217;s explaining you realize he might have missed a simpler answer, so you ask him if [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/helpful-developers-and-angry-coworkers/"><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;re taking a break from the two week project and bump into Joe at the coffee machine. He&#8217;s a little frazzled and starts telling you about this little task he took on Monday that is kicking his butt. While he&#8217;s explaining you realize he might have missed a simpler answer, so you ask him if he tried it. He immediately gets angry, of course he tried it, what are you trying to say? And here&#8217;s all the ways that wouldn&#8217;t work, and so on, then disappears back into his office. </p>
<p>Why is Joe always so annoyed? He needs to work on his communication skills.</p>
<h3>Joe&#8217;s Perspective</h3>
<p>You&#8217;re three days into a one hour problem, having chased down and exhausted 4 different approaches before finally finding an approach that is going to work. It&#8217;s a little ugly and you&#8217;re a little frustrated that it&#8217;s Wednesday afternoon on a task you though would be done by lunch on Monday. While you&#8217;re waiting for the coffee machine to do it&#8217;s thing, Mary joins you and asks how it&#8217;s going. Being top of mind, you start talking about the frustrating problem you&#8217;re working on and the (annoyingly) complex solution you&#8217;ve come up with. </p>
<p>Two sentences in, Mary jumps in, <i>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you do X?&#8221;</i></p>
<p><i>&#8220;What, you think I didn&#8217;t try that already?&#8221;</i> your inner voice wants to respond. </p>
<p>It puts you on the defensive, so you quickly explain why that wouldn&#8217;t work, maybe putting a little too much annoyance in your voice (but then again, she did assume you missed the solution she came up with in 5 seconds for a problem you&#8217;ve spent 2 days and 4 solutions on…). </p>
<p>Why does Mary always think so little of others?</p>
<h2><i>&#8220;Why did you…&#8221;</i> sounds different on the receiving end</h2>
<p>We&#8217;re problem solvers and want to solve challenges. It might be to help someone, it might be to help reinforce an image of ourselves as the smartest person on the team, or it might just be because problem solving is fun. When we offer a better solution and someone bites our hand off for it, we walk away thinking a little bit worse of them.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s easy to blame &#8220;Joe&#8221; and call him quick to anger, but sometimes we&#8217;re the &#8220;Joe&#8221; in the story and don&#8217;t know why we have to prove everything we say.</p>
<p><i>&#8220;Why did&#8230;&#8221;</i> can sound like a demand for an explanation or a challenge to our ability when we&#8217;re stressed and on the receiving end. However from the asking side it&#8217;s just words, most of the time we&#8217;re saying <i>&#8220;Why did you&#8230;?&#8221;</i> but thinking <i>&#8220;I wonder if they tried&#8230;?&#8221;</i>.</p>
<p>Communication takes two people, so weis the listener as well as the speaker. In the story above, Joe and Mary failed to communicate and it escalated. if it occurs frequently enough, it will leave them predisposed to one another and they&#8217;ll start purposefully treating one another antagonistically.</p>
<h2><i>&#8220;Have you considered…?&#8221;</i></h2>
<p>A few years back I was frequently butting heads (and vice versa) with a developer I respect a lot and consider a friend. It was a small team and I was spending more time developing then managing, so besides having naturally strong opinions as a developer, I had the manager title adding greater emphasis to everything I said.</p>
<p>Our conversations frequently devolved into defensive debates, and one day during a one-on-one we realized that the word choice we started conversations was the thing that tended to start off us of on the wrong foot. We decided to start using the phrase <i>&#8220;Have you considered&#8230;?&#8221;</i> in all of those cases where we would normally use <i>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you&#8230;?&#8221;</i></p>
<p>The change was instant and our conversations and whiteboarding sessions were immediately an order of magnitude better.</p>
<h2>Here&#8217;s why we think it worked</h2>
<p><i>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t [you]&#8230;?&#8221;</i> is really asking you to explain your actions (or lack of). It sounds like a challenge and it&#8217;s not hard to wonder if they also meant <i>&#8220;&#8230;and I assume you didn&#8217;t think of that&#8221;</i>. Add in some stress to exaggerate the possibility of a challenge into hearing one that most of the time isn&#8217;t there, and we&#8217;re instantly on the defensive.</p>
<p><i>&#8220;Have you considered&#8230;?</i>&#8221; is a more collaborative question. It forces you to acknowledge that they might have already considered what you&#8217;re about to say and, if you continue to say it, invites a conversation instead of an explanation. You have to actually want to hear about it if they tried the suggestion and it didn&#8217;t work. And the times where you did just want to drop in the answer and walk on, it forces you to rethink whether you want to be the person that assumes the folks around you can miss something for days that you noticed in 30 seconds (even if it&#8217;s true 90% of the time, you&#8217;re going to be wrong 10% of the time and annoying 110% of the time).</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t believe me? Try out these phrases:</p>
<p><i><br />
&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you use the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Have you considered using the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Why aren&#8217;t you using Angular for that project?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Have you considered Angular for that project?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you break that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Have you considered breaking that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
</i></p>
<p>Now try reading them in the other order:</p>
<p><i><br />
&#8220;Have you considered using the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you use the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Have you considered Angular for that project?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Why aren&#8217;t you using Angular for that project?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Have you considered breaking that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you break that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
</i></p>
<p>Can both versions of these questions be interpreted the same? Absolutely. But as you add stress, distraction, any history of interrupting folks to tell them at length how they should be solving their problems, &#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you&#8230;&#8221; does start to sound more like a challenge.</p>
<h2>The results as we spread it further</h2>
<p>It absolutely worked in our situation, to the degree that we shared the phrase and results with the rest of the team a few weeks later and, several years later, we continue to use it and introduce it to new folks. It may not be exactly the phrase you need in your environment, but find a phrase that everyone interprets as &#8220;I respect you, would like to know more about the problem, and wonder what you found when trying X&#8221; and use it.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/helpful-developers-and-angry-coworkers/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/helpful-developers-and-angry-coworkers/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m talking SQL Server, Azure, and Extended Events at SQLintersection]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/" />
		<id>/?p=4664</id>
		<updated>2016-09-08T19:38:07Z</updated>
		<published>2016-08-18T13:59:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ll be in Las Vegas October 24-28, 2016 for SQLintersection, part of the DEVintersection conference series! Why attend DEVintersection? It “brings your favorite Microsoft leaders, engineers and industry experts together to educate, network, and share their expertise with you. Just this year, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server 2016, Visual Studio 2015, Windows 10 and SharePoint 2016 [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ll be in Las Vegas October 24-28, 2016 for <a href="https://devintersection.com/#!/SQL-Conference">SQLintersection</a>, part of the <a href="https://devintersection.com/#!/">DEVintersection</a> conference series! Why attend DEVintersection? It “brings your favorite Microsoft leaders, engineers and industry experts together to educate, network, and share their expertise with you. Just this year, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server 2016, Visual Studio 2015, Windows 10 and SharePoint 2016 launched. The new release of Windows Server is on the horizon and open source is becoming the norm. The cloud is real and so is cloud scaling. Are you ready?”</p>
<p>What’s that about SQL Server and Azure? I’m talking about both of them a lot that week! On Monday, October 24, I’m leading a full-day workshop, Get Started With SQL Server In Azure. This is seven hours of discussion about Azure fundamentals, the difference between IaaS (VMs) and PaaS (SQL Database). I talk about when to use each, along with how to create, maintain, and monitor them. If your organization wants to start putting data in Azure (or has already started), you don’t want to miss this!</p>
<p>But that’s not it! I have three other sessions throughout the week.</p>
<ul>
<li>SQL Server in Azure: Essentials for the Database Administrator – In this 75-minute session, I distill the most important information any DBA needs to know about SQL Server VMs and SQL Database. You’re going to learn how to choose the right service, how to perform your essential admin tasks, how to monitor them, and more!</li>
<li>SQL Server in Azure: Essentials for the Database Developer – This 60-minute session covers what you need to know about writing and tuning T-SQL for SQL Server VMs and SQL Database. There are differences in syntax and tools; join me to learn more!</li>
<li>Everyday Extended Events – First, go to Erin Stellato’s session, Kicking and Screaming: Replacing Profiler with Extended Events. She covers all the basics – what XE is, how to create sessions, and how to view the data. Then, stick around for my session, where I show you the sessions used most frequently. Tasks like capturing query performance, gathering deadlock information, and integrating XE and SQL Server Agent will be covered.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are dozens of other SQL Server workshops and sessions, not to mention the Azure, Visual Studio, and SharePoint sessions running concurrently. On Thursday evening, you won’t want to miss SQL after Dark, hosted by Paul Randal &amp; Kimberly Tripp! Check out <a href="https://devintxcontent.blob.core.windows.net/showcontent/Schedule/DEVintersection_Fall%2016_SQL_Schedule.pdf">the full SQLintersection schedule here</a>! Hurry and <a href="https://devintersection.com/#!/register">register today</a>! Prices increase on September 13, and again on September 28, so don’t delay!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn more about Azure + SQL Server at SQLSaturday Minnesota]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/" />
		<id>/?p=4661</id>
		<updated>2016-08-15T20:48:43Z</updated>
		<published>2016-08-15T20:48:43Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;m excited to cross the Mississippi River again this autumn to present at SQLSaturday #557 Minnesota 2016. First, I&#8217;ll be giving a full-day pre-conference session, &#8220;Get Started With SQL Server in Azure&#8221;, on Friday, September 30. Tickets are only $110, include lunch, and you&#8217;ll get to hear me talk about What you need to know about [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m excited to cross the Mississippi River again this autumn to present at <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQLSaturday #557 Minnesota 2016</a>.</p>
<p>First, I&#8217;ll be giving a full-day pre-conference session, &#8220;Get Started With SQL Server in Azure&#8221;, on Friday, September 30. Tickets are only $110, include lunch, and you&#8217;ll get to hear me talk about</p>
<ul>
<li>What you need to know about Azure networking before creating a single database</li>
<li>The differences between the IaaS and PaaS offerings, and when to use each</li>
<li>How to create, manage, and monitor IaaS SQL Server VMs</li>
<li>How to create, manage, and monitor PaaS SQL Databases</li>
</ul>
<p>Every attendee will get a link to my GitHub repository with scripts to accomplish many of the tasks I talk about! <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#CL1" target="_blank">Register today for this great class</a>!</p>
<p>Second, I&#8217;ll be attending and presenting on Saturday, October 1. My session is &#8220;SQL Server in Azure: Essentials for the Database Administrator&#8221;. I cover what DBAs need to know about SQL Server VMs, SQL Database, networking, security, and monitoring to make Azure fit into their current environments.</p>
<p>But I&#8217;m giving only <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/Sessions/Schedule.aspx" target="_blank">1 of 48 sessions</a>! SQLSaturday has something for everyone &#8211; the DBA, the database developer, the BI practitioner. I hope to see you at SQLSaturday Minnesota!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Paul Timmerman</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing SQL Saturday Minnesota #557 Pre-Conference Seminars!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/" />
		<id>/?p=4639</id>
		<updated>2016-07-21T21:15:12Z</updated>
		<published>2016-07-21T21:15:12Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before we know it, October will be upon us and it will be time for another SQL Saturday Minnesota!  If you have not yet registered for this free day of training on Saturday October 1st, please visit the site and sign up now! Since no SQL Saturday Minnesota would be complete without a full slate of pre-cons, PASSMN and the organizers of SQL [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/"><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #272727">Before we know it, October will be upon us and it will be time for another <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQL Saturday Minnesota</a>!  If you have not yet registered for this free day of training on Saturday October 1st, please visit the <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">site </a>and sign up now!</span></p>
<p>Since no <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQL Saturday Minnesota</a> would be complete without a full slate of pre-cons, <a href="http://passmn.org/" target="_blank">PASSMN</a> and the organizers of SQL Saturday #557 are proud to announce the addition of <strong>four</strong> day long pre-cons to be held on <span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ">Friday, September 30th</span></span> from <span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ">9AM &#8211; 5PM</span></span>. Sessions will once again be held at Dakota County Technical College in Rosemount, MN.</p>
<p>For the low price of only <strong>$110</strong> you join Jes Borland and get started with SQL Server in Azure, learn about using R in SQL Server from Pragmatic Works very own Ginger Grant, get a complete primer on infrastructure tuning for your SQL Server from David Klee, or craft a complete strategy for securing your data platform assets with Ed Leighton-Dick.</p>
<p>Visit the links below to review the complete abstracts for these amazing sessions.</p>
<p>Any one of these sessions represents an amazing value for your training dollars!</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="color: black"><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#CL1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Jes Borland</span></a></strong>: </span><span style="color: #272727">Get Started With SQL Server in Azure</span></p>
<p><span style="color: black"><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#BI1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Ginger Grant</span></a></strong>: R School for SQL Pros</span></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#DB1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">David Klee</span></a></strong><span style="color: black">: </span><span style="color: #272727">The Complete Primer to SQL Server Infrastructure Tuning</span></p>
<p><span style="color: black"><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#DB2" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Ed Leighton-Dick</span></a></strong>: </span><span style="color: #272727">Securing the Data Platform: Crafting a Strategy That Works</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Upon successful registration, you will receive a confirmation email from the SQLSaturday #557 team within 48 hours.</p>
<p><span style="color: #272727">You may also access this information by visiting the <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/EventHome.aspx" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">SQL </span><span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ"><span style="color: #1155cc">Saturday</span></span></span><span style="color: #1155cc"> #557 homepage</span></a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #272727">Please direct any questions regarding the pre-cons to the SQL Saturday #557 team at </span><a href="mailto:sqlsaturday557@sqlsaturday.com" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc"><span style="color: #1155cc">sqlsaturday557@sqlsaturday.</span>com</span></a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Help me kick off Wausau PASS!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/" />
		<id>/?p=4630</id>
		<updated>2016-07-19T21:43:21Z</updated>
		<published>2016-07-20T14:00:27Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I started attending Wisconsin SQL Server Users Group in 2009, that was the only PASS chapter in Wisconsin. Since then, we&#8217;ve expanded to include MADPASS, FoxPASS, Western WI PASS, and Microsoft BI Professionals &#8211; WI. These chapters have provided hundreds of hours of free training for hundreds of data professionals in the last few [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/"><![CDATA[<p>When I started attending <a href="http://wisconsin.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Wisconsin SQL Server Users Group</a> in 2009, that was the only PASS chapter in Wisconsin. Since then, we&#8217;ve expanded to include <a href="http://madpass.org/" target="_blank">MADPASS</a>, <a href="http://fox.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">FoxPASS</a>, <a href="http://westwisc.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Western WI PASS</a>, and <a href="http://wisconsinbi.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Microsoft BI Professionals &#8211; WI</a>. These chapters have provided hundreds of hours of free training for hundreds of data professionals in the last few years.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s been missing, in my opinion, is a lack of options for people living in north-central Wisconsin and Michigan&#8217;s UP. However, starting next month, they have a closer chapter! Jesse Seymour (<a href="http://www.jesseseymour.com/" target="_blank">b</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/JesseBizInt" target="_blank">t</a>) is starting <a href="http://wausau.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Wausau PASS</a>, based in (surprise!) Wausau, WI. The first meeting will be Wednesday, August 17, 2016. We&#8217;re meeting at Northcentral Technical College starting at 6:30 PM.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be presenting &#8220;Execution Plans: The Secret to Query Tuning Success&#8221;:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">SQL Server will tell you exactly what ingredients it used and steps it took to return the results of your query. By being able to read this &#8220;recipe&#8221;, you can tell where you can improve it! This session will show you how to read execution plans, what common problems can be uncovered, and what the execution plan doesn&#8217;t tell you. You&#8217;ll leave this session able to go to work, open a plan, and identify where to start fine-tuning the query.</p>
<p>If you can join, we&#8217;d love to see you! Please <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wausaupass-august-meeting-tickets-25795334540" target="_blank">RSVP for the event</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="https://www.sqlpass.org/RegisterforSQLPASS.aspx?returnurl=https://wausau.sqlpass.org/Home.aspx" target="_blank">register for Wausau PASS&#8217;s mailing list</a> to be notified of future meetings and events!</p>
<p>Kudos to Jesse for getting this chapter started!</p>
<div id="attachment_4632" style="width: 303px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4632" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS-293x300.png" alt="PASS chapters in Wisconsin" width="293" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS-293x300.png 293w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS.png 575w" sizes="(max-width: 293px) 100vw, 293px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">PASS chapters in Wisconsin</p></div>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned on SQL Cruise 2016]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/" />
		<id>/?p=4366</id>
		<updated>2016-02-15T15:11:25Z</updated>
		<published>2016-02-15T15:11:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[1. Tim and Amy Ford put a lot of hard work into making this event run. They do a great job. Everyone learns, shares, has fun, relaxes, and did I mention learns? 2. Jason Hall from SQL Sentry taught his class Tempdb Parasites, and I learned about temp table caching. This is amazing! SQL Sentry [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/"><![CDATA[<p>1. Tim and Amy Ford put a lot of hard work into making this event run. They do a great job. Everyone learns, shares, has fun, relaxes, and did I mention learns?</p>
<p>2. <a href="https://twitter.com/SQLSaurus" target="_blank">Jason Hall</a> from <a href="http://www.sqlsentry.com/" target="_blank">SQL Sentry</a> taught his class Tempdb Parasites, and I learned about temp table caching. This is amazing! SQL Sentry also gave cruisers some amazing, to-be-jealous-of swag. If you were there, you would have gotten it!</p>
<p>3. Zip lining through the canopy on Tortola is amazing.</p>
<div id="attachment_4369" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-4369 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792-300x169.jpg" alt="SQLCruiseTortola" width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792-1024x579.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792.jpg 1344w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The view from the zip lining platform.</p></div>
<p>4. <a href="https://twitter.com/GFritchey" target="_blank">Grant Fritchey</a> from <a href="http://www.red-gate.com/" target="_blank">Red Gate</a> brought his A game to talk about Query Store, a new feature in SQL Server 2016&#8230;but already available in Azure SQL Database. Red Gate continues to be an awesome sponsor of the cruise, and I&#8217;m thrilled they sent Grant to speak.</p>
<div id="attachment_4368" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4368" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1840-300x168.jpg" alt="Listening to Grant talk. " width="300" height="168" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1840-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1840-1024x576.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Listening to Grant talk.</p></div>
<p>5. <a href="https://twitter.com/sqllensman" target="_blank">Patrick Flynn</a> is an Ironman!</p>
<p>6. During Office Hours, one cruiser asked, &#8220;How do you do *it* &#8211; keeping up with the community/speaking/blogging, while having a family and a job?&#8221; That turned into one of the most honest discussions I&#8217;ve been part of on that topic. It&#8217;s not easy &#8211; for any of us. It requires balance. Those conversations are what Office Hours is all about.</p>
<p>7. Running a 5K in Charlotte Amalie, St Thomas, is a lot of work. Those hills! Those 99 Stairs! But having two fellow cruisers along makes it a lot more fun. (Thanks Jared and Drew!)</p>
<div id="attachment_4367" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4367" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1750-300x169.jpg" alt="We ran up to that view. RAN. UP! " width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1750-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1750-1024x579.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">We ran up to that view. RAN. UP!</p></div>
<p>8. The rum at John Watling&#8217;s Distillery in Nassau is amazing. Belly up to the bar for a tasting and one of their house cocktails.</p>
<div id="attachment_4370" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4370" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862-300x169.jpg" alt="A class in how rum is distilled, stored, and bottled at John Watling's. " width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862-1024x579.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862.jpg 1344w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">A class in how rum is distilled, stored, and bottled at John Watling&#8217;s.</p></div>
<p>9. <a href="https://twitter.com/kleegeek" target="_blank">David Klee</a> of <a href="http://heraflux.com/" target="_blank">Heraflux Technologies </a>is an amazing resource for anything infrastructure related, and has great resources on his website.</p>
<p>10. Not that we didn&#8217;t know, but <a href="https://twitter.com/DBArgenis" target="_blank">Argenis Fernandez</a> reminded us, &#8220;Security is not easy&#8221;&#8230;as he hacked SQL Server data from packets and read through dlls for dangerous data.</p>
<p>11. The 2017 itineraries are going to be amazing. Keep an eye on <a href="http://sqlcruise.com/" target="_blank">http://sqlcruise.com/</a> for the details!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/#comments" thr:count="3"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/feed/atom/" thr:count="3"/>
		<thr:total>3</thr:total>
		</entry>
	</feed>
