<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Professional Development &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-03-09T12:50:36Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/" />
	<id>/index.php/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/category/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Catch my keynote at Chicago Code Camp 2017!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/" />
		<id>/?p=8628</id>
		<updated>2017-03-28T20:37:55Z</updated>
		<published>2017-03-28T20:37:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a notebook for my Ideas, and Dreams, and Goals. Here&#8217;s one of my Ideas. I watched a very inspiring keynote at That Conference, and I decided I wanted to be the person at the front of the room, giving a keynote, inspiring the audience. Achievement unlocked: on Saturday, April 29, 2017, I&#8217;ll be [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8631" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook-225x300.jpg" alt="notebook" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Notebook.jpg 1512w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a></p>
<p>I have a notebook for my Ideas, and Dreams, and Goals.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s one of my Ideas.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8632" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal-225x300.jpg" alt="goal" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Goal.jpg 1512w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a></p>
<p>I watched a very inspiring keynote at <a href="https://www.thatconference.com/">That Conference</a>, and I decided I wanted to be the person at the front of the room, giving a keynote, inspiring the audience.</p>
<p>Achievement unlocked: on Saturday, April 29, 2017, I&#8217;ll be the keynote speaker at <a href="https://www.chicagocodecamp.com/">Chicago Code Camp 2017</a>! This event, in its ninth year, is a free, volunteer-run, day-long conference in downtown Chicago. There&#8217;s a huge list of technical sessions, ranging from React to Machine Learning to Docker.</p>
<p>My keynote is &#8220;Busy is a Four Letter Word&#8221;. I&#8217;m tired of asking people, &#8220;How are you?&#8221; only to hear, &#8220;I&#8217;m so busy.&#8221; What I want to hear is, &#8220;I&#8217;m learning a new skill or language&#8221;, or &#8220;I recently had this great adventure&#8221;, or &#8220;I&#8217;m content with my life.&#8221; How do we, as over-worked, over-scheduled, over-tired people get to that state? I&#8217;m going to share what I&#8217;ve learned about how to be less busy &#8211; how to say no, how to set a priority, and how to enjoy being bored again!</p>
<p>Register today to attend this free event and get a great day of technical training!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/#comments" thr:count="4"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/catch-my-keynote-at-chicago-code-camp-2017/feed/atom/" thr:count="4"/>
		<thr:total>4</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[You Are Responsible for Telling Your Story]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/" />
		<id>/?p=5006</id>
		<updated>2017-01-27T02:11:08Z</updated>
		<published>2017-01-27T13:00:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="IT Professionals" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I’m writing this, it’s January, and I see a steady stream of “working on my annual review” tweets. You want something. (We all do.) It could be a raise or a promotion at your current job, a new job, or a board position at a non-profit you love. How do you get that something? [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/"><![CDATA[<p>As I’m writing this, it’s January, and I see a steady stream of “working on my annual review” tweets.</p>
<p>You want something. (We all do.) It could be a raise or a promotion at your current job, a new job, or a board position at a non-profit you love. How do you get that something? You tell people what you’ve already accomplished, and why you deserve more.</p>
<h3>Why <em>you</em> need to be the one to tell your story</h3>
<p>What you need to keep in mind, always, is that you are the only one that knows what you have done. Projects you’ve completed, milestones you’ve reached, and goals you’ve conquered haven’t been noticed by everyone. Your manager can’t know everything (and probably doesn’t write down everything she does know). Your team members are too busy taking care of their own work to notice. Your customers are happy you’ve done the work, but don’t know what went into it. No one else is keeping a list of your accomplishments.</p>
<p>You are in charge of telling your story.</p>
<h3>How do I tell my story?</h3>
<p>The first step is to make a list of what you’ve accomplished. <strong>Be specific</strong>. Write down as many details as you can remember. Dig through emails to find more information. Look through notes you kept about a project. Read documentation you wrote.</p>
<p>Now, pull out the main points.</p>
<p>Then, tell the story.</p>
<p>Let’s travel back to middle school English class. Every story has five parts: exposition, rising action, climax, falling action, resolution.  Your story should have the same.</p>
<p>Exposition is where you set the stage. What is the background of the project or task you were working on? Was it an internal or external request? Was it something you’d done before and were optimizing, or a new task you had to learn?</p>
<p>Rising action is where you can list what went into planning and executing the project. What resources did you need to gather, and how did you do so? What new skills did you learn?</p>
<p>At the climax, you’ve accomplished the goal. Brag about it. Did you meet deadlines, stay within budget, surpass expectations? List these things! This can be hard. It takes a lot of effort to put yourself front and center. Remember your end goal, what it is you want. Without talking about what you’ve done, you can’t get to that goal.</p>
<p>Falling action is also very important – after the main part of the project, what impact did it have? Have you gotten compliments on the work? Add those. If you can add specific impact, such as hours or money saved by a process, do so!</p>
<p>Resolution is where you let people know why it’s important to you. Did you learn something fascinating? Did you accomplish a major goal? Did you free up time to be able to do something else?</p>
<p>Segue this into what you want. You’re clearly making the case for something – that raise, promotion, or new position. Another thing to remember, which could be a blog post of its own, is that you don’t get what you don’t ask for. This is why we tell our story – so we can get what we want <em>and</em> need.</p>
<h3>When to tell your story</h3>
<p>Writing your story about your accomplishments isn’t something you should be doing just once a year, in January, when your annual review is due. It should be a regular part of your professional development process.</p>
<p>If you haven’t put together a list of your accomplishments for six months or more, open up a document and start writing, right now.</p>
<p>Today is also a great day to start keeping notes for your future story. It can be in a format as simple as a notebook where you take notes every day or week. I love using OneNote. You could use a Word document. Use whatever format works for you.</p>
<p>Don’t wait until the end of the year to update it. If you have to, put an appointment on your calendar or a task on your list at least every month to update this.</p>
<p>In order to get what you want, you have to prove why you deserve it. Write your story so you can get it.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/#comments" thr:count="3"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/you-are-responsible-for-telling-your-story/feed/atom/" thr:count="3"/>
		<thr:total>3</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m talking SQL Server, Azure, and Extended Events at SQLintersection]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/" />
		<id>/?p=4664</id>
		<updated>2016-09-08T19:38:07Z</updated>
		<published>2016-08-18T13:59:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ll be in Las Vegas October 24-28, 2016 for SQLintersection, part of the DEVintersection conference series! Why attend DEVintersection? It “brings your favorite Microsoft leaders, engineers and industry experts together to educate, network, and share their expertise with you. Just this year, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server 2016, Visual Studio 2015, Windows 10 and SharePoint 2016 [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ll be in Las Vegas October 24-28, 2016 for <a href="https://devintersection.com/#!/SQL-Conference">SQLintersection</a>, part of the <a href="https://devintersection.com/#!/">DEVintersection</a> conference series! Why attend DEVintersection? It “brings your favorite Microsoft leaders, engineers and industry experts together to educate, network, and share their expertise with you. Just this year, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server 2016, Visual Studio 2015, Windows 10 and SharePoint 2016 launched. The new release of Windows Server is on the horizon and open source is becoming the norm. The cloud is real and so is cloud scaling. Are you ready?”</p>
<p>What’s that about SQL Server and Azure? I’m talking about both of them a lot that week! On Monday, October 24, I’m leading a full-day workshop, Get Started With SQL Server In Azure. This is seven hours of discussion about Azure fundamentals, the difference between IaaS (VMs) and PaaS (SQL Database). I talk about when to use each, along with how to create, maintain, and monitor them. If your organization wants to start putting data in Azure (or has already started), you don’t want to miss this!</p>
<p>But that’s not it! I have three other sessions throughout the week.</p>
<ul>
<li>SQL Server in Azure: Essentials for the Database Administrator – In this 75-minute session, I distill the most important information any DBA needs to know about SQL Server VMs and SQL Database. You’re going to learn how to choose the right service, how to perform your essential admin tasks, how to monitor them, and more!</li>
<li>SQL Server in Azure: Essentials for the Database Developer – This 60-minute session covers what you need to know about writing and tuning T-SQL for SQL Server VMs and SQL Database. There are differences in syntax and tools; join me to learn more!</li>
<li>Everyday Extended Events – First, go to Erin Stellato’s session, Kicking and Screaming: Replacing Profiler with Extended Events. She covers all the basics – what XE is, how to create sessions, and how to view the data. Then, stick around for my session, where I show you the sessions used most frequently. Tasks like capturing query performance, gathering deadlock information, and integrating XE and SQL Server Agent will be covered.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are dozens of other SQL Server workshops and sessions, not to mention the Azure, Visual Studio, and SharePoint sessions running concurrently. On Thursday evening, you won’t want to miss SQL after Dark, hosted by Paul Randal &amp; Kimberly Tripp! Check out <a href="https://devintxcontent.blob.core.windows.net/showcontent/Schedule/DEVintersection_Fall%2016_SQL_Schedule.pdf">the full SQLintersection schedule here</a>! Hurry and <a href="https://devintersection.com/#!/register">register today</a>! Prices increase on September 13, and again on September 28, so don’t delay!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/im-talking-sql-server-azure-and-extended-events-at-sqlintersection/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn more about Azure + SQL Server at SQLSaturday Minnesota]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/" />
		<id>/?p=4661</id>
		<updated>2016-08-15T20:48:43Z</updated>
		<published>2016-08-15T20:48:43Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;m excited to cross the Mississippi River again this autumn to present at SQLSaturday #557 Minnesota 2016. First, I&#8217;ll be giving a full-day pre-conference session, &#8220;Get Started With SQL Server in Azure&#8221;, on Friday, September 30. Tickets are only $110, include lunch, and you&#8217;ll get to hear me talk about What you need to know about [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m excited to cross the Mississippi River again this autumn to present at <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQLSaturday #557 Minnesota 2016</a>.</p>
<p>First, I&#8217;ll be giving a full-day pre-conference session, &#8220;Get Started With SQL Server in Azure&#8221;, on Friday, September 30. Tickets are only $110, include lunch, and you&#8217;ll get to hear me talk about</p>
<ul>
<li>What you need to know about Azure networking before creating a single database</li>
<li>The differences between the IaaS and PaaS offerings, and when to use each</li>
<li>How to create, manage, and monitor IaaS SQL Server VMs</li>
<li>How to create, manage, and monitor PaaS SQL Databases</li>
</ul>
<p>Every attendee will get a link to my GitHub repository with scripts to accomplish many of the tasks I talk about! <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#CL1" target="_blank">Register today for this great class</a>!</p>
<p>Second, I&#8217;ll be attending and presenting on Saturday, October 1. My session is &#8220;SQL Server in Azure: Essentials for the Database Administrator&#8221;. I cover what DBAs need to know about SQL Server VMs, SQL Database, networking, security, and monitoring to make Azure fit into their current environments.</p>
<p>But I&#8217;m giving only <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/Sessions/Schedule.aspx" target="_blank">1 of 48 sessions</a>! SQLSaturday has something for everyone &#8211; the DBA, the database developer, the BI practitioner. I hope to see you at SQLSaturday Minnesota!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/learn-more-about-azure-sql-server-at-sqlsaturday-minnesota/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Paul Timmerman</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing SQL Saturday Minnesota #557 Pre-Conference Seminars!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/" />
		<id>/?p=4639</id>
		<updated>2016-07-21T21:15:12Z</updated>
		<published>2016-07-21T21:15:12Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before we know it, October will be upon us and it will be time for another SQL Saturday Minnesota!  If you have not yet registered for this free day of training on Saturday October 1st, please visit the site and sign up now! Since no SQL Saturday Minnesota would be complete without a full slate of pre-cons, PASSMN and the organizers of SQL [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/"><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #272727">Before we know it, October will be upon us and it will be time for another <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQL Saturday Minnesota</a>!  If you have not yet registered for this free day of training on Saturday October 1st, please visit the <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">site </a>and sign up now!</span></p>
<p>Since no <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQL Saturday Minnesota</a> would be complete without a full slate of pre-cons, <a href="http://passmn.org/" target="_blank">PASSMN</a> and the organizers of SQL Saturday #557 are proud to announce the addition of <strong>four</strong> day long pre-cons to be held on <span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ">Friday, September 30th</span></span> from <span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ">9AM &#8211; 5PM</span></span>. Sessions will once again be held at Dakota County Technical College in Rosemount, MN.</p>
<p>For the low price of only <strong>$110</strong> you join Jes Borland and get started with SQL Server in Azure, learn about using R in SQL Server from Pragmatic Works very own Ginger Grant, get a complete primer on infrastructure tuning for your SQL Server from David Klee, or craft a complete strategy for securing your data platform assets with Ed Leighton-Dick.</p>
<p>Visit the links below to review the complete abstracts for these amazing sessions.</p>
<p>Any one of these sessions represents an amazing value for your training dollars!</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="color: black"><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#CL1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Jes Borland</span></a></strong>: </span><span style="color: #272727">Get Started With SQL Server in Azure</span></p>
<p><span style="color: black"><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#BI1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Ginger Grant</span></a></strong>: R School for SQL Pros</span></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#DB1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">David Klee</span></a></strong><span style="color: black">: </span><span style="color: #272727">The Complete Primer to SQL Server Infrastructure Tuning</span></p>
<p><span style="color: black"><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday557preconreg/home#DB2" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Ed Leighton-Dick</span></a></strong>: </span><span style="color: #272727">Securing the Data Platform: Crafting a Strategy That Works</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Upon successful registration, you will receive a confirmation email from the SQLSaturday #557 team within 48 hours.</p>
<p><span style="color: #272727">You may also access this information by visiting the <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/557/EventHome.aspx" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">SQL </span><span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ"><span style="color: #1155cc">Saturday</span></span></span><span style="color: #1155cc"> #557 homepage</span></a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #272727">Please direct any questions regarding the pre-cons to the SQL Saturday #557 team at </span><a href="mailto:sqlsaturday557@sqlsaturday.com" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc"><span style="color: #1155cc">sqlsaturday557@sqlsaturday.</span>com</span></a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-557-pre-conference-seminars/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Help me kick off Wausau PASS!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/" />
		<id>/?p=4630</id>
		<updated>2016-07-19T21:43:21Z</updated>
		<published>2016-07-20T14:00:27Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I started attending Wisconsin SQL Server Users Group in 2009, that was the only PASS chapter in Wisconsin. Since then, we&#8217;ve expanded to include MADPASS, FoxPASS, Western WI PASS, and Microsoft BI Professionals &#8211; WI. These chapters have provided hundreds of hours of free training for hundreds of data professionals in the last few [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/"><![CDATA[<p>When I started attending <a href="http://wisconsin.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Wisconsin SQL Server Users Group</a> in 2009, that was the only PASS chapter in Wisconsin. Since then, we&#8217;ve expanded to include <a href="http://madpass.org/" target="_blank">MADPASS</a>, <a href="http://fox.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">FoxPASS</a>, <a href="http://westwisc.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Western WI PASS</a>, and <a href="http://wisconsinbi.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Microsoft BI Professionals &#8211; WI</a>. These chapters have provided hundreds of hours of free training for hundreds of data professionals in the last few years.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s been missing, in my opinion, is a lack of options for people living in north-central Wisconsin and Michigan&#8217;s UP. However, starting next month, they have a closer chapter! Jesse Seymour (<a href="http://www.jesseseymour.com/" target="_blank">b</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/JesseBizInt" target="_blank">t</a>) is starting <a href="http://wausau.sqlpass.org/" target="_blank">Wausau PASS</a>, based in (surprise!) Wausau, WI. The first meeting will be Wednesday, August 17, 2016. We&#8217;re meeting at Northcentral Technical College starting at 6:30 PM.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be presenting &#8220;Execution Plans: The Secret to Query Tuning Success&#8221;:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">SQL Server will tell you exactly what ingredients it used and steps it took to return the results of your query. By being able to read this &#8220;recipe&#8221;, you can tell where you can improve it! This session will show you how to read execution plans, what common problems can be uncovered, and what the execution plan doesn&#8217;t tell you. You&#8217;ll leave this session able to go to work, open a plan, and identify where to start fine-tuning the query.</p>
<p>If you can join, we&#8217;d love to see you! Please <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wausaupass-august-meeting-tickets-25795334540" target="_blank">RSVP for the event</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="https://www.sqlpass.org/RegisterforSQLPASS.aspx?returnurl=https://wausau.sqlpass.org/Home.aspx" target="_blank">register for Wausau PASS&#8217;s mailing list</a> to be notified of future meetings and events!</p>
<p>Kudos to Jesse for getting this chapter started!</p>
<div id="attachment_4632" style="width: 303px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4632" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS-293x300.png" alt="PASS chapters in Wisconsin" width="293" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS-293x300.png 293w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/07/WI-PASS.png 575w" sizes="(max-width: 293px) 100vw, 293px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">PASS chapters in Wisconsin</p></div>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/help-me-kick-off-wausau-pass/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned on SQL Cruise 2016]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/" />
		<id>/?p=4366</id>
		<updated>2016-02-15T15:11:25Z</updated>
		<published>2016-02-15T15:11:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[1. Tim and Amy Ford put a lot of hard work into making this event run. They do a great job. Everyone learns, shares, has fun, relaxes, and did I mention learns? 2. Jason Hall from SQL Sentry taught his class Tempdb Parasites, and I learned about temp table caching. This is amazing! SQL Sentry [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/"><![CDATA[<p>1. Tim and Amy Ford put a lot of hard work into making this event run. They do a great job. Everyone learns, shares, has fun, relaxes, and did I mention learns?</p>
<p>2. <a href="https://twitter.com/SQLSaurus" target="_blank">Jason Hall</a> from <a href="http://www.sqlsentry.com/" target="_blank">SQL Sentry</a> taught his class Tempdb Parasites, and I learned about temp table caching. This is amazing! SQL Sentry also gave cruisers some amazing, to-be-jealous-of swag. If you were there, you would have gotten it!</p>
<p>3. Zip lining through the canopy on Tortola is amazing.</p>
<div id="attachment_4369" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-4369 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792-300x169.jpg" alt="SQLCruiseTortola" width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792-1024x579.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1792.jpg 1344w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The view from the zip lining platform.</p></div>
<p>4. <a href="https://twitter.com/GFritchey" target="_blank">Grant Fritchey</a> from <a href="http://www.red-gate.com/" target="_blank">Red Gate</a> brought his A game to talk about Query Store, a new feature in SQL Server 2016&#8230;but already available in Azure SQL Database. Red Gate continues to be an awesome sponsor of the cruise, and I&#8217;m thrilled they sent Grant to speak.</p>
<div id="attachment_4368" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4368" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1840-300x168.jpg" alt="Listening to Grant talk. " width="300" height="168" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1840-300x168.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1840-1024x576.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Listening to Grant talk.</p></div>
<p>5. <a href="https://twitter.com/sqllensman" target="_blank">Patrick Flynn</a> is an Ironman!</p>
<p>6. During Office Hours, one cruiser asked, &#8220;How do you do *it* &#8211; keeping up with the community/speaking/blogging, while having a family and a job?&#8221; That turned into one of the most honest discussions I&#8217;ve been part of on that topic. It&#8217;s not easy &#8211; for any of us. It requires balance. Those conversations are what Office Hours is all about.</p>
<p>7. Running a 5K in Charlotte Amalie, St Thomas, is a lot of work. Those hills! Those 99 Stairs! But having two fellow cruisers along makes it a lot more fun. (Thanks Jared and Drew!)</p>
<div id="attachment_4367" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4367" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1750-300x169.jpg" alt="We ran up to that view. RAN. UP! " width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1750-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1750-1024x579.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">We ran up to that view. RAN. UP!</p></div>
<p>8. The rum at John Watling&#8217;s Distillery in Nassau is amazing. Belly up to the bar for a tasting and one of their house cocktails.</p>
<div id="attachment_4370" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4370" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862-300x169.jpg" alt="A class in how rum is distilled, stored, and bottled at John Watling's. " width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862-1024x579.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/IMAG1862.jpg 1344w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">A class in how rum is distilled, stored, and bottled at John Watling&#8217;s.</p></div>
<p>9. <a href="https://twitter.com/kleegeek" target="_blank">David Klee</a> of <a href="http://heraflux.com/" target="_blank">Heraflux Technologies </a>is an amazing resource for anything infrastructure related, and has great resources on his website.</p>
<p>10. Not that we didn&#8217;t know, but <a href="https://twitter.com/DBArgenis" target="_blank">Argenis Fernandez</a> reminded us, &#8220;Security is not easy&#8221;&#8230;as he hacked SQL Server data from packets and read through dlls for dangerous data.</p>
<p>11. The 2017 itineraries are going to be amazing. Keep an eye on <a href="http://sqlcruise.com/" target="_blank">http://sqlcruise.com/</a> for the details!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/#comments" thr:count="3"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/what-i-learned-on-sql-cruise-2016/feed/atom/" thr:count="3"/>
		<thr:total>3</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about SQL Server in Azure in Madison, WI]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/learn-about-sql-server-in-azure-in-madison-wi/" />
		<id>/?p=4326</id>
		<updated>2016-01-27T16:12:33Z</updated>
		<published>2016-01-27T16:05:21Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Azure" /><category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You: curious about Azure, wondering if it&#8217;s right for your organization. You run some SQL Server databases, but don&#8217;t know if you would use a VM in Azure, or should jump into an Azure SQL Database. You know there are some differences and complexities, but aren&#8217;t sure how to work with them. Me: ready to [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/learn-about-sql-server-in-azure-in-madison-wi/"><![CDATA[<p>You: curious about Azure, wondering if it&#8217;s right for your organization. You run some SQL Server databases, but don&#8217;t know if you would use a VM in Azure, or should jump into an Azure SQL Database. You know there are some differences and complexities, but aren&#8217;t sure how to work with them.</p>
<p>Me: ready to spend a day teaching you how to get started!</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be presenting my full-day class <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/sql-sat-madison-pre-con-get-started-with-sql-server-in-azure-wjes-borland-tickets-20990868252" target="_blank">Get Started With SQL Server in Azure </a>at Globe University in Madison, WI on Friday, April 8, 2016. (Conveniently, the day before the fifth annual SQLSaturday in Madison.) You can get a full day of learning for only $125! Here are the details about the class:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Microsoft Azure is a mature, stable ecosystem, but some people and companies are still hesitant to adopt it. In this full day class, I&#8217;ll teach you why building SQL Server environments in Azure is safe, easy, and reliable and how to do it.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">We&#8217;ll begin with an overview of the Azure ecosystem. SQL Server is one of a large number of services being offered, and many work together. I&#8217;ll walk through the main management tool, the Azure Portal, to show you how to use it. I&#8217;ll cover the security and compliance of features of Azure, which are numerous. You&#8217;ll understand the differences between Azure Infrastructure as a Service (Iaas) and Platform as a Service (PaaS) offerings.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">You&#8217;ll see how to build IaaS SQL Server VMs. I&#8217;ll talk through licensing, networking, security, and what you&#8217;ll pay for. We&#8217;ll talk about how to move your current data into the VM, how to connect to the databases for management or from the application, and uses for VMs such as DR. The HA/DR options for IaaS will be explained.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">You&#8217;ll also see how to build PaaS Azure SQL Databases, with the same information networking, security, and what you&#8217;ll pay for. I&#8217;ll show you how to move your current data to the database, and how it differs from the IaaS product. You&#8217;ll learn how to connect to and manage the databases. We&#8217;ll also cover how HA/DR is handled with PaaS databases.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I&#8217;ll cover intricacies learned from hands-on experience, such as security and networking settings to be aware of, and how to use Azure&#8217;s ability to scale up and down as necessary. You&#8217;ll come away from this class fully prepared to build your first IaaS or PaaS deployment.</p>
<h3>Call To Action</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/sql-sat-madison-pre-con-get-started-with-sql-server-in-azure-wjes-borland-tickets-20990868252" target="_blank">Register today</a> for this one-day training opportunity. Don&#8217;t forget to register for <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/499/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQLSaturday Madison</a> &#8211; a free, one-day event where you can choose from over 30 SQL Server sessions &#8211; as well!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/learn-about-sql-server-in-azure-in-madison-wi/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/learn-about-sql-server-in-azure-in-madison-wi/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Questions with Derik Hammer]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/5-questions-with-derik-hammer/" />
		<id>/?p=4278</id>
		<updated>2015-12-09T22:25:00Z</updated>
		<published>2015-12-09T22:25:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was October 2013, and I was in Charlotte, NC. I&#8217;d attended Red Gate&#8217;s SQL in the City event during the day, and was heading over to register for PASS Summit. I started chatting with one of the SQL in the City attendees. He was a DBA familiar with Red Gate&#8217;s tools and events, but [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/5-questions-with-derik-hammer/"><![CDATA[<p>It was October 2013, and I was in Charlotte, NC. I&#8217;d attended Red Gate&#8217;s SQL in the City event during the day, and was heading over to register for PASS Summit. I started chatting with one of the SQL in the City attendees. He was a DBA familiar with Red Gate&#8217;s tools and events, but he&#8217;d never heard of PASS or PASS Summit. You bet I started talking about how amazing the organization, the conference, and most importantly the community is. I gave him my card and said I hoped to hear from him soon.</p>
<p>This is how I met Derik Hammer (<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sqlhammer" target="_blank">linkedin </a>| <a href="http://www.sqlhammer.com/blog/" target="_blank">blog</a>| <a href="https://twitter.com/SQLHammer" target="_blank">twitter</a>) , and gosh, am I glad I did! A week after Summit, I emailed Derik with some information such as his local chapter and some of my favorite community resources. I followed his Twitter account. He did the rest on his own &#8211; continued to blog, started a PASS chapter, and started speaking. He has been getting after his own career! What he has done in the past two years should motivate all of us!</p>
<p>I got a chance to ask him a few questions via email recently!</p>
<h3>You blog about a lot of great things. What&#8217;s your current favorite SQL Server feature?</h3>
<p>I have to say that I have two favorite SQL Server features. The one that I enjoy playing with the most is Availability Groups. Anyone who reads my blog likely noticed a heavier focus on AGs and they are also the topic that I speak on. High Availability and Disaster Recovery are areas that I cannot get enough of. When someone fails to deliver a feature on time, the company is usually not in any real danger. When mission critical systems drop offline for hours, careers end. An AG can keep an entire company alive. When I see an automatic failover and all the applications gracefully retry, I can&#8217;t help but drown in pride.</p>
<p>[<em>Aside from Jes: Derik&#8217;s blogs on AGs have answered more than one of my questions in the last year. Thank you</em>!]</p>
<p>My other favorite is the optimizer. The optimizer is the work of geniuses and I continue to be in awe of its sophistication.</p>
<h3>On the other hand, what feature do you use regularly that you think needs the most improvement?</h3>
<p>Replication (transactional/merge/peer-to-peer) has always driven me crazy. Replication is a great feature but the library of stored procedures is a challenge to use. In addition, the replication monitor leaves a lot of room for improvement. I feel that the underlying feature could remain mostly the same if its usability were to improve.</p>
<h3>Within two years, you went from not knowing about PASS Summit to being very involved in the community &#8211; you&#8217;re a chapter leader and a speaker. What is it the draws you to the SQL Server community?</h3>
<p>In 2013, I was close to exhausting what I could learn from the DBAs in my immediate vicinity and I was looking for something more. That is when I drove down to Charlotte, NC and attended the Red-Gate SQL in the City, where we met. On day one I was overwhelmed by the community. I walked up to Grant Fritchey and had a lengthy conversation about replication where he was genuinely interested in my challenges and experiences. Next thing I knew I was walking with you down the block. Your passion and energy is always intoxicating. When we parted I was jazzed up to seek out the Buffalo Wild Wings networking event that Steve Jones was planning. Upon arrival, I was once again shocked as Steve introduced me a number of people and took time to talk to them about me as if we were friends, even though we had just met.</p>
<p>From that point, there was no turning back. I&#8217;m like Megatron thirsting for more Energon. Above all things, I love going to a SQLSaturday or PASS Summit and being welcomed by friends. Many people call the PASS Summits, family reunions. I can definitely see the similarities. The PASS mission statement spells out the goal well. Connect. Share. Learn. By simply participating, you join a positive feedback loop that empowers you.</p>
<p>The #sqlfamily is like no other technical community. I cannot even imagine what my life would be like if I hadn&#8217;t found it.</p>
<h3>Tell me about your Epic Life Quest. What sparked that, what have you accomplished, and what&#8217;s next on the list?</h3>
<p>I joined the U.S. Navy right out of high school. Once enlisted, I realized that the Navy, as an organization, was deeply flawed. I was contracted to live with that for a minimum of 6 years which motivated me to try and improve my situation. Making positive change in the Navy, however, is not easy. I quickly learned how to pursue meaningful long-term goals rather than spin my wheels on minor short-term struggles.</p>
<p>After separating from the Navy, I became a DBA and found myself without a solid understanding of where I wanted to go with my career. In the first couple of years I just hoped around learning different areas of the SQL Server suite. Then I began pin pointing celebrity role models to learn from. Brent Ozar was one of those role models. What makes Brent a particularly good example is that he is extremely open about how he go to where he is. In addition, his published content is not strictly technical, it includes invaluable information on how to be successful in general.</p>
<p>I stumbled upon Brent&#8217;s Epic Life Quest and found the method of goal achievement appealing. What I liked the most is that I could define a large number of small goals which all build to a larger target and then work on them out of order. Most goal setting methodologies that I&#8217;ve learned require a strict road map. With My Epic Life Quest, I can treat my life more like building rather than traveling. I can assemble pieces out of order, as long as they contribute to the whole. It also makes for a pretty great day when I glance at my web page and realize that I just leveled up again.</p>
<p>My Epic Life Quest goals / achievements typically fall into one of three categories; family, community, and career. In 2016 I hope to finish my SQL Server MCSA, hit 250,000 unique views on sqlhammer.com, and be selected to speak at #summit16.</p>
<h3>What advice would you give to 2005 Derik about his career?</h3>
<p>Let me geek-out on you for a second and attempt to define the time travel scenario. If I were to travel back in time and retain everything I know today, I would never head off to Navy boot camp. I figure that, I&#8217;ve already learned what I needed from that era of my life and would not need to re-experience it. Instead, I would dive into the SQL community and move forward like I am now, only 10 years younger and with far less responsibilities and ties.</p>
<p>2005 Derik was just about to join the Navy and leave his home for the first significant period of time ever. If I was speaking to myself as a stranger, I would encourage 2005 Derik to join the Navy. I would explain that the sword never thanks the anvil for its forging but is better for it anyways. Above all else, I would advise him to work on breaking out of his shell and participate. I find it the most amazingly simple concept to simply be involved, in everything. When you engage with others you find yourself. </p>
<hr>
<p>Have questions about how to get involved in the community? Reach out to Derik &#8211; he&#8217;s a great example of someone who has done just that!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/5-questions-with-derik-hammer/#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/5-questions-with-derik-hammer/feed/atom/" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare to Set Sail on SQL Cruise Caribbean 2016]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/prepare-to-set-sail-on-sql-cruise-caribbean-2016/" />
		<id>/?p=4266</id>
		<updated>2015-11-23T16:36:13Z</updated>
		<published>2015-11-23T14:14:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Microsoft SQL Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Professional Development" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here in the Frozen Tundra of Wisconsin, winter is setting in &#8211; this weekend, temperatures didn&#8217;t rise above freezing, and snow fell in some parts of the state. I have my cold-weather running gear out &#8211; fleece-lined tights, wind-proof jacket, hats, mittens, and trail shoes &#8211; and my snowshoes are hanging in the garage. For [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/prepare-to-set-sail-on-sql-cruise-caribbean-2016/"><![CDATA[<p>Here in the Frozen Tundra of Wisconsin, winter is setting in &#8211; this weekend, temperatures didn&#8217;t rise above freezing, and snow fell in some parts of the state. I have my cold-weather running gear out &#8211; fleece-lined tights, wind-proof jacket, hats, mittens, and trail shoes &#8211; and my snowshoes are hanging in the garage. For now, I&#8217;m looking forward to winter.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m also still digesting all the great things I learned at <a href="http://sqlpass.org/summit/2015" target="_blank">PASS Summit </a>and MVP Summit a month ago. I attended great sessions on Azure topics, professional development, and learned what&#8217;s coming in SQL Server 2016. I&#8217;m recharged from spending time with old friends and meeting new ones.</p>
<p>But I know myself, and I know that come mid-January, the cold weather and windy days will have me cursing winter. I know that I&#8217;ll be missing my SQL community, wishing for the first <a href="http://sqlsaturday.com/" target="_blank">SQL Saturday</a> of the year to arrive so I can spend time with friends that also happen to be geeks.</p>
<p>The good news is that I have a cure for all that will ail me mid-January: <a href="http://sqlcruise.com/" target="_blank">SQL Cruise</a>. The Norwegian Escape sets sail on Saturday, January 30, 2016 and returns on Saturday, February 6. Seven fun-filled days of sailing, snorkeling, shuffleboard, and SQL Server training will happen between.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right&#8230;adventure on the high seas! Pirates! Rum! SQL Server!</p>
<div id="attachment_3238" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IMAG0532_1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3238" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IMAG0532_1-300x169.jpg" alt="On the beach in Nassau after the best on-shore day ever " width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IMAG0532_1-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IMAG0532_1-1024x579.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">SQL Cruise 2015 &#8211; On the beach in Nassau after the best on-shore day ever</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;ve <a href="/index.php/uncategorized/sql-cruise-caribbean-2015-more-than-a-cruise-with-classes-much-more/" target="_blank">written about SQL Cruise before</a>, and how it&#8217;s changed my career. It&#8217;s given me new friendships and strengthened old ones. Because of this, I highly, highly recommend anyone looking for a learning event with top-notch instructors and a very low teacher-to-student ratio consider SQL Cruise. The Technical Leads this year are an incredible group: Tim Ford, Grant Fritchey, David Klee, and Jason Hall.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m beyond delighted that Tim Ford, our fearless captain, has asked me to be a Technical Lead, too! I&#8217;ll be delivering two new sessions this year:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px"><strong>Everyday Extended Events</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">As a DBA or developer, you want to know what is happening inside SQL Server. Extended Events are the modern framework for finding and interpreting SQL Server&#8217;s actions. In this session, you&#8217;ll see practical examples to solve everyday problems, such as capturing queries and their resources, measuring wait statistics, tracking I/O for database files, and capturing index activity. Many useful features will be shown, such as the depth of events, filtering, and multiple target types!</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px"><strong>Beyond CXPACKET: Understanding Wait Statistics</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">&#8216;Time and tide wait for no man&#8217;, but SQL Server must wait for resources when executing a query. The lifecycle of a query is full of waiting, and SQL Server records when it&#8217;s waiting, why, and for how long. By learning how each query is executed, and observing how waits can accumulate along the way, you can unlock the secrets to what resources or code changes are needed to improve your query and server performance.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever considered attending SQL Cruise, today is the day to <a href="http://sqlcruise.com/registerme/" target="_blank">register</a>! No one has ever regretted setting sail on SQL Cruise.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/prepare-to-set-sail-on-sql-cruise-caribbean-2016/#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/prepare-to-set-sail-on-sql-cruise-caribbean-2016/feed/atom/" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
		</entry>
	</feed>
