<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Interview With Rod Colledge About The Book SQL Server 2008 Administration in Action</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 12:40:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Naomi Nosonovsky</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1966</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Naomi Nosonovsky]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 15:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hopefully it would not require another writing contest.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hopefully it would not require another writing contest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: SQLDenis</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1965</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 14:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1965</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Winner has been notified.....come back next week...I might give away a boxed copy of Windows 7 (have to first see if it arrives in the mail)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Winner has been notified&#8230;..come back next week&#8230;I might give away a boxed copy of Windows 7 (have to first see if it arrives in the mail)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: BinaryHacker</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1964</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BinaryHacker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 12:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1964</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Loved the interview and definitely would love to get hands on this book. I read the reviews and list of chapters and guess it covers pretty much everything.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My Fav question: &quot;Will DBAs finally realize high availability with mirroring is not a disasterrecovery solution after reading SQL Server 2008 Administration in Action?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is kind of funny though its a common mistake and understanding this aspect is really important for any DBA. Not only this adding this question also gives a hint about, the depth to which author has tried to cover and explain the things that DBAs are really missing.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Loved the interview and definitely would love to get hands on this book. I read the reviews and list of chapters and guess it covers pretty much everything.</p>
<p>My Fav question: &#8220;Will DBAs finally realize high availability with mirroring is not a disasterrecovery solution after reading SQL Server 2008 Administration in Action?&#8221;</p>
<p>This is kind of funny though its a common mistake and understanding this aspect is really important for any DBA. Not only this adding this question also gives a hint about, the depth to which author has tried to cover and explain the things that DBAs are really missing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: sqlsister</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1963</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sqlsister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 12:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1963</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I enjoyed the whole interview but the question that hit home for me was:&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;What are the most important things a person can do to become an exceptional DBA?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Planning for disaster is so important. In my very first job with SQL Server, I learned about backups and had a good plan for making them (Yay me, at least I had a bcakup when I needed one!), but never practiced restores. Consequently the first time I needed to restore something, I had a panic attack. I knew where to find the code to do the restore (thank you, Books Online!), but had never actually done one and that was an additional pressure I didn&#039;t need with a bunch of senior managers breathing down my neck to get things up and running. Well we learn by doing and I won&#039;t make that particular mistake again. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I also loved the comment about there is only so much we can learn in our current job. That is so very true and without learning more, how can we progress to do more interesting things or at least stay current as we move to new versions of the software?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed the whole interview but the question that hit home for me was:<br />
&#8220;What are the most important things a person can do to become an exceptional DBA?&#8221;</p>
<p>Planning for disaster is so important. In my very first job with SQL Server, I learned about backups and had a good plan for making them (Yay me, at least I had a bcakup when I needed one!), but never practiced restores. Consequently the first time I needed to restore something, I had a panic attack. I knew where to find the code to do the restore (thank you, Books Online!), but had never actually done one and that was an additional pressure I didn&#8217;t need with a bunch of senior managers breathing down my neck to get things up and running. Well we learn by doing and I won&#8217;t make that particular mistake again. </p>
<p>I also loved the comment about there is only so much we can learn in our current job. That is so very true and without learning more, how can we progress to do more interesting things or at least stay current as we move to new versions of the software?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Jungchanhsieh</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1962</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jungchanhsieh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 23:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1962</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I like all the interview questions and answers; Specially, &#039;What new features in Sql Server 2008 are you most excited about as a DBA?&#039; since SQL 2008 provides over top ten features.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &#039;SQL Server 2008 Administration in Action&#039; would help me to accomplish SQL DBA&#039;s responsibilities.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like all the interview questions and answers; Specially, &#8216;What new features in Sql Server 2008 are you most excited about as a DBA?&#8217; since SQL 2008 provides over top ten features.</p>
<p>The &#8216;SQL Server 2008 Administration in Action&#8217; would help me to accomplish SQL DBA&#8217;s responsibilities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ted Krueger (onpnt)</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1961</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 22:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1961</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I read the interview as soon as it was posted and took a great deal out of it.  I keyed in on DR / mirroring along with the resource governor remarks at first.  I did want to say amen to, &quot;disaster recovery planning begins and ends with a single feature such as database mirroring&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This shows nothing more than great depth in a DBA and gives me the ambition to go out and read anything they put out for the SQL Server community to read.  Amazes me still to this day when backup/restore is a DBAs pride and joy DR plans.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The resource governor was an addition I was most excited about in ’08 and looked forward to the answer to that question.  I was almost jumping off my chair waiting for the chance to play with it.  I think now that I have and it’s at my disposal, I’m relieved to hear the same comments and wants in IO, network and such.  The resource governor truly is a great upgrade to the list of tools we have to keep our database servers doing nothing short of serving the data at high rates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think hands down you have to say, &quot;…becoming an exceptional DBA&quot; is the best question and best remarks to take away.  Anytime you get the opportunity to have someone at Rod Colledge’s level talk about how you can achieve this, you should listen up!  I can’t say enough how much I agree to the SLA comments.  The hiding in the corner DBA is no more.  You need to learn the business and know how it turns in order to support the data the best way.  Again, glad to hear the remarks on DR being critical to be an exceptional DBA.  I still to this day feel I had nothing until the entire world stopped turning and my database servers went down.  Yes, I’ve been there but yes, I was prepared.  Thank god!  If I would hope to any person that reads Rod’s interview here, it would be that you HAVE to have a sound DR strategy and tested one to be an exceptional DBA.  As hard as it is to say you’re not experienced, I still think the ultimate experience is to put that strategy to test in a real life disaster.  I wish the heart pounding experience on no one, but it does make us exceptional to bring it all online.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Good stuff and thanks for putting the book together Rod&lt;br /&gt;]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I read the interview as soon as it was posted and took a great deal out of it.  I keyed in on DR / mirroring along with the resource governor remarks at first.  I did want to say amen to, &#8220;disaster recovery planning begins and ends with a single feature such as database mirroring&#8221;.</p>
<p>This shows nothing more than great depth in a DBA and gives me the ambition to go out and read anything they put out for the SQL Server community to read.  Amazes me still to this day when backup/restore is a DBAs pride and joy DR plans.  </p>
<p>The resource governor was an addition I was most excited about in ’08 and looked forward to the answer to that question.  I was almost jumping off my chair waiting for the chance to play with it.  I think now that I have and it’s at my disposal, I’m relieved to hear the same comments and wants in IO, network and such.  The resource governor truly is a great upgrade to the list of tools we have to keep our database servers doing nothing short of serving the data at high rates.</p>
<p>I think hands down you have to say, &#8220;…becoming an exceptional DBA&#8221; is the best question and best remarks to take away.  Anytime you get the opportunity to have someone at Rod Colledge’s level talk about how you can achieve this, you should listen up!  I can’t say enough how much I agree to the SLA comments.  The hiding in the corner DBA is no more.  You need to learn the business and know how it turns in order to support the data the best way.  Again, glad to hear the remarks on DR being critical to be an exceptional DBA.  I still to this day feel I had nothing until the entire world stopped turning and my database servers went down.  Yes, I’ve been there but yes, I was prepared.  Thank god!  If I would hope to any person that reads Rod’s interview here, it would be that you HAVE to have a sound DR strategy and tested one to be an exceptional DBA.  As hard as it is to say you’re not experienced, I still think the ultimate experience is to put that strategy to test in a real life disaster.  I wish the heart pounding experience on no one, but it does make us exceptional to bring it all online.  </p>
<p>Good stuff and thanks for putting the book together Rod</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Naomi Nosonovsky</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1960</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Naomi Nosonovsky]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 22:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/interview-with-rod-colledge-about-the-bo/#comment-1960</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I read the interview in its entirety when it was first published and re-read again right now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I liked all the questions and answers, and in particular this question &quot;What are the most important things a person can do to become an exceptional DBA?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#039;m sure I would benefit from your book and become a good DBA once I read it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All the best.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I read the interview in its entirety when it was first published and re-read again right now.</p>
<p>I liked all the questions and answers, and in particular this question &#8220;What are the most important things a person can do to become an exceptional DBA?&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure I would benefit from your book and become a good DBA once I read it.</p>
<p>All the best.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
