<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>64 bit &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/64-bit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Force installation of 64-bit ACE OLE DB provider</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/force-ace-installation/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/force-ace-installation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 06:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[64 bit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ace ole db]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[run64bitruntime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/04/force-ace-installation/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This blog post describes how you can install the 64-bit ACE OLE DB provider when you have 32-bit Office components installed.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Anyone working with SSIS and Excel probably had the following issue: you are creating an SSIS package using an Excel file in BIDS/SSDT – which is a 32-bit application – and when you try to run the package, it crashes. This is easily fixed by setting the project property <em>Run64BitRuntime</em> to False. The package now runs in 32-bit mode and uses the 32-bit ACE OLE DB provider which was installed alongside Office (if you installed the 32-bit version at least).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you want to run the package in a SQL Server job, you’d need to set the job step to use the 32-bit version by selecting the checkbox <em>Use 32-bit runtime</em> in the Execution options in SQL Server 2008 or later, or by using the 32-bit version of DTEXEC in the command line arguments in SQL Server 2005. (For an overview, check out this excellent blog post by Todd McDermid (<a href="http://toddmcdermid.blogspot.be/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/Todd_McDermid">twitter</a>): <a href="http://toddmcdermid.blogspot.be/2009/10/quick-reference-ssis-in-32-and-64-bits.html">Quick Reference: SSIS in 32- and 64-bits</a>)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">But what if you want to run the package in 64-bit mode? Easy, you install the 64-bit ACE OLE DB provider which you can download <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=13255">here</a>. Note that there isn’t a 64-bit version available for the 2007 redistributable and that at the time of writing the 2013 version hasn’t been released at all. With the 64-bit provider installed, you can run your packages on a 64-bit server.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you don’t install the provider, you get the following error when you try to run such a package on a 64-bit SQL Server:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>The requested OLE DB provider Microsoft.ACE.OLEDB.12.0 is not registered. If the 64-bit driver is not installed, run the package in 32-bit mode. … Description: “Class not registered”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em> </em></p>
<div class="image_block"><em><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/ExecutionResult_2.png?mtime=1366689582"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/ExecutionResult_2.png?mtime=1366689582" alt="" width="857" height="137" /></a></em></div>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">However, if Office is installed in the 32-bit version, the installation of the 64-bit ACE OLE DB provider fails with the following message:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>You cannot install the 64-bit version of Microsoft Access Database Engine 2010 because you currently have 32-bit Office products installed.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em> </em></p>
<div class="image_block"><em><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/Error_64.png?mtime=1366689573"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/Error_64.png?mtime=1366689573" alt="" width="362" height="190" /></a></em></div>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">It basically tells us to uninstall Office before you can proceed with the installation. The funny part is that when I try to install the 32-bit version of the ACE OLE DB provider, I’m greeted with the same message:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> </p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/Error_32.png?mtime=1366689566"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/Error_32.png?mtime=1366689566" alt="" width="362" height="190" /></a></div>
<p>Apparently a teensy-weensy part of Office was installed in 64-bit, so I can’t install the 32-bit provider either. Normally you wouldn’t have these problems on a production server, as no Office components are installed. But what if you want to test your SQL Server Agent job on your development machine? Or what if you are reading the Excel file using an OPENROWSET command in SSMS? You need that 64-bit provider badly!</p>
<p>Luckily I came across a solution offered by Lowell in this <a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/Forums/Topic1407044-391-1.aspx">thread</a>: apparently it works when you install the provider through the command line. All you need to do is add the <strong>/passive</strong> switch and the installation runs without an issue.</p>
<p>Let’s test if this solves our issue. I created a simple SSIS package reading from an Excel file. Nothing too fancy.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/BIDS_Setup.png?mtime=1366689558"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/BIDS_Setup.png?mtime=1366689558" alt="" width="547" height="304" /></a></p>
<p>When I deploy it to the SSIS catalog and execute it in 64-bit, I see the package has ran successfully:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/ExecutionResult_3.png?mtime=1366689588"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ForceACE/ExecutionResult_3.png?mtime=1366689588" alt="" width="307" height="162" /></a></p>
<p>What’s interesting is that on my new laptop, which has Office 2013 64-bit installed, I could install the 32-bit provider without an issue. So maybe the Office team fixed the issue in their latest release.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>This blog post shows a very simple solution on how to solve a very common problem with SSIS and Excel. I’d like to thank Lowell for pointing me out to this solution in the thread I mentioned earlier.</p>
<p><em>Update: Installing both the providers on the same machine with Office components installed doesn&#8217;t mean your life is issue-free from now on. Apparently this set-up can cause issues in other places. Check out the comments for more details.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/force-ace-installation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enabling 64-bit VM support on a HP Probook</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/hardware/enabling-64-bit-vm-support/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/hardware/enabling-64-bit-vm-support/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Axel Achten (axel8s)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[64 bit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data execution prevention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[probook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trusted execution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtualization technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware player]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/04/enabling-64-bit-vm-support/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When you have a 64-bit machine with a 64-bit OS, you just want you're Virtual Machines to run in 64-bit mode. I use VMWare Player to run my VM's but when I started the install of a 64-bit OS on the out-of-the-box configuration of my HP Probook I got thi&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you have a 64-bit machine with a 64-bit OS, you just want you&#8217;re Virtual Machines to run in 64-bit mode. I use VMWare Player to run my VM&#8217;s but when I started the install of a 64-bit OS on the out-of-the-box configuration of my HP Probook I got this error message:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios1.png?mtime=1333624722"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios1.png?mtime=1333624722" width="432" height="201" /></a></div>
<p>The error message itself is clear, but where do you find the settings on you&#8217;re machine? Googling/binging will return lots of hits with posts from people asking the same question. So I increased my geek factor by taking some pictures of my BIOS settings to make this post. To get started boot up you&#8217;re machine and start hitting the ESC key untill you reach this menu:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios2.png?mtime=1333624733"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios2.png?mtime=1333624733" width="206" height="301" /></a></div>
<p>Now hit you&#8217;re F10 key so you get in the BIOS Setup screen en click on the System Configuration tab:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios3.png?mtime=1333624755"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios3.png?mtime=1333624755" width="500" height="201" /></a></div>
<p>Next click on the Device Configuration link:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios4.png?mtime=1333624767"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios4.png?mtime=1333624767" width="305" height="282" /></a></div>
<p>Finally we arrive in the menu we need, first check the Virtualization Technology check box so you&#8217;re hardware supports 64-bit virtualization:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios5.png?mtime=1333624778"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios5.png?mtime=1333624778" width="501" height="201" /></a></div>
<p>But don&#8217;t stop here, there is one more option to change, Data Execution needs to be enabled. Normally you would like to prevent execution of code from a non-executable memory region but not deselecting the Data Execution Prevention checkbox will result in the same error. So scroll up to the DEP checkbox and uncheck it:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios6.png?mtime=1333624823"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/64Bios6.png?mtime=1333624823" width="500" height="272" /></a></div>
<p>Now you can exit the BIOS, make sure you save the changes and start having fun installing a 64-bit Virtual Machine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/hardware/enabling-64-bit-vm-support/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>If you are suffering from Cisco VPN on 64 bit Windows then use the Shrew Soft VPN client</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/if-you-are-suffering-from-cisco-vpn-on-6/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/if-you-are-suffering-from-cisco-vpn-on-6/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Software and Configuration Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[64 bit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vpn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/02/if-you-are-suffering-from-cisco-vpn-on-6/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By now you probably have heard or seen the complains that there is no viable 64 bit VPN client that will work with a Cisco VPN. I myself either used a Virtual Machine (Virtual Box) or I have a dual boot system where I boot into the Fisher Price looking OS to VPN into work. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By now you probably have heard or seen the complains that there is no viable 64 bit VPN client that will work with a Cisco VPN. I myself either used a Virtual Machine (Virtual Box) or I have a dual boot system where I boot into the Fisher Price looking OS to VPN into work.</p>
<p>Yesterday my suffering ended. I downloaded the Shrew Soft VPN Client For Windows and it has been working great. It will even import Cisco pcf files so that you don&#8217;t need to configure the VPN client if you already have the Cisco pcf files.</p>
<p>Download the Shrew Soft VPN client here: http://www.shrew.net/download/vpn<br />
After it is installed start it up, click on <em>file</em> and then <em>import</em>. You should be presented with a dialog like the one in the screenshot below. Change the dropdown to Cisco PCF file and navigate to the location where your files are. Repeat the process for each PCF file you have.</p>
<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//Import.png" alt="" title="" width="630" height="434" /></div>
<p>After you have imported everything you need, click on one of the connections with a blue padlock icon and after that click on connect</p>
<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//connect.png" alt="" title="" width="415" height="320" /></div>
<div>
<p>Fill in you username and password, click connect and you should see the following screen</p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//Connected.png" alt="" title="" width="307" height="308" /></div>
<p>If everything is successful you should see something like the following in the  text area above the credentials</p>
<p><em>config loaded for site &#8216;connectDC.pcf&#8217;<br />
configuring client settings&#8230;<br />
attached to key daemon &#8230;<br />
peer configured<br />
iskamp proposal configured<br />
esp proposal configured<br />
client configured<br />
local id configured<br />
pre-shared key configured<br />
bringing up tunnel &#8230;<br />
network device configured<br />
tunnel enabled</em></p>
<p>If something is wrong you will see a message indicating a status in the same text area.</p>
<p>Documentation is also available here: http://www.shrew.net/static/help-2.1.x/vpnhelp.htm</p>
<p>The  Shrew Soft VPN client is free but if it solves a problem for you consider donating something.</p>
<p>That is it for this post, hopefully I will save a person or two from this 64 bit VPN hell.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/if-you-are-suffering-from-cisco-vpn-on-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>My top ten favorite technologies of this decade.</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/my-top-ten-favorite-technologies-of-this/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/my-top-ten-favorite-technologies-of-this/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 16:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[64 bit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hdtv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lookback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zune hd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/12/my-top-ten-favorite-technologies-of-this/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since we are wrapping up this decade I decided to look back and mention the things that happened in technology that I found interesting. Below is my list of ten technologies. Wireless/Broadband Most of us were probably on dial up at the start of this decade (I was) but these days it is hard to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since we are wrapping up this decade I decided to look back and mention the things that happened in technology that I found interesting. Below is my list of ten technologies.</p>
<p><strong>Wireless/Broadband</strong><br />
Most of us were probably on dial up at the start of this decade (I was) but these days it is hard to find a person that still uses dial up; I only know one person that still uses dial up. We also have to thank Intel Centrino to make the wireless experience on laptops so easy when it just came out; there was no need any more to add wireless cards to the laptop…it was all built in. Of course now that wireless is everywhere and everyone is using it some carriers are having trouble with their networks.</p>
<p><strong>Personal Media Player</strong><br />
The personal media player has come a long way. In the 80s I got the <a href="http://www.walkmancentral.com/products/wm-1">WM-1</a> by Sony in 1982 as a present. This thing took 4 AA batteries, it didn’t even have autoreverse. You want to ruin your tape? Shake the player while you are  listening..fun times…oh and who remembers those metal and chromium dioxide tapes? </p>
<p>In the 90s I bought the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rio_PMP300">Rio PMP300</a>. This was the first available mp3 player in the US after Creative won the lawsuit against the RIAA who claimed claiming the player violated the 1992 Audio Home Recording Act. This player had a whopping 32MB (yes that is megabyte) of internal memory and also had a smartmedia slot. I remember encoding songs at 64 kb/s so that I could fit more than 10 songs on the device. Over the years I had a plethora of devices and my current device is a Zune HD. </p>
<p>The devices that you can buy these days are so much better than that first MP3 player, you can&#8217;t compare this at all. These devices do a lot more than just play songs, they will play video, they have apps a wireless connection and some of them can even output to a HDTV screen. Of course everyone knows that Apple owns this market now with the iPod and the iPod Touch.</p>
<p><strong>Smart phones</strong><br />
These days a smart phone is more powerful than the computer you had at the beginning of this decade; it definitely has way more memory than your desktop just 5 years ago. Thanks to Moore’s Law this will continue until these devices will replace our desktops and laptops.</p>
<p><strong>64 Bit</strong><br />
This is a biggie for me since I am a database guy and we all know that reading data from disk is 1000 times more expensive than reading data from RAM. The nice thing with 64 Bit is that your computer can see more than 4GB of RAM. If you do a lot of video encoding or if you need to run several virtual machines at the same time then 8GB is a minimum these days.</p>
<p><strong>Multi core chips</strong><br />
The beginning of the decade was all about speed; it started with about 1.4 GHz. By February 2, 2004 the Pentium 4 was running at 3.4 GHz. Then we started to get Hyper-Threading which would look like you had 2 CPUs and then finally we got Multi Core Sockets. But the speed on these Multi Core chips did not get faster, as a matter of fact most of them were in the 2 GHz range; just now we are seeing the Extreme Edition chips run faster than 3 GHz. I expect to have 100+ multi core chips by the end of the next decade, programming against those is another story, I am sure someone will figure this parallel thing out by then.</p>
<p><strong>Ebook readers</strong><br />
If you go on a trip and you look to read you don’t have to bring 6 books with you anymore and because you are not sure which book you want to read on the beach; with an ebook reader you can bring them all. But there is a predator lurking…..this is of course the Apple Tablet (iSlate or perhaps iTablet??). There is a rumor that when this Apple Tablet gets announced in January at an Apple event that Ebay will have a lot of Kindles listed the next day.</p>
<p><strong>Web 2.0/The social web</strong><br />
I wouldn’t really call this Web 2.0 anymore; this is the web period.  You can’t ignore any of these sites anymore; most likely you are using at least 5 of these. Here are some I use on a regular basis</p>
<p>Twitter<br />
Flikr<br />
Del.icio.us<br />
Reddit<br />
Youtube</p>
<p>I think that most young people only go to sites like that. How would you go to a relative in the 1990s? You would call up ask for directions, write them down and hope for the best. These days you can use GPS or a mapping site like Google Maps, type your destination, get directions (including reverse directions) and print them out and you are done. You like to track your finances? No problem there is <a href="http://www.mint.com/">mint</a>. For everything that you can think of there will be a website that caters to your needs. When was the last time you bought an actual encyclopedia? Why would you, there is Wikipedia</p>
<p><strong>Solid State Drives </strong><br />
Solid State Drives are the future and by the end of next decade I don’t think that there will be a lot of computers sold with regular hard drives at all. Adding a Solid State Drive to your computer is like adding more RAM, the seek time on these drives is just amazing. Just take a look at this video<br />
<object width="560" height="340"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/96dWOEa4Djs&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;rel=0" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/96dWOEa4Djs&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="560" height="340"></embed></object></p>
<p><strong>Touch devices</strong><br />
Touch especially on handheld devices is now common; just take a look at the iPhone, the Droid, the Zune HD, the Palm Pre or the Blackberry Bold. You can also buy a Windows 7 touch screen PC</p>
<p><strong>HDTV</strong><br />
Compare a HDTV to a regular TV and you can count the lines in the regular one, there is no comparison. I wonder were this will stop, we went from 720p to 1080p, what is next will we go to 2000 lines in the next decade?</p>
<p>So this is my list, if you can think of something major that I forgot leave me a comment. Also what do you think will be big in the next decade? Will it be nanotech or biotech, perhaps robotics or maybe even the start of the synthesis between man and machine (yes I can’t wait for that cyborg to knock on my door)?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/my-top-ten-favorite-technologies-of-this/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Windows Server 2008 R2 is the first Windows OS platform to go 64-bit only</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows-server-2008-r2-is-the-first-wind/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows-server-2008-r2-is-the-first-wind/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 14:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Operating Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[64 bit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows server 2008]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/10/windows-server-2008-r2-is-the-first-wind/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Windows Server 2008 R2 is the first Windows OS platform to go 64-bit only That is right First and foremost, 32-bit is done. History. Archives. Windows Server 2008 R2 is the first Windows OS platform to go 64-bit only, and frankly it was high time. Customers have been unable to purchase a 32-bit server CPU [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong> Windows Server 2008 R2 is the first Windows OS platform to go 64-bit only</strong></p>
<p>That is right</p>
<blockquote><p>First and foremost, 32-bit is done. History. Archives. Windows Server 2008 R2 is the first Windows OS platform to go 64-bit only, and frankly it was high time. Customers have been unable to purchase a 32-bit server CPU for over two years now, and the advancements in CPU architectures really dictated that we squeeze as much performance out of customers’ hardware purchases as possible. The move to 64-bit is a first step</p></blockquote>
<p>Mmm, that means that I will have no choice but to deploy the 64 bit version of SQL server 2008 later on (I was planning on going to 64 bit anyway)<br />
I think this is a good thing, servers should not be running 32 bit nowadays anyway.</p>
<p>Read the complete blogpost here: http://blogs.technet.com/windowsserver/archive/2008/10/28/announcing-windows-server-2008-r2.aspx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows-server-2008-r2-is-the-first-wind/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
