<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>google &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/google/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Bing, worth switching from Google?</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bing-worth-switching-from-google/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bing-worth-switching-from-google/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 15:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engines]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/06/bing-worth-switching-from-google/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bing is the latest version of a search engine developed by Microsoft. Microsoft was developing and testing for the last couple of months a search engine with the name Kumo which in Japanese means spider or cloud. Kumo was of course just the code name for what would become eventually Bing. Search is very important [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bing is the latest version of a search engine developed by Microsoft. Microsoft was developing and testing for the last couple of months a search engine with the name Kumo which in Japanese means spider or cloud. Kumo was of course just the code name for what would become eventually Bing. </p>
<p>Search is very important because 1% of the search market is roughly worth 1 billion dollars. This means that the number two player can make some decent money. Microsoft doesn&#8217;t have to become number one but they need to just grab around 30% or so and they are in good shape. Since Bing was launched it actually surpassed Yahoo and took market share away from both Google and Yahoo. Google must be eyeing this with great interest because a couple of weeks ago the <a href="http://www.wolframalpha.com/">WolframAlpha</a> decision engine was launched and now Bing is here. Did you see the pathetic answer from Google to WolframAlpha named <a href="http://www.google.com/squared/search?q=wolfram">Google Squared</a></p>
<p>I have tried to use a search engine developed by Microsoft several times in the past. I tried MSN search and it didn’t do the job, I tried LiveSearch and that was barely better. </p>
<p>With Bing Microsoft finally hit the nail on its head. The search works and finally you can use Bing as a verb: let me Bing that. That is much better than let me MSNSearch that for you. </p>
<p>I switched all my browsers for a week and I must say surprisingly that I did not use Google even once. Bing is as good as Google and has also some nice additional features. Type <a href="http://www.bing.com/search?q=New+York+to+miami+flights&amp;go=&amp;form=QBRE">New York to miami flights</a> into the search bar. Here is what you see. </p>
<p><img src="http://imgur.com/Y9K9g.png" alt="New York to miami flights" /></p>
<p></p>
<p>Look at the green arrow and the process predicted to rise box. This is a nice feature; buy the ticket now because the price is predicted to go up soon</p>
<p>If you type <a href="http://www.bing.com/shopping/search?q=Nike+Shoes&amp;mkt=en-US&amp;FORM=BPFD">Nike Shoes</a> and click on shopping you will get something like this.</p>
<p><img src="http://imgur.com/uj1A7.png" alt="Nike Shoes search on Bing" /></p>
<p></p>
<p>If you then click on <a href="http://www.bing.com/maps/default.aspx?q=Nike+Shoes&amp;mkt=en-US&amp;FORM=BYFD">maps</a> from the menu on top you will get a list of stores on a map.</p>
<p>If you do a search for something like <a href="http://www.bing.com/search?q=leave+Britney+alone&amp;go=&amp;form=QBRE">leave Britney alone</a> you will see a bunch of video on top</p>
<p><img src="http://imgur.com/brZq5.png" alt="leave Britney alone" /></p>
<p></p>
<p>If you just hover over the play button the video will start to play</p>
<p>If you are a developer then take a look at the <a href="http://www.bing.com/developers/?FORM=ZZFD3">Project Silk Road</a></p>
<p><strong>Bing API 2.0</strong><br />
A key part of Project Silk Road is a re-architected Bing API that offers open, flexible options for building or enhancing your site or applications. Developing an application with the new API is straightforward: Choose a SourceType (or SourceTypes – you’re not limited to one), choose an output protocol (JSON, SOAP, or XML) and then customize according to your needs. All you need to get going is an AppID.<br />
Key improvements to the Bing API include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Multiple protocols: JSON, XML, SOAP</li>
<li>Multiple SourceTypes: Web, Images, InstantAnswer, Phonebook, RelatedSearch, Spell, and more…</li>
<li>Unlimited use for customer-facing sites and applications</li>
<li>Flexible presentation options: No restrictions on ordering and blending results</li>
</ul>
<p>I doubt that a majority of people will make the switch because I don’t think it is so much better than Google to make people switch who have been using Google for a long time. For new computer users Bing is good enough that there is no reason to switch to Google</p>
<p><strong>How do you make Bing your default search engine?</strong><br />
In FireFox just go to this link and download the Bing search engine<br />
https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/browse/type:4/cat:all?sort=name</p>
<p>In Internet Explorer 8 you can get bing from here: http://www.ieaddons.com/en/searchproviders</p>
<p>In Chrome you click on the tools icon, select options, default search engine and then click manage (see picture below)</p>
<p><img src="http://imgur.com/a4dEo.png" alt="Make Bing default in Chrome" /></p>
<p></p>
<p>I would love to hear your opinion, did you try Bing and what did you think of it?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bing-worth-switching-from-google/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>FireFox, Chrome and Internet Explorer 8 Memory Usage, IE8 Uses More Memory Than Chrome and FireFox Combined</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/firefox-chrome-and-internet-explorer-8-m/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/firefox-chrome-and-internet-explorer-8-m/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory leak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mozilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/03/firefox-chrome-and-internet-explorer-8-m/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I decided to do a little test on one of my machines with the three browsers I use most. In each browser I opened up Gmail, Google Reader and CNNMoney. I did this on Friday and did not look at the memory usage until Monday. After a little less than 3 days, we get the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I decided to do a little test on one of my machines with the three browsers I use most. In each browser I opened up <a href="http://mail.google.com/mail/?tab=ym">Gmail</a>, <a href="http://www.google.com/reader/">Google Reader</a> and <a href="http://money.cnn.com/?cnn=yes">CNNMoney</a>.<br />
I did this on Friday and did not look at the memory usage until Monday. After a little less than 3 days, we get the following numbers</p>
<p><strong>Chromium 1.0.154.48</strong><br />
180,157k</p>
<p><strong>IE 8.00.6001.18372</strong><br />
362,223k</p>
<p><strong>Firefox 3.0.4</strong><br />
100,148k</p>
<p>Looking at these numbers makes you think that Google wrote Gmail and Google Reader in such a way that it on purpose made Internet Explorer leak memory like a bucket without a bottom.</p>
<pre>If IE 
   then leak memory 
else 
   behave normally</pre>
<p>I don&#8217;t know but this is just crazy, don&#8217;t come to me either saying that IE8 is beta, so what, this is insane! IE8 uses 362MB while FireFox 3 only uses 100MB. Chrome compared to Firefox uses almost double the memory. Chrome + FireFox combine still use 80MB less than Internet Explorer 8</p>
<p>Below is a screen shot of what memory usage looks like</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/3322981762/" title="FireFox, Chrome and Internet Explorer 8 Memory Usage"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3594/3322981762_be28114019_o.jpg" width="654" height="192" alt="Browsers" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/firefox-chrome-and-internet-explorer-8-m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Has Google Been Hacked? Every search result shows This site may harm your computer.</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/has-google-been-hacked-every-search-resu/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/has-google-been-hacked-every-search-resu/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 12:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/01/has-google-been-hacked-every-search-resu/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What is going on with Google today? Every search I do has This site may harm your computer.

See the image below 


  

And how ironic is this? Google itself shows up as malware  LOL
  



Google seemed to have fixed this problem, Took about&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What is going on with Google today? Every search I do has <strong>This site may harm your computer</strong>.</p>
<p>See the image below </p>
<p><a href="http://tinypic.com/" target="_blank"><img src="http://i39.tinypic.com/t7ecmq.jpg" border="0" alt="This site may harm your computer" /></a></p>
<p>And how ironic is this? Google itself shows up as malware  LOL</p>
<p><a href="http://tinypic.com/" target="_blank"><img src="http://i41.tinypic.com/2gvr5dv.jpg" border="0" alt="Google Is Malware?" /></a></p>
<p>Google seemed to have fixed this problem, Took about an hour or so&#8230;..wonder if they lost any money during this time</p>
<p>Here is what happened according to the <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2009/01/this-site-may-harm-your-computer-on.html">Official Google Blog</a></p>
<blockquote><p>What happened? Very simply, human error. Google flags search results with the message &#8220;This site may harm your computer&#8221; if the site is known to install malicious software in the background or otherwise surreptitiously. We do this to protect our users against visiting sites that could harm their computers. We maintain a list of such sites through both manual and automated methods. We work with a non-profit called StopBadware.org to come up with criteria for maintaining this list, and to provide simple processes for webmasters to remove their site from the list.</p>
<p>We periodically update that list and released one such update to the site this morning. Unfortunately (and here&#8217;s the human error), the URL of &#8216;/&#8217; was mistakenly checked in as a value to the file and &#8216;/&#8217; expands to all URLs. Fortunately, our on-call site reliability team found the problem quickly and reverted the file. Since we push these updates in a staggered and rolling fashion, the errors began appearing between 6:27 a.m. and 6:40 a.m. and began disappearing between 7:10 and 7:25 a.m., so the duration of the problem for any particular user was approximately 40 minutes.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/has-google-been-hacked-every-search-resu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Interview Questions</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/google-interview-questions/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/google-interview-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 10:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/10/google-interview-questions/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Google Interview Questions

So the economy is really bad and your job might be on the line, Google is always looking for new talent. Here are 2 questions that they asked a friend of mine. What would you answer?

1. You have been shrunk down to the s&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Google Interview Questions</h3>
<p>So the economy is really bad and your job might be on the line, Google is always looking for new talent. Here are 2 questions that they asked a friend of mine. What would you answer?</p>
<p><em>1. You have been shrunk down to the size of a nickel and tossed into a blender. You are told that the blender blades will start in 60 seconds.What would you do to save your life?</p>
<p>2. Design and describe a system/application that will most efficiently produce a report of the top 1 million Google search requests.These are the particulars.</p>
<p>* You are given 12 servers to work with. They are all dual-processor machines with 4Gb of RAM, 4x400GB hard drives and networked together.(Basically, nothing more than high-end PC&#8217;s)</p>
<p>* The log data has already been cleaned for you. It consists of 100 Billion log lines, broken down into 12 320 GB files of 40-byte search terms per line.</p>
<p>* You can use only custom written applications or available free open-source software.</em></p>
<p>So what do you think, could you answer these questions?</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget, if you have any tech questions then don&#8217;t hesitate to ask in our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/">forums</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/google-interview-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Chrome Dev Channel: Early Access to Features and Fixes</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/google-chrome-dev-channel-early-access-t/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/google-chrome-dev-channel-early-access-t/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 16:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/google-chrome-dev-channel-early-access-t/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you want to get the new Chrome features as soon as possible then you are in luck; Google has launched the Google Chrome Dev Channel. The Google Chrome Dev Channel will give you early access to features and fixes. The Dev channel is useful for: Web developers who want to test their sites or [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you want to get the new Chrome features as soon as possible then you are in luck; Google has launched the Google Chrome Dev Channel. The Google Chrome Dev Channel will give you early access to features and fixes.</p>
<p>The Dev channel is useful for:<br />
<strong>Web developers</strong> who want to test their sites or scripts with pre-release versions of Google Chrome<br />
<strong>Testers</strong> who need to make sure they&#8217;re working with the latest bug fixes<br />
<strong>Anyone who wants to help make Google Chrome better</strong> &#8212; your feedback helps us turn good new features into great features, and using the Dev channel is a simple way for anyone to help.</p>
<p>Dev channel releases are less stable than Beta channel releases. Expect the occasional &#8220;sad tab&#8221; or even browser crashes (if you turn on &#8216;Help make Google Chrome better..&#8217; in Options, we&#8217;ll get the crash reports so we can fix the bugs).</p>
<p>Automatic updates of new Dev channel releases are published every 1-2 weeks</p>
<p>Get all the details and what you need to download here: http://dev.chromium.org/getting-involved/dev-channel</p>
<p>The first version has been posted. There are a bunch of fixes<br />
<strong>Plugins</strong><br />
r1735 Fixes bugs with Silverlight plugin not displaying correctly (issues 248, 666)<br />
r1859 Fix YouTube (and other Flash videos) halting if the time-advance slider is used.<br />
r1958 Fixes a problem with Shockwave/Flash games not loading (issue 643)</p>
<p><strong>Crashes</strong><br />
r1662 Fix occasional crash when trying to make Google Chrome the default browser (b/1355679)<br />
r1708 Fix crash in history view when deleting a day of history (b/1358107)</p>
<p>More here: http://sites.google.com/a/chromium.org/dev/getting-involved/dev-channel/release-notes/release-notes-021521</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/google-chrome-dev-channel-early-access-t/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
