<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ssis &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/ssis-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL 2016 Preview has been released!</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/sql-2016-preview-has-been-released/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/sql-2016-preview-has-been-released/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 10:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ctp2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3394</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For those who haven&#8217;t noticed already: SQL Server 2016 CTP2 (or Preview as some call it) has just been released! This means it is play time! 🙂 You can either download a copy if you&#8217;re old school like me, or you can spin up a VM in Azure like all the cool kids. SQL Server [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those who haven&#8217;t noticed already:</p>
<p>SQL Server 2016 CTP2 (or Preview as some call it) has just been released!<br />
This means it is play time! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>You can either download a copy if you&#8217;re old school like me, or you can spin up a VM in Azure like all the cool kids.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/dataplatforminsider/archive/2015/05/27/sql-server-2016-first-public-preview-now-available.aspx">SQL Server 2016 first public preview now available!</a></p>
<p>Some of my favorite features (although some are not yet in the preview):</p>
<ul>
<li>SSIS incremental deployment model (aka deploy only 1 package to the SSIS catalog). Although I understand the reason of the SSIS team to first allow only deployments of full projects, there are a lot of customers that want this functionality.</li>
<li>Power Query in all the things! (more specifically: in SSIS and SSRS)</li>
<li>R integration in SSRS (this should allow you to do amazing things with SSRS)</li>
<li>SSRS revamp (still have to see it though, but I&#8217;m already excited!)</li>
<li><a href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dn935015(v=sql.130).aspx">Temporal tables </a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2015/05/announcing-live-query-execution-plans/">Live query plans</a> (seems pretty awesome)</li>
<li>DAX enhancements (many 2 many, median, percentiles, and so on)</li>
</ul>
<p>Here&#8217;s a good overview of what you can expect in SQL Server 2016:</p>
<p><a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jorg_klein/archive/2015/05/22/bi-on-your-terms-with-sql-server-2016.aspx">BI on your terms with SQL Server 2016</a></p>
<p>Be careful, if you install Polybase, you apparently need the Oracle JRE. Boooo.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/polybase_jre.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3395" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/polybase_jre.jpg" alt="polybase_jre" width="594" height="285" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/polybase_jre.jpg 594w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/05/polybase_jre-300x143.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 594px) 100vw, 594px" /></a></p>
<p>Anyway, a lot of goodness and I am very excited about this release.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/sql-2016-preview-has-been-released/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The shaky bug in SSIS</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/the-shaky-bug-in-ssis/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/the-shaky-bug-in-ssis/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 11:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You may or may not have noticed it after installing SQL Server 2012: the designer interface in Visual Studio 2010/2012 has had a make-over. Nothing too drastic, but at least the undo button works. However, sometimes when you drag or move tasks/components on the canvas, they start to shake. A lot. And very annoyingly as [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">You may or may not have noticed it after installing SQL Server 2012: the designer interface in Visual Studio 2010/2012 has had a make-over. Nothing too drastic, but at least the undo button works. However, sometimes when you drag or move tasks/components on the canvas, they start to shake. A lot. And very annoyingly as well. (Quite impossible to take a screenshot of that, so sorry). This behaviour emerged after applying CU6. There are Connect items logged about this issue:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/details/790470/when-dragging-ssis-objects-on-canvas-the-objects-shake-jiggle-jitter">When dragging SSIS objects on canvas the objects shake/jiggle/jitter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/details/776664/ssis-2012-control-flow-moving-objects-is-unusable">SSIS 2012 Control Flow moving objects is unusable</a></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify">Luckily Microsoft patched this bug in CU7. You can download the hotfix <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/kb/2883424/en-us?wa=wsignin1.0">here</a>. If your environment is up-to-date with the latest patches, most likely you won&#8217;t experience this bug.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I patched the Visual Studio 2010 environment at the client and the issue went away. But at home I use Visual Studio 2012 and the issue was still there, even after applying the fix. Fortunately, Twitter was there with the answer:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/Ko_Ver">@Ko_Ver</a> Ok, because the CU that fixes that only updates the DLL&#8217;s for VS2010, you need to manually overwrite the assemblies in VS2012 folder</p>
<p>— Jan Van humbeek (@janvanhumbeek) <a href="https://twitter.com/janvanhumbeek/status/517569881672544256">October 2, 2014</a></p></blockquote>
<p>If you go back to the <a href="https://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/details/790470/when-dragging-ssis-objects-on-canvas-the-objects-shake-jiggle-jitter">first Connect item</a>, these steps are described in the work arounds and they work like a charm.</p>
<p>The issue has also been <a href="https://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/details/1013088/ssis-2014-control-flow-moving-objects-is-unusable">reported for SSIS 2014</a>, and while the item has been closed as fixed, there&#8217;s no explanation on how it is fixed. Maybe in an upcoming CU for SQL Server 2014? It&#8217;s possible the same work around works for SSIS 2014, but I haven&#8217;t tried it (I don&#8217;t have the bug in Visual Studio 2013) so if you do try it, it&#8217;s at your own risk.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/the-shaky-bug-in-ssis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>T-SQL Tuesday #63: How do you manage security</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/t-sql-tuesday-63-how-do-you-manage-security/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/t-sql-tuesday-63-how-do-you-manage-security/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 08:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t-sql tuesday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3165</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is hosted by Kenneth Fisher (blog &#124; twitter) and its subject is about security. Security is one of those subjects that most DBAs have to deal with regardless of specialty. So as something we all have to work with at some point or another what are some tips you’d like to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://sqlstudies.com/2015/02/03/tsql-tuesday-63-how-do-you-manage-security/"><img style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/TSQL2sday.png" alt="TSQL2sday" width="133" height="134" /></a>This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is hosted by Kenneth Fisher (<a href="http://sqlstudies.com/">blog </a>| <a href="https://twitter.com/sqlstudent144">twitter</a>) and its subject is about security.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em>Security is one of those subjects that most DBAs have to deal with regardless of specialty. So as something we all have to work with at some point or another what are some tips you’d like to share? What’s the best security design? You’ve picked up a legacy system and the security is awful, how do you fix it? Any great tools out there you’d like to share? Hate it or love it I’m betting we all have something to say.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Now, I’m not exactly a DBA but even ETL developers have to deal with security from time to time. In this blog post, I’d like to talk about the built-in security of the SSIS packages. You see, SSIS packages can store sensitive data inside them, such as the passwords for the connection managers for example. In order to protect that information, SSIS uses <a href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms141747.aspx">protection levels</a> which is a package-level property. These are the available protection levels:</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify">
<li><strong>DontSaveSensitive</strong>, which is my personal favorite as it forces you to use either configurations or parameters.</li>
<li><strong>EncryptSensitiveWithPassword</strong>. Other people can still open the package if they don&#8217;t have the password,  but the passwords in the connection managers are lost and need to be re-entered..</li>
<li><strong>EncryptAllWithPassword</strong>, for the paranoia people.</li>
<li><strong>EncryptSensitiveWithUserKey</strong>, which is the default. And as usual, they choose the absolute worst choice as the default. This setting basically means only you can access the sensitive data. Real peachy when you are in a team with multiple developers. Other developers can still open the package (then ignore a few warnings) but they have to re-enter all the passwords in the connection managers.</li>
<li><strong>EncryptAllWithUserKey</strong>, when you are really possessive over your packages.</li>
<li><strong>ServerStorage</strong>. When you deploy a package to the server, you trust SQL Server in protecting the sensitive data. This is default when you deploy packages to the SSIS catalog with the project deployment model.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify">Protection levels were really important before SSIS 2012, as they specified how sensitive data was protected. However, the default of EncryptSensitiveWithUserKey is a really crappy one. If you schedule a package with this protection level using SQL Server Agent, the package can still run if there is no actual sensitive data in the package, but a lot of unnecessary warnings are generated. It&#8217;s best to avoid this protection level at all costs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Protecting the package with a password is a good option. However, when deploying the package with the package deployment model (or every version of SSIS before 2012), you had to enter the password when you were scheduling the package with Agent. This means though that the password is stored in MSDB, so it isn&#8217;t that secure. My advice is to use DontSaveSensitive and store sensitive information inside a SQL Server configuration table.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">With the project deployment model however, configurations are gone. They are replaced with parameters and environments. Since parameters are configured inside the package or project, this means the sensitive data is stored inside the package again. In this case it makes sense to protect the package with a password if needed. There is no issue on the server side, since the protection level is automatically converted to ServerStorage during deployment. Keep in mind that all the packages and the project itself need to have the same protection level, otherwise you get an error when the .ispac file is built.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Conclusion:</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify">
<li>when using earlier version of SSIS or when using the package deployment: the DontSaveSensitive protection level in combination with a configuration table is the most secure option.</li>
<li>when using the project deployment model: use parameters and environments to replace the configurations. Protect the package with a password if you want to secure those parameters.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify">Note:<br />
when using Windows Authentication for all sources and destinations, there is almost nothing to be secured in a package. Obviously, this is even more secure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/t-sql-tuesday-63-how-do-you-manage-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The mysterious permission issue</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/the-mysterious-permission-issue/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/the-mysterious-permission-issue/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 14:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[0xC020200E]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannot open data file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flat file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[permission issue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[share]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3150</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As you might have realized, this is not the title of an Agatha Christie book, but rather about some nasty permission issue I encountered with SSIS. At a new project, someone mentioned me that a scheduled job has been failing for quite some time now (actually since they created the job, yay for testing!). So [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/poirot.jpg"><img style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/poirot-150x150.jpg" alt="poirot" width="100" height="100" /></a>As you might have realized, this is not the title of an Agatha Christie book, but rather about some nasty permission issue I encountered with SSIS. At a new project, someone mentioned me that a scheduled job has been failing for quite some time now (actually since they created the job, yay for testing!). So I put my detective hat on (with my fake Poirot&#8217;stache) and started investigating.</p>
<p>The SSIS catalog report <em>All Executions</em> gave me the following wonderfull error messages:</p>
<blockquote><p>Error: FF_DST Write to Flat file failed the pre-execute phase and returned error code 0xC020200E.<br />
DFT Export to Flat File:Error: Cannot open the datafile &#8220;\\myServer\c$\rootfolder\myExport\myFlatFile.txt&#8221;.</p></blockquote>
<p>There was also a little warning with a more useful message:</p>
<blockquote><p>DFT Export to Flat File:Warning: Access is denied.</p></blockquote>
<p>I immediately thought: &#8220;Haha, no proxy is used in the SQL Server Agent job step!&#8221;<br />
However, when I checked the job step there was a proxy configured. OK then, they must have forgot to assign permissions to the folder. Alas, permissions were correctly set as well. The plot thickens!</p>
<p>Just to be sure, I gave the user account used by the proxy full permission to the root folder (as someone suggested on a forum). No dice, the job still failed with the exact same error message. I googled around for a bit (like any good detective) for the error code 0xC020200E. Another suggestion I came across was adding the user <em>Network Service</em> to the folder but that was a dead end as well. FYI, the package ran flawlessly in SSDT. Of course it did.</p>
<p>Finally I stumbled upon a MSDN thread where someone suggested it might be an issue with the UNC file path. Apparently sometimes there can be an issue when the drive letter is in the path. In this case: c$. So I created a dedicated share called //myServer/myExport and gave explicit read/write permissions to the proxy account. And lo and behold, the job ran without issues!</p>
<p>The moral of this story: Windows can be a real PITA <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/the-mysterious-permission-issue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Overview of Published Articles – 2014Q4</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/overview-of-published-articles-2014q4/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/overview-of-published-articles-2014q4/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 20:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mssqltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3145</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here is an overview of the articles I published in the last quarter of 2014. INTENSE SCHOOL MCSE Prep: Overview of T-SQL Windowing Functions Part 1 MCSE Prep: Overview of T-SQL Windowing Functions Part 2 The third and final part of this series will probably be published this month, so keep an eye on the site [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #2f2f2f">Here is an overview of the articles I published in the last quarter of 2014.</span></p>
<p><strong style="color: #2f2f2f">INTENSE SCHOOL</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/mcse-prep-overview-of-t-sql-windowing-functions-part-1/">MCSE Prep: Overview of T-SQL Windowing Functions Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/mcse-prep-overview-of-t-sql-windowing-functions-part-2/">MCSE Prep: Overview of T-SQL Windowing Functions Part 2</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The third and final part of this series will probably be published this month, so keep an eye on the site for more window functions awesomeness <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><strong style="color: #2f2f2f">MSSQLTIPS</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3374/format-durations-in-sql-server-analysis-services/">Format Durations in SQL Server Analysis Services</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3395/creating-a-box-plot-graph-in-sql-server-reporting-services/">Creating a box plot graph in SQL Server Reporting Services</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3417/sql-server-reporting-services-add-calculated-series-to-a-graph/">SQL Server Reporting Services Add Calculated Series to a Graph</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3432/add-a-linear-trendline-to-a-graph-in-sql-server-reporting-services/">Add a linear trendline to a graph in SQL Server Reporting Services</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Yes, I had quite some SSRS inspiration the past months. Regarding the first tip about formatting durations: I wrote about potential issues with NULL values in the blog post <a href="/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/formatting-durations-in-ssas-caveat/">Formatting Durations in SSAS: Caveat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/overview-of-published-articles-2014q4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PASS BI VC recording is available now</title>
		<link>/index.php/uncategorized/pass-bi-vc-recording-is-available-now/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/uncategorized/pass-bi-vc-recording-is-available-now/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 12:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[etl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual chapter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The recording of the webinar I did for the PASS BI virtual chapter is live! (Quick reminder: it was the same session as on the SQLServerDays: How to (not) torment your fellow SSIS developer?) I&#8217;m quite pleased with the recording, although I sound like a drunk German scientist sometimes. The slides can be downloaded here. Let [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The recording of the <a href="/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/pass-bi-vc-how-to-not-torment-your-fellow-ssis-developer/">webinar </a>I did for the PASS BI virtual chapter is live!<br />
(Quick reminder: it was the same session as on the SQLServerDays: <a style="color: #c04623" href="/index.php/uncategorized/speaking-at-sql-server-days-2014/">How to (not) torment your fellow SSIS developer?</a>)</p>
<p>I&#8217;m quite pleased with the recording, although I sound like a drunk German scientist sometimes.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-N7gxmAdceM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The slides can be downloaded <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/KoenVerbeeck/sql-server-days-2014-how-to-not-torment-your">here</a>.</p>
<p>Let me know in the comments if you like it or not!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/uncategorized/pass-bi-vc-recording-is-available-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominated for Author of the Year</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/nominated-for-author-of-the-year/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/nominated-for-author-of-the-year/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 13:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[award]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mssqltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vote]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have the great pleasure to announce that I have been nominated for the &#8220;Author of the Year&#8221; award at the MSSQLTips website. This means however I have to persuade people to vote for me, hence this blog post 😉 You can vote for me at the following URL: http://www.mssqltips.com/MSSQLTipsAuthorVoting.asp Note that you can cast a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">I have the great pleasure to announce that I have been nominated for the &#8220;Author of the Year&#8221; award at the <a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/">MSSQLTips </a>website. This means however I have to persuade people to vote for me, hence this blog post <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">You can vote for me at the following URL:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/MSSQLTipsAuthorVoting.asp">http://www.mssqltips.com/MSSQLTipsAuthorVoting.asp</a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Note that you can cast a vote each day until the end of December, so you can vote for me multiple times!<br />
Also, the votes are distinguished by IP address, so you can use your mobile phone to vote even more! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Thanks in advance!<br />
Koen</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/MSSQLTipsAuthorVoting.asp"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3068" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/mssql_logo.jpg" alt="mssql_logo" width="224" height="133" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/nominated-for-author-of-the-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PASS BI VC: How to (not) torment your fellow SSIS developer?</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/pass-bi-vc-how-to-not-torment-your-fellow-ssis-developer/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/pass-bi-vc-how-to-not-torment-your-fellow-ssis-developer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 11:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webinar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3058</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On November 17th 2PM CET I will redo my SQL Server Days presentation How to (not) torment your fellow SSIS developer? for the PASS BI virtual chapter. This is great news for the people who couldn&#8217;t attend my session at the SQL Server Days and who still want to see it (I hope those people [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">On November 17th 2PM CET I will redo my SQL Server Days presentation <a href="/index.php/uncategorized/speaking-at-sql-server-days-2014/">How to (not) torment your fellow SSIS developer?</a> for the <a href="http://bi.sqlpass.org/">PASS BI virtual chapter</a>. This is great news for the people who couldn&#8217;t attend my session at the SQL Server Days and who still want to see it (I hope those people actually exist).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What is even better is that the PASS BI virtual chapter afterwards always uploads the webinars to Youtube, so there won&#8217;t be any excuse for not watching my session <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />
Check out other amazing BI sessions from the SQL community on<a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/passbivc"> their Youtube channel</a>!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">You can register for the webinar <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/register/8118983337165731074">here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/passbivc"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3059 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/passbivc-300x150.jpg" alt="passbivc" width="300" height="150" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/passbivc-300x150.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/11/passbivc.jpg 400w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/pass-bi-vc-how-to-not-torment-your-fellow-ssis-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Overview of Published Articles – 2014Q3</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/overview-of-published-articles-2014q3/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/overview-of-published-articles-2014q3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 08:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3024</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here is an overview of the articles I published in the third quarter of 2014. INTENSE SCHOOL MCSE Prep (SQL) – Using Parameters in Reporting Services Reports (Part 2) Book Review: SQL Server 2012 Integration Services Design Patterns MSSQLTIPS Adding Custom Reports to SQL Server Management Studio More Text Analysis with the SSIS Term Lookup [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is an overview of the articles I published in the third quarter of 2014.</p>
<p><strong>INTENSE SCHOOL</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/mcse-prep-sql-using-parameters-in-reporting-services-reports-part-2/">MCSE Prep (SQL) – Using Parameters in Reporting Services Reports (Part 2)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/book-review-sql-server-2012-integration-services-design-patterns/">Book Review: SQL Server 2012 Integration Services Design Patterns</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>MSSQLTIPS</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3291/adding-custom-reports-to-sql-server-management-studio/">Adding Custom Reports to SQL Server Management Studio</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3315/more-text-analysis-with-the-ssis-term-lookup-component/">More Text Analysis with the SSIS Term Lookup Component</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3356/custom-ssms-report-to-show-sql-server-tables-per-filegroup/">Custom SSMS report to show SQL Server tables per filegroup</a></li>
</ul>
<p>I have two more tips in the pipeline, one about formatting durations in SSAS and one about creating box plots in SSRS, so keep an eye on the <a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/">MSSQLTips</a> website.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/overview-of-published-articles-2014q3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Server Days 2014 &#8211; Slide deck</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/sql-server-days-2014-slide-deck/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/sql-server-days-2014-slide-deck/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 07:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[integration services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server days]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SQL Server Days 2014 is over, but it has been one great event. A very big thanks to the organizers! My session went pretty well, somewhere around 60 attendees I would guess and they didn&#8217;t seem too bored. I saw some other great sessions as well, such as Buck Woody (twitter) on Big Data (and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SQL Server Days 2014 is over, but it has been one great event. A very big thanks to the organizers! My session went pretty well, somewhere around 60 attendees I would guess and they didn&#8217;t seem too bored. I saw some other great sessions as well, such as Buck Woody (<a href="https://twitter.com/buckwoody">twitter</a>) on Big Data (and a fantastic keynote) and a demo session on Azure ML. I also attended Grants (<a href="https://twitter.com/GFritchey">twitter </a>| <a href="http://www.scarydba.com/">blog</a>) precon on execution plans and I definitely learned a lot.</p>
<p>It was great to meet up with the #sqlfamily and I can&#8217;t wait for next years edition.</p>
<p>I have uploaded my slides to <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/KoenVerbeeck/sql-server-days-2014-how-to-not-torment-your">Slideshare</a>, in case you&#8217;re interested.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/sql-server-days-2014-slide-deck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
