<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	>
	<title type="text">Comments on Bringing your thoughts back into line</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-02-26T12:40:14Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comments" />
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/feed/atom/" />
	<id>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/feed/atom/</id>
<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<title>By: traingamer</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1625" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>traingamer</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1625</id>
		<updated>2009-07-22T13:36:56Z</updated>
		<published>2009-07-22T13:36:56Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1625"><![CDATA[<p>If you are putting in 14+ hour days *often*, there is a problem. It is very important that I do a good job at work, but other than the occasional &#8220;Something&#8217;s broken &#8211; it needs fixed at any cost.&#8221; or &#8220;we need help to get past this government audit.&#8221; you should not be putting in hours like that. <br />
Someone else&#8217;s piss-poor project planning and chronic understaffing should not become your regular 70 hour work week.<br />
It is difficult to stay on top of all of the new technology and tools, so as several others have stated, you need to specialize. (I know that this is not always posssible.)<br />
It&#8217;s great that you have found cool new things to learn &#8211; these are the things that keep us from burnout.<br />
Best of luck!</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: SQLDenis</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1624" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1624</id>
		<updated>2009-07-21T15:23:41Z</updated>
		<published>2009-07-21T15:23:41Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1624"><![CDATA[<p>tarwn , specialization will be the key&#8230;I already see SQL Server guys who specialize in just one thing and this might be indexing, query tuning, SAN setup and tuning, Data Warehousing etc etc.. Same thing in other technologies&#8230;you might have someone in your company who just does Hadoop or WCF or .NET/Java profiling/performance testing etc etc&#8230;&#8230;&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1623" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1623</id>
		<updated>2009-07-21T14:09:15Z</updated>
		<published>2009-07-21T14:09:15Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1623"><![CDATA[<p>Denis, I would actually go so far as to add that (the diminishing size of our hard-earned knowledge relative to the growing technologies we use) to the list of items above that make it harder to do our jobs long term. Sure we are getting better in a general sense as time goes on, but we also have to cope with watching things we were once experts in grow in scope to the point where it&#8217;s no longer possible to be an expert (or if it is, it won&#8217;t be next year). if we don&#8217;t take a step back and recognize this issue then it is easy to fall prey to feelings that we are not able to keep up or are not as sharp as we once were. Technology is constantly exploding and the scope of what someone can be an expert in is constantly shrinking in relation to the scope of those technologies. Nine years ago if you had told me people would be getting famous off of writing books about JavaScript libraries I never would have believed it, even JavaScript as a whole was just coming into it&#8217;s own (I&#8217;m thinking JQuery as a subset of the AJAX movement, as a subset of the Web 2.0 movement, as a subset of Javascript).</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: SQLDenis</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1622" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1622</id>
		<updated>2009-07-21T13:00:33Z</updated>
		<published>2009-07-21T13:00:33Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/#comment-1622"><![CDATA[<p>I really like the honesty in your post, lots of people will never acknowledge that something is wrong or that they are trashing 2 days trying to find that answer to the problem.</p>
<p>I also find it helpful to split up task in more manageable chunks, what we do at my job is split it up in no more than what one workday (7 hours in my case) would be.</p>
<p>You also need to be aware of people&#8217;s skills around you, if someone knows a technology better than you then ask that person for help if you are dealing with that technology&#8230;.there is no shame in doing that, nowadays more than ever nobody knows everything</p>
<p>Just take a look at SQL Server, back in the 2000 and 7 days you might have known pretty much everything that there was to know&#8230;..these days that is just impossible with all the new things that they added like SSIS, SSRS, SSAS, Service Broker, SQLCLR, Extended Events, XML, Resource Governor, Powershell, VB, C#&#8230;and the list goes on and on&#8230;..</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/07/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bringing-your-thoughts-back-into-line-1/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
</feed>
