<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>open source &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/open-source/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Backup to the cloud by using duplicati</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/backup-to-the-cloud-by/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/backup-to-the-cloud-by/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 23:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software and Configuration Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skydrive]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/05/backup-to-the-cloud-by/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I decided to give Duplicati a try to backup some of my stuff to the cloud. Duplicati is free/libre/open-source software (FLOSS). Duplicati works with Amazon S3, Windows Live SkyDrive, Google Drive (Google Docs), Rackspace Cloud Files or WebDAV, SSH, FTP&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I decided to give <a href="http://www.duplicati.com/">Duplicati</a> a try to backup some of my stuff to the cloud. Duplicati is free/libre/open-source software (FLOSS). Duplicati works with Amazon S3, Windows Live SkyDrive, Google Drive (Google Docs), Rackspace Cloud Files or WebDAV, SSH, FTP. </p>
<p>Duplicati uses Pre-Internet Encryption, you know that nobody can decrypt your files. When working with the cloud you have to be in TNO (Trust No One) mode. You never know what malicious person could be on the other side. Duplicati has built-in AES-256 encryption and backups can be signed using GNU Privacy Guard</p>
<p>Duplicati is available for the following platforms</p>
<p>Duplicati 1.3.2 for Windows &#8211; (32bit, msi)<br />
Duplicati 1.3.2 for Windows &#8211; (64bit, msi)<br />
Duplicati 1.3.2 for Mac OS X &#8211; (dmg)<br />
Duplicati 1.3.2 for Debian, Ubuntu, LinuxMint &#8211; (deb)<br />
Duplicati 1.3.2 for Fedora, RedHat, OpenSuSE &#8211; (rpm)<br />
Duplicati 1.3.2 &#8211; (Binaries, zip)<br />
Duplicati 1.3.2 &#8211; (Linux binary, tgz)</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at how easy it is to use. After you install Duplicati, run it. When you run it the first time a wizard will pop up. Pick select a new backup</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati01.PNG?mtime=1337909180"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati01.PNG?mtime=1337909180" width="506" height="379" /></a></div>
<p>A bunch of typical folders that hold your pictures, music, documents etc are shown by default. I decided to create a new folder and dump some pics in that folder</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati02.PNG?mtime=1337909180"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati02.PNG?mtime=1337909180" width="501" height="372" /></a></div>
<p>Next you give a password for your backups</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati03.PNG?mtime=1337909181"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati03.PNG?mtime=1337909181" width="506" height="370" /></a></div>
<p>Then you pick where you want to back this up to</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati04.PNG?mtime=1337909182"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati04.PNG?mtime=1337909182" width="511" height="340" /></a></div>
<p>I picked SkyDrive</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati05.PNG?mtime=1337909183"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati05.PNG?mtime=1337909183" width="506" height="372" /></a></div>
<p>On the advanced page, you can add custom filters, set up the frequency and add limits</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati06.PNG?mtime=1337909235"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati06.PNG?mtime=1337909235" width="510" height="376" /></a></div>
<p>On the next page you can now fill the details in for the stuff you picked in the previous page</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati07.PNG?mtime=1337909236"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati07.PNG?mtime=1337909236" width="505" height="377" /></a></div>
<p>Backup is running&#8230;.and it is done</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati08.PNG?mtime=1337909236"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati08.PNG?mtime=1337909236" width="472" height="412" /></a></div>
<p>I checked that there was something in the SkyDrive folder</p>
<p>Next I wiped out the folder on my PC and decided to do a restore. I ran the app, clicked on the wizard and picked the restore option</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati09.PNG?mtime=1337909237"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati09.PNG?mtime=1337909237" width="505" height="376" /></a></div>
<p>I picked restore from an existing backup</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati10.PNG?mtime=1337909238"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati10.PNG?mtime=1337909238" width="504" height="376" /></a></div>
<p>I picked the backup I wanted to restore</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati11.PNG?mtime=1337909271"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati11.PNG?mtime=1337909271" width="505" height="378" /></a></div>
<p>It is downloading the backup</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati12.PNG?mtime=1337909271"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Duplicati/Duplicati12.PNG?mtime=1337909271" width="507" height="377" /></a></div>
<p>I checked the folder and all the pictures that I wiped out were restored</p>
<p>It is pretty easy to use, I will test this out over the coming weeks to get more familiar with this product</p>
<p>Duplicati is an open source project, licensed under LGPL, the source can be downloaded here http://code.google.com/p/duplicati/source/checkout</p>
<p>Try it out and let me know what you think, the main product page is here: http://www.duplicati.com/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/softwareandconfigmgmt/backup-to-the-cloud-by/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oracle Details Its Plans For MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice And Open Source</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 09:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Java EE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glassfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netbeans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openoffice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtualization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oracle has updated the Sun Acquisition FAQ. The FAQ now has Oracle's plans for MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice, Open Source and other things.

Below are the relevant pieces from that document.

What are Oracle’s plans fo&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oracle has updated the <a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/sun/038563.pdf">Sun Acquisition FAQ</a>. The FAQ now has Oracle&#8217;s plans for MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice, Open Source and other things.</p>
<p>Below are the relevant pieces from that document.</p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for the GlassFish Enterprise (Java<br />
EE) Server after the transaction closes?</strong><br />
Oracle plans to continue evolving GlassFish Enterprise Server, delivering<br />
it as the open source reference implementation (RI) of the Java Enterprise<br />
Edition (Java EE) specifications, and actively supporting the large GlassFish<br />
community.  Additionally, Oracle plans to invest in aligning common<br />
infrastructure components and innovations from Oracle WebLogic Server<br />
and GlassFish Enterprise Server to benefit both Oracle WebLogic Server and<br />
GlassFish Enterprise Server customers.</p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for NetBeans?</strong><br />
Oracle has a strong track record of demonstrating commitment to choice for<br />
Java developers. As such, NetBeans is expected to provide an additional open<br />
source option and complement to the two free tools Oracle already offers for<br />
enterprise Java development: Oracle JDeveloper and Oracle Enterprise Pack for<br />
Eclipse. While Oracle JDeveloper remains Oracle’s strategic development tool<br />
for the broad portfolio of Oracle Fusion Middleware products and for Oracle’s<br />
next generation of enterprise applications, developers will be able to use<br />
whichever free tool they are most comfortable with for pure Java and Java EE<br />
development:  JDeveloper, Enterprise Pack for Eclipse, or NetBeans. </p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for MySQL?</strong><br />
Oracle plans to spend more money developing MySQL than Sun does now.<br />
Oracle expects to continue to develop and provide the open source MySQL<br />
database after the transaction closes. Oracle plans to add MySQL to Oracle’s<br />
existing suite of database products, which already includes Berkeley DB, an<br />
open source database. Oracle also currently offers InnoDB, an open source<br />
transactional storage engine and the most important and popular transaction<br />
engine under MySQL. Oracle already distributes MySQL as part of our<br />
Enterprise Linux offering.</p>
<p><strong>What is Oracle’s plan for OpenOffice?</strong><br />
Oracle has a history of developing complete, integrated, and open products,<br />
making integration quicker and less costly for our customers. Based on the<br />
open ODF standard, OpenOffice is expected to create a compelling desktop<br />
integration bridge for our enterprise customers and offers consumers another<br />
choice on the desktop. After the transaction closes, Oracle plans to continue<br />
developing and supporting OpenOffice as open source. As before, some of<br />
the larger customers will ask for extra assurances, support, and enterprise<br />
tools. For these customers we expect to offer a typical commercial license<br />
option.</p>
<p><strong>How does Oracle support open source?</strong><br />
Oracle has long been committed to developing, supporting, and promoting<br />
open source. Oracle has been, and continues to be, committed to offering<br />
choice, flexibility, and a lower cost of computing for end users. Oracle<br />
has invested significant resources in developing, testing, optimizing and<br />
supporting open source technologies such as Linux, PHP, Apache, Eclipse,<br />
Berkeley DB, and InnoDB. Oracle continues to embrace and offer open source<br />
solutions as a viable choice for development and deployment. More information<br />
about Oracle’s support of open source can be found at<br />
oracle.com/opensource. </p>
<p><strong>Will Oracle continue Sun’s virtualization strategy?</strong><br />
Yes, Oracle plans to continue Sun’s “desktop to datacenter virtualization”<br />
strategy and integrate with Oracle’s virtualization products. By unifying<br />
management across desktop virtualization, server virtualization, storage<br />
virtualization, and network virtualization, Oracle and Sun provide<br />
comprehensive, flexible, eco-efficient solutions to maximize utilization,<br />
consolidate to reduce costs, increase productivity, and decrease management<br />
complexity. We expect to continue Sun’s desktop virtualization products:<br />
VDI, Secure Global Desktop, Sun Ray, and VirtualBox.</p>
<p><strong>Delivering increased investment and innovation in Java</strong><br />
Oracle plans to accelerate investment in the Java platform for the<br />
benefit of customers and the Java community. Java is one of the<br />
computer industry’s best-known brands and the Java platform is<br />
one of the industry’s most widely deployed technologies. Oracle has<br />
been a leader in the Java community since the inception of the Java<br />
programming language and already has the world’s largest investment<br />
in the Java platform, which provides the foundation for its Oracle<br />
Fusion Middleware products and its next-generation enterprise<br />
applications.<br />
Oracle plans to not only broaden and accelerate its own investment in the<br />
Java platform, but also plans to increase the commitment to the community<br />
that helps make Java an ubiquitous, innovative platform unified around<br />
open standards. </p>
<p>So what do you think, is there still a reason to fear what will happen to these technologies after this deal closes?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Simple advice for choosing an ESB</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/enterprisearchitecture/simple-advice-for-choosing-an-esb/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/enterprisearchitecture/simple-advice-for-choosing-an-esb/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 18:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[damber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information and Integration Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ibm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[integration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle fusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap xi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webmethods]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/04/simple-advice-for-choosing-an-esb/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I thought I would share a recent question that was raised on LinkedIn, which asked:


Starting the Holy Wars on ESB? Who brings the best package deal to the table i.e IBM, MSFT...... Look at this way " A mid sized cash crunched has to implement ESB w&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I thought I would share a recent question that was raised on LinkedIn, which asked:</p>
<blockquote><p>
<em><strong>Starting the Holy Wars on ESB? Who brings the best package deal to the table i.e IBM, MSFT&#8230;&#8230; Look at this way &#8221; A mid sized cash crunched has to implement ESB what are the options it has&#8221; or rather who should it be married to. Any thoughts</strong></em></p>
<p>Tons of ESB from various players are in the market IBM, MSFT, Oracle , SAP but remember its a cash crunched company which requires the ESB. I can provide more details on the technical side. The idea is to throw open the debate to get various perspective.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Well, let&#8217;s forget for the moment that the question was raised by a Microsoft employee, and focus more on the general principle of the question&#8230; What should companies look for in an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enterprise_service_bus">ESB</a>?  In my brief answer, I aim to get across the point that asking which ESB vendor you should be &#8220;Married to&#8221; is very much the wrong question to ask, and to consider that there is more to solving this problem intelligently (and thus cost effectively) than simply &#8216;buying technology&#8217;. No single technology will solve your problem out of the box, so be careful not to expect or ask it to do so.  </p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the Answer in full:</p>
<blockquote><p>
As always&#8230; understand the problem first&#8230;</p>
<p>Step 1: Understand the problem you are trying to solve (e.g. Imperatives, Current Pain Points, As-Is Landscape, Use Cases, etc)<br />
Step 2: Design a Target Architecture (NOT based on a particular technology) that solves this problem, including reference models, design patterns, architecture paradigms, principles, etc<br />
Step 3: Create a high level Roadmap to get from your current environment to your target architecture<br />
Step 4: Now&#8230; Search for a technology that will support this need.</p>
<p>I would highly recommend not starting by talking to vendors about how they will solve your problem. Strangely enough, their products always have the answer <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>ok.. let&#8217;s look at what integration is all about:</p>
<p>Openness<br />
Interoperability<br />
Standardisation<br />
Flexibility</p>
<p>&#8211; This is where you need to really think about why you have an integration problem in the first place&#8230; closed, insular approaches to application design. This indicates that we want an OPEN and INTEROPERABLE environment which is based on STANDARDS to give you FLEXIBILITY.</p>
<p>The problem with a lot of products on the market if not understood or used properly is that you can very soon become (in your words) &#8220;Married&#8221; to that vendor&#8217;s solution. This destroys the core principles of what integration is all about &#8211; you are simply adding the same problem on top of the original problems.</p>
<p>In many ways the open source integration solutions (incl. ESBs &#8211; e.g. SOPERA (commercial and more advanced version of Eclipse Swordfish), Apache FUSE, JBoss,etc) lend themselves to these principles very well, however this does not guarantee they will fit your need, or perform to the level of some COTS/Closed Source options.</p>
<p>Additionally, you need to consider that properly integrating your environment is not just about purchasing / implementing an ESB. This is just one component of the overall solution, which should consider the need for MDM, Data Architecture and Canonicalisation, Portals, Business Rules, Registry/Repository, Modelling Tools, Business Process Management and Orchestration, amongst others. The commercial vendors will be more than willing to sell you complete stacks for these things, but be prepared to do things their way, and have a certain amount of lock-in to that vendor.</p>
<p>As you work there, I&#8217;m sure you realise that Microsoft is very Microsoft focused, so is only really sensible for Microsoft only environments. However, your recent deal with SOPERA now gives support for both native .NET and Java environments. Maybe there is hope&#8230;</p>
<p>Oracle and SAP have some good concepts, but unfortunately they are again very insular &#8211; if you only have SAP then XI will be wonderful for you, same with Oracle Fusion and their AIA offering &#8211; extending outside the environment is possible, but often ugly.</p>
<p>IBM is (imho) conceptually better at being application/solution agnostic, as it doesn&#8217;t sell applications to integrate, therefore focuses on supporting a diverse range of approaches. However, they have a history of a somewhat convoluted and overlapping solution set.</p>
<p>Webmethods provides you with a well integrated set of tools and features, again application agnostic, though it&#8217;s sweet spot is Process Management, and isn&#8217;t the most open/standards compliant.</p>
<p>If a company is really strapped for cash&#8230; then an open source option may be best. But you may have to work harder to get a complete solution up and running.</p>
<p>You can get all of the components to integrate your environment for free &#8211; but you have to implement them, they may not be that pretty/easy to use, or performant, and if you choose not to pay for ongoing support then you are putting your company at risk.</p>
<p>You also have to ask yourself if you are really doing pure SOA, or whether you are needing to do application integration&#8230;</p>
<p>above all, the right architecture will win over a technology choice
</p></blockquote>
<p>So, the answer was as you would expect for a general Q&amp;A site &#8211; relatively simple/brief (there is a post size limit!) and a little on the generic side to cater for the limited information available.  </p>
<p>I touch briefly on a couple of points I want to highlight here.  </p>
<p><strong>The first point</strong> being the potential benefit but also risk of using Open Source integration technologies.  Put simply, open source&#8217;s core principles are very much aligned with those of integration, and as such makes an excellent candidate for the technology that glues together all of our other bits and pieces of technology.  But, as it is in it&#8217;s relative infancy, there are some potential risks.  These are rapidly being addressed technically, and given a few more years of well rounded practical implementations, many of these issues will be addressed.  Although I wont go into detail in this post, I suggest having a look at some of the open source options available, including:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sopera.com/">SOPERA</a> &#8211; very open modular design, with a strong plugin architecture, with integrations to many other software components, including Microsoft .NET &#8211; this is the product behind Eclipse Swordfish.<br />
<a href="http://www.jboss.com/products/platforms/soa/">JBoss</a> &#8211; a well known middleware/application server vendor with parent company Redhat.  A well rounded offering, though slightly immature ESB.</p>
<p>There are others (e.g. Apache FUSE), though I&#8217;ll save the details for another day &#8211; check out the above and see how it may suit your needs.</p>
<p><strong>The second point</strong> is the question of whether you are really doing pure SOA or not, or whether you&#8217;re either doing application integration (not too dissimilar in objective, but different in concept) or just &#8216;web services&#8217;.  Have a think about that&#8230; what exactly is SOA to you?  And do you think everyone else thinks the same?  Feel free to post your thoughts below&#8230;</p>
<p><em>The full Q&amp;A from linkedin here:</em><br />
http://www.linkedin.com/answers/technology/enterprise-software/TCH_ENT/441250-2894850?browseIdx=1&#038;sik=1239049806947</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/enterprisearchitecture/simple-advice-for-choosing-an-esb/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenOffice 3.0 is now available</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/openoffice-3-0-is-now-available/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/openoffice-3-0-is-now-available/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 23:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openoffice 3.0]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/10/openoffice-3-0-is-now-available/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[OpenOffice.org 3.0 is now available, but because of extreme demand you will see this message Apologies &#8211; our website is struggling to cope with the unprecedented demand for the new release 3.0 of OpenOffice.org. The technical teams are trying to come up with a solution. Thank you for your patience. So what is new? I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenOffice.org 3.0 is now available, but because of extreme demand you will see this message</p>
<blockquote><p>Apologies &#8211; our website is struggling to cope with the unprecedented<br />
demand for the new release 3.0 of OpenOffice.org. The technical teams are<br />
trying to come up with a solution.</p>
<p>Thank you for your patience.</p></blockquote>
<p>So what is new? I would like to know also but when visiting this link http://www.openoffice.org/dev_docs/features/3.0/ I am greeted with this</p>
<blockquote><p>The requested URL /dev_docs/features/3.0/ was not found on this server.</p>
<p>Additionally, a 404 Not Found error was encountered while trying to use an ErrorDocument to handle the request.<br />
Apache/2.0.46 (Red Hat) Server at lemonlime.sfo.collab.net Port 80</p></blockquote>
<p>You can download OpenOffice 3.0 here: http://www.openoffice.org/ and that link does work <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/openoffice-3-0-is-now-available/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mono 2.0 Has Been Released</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/mono-2-0-has-been-released/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/mono-2-0-has-been-released/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 00:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mono]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/10/mono-2-0-has-been-released/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Mono 2.0 Has Been Released Mono 2.0 is a portable and open source implementation of the .NET framework for Unix, Windows, MacOS and other operating systems. Some Details: Microsoft Compatible APIs ADO.NET 2.0 API for accessing databases. ASP.NET 2.0 API for developing Web-based applications. Windows.Forms 2.0 API to create desktop applications. System.XML 2.0: An API [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mono 2.0 Has Been Released</strong></p>
<p>Mono 2.0 is a portable and open source implementation of the .NET framework for Unix, Windows, MacOS and other operating systems.</p>
<p>Some Details:</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft Compatible APIs</strong><br />
ADO.NET 2.0 API for accessing databases.<br />
ASP.NET 2.0 API for developing Web-based applications.<br />
Windows.Forms 2.0 API to create desktop applications.<br />
System.XML 2.0: An API to manipulate XML documents.<br />
System.Core: Provides support for the Language Integrated Query (LINQ).<br />
System.Xml.Linq: Provides a LINQ provider for XML.<br />
System.Drawing 2.0 API: A portable graphics rendering API. </p>
<p><strong>Mono APIs </strong><br />
Gtk# 2.12: A binding to the Gtk+ 2.12 and GNOME libraries for creating desktop applications on Linux, Windows and MacOS X.<br />
Mono.Cecil: A library to manipulate ECMA CLI files (the native format used for executables and libraries).<br />
Mono.Cairo: A binding to the Cairo Graphics library to produce 2D graphics and render them into a variety of forms (images, windows, postscript and PDF).<br />
Mono&#8217;s SQLite support: a library to create and consume databases created with SQLite.<br />
Mono.Posix: a library to access Linux and Unix specific functionality from your managed application. With both a low-level interface as well as higher level interfaces. </p>
<p>Download Mono 2.0 here: http://www.go-mono.com/mono-downloads/download.html</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/mono-2-0-has-been-released/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
