<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>upgrading &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/upgrading/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL Server 2008 Upgrade Technical Reference Guide Available For Download</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-upgrade-technical-refere/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-upgrade-technical-refere/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 12:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2000]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2005]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrading]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/11/sql-server-2008-upgrade-technical-refere/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This 490-page document covers the essential phases and steps to upgrade existing instances of SQL Server 2000 and 2005 to SQL Server 2008 by using best practices. These include preparation tasks, upgrade tasks, and post-upgrade tasks. It is intended to be a supplement to SQL Server 2008 Books Online. Chapter 1 gives an overview of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This 490-page document covers the essential phases and steps to upgrade existing instances of SQL Server 2000 and 2005 to SQL Server 2008 by using best practices. These include preparation tasks, upgrade tasks, and post-upgrade tasks. It is intended to be a supplement to SQL Server 2008 Books Online.</p>
<ul>
<li>Chapter 1 gives an overview of the technical issues and decisions that are involved in an upgrade to SQL Server 2008, as well as recommendations for planning and deploying an upgrade.</li>
<li>Chapter 2 addresses issues related to upgrading to SQL Server 2008 Management Tools.</li>
<li>Chapters 3 through 8 focus on upgrade issues for SQL Server relational databases.</li>
<li>Chapter 9 addresses upgrading to SQL Server 2008 Express.</li>
<li>Chapters 10 through 14 focus on upgrading to SQL Server 2008 Business Intelligence<br />
 components: Analysis Services, Data Mining, Integration Services, and Reporting Services.</li>
<li>Chapter 15 addresses the implications of upgrading to SQL Server 2008 for other Microsoft applications and platforms.</li>
<li>Appendix 1 contains a table of allowed SQL Server 2008 version and edition upgrade paths.</li>
<li>Appendix 2 contains an upgrade planning checklist.</li>
</ul>
<p>Download it here: http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=66D3E6F5-6902-4FDD-AF75-9975AEA5BEA7&amp;displaylang=en</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-upgrade-technical-refere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
