<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>kaspersky &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/kaspersky/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Kaspersky Web Site Hacked With SQL Injection, How Embarrassing Is This?</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/kaspersky-web-site-hacked-with-sql-injec/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/kaspersky-web-site-hacked-with-sql-injec/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 12:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acunetix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaspersky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql injection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/kaspersky-web-site-hacked-with-sql-injec/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We all know that Kaspersky is a security firm and they make a very nice product, you can see a list of their products here: http://www.kaspersky.com/ What I found out today on twitter is that their site got hacked by a SQL Injection attack. The tool that was used was the Acunetix Web Security Scanner. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all know that Kaspersky  is a security firm and they make a very nice product, you can see a list of their products here: http://www.kaspersky.com/</p>
<p>What I found out today on <a href="http://twitter.com/kbriankelley/status/1195496252">twitter</a> is that their site got hacked by a SQL Injection attack. The tool that was used was the <a href="http://www.acunetix.com/">Acunetix Web Security Scanner</a>. Tools are used by admins to protect their sites but the same tools are also used by hackers to attack your site. I have written about another such tool Metasploit before here: <a href="/index.php/SysAdmins/OS/do-you-use-metasploit-to-check-if-your-s">Do you use Metasploit to check if your servers are vulnerable?</a><br />
People should really take advantage of these tools to check their own site before the hackers do. I will create a post one of these days with all the tools you can use to check for SQL attacks. </p>
<p>So what actually happened with Kaspersky? Here is what ChannelWeb had to say about this</p>
<blockquote><p>A security vulnerability in Moscow-based Kaspersky Lab&#8217;s U.S. Web site was made public after a hacker launched a SQL attack and posted listings of tables contained on the security company&#8217;s site.<br />
The hacker, known as Unu, posted screen shots as well as a list of tables Feb. 7 to a blog after hacking into the security company&#8217;s Web site via a simple SQL injection attack that allowed information to be exposed by entering secret username and password information.</p>
<p>&#8220;Kaspersky is one of the leading companies in the security and antivirus market. It seems as though they are not able to secure their own databases,&#8221; the hacker said on a hackerblog.org posting. &#8220;Alter one of the parameters and you have access to EVERYTHING: users, activation codes, lists of bugs, admins, shop, etc.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>You can read that whole article here: http://www.crn.com/security/213401972</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/kaspersky-web-site-hacked-with-sql-injec/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
