<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>nodejs &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/nodejs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Windows Azure Training Kit April 2013 Released</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/azure/windows-azure-training-kit-april/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/azure/windows-azure-training-kit-april/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hdinsight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nodejs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/04/windows-azure-training-kit-april/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Miscrosoft has released the Windows Azure Training Kit April 2013.

The Windows Azure Training Kit includes a comprehensive set of technical content designed to help you learn how to use Windows Azure. The kit includes hands-on labs, presentations, de&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/EnterpriseDev/windows_azure_small.jpg?mtime=1312531635"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/EnterpriseDev/windows_azure_small.jpg?mtime=1312531635" width="300" height="169" /></a></div>
<p>Microsoft has released the Windows Azure Training Kit April 2013.</p>
<p>The Windows Azure Training Kit includes a comprehensive set of technical content designed to help you learn how to use Windows Azure. The kit includes hands-on labs, presentations, demos, and code samples for every aspect of developing applications for Windows Azure. You can use the resources in the training kit to teach yourself or train others.</p>
<p>There have been a number of improvements in this release alongside the refresh to the Infrastructure Services content including:</p>
<p>New Presentation: Windows Azure Mobile Services and Android<br />
New Lab: Windows Azure Mobile Services and Android<br />
New Lab: Windows Azure Mobile Services and Windows Phone<br />
New Presentation: Introduction to Windows Azure HDInsight Service<br />
New Lab: Introduction to Windows Azure HDInsight<br />
Updated ITPro Content + Agenda<br />
Updated Presentations for new feature support Windows Azure Overview, Windows Azure Web Sites, Windows Azure Virtual Machines &amp; Windows Azure Mobile Services.</p>
<p><strong>Hands-on Labs</strong></p>
<p>Windows Azure Service Bus Remoting (VS2012): This hands-on lab walks you through this scenario using a sample application that replicates, albeit in a simplistic manner, the application architecture at Fictional Bank.</p>
<p>Node.js &amp; Windows Azure Web Sites (OSX): In this hands-on lab, you will learn the basics of the Windows Azure Web Sites service for Node.js applications.</p>
<p>PHP &amp; Windows Azure Web Sites (OSX): In this hands-on lab, you will explore the basic elements of the Windows Azure Web Sites service by creating a simple PHP application and deploying it using FTP deployment.</p>
<p>Windows Azure Web Sites Gallery (OSX): In this hands-on lab you will learn how to create a new web site in Windows Azure by using a template from the pre-packaged applications gallery.</p>
<p>Download it here: http://www.windowsazure.com/en-us/develop/net/other-resources/training-kit/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/azure/windows-azure-training-kit-april/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
