<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>madison &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/madison/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL Server 2008 R2 to be released in May</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-to-be-released-in-may/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-to-be-released-in-may/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 15:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/01/sql-server-2008-r2-to-be-released-in-may/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A quick post. It has just been announced, SQL Server 2008 R2 will be released in May. Customers with Software Assurance can upgrade to SQL Server 2008 R2 and take advantage of the new features without incurring additional licensing costs. I am glad I have Software Assurance so hopefully I can roll this out sometimes [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A quick post. It has just been announced,  SQL Server 2008 R2 will be released in May.</p>
<blockquote><p>Customers with Software Assurance can upgrade to SQL Server 2008 R2 and take advantage of the new features without incurring additional licensing costs.</p></blockquote>
<p>I am glad I have Software Assurance so hopefully I can roll this out sometimes this year</p>
<p>More about this announcement here: http://blogs.technet.com/dataplatforminsider/archive/2010/01/19/sql-server-2008-r2-gets-an-official-date.aspx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-to-be-released-in-may/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Server 2008 R2 November CTP Available For Download</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-november-ctp-availabl/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-november-ctp-availabl/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 18:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/11/sql-server-2008-r2-november-ctp-availabl/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week I wrote that SQL Server 2008 R2 Editions pricing has been announced, Microsoft today made availabe for download the SQL Server 2008 R2 November CTP. SQL Server 2008 R2 November CTP is available today for MSDN and TechNet subscribers and it will be available to the general public on November 11th Go to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week I wrote that <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBAdmin/MSSQLServerAdmin/sql-server-2008-r2-editions-pricing-anno">SQL Server 2008 R2 Editions pricing has been announced</a>, Microsoft today made availabe for download the SQL Server 2008 R2 November CTP. SQL Server 2008 R2 November CTP is available today for MSDN and TechNet subscribers and it will be available to the general public on November 11th</p>
<p>Go to http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/2008/en/us/R2.aspx to get more information and to download!</p>
<p>The November CTP is &#8220;feature complete&#8221; so try out the new features in this CTP release which include: </p>
<ul>
<li>Support for Windows Server 2008 R2, including Hyper-V with Live Migration </li>
<li>Enhanced data compression with support for Unicode UCS-2 </li>
<li>PowerPivot for Microsoft® Excel and Microsoft SharePoint Server * </li>
<li>Report Builder 3.0 with Report Part Gallery and new visualizations (sparklines, databars) </li>
<li>Master Data Services (MDS) </li>
</ul>
<p>Enhancements to the capabilities delivered in the August CTP:</p>
<ul>
<li>A Control Point Explorer in SQL Server Management Studio for central multi-instance and application utilization management. </li>
<li>Built-in wizards to help you quickly set up and enroll instances and Data-Tier Application components into central management. </li>
<li>Dashboard viewpoints for quick insight into application and instance utilization. </li>
<li>StreamInsight core technology engine for Complex Event Processing. </li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-november-ctp-availabl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Server 2008 R2 Editions Pricing Announced</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-editions-pricing-anno/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-editions-pricing-anno/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 12:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/11/sql-server-2008-r2-editions-pricing-anno/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has announced pricing and also what is new in the SQL Server 2008 R2 editions. First here is the pricing Editions Per Processor PricingRetail ** Per Server Plus CAL PricingRetail ** Parallel Data Warehouse $57,498 Not offered via Server CAL Datacenter $57,498 Not offered via Server CAL Enterprise $28,749 $13,969 with 25 CALs Standard [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has announced pricing and also what is new in the SQL Server 2008 R2 editions. First here is the pricing</p>
<table cellspacing="10">
<tr>
<td><strong>Editions</strong></td>
<td><strong>Per Processor PricingRetail **</strong></td>
<td><strong>Per Server Plus CAL PricingRetail **</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Parallel Data Warehouse</td>
<td>$57,498</td>
<td>Not offered via Server CAL</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Datacenter</td>
<td>$57,498</td>
<td>Not offered via Server CAL</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Enterprise</td>
<td>$28,749</td>
<td>$13,969 with 25 CALs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Standard</td>
<td>$7,499</td>
<td>$1,849 with 5 CALs</td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>I wonder how many people will go to Datacenter or Parallel Data Warehouse editions? To be fair Sybase IQ charges I believe $40K per core, SQL Server 2008 R2 is priced per socket and would still be a lot cheaper than Sybase IQ</p>
<p>Here are the other details:</p>
<h2>New Premium Editions</h2>
<p><em><br />
<strong>Datacenter</strong></p>
<p>Built on SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise, SQL Server 2008 R2 Datacenter is designed to deliver a high-performing data platform that provides the highest levels of scalability for large application workloads, virtualization and consolidation, and management for an organization’s database infrastructure. Datacenter helps enable organizations to cost effectively scale their mission-critical environment.</p>
<p><strong>Key features new to Datacenter:</strong></p>
<p>Application and Multi-Server Management for enrolling, gaining insights and managing over 25 instances<br />
Highest virtualization support for maximum ROI on consolidation and virtualization<br />
High-scale complex event processing with SQL Server StreamInsight<br />
Supports more than 8 processors and up to 256 logical processors for highest levels of scale<br />
Supports memory limits up to OS maximum</p>
<p><strong>Parallel Data Warehouse</strong></p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Parallel Data Warehouse is a highly scalable data warehouse appliance-based solution. Parallel Data Warehouse delivers performance at low cost through a massively parallel processing (MPP) architecture and compatibility with hardware partners – scale your data warehouse from tens and hundreds of terabytes to the petabyte range.</p>
<p><strong>Key features new to Parallel Data Warehouse:</strong></p>
<p>10s to 100s TBs to 1+ PB enabled by MPP architecture<br />
Advanced data warehousing capabilities like Star Join Queries and Change Data Capture<br />
Integration with SSIS, SSRS, and SSAS<br />
Supports industry standard data warehousing hub and spoke architecture and parallel database copy</p>
<p></em><br />
<h2>Investments in Core Editions</h2>
<p>This section has all the new stuff in the Enterprise and Standard editions, it claims Standard does backup compression but I believe that is only restore not the backup itself, the following URL does not mention anything about Standard Edition being able to compress backups: http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb964719.aspx</p>
<blockquote><p>Creating compressed backups is supported only in SQL Server 2008 Enterprise and later, but beginning in SQL Server 2008, every edition can restore a compressed backup.</p></blockquote>
<p><em><strong>SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise</strong></p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise delivers a comprehensive data platform that provides built-in security, availability, and scale coupled with robust business intelligence offerings—helping enable the highest service levels for mission-critical workloads.</p>
<p><strong>The following capabilities are new to Enterprise:</strong></p>
<p>PowerPivot for SharePoint to support the hosting and management of PowerPivot applications in SharePoint<br />
Application and Multi-Server Management for enrolling, gaining insights and managing up to  25 instances<br />
Master Data Services for data consistency across heterogeneous systems<br />
Data Compression now enabled with UCS-2 Unicode support</p>
<p><strong>SQL Server 2008 R2 Standard</strong></p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Standard delivers a complete data management and business intelligence platform for departments and small organizations to run their applications—helping enable effective database management with minimal IT resources.</p>
<p><strong>The following capabilities are new to Standard:</strong></p>
<p>Backup Compression to reduce data backups by up to 60% and help reduce time spent on backups *<br />
Can be managed instance for Application and Multi-Server Management capabilities</p>
<p></em><br />
You can find all that stuff on this page here: http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/2008/en/us/R2-editions.aspx</p>
<p></p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-editions-pricing-anno/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learn About SQL Server 2008 R2 Project Gemini And Project Madison By Watching These Videos</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/learn-about-sql-server-2008-r2-project-g/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/learn-about-sql-server-2008-r2-project-g/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 22:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/09/learn-about-sql-server-2008-r2-project-g/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Channel 9 has two videos up about Project Gemini And Project Madison. These two videos will give you a good overview what Gemini and Madison are all about. Both videos are available in a variety of formats Introduction to SQL Server Project Madison The SQL Server team is working on a new project code-named “Madison”. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Channel 9 has two videos up about Project Gemini And Project Madison. These two videos will give you a good overview what Gemini and Madison are all about. Both videos are available in a variety of formats</p>
<p><strong>Introduction to SQL Server Project Madison</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>The SQL Server team is working on a new project code-named “Madison”. &#8220;Madison&#8221; is a highly scalable data warehouse appliance that delivers performance at low cost through massively parallel processing (MPP). How does it work? What&#8217;s the story? Well, &#8220;Madison&#8221; Product Unit Manager Christian Kleinerman sure knows the answers and he provides an introduction to this new SQL data warehousing technology</p></blockquote>
<p>The Madison video is 27 minutes and 48 seconds and you can watch/download it here: http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/Charles/Christian-Kleinerman-Introduction-to-SQL-Server-Project-Madison/</p>
<p><strong>Inside Project Gemini</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>Office Marketing says: &#8220;Need to make timely business decisions without having to use complicated and sluggish analytical applications? Love to use Excel? Project Gemini is an Excel 2010 add-in that allows you to create powerful analyses by quickly manipulating millions of rows of data into a single Excel workbook and utilize Microsoft Office 2010 to share and collaborate on your insights with your team.&#8221;</p>
<p>Donald Farmer and Julie Strauss are Program Managers behind this new technology &#8220;Gemini&#8221;. What is &#8220;Gemini&#8221;? How does it work? Why? What&#8217;s it all really mean, anyway? </p>
<p>Tune in. Very interesting technology here. For all you spreadsheet jockeys out there, this should prove extraordinarliy useful to you when you need to crunch and analyze lots of data effeciently. Wow. 1,000,000 rows in Excel without causing a hang. Nice work, &#8220;Gemini&#8221; team!</p></blockquote>
<p>The Gemini video is 29 minutes and 17 seconds and you can watch/download it here: http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/Charles/Donald-Farmer-and-Julie-Strauss-Inside-Project-Gemini/</p>
<p></p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/learn-about-sql-server-2008-r2-project-g/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Server 2008 R2  August Community Technology Preview (CTP) Announced</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-august-community-tech/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-august-community-tech/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 12:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/08/sql-server-2008-r2-august-community-tech/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has just announced the release of the August Community Technology Preview (CTP) of SQL Server 2008 R2. You might have heard about this before when people talked about Kilimanjaro and Project Gemini.

Why should you download the CTP?

  Exp&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has just announced the release of the August Community Technology Preview (CTP) of SQL Server 2008 R2. You might have heard about this before when people talked about <em>Kilimanjaro</em> and <em>Project Gemini</em>.</p>
<p>Why should you download the CTP?</p>
<ul>
<li>Explore the enhanced database management capabilities in SQL Server Management Studio.</li>
<li>Preview SQL Server StreamInsight, Microsoft’s new complex event processing technology</li>
<li>Be the first in your organization to run SQL Server on more than 64 processor cores.</li>
<li>Provide early feedback to the development team.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 August Community Technology Preview (CTP)<br />
includes Application and Multi-server Management which will help<br />
organizations manage database environments efficiently at scale with<br />
increased visibility and control across the application lifecycle. Also<br />
included is Report Builder 3.0 with support for geospatial visualization<br />
(mapping, routing, custom shapes) which can help produce new insights and<br />
discoveries well beyond what can be achieved with standard tables and charts<br />
when geospatial data is combined with business information. Microsoft® SQL<br />
Server® StreamInsight will also be made available for Community Technology<br />
Preview in the coming weeks. This new complex event processing technology<br />
will help businesses derive better insights by correlating event streams<br />
from multiple sources with near-zero latency.</p>
<p>Learn more about SQL Server 2008 R2 here: http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/2008/en/us/r2.aspx</p>
<p><a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/evalcenter/ee315247.aspx">Download</a> the SQL Server 2008 R2 August CTP<br />
Available on August 10th to TechNet/MSDN Subscribers and on August 12th to the general public</p>
<p>The download link does not work yet but will be available very soon. You can also find it in MSDN under Updated Products&#8211;>SQL Server 2008, here is what is available<br />
<em>SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise Evaluation (x86) &#8211; (English)<br />
1,249.31 (MB)</p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise Evaluation (x64) &#8211; (English)<br />
1,350.25 (MB)</p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise Evaluation (ia64) &#8211; (English)<br />
1,334.92 (MB)</p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Express Edition CTP (x86 and x64 WoW) &#8211; (English)<br />
100.76 (MB)</p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Express Edition CTP (x64) &#8211; (English)<br />
113.46 (MB)</p>
<p>SQL Server 2008 R2 Express Edition CTP (x86) &#8211; (English)<br />
86.33 (MB)</em></p>
<p>There is a lot more coming, from the <a href="http://blogs.technet.com/dataplatforminsider/archive/2009/08/10/download-sql-server-2008-r2-august-ctp-today.aspx">SQL Server news blog</a></p>
<blockquote><p>SQL Server 2008 R2 August CTP is only the first in a string of CTPs launching this month. In the coming weeks we’ll also launch CTPs for low latency complex event processing now called StreamInsight, the first CTP for SQL Azure Database, a limited preview of Project “Gemini” Excel and SharePoint add-ins and a private technology preview of Project Madison, Microsoft’s massively scalable data warehousing solution, with a select group of customers. Stay tuned to this page, where we’ll be announcing new CTPs as they become available.</p>
<p>We’re very excited about the progress toward the big launch of SQL Server 2008 R2 next year and are looking forward to your feedback to help us get there!</p></blockquote>
<p>Make sure to check out the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb500435(SQL.105).aspx">SQL Server 2008 R2 Books Online (August CTP)</a> which has information what is new in this release.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc645579(SQL.105).aspx">SQL Server 2008 R2 Books Online (August CTP)</a></p>
<blockquote><p>Creating a SQL Server utility control point (UCP): Install a single instance of the SQL Server 2008 R2 Database Engine and then promote it to be the UCP. The UCP is the central repository for configuration and performance data collected for all the instances enrolled in the SQL Server Utility. The UCP is the central reasoning point for the SQL Server Utility. It supports actions such as applying central policies, or analyzing resource utilization trends of an instance to predict when it might exceed central resource utilization polices.</p></blockquote>
<p>You can find more info in the link above about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Overview of SQL Server Utility.</li>
<li>How to: Create a SQL Server Utility Control Point (SQL Server Utility).</li>
<li>How to: Enroll an Instance of SQL Server (SQL Server Utility).</li>
<li>Monitoring Instances of SQL Server in the SQL Server Utility.</li>
</ul>
<p>Also mentioned is Data-Tier Application</p>
<p><strong>Data-Tier Application</strong><br />
A data-tier application (DAC) simplifies the development, deployment, and management of the data-tier objects that support a multi-tier or client-server application. A DAC defines all of the Database Engine schema and instance objects, such as tables, views, and logins, required to support the application. The DAC operates as a single unit of management through the development, deployment, and management lifecycle of the associated application. The DAC also contains policies that define the deployment prerequisites for the DAC.</p>
<p></p>
<p>*** <strong>If you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-2008-r2-august-community-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
