<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>bids &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/bids/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL 2014 CTP1, where is my BIDS?</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/sql-2014-ctp1-where-is/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/sql-2014-ctp1-where-is/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ctp1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2014]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server data tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssdt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssdtbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/06/sql-2014-ctp1-where-is/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh wait sorry, I meant SSDT. Or was it SSDTBI? To avoid confusion about the developer tool to create BI solutions, Microsoft has changed its name a few times. You know, to make it less confusing. Here’s a nice overview:

BIDS or Business Intelligence&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Oh wait sorry, I meant SSDT. Or was it SSDTBI? To avoid confusion about the developer tool to create BI solutions, Microsoft has changed its name a few times. You know, to make it less confusing. Here’s a nice overview:</p>
<ul style="margin-left:20pt;list-style-position:outside;text-align: justify;">
<li><em>BIDS or Business Intelligence Development Studio.</em> The most non-confusing name of the bunch. This piece of software was delivered to you when you installed SQL Server 2005, SQL Server 2008 or SQL Server 2008 R2.</li>
<li><em>SSDT or SQL Server Data Tools. </em>Introduced with SQL Server 2012. However, you have a tool with the same name for creating database projects, which you had to download and install separately (don’t get me started on which names this tool had before. Mildly schizophrenic to say the least.) This development environment uses the Visual Studio 2010 shell and you use it to build BI solutions solely for SQL Server 2012. So two tools with the same name. One for database projects, one for BI projects. One to download, one that came with the SQL Server install media. Enter confusion. Read more about it on the blog of Jamie Thomson (<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jamie_thomson/default.aspx">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/jamiet">twitter</a>): <a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jamie_thomson/archive/2013/01/16/more-ssdt-naming-confusion.aspx">More SSDT naming confusion</a>. Also read his blog posts about the database project part of SSDT, they are mighty interesting.</li>
<li><em>SSDTBI or SQL Server Data Tools – Business Intelligence</em>. In an effort to swiftly put a stop to all this confusion, SSDTBI was <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/analysisservices/archive/2013/03/06/sql-server-data-tools-business-intelligence-for-visual-studio-2012-released-online.aspx">released with Visual Studio 2012</a>. It’s basically still BIDS – or SSDT from the SQL Server installation media – but now with BI appended to make its purpose more clear. This environment uses the Visual Studio 2012 shell obviously, but is still used to create BI solutions for SQL Server 2012. Great deal of fun when you have two developers on the same project: one with SSDT (Visual Studio 2010) and one with SSDTBI (Visual Studio 2012).</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Each tool exists in two flavors: either you already have Visual Studio and the BI templates are installed into your existing installation, or you don’t have Visual Studio and SQL Server install a shell for you, only capable of creating BI solutions. Less confusing now? OK, let’s move on to the real point of this blog post: which development environment do we use in SQL Server 2014 CTP1? (Which is <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/sqlserver/sql-server-2014.aspx">just released</a> in case you missed it)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">When we start up the installation of SQL Server 2014 (try downloading the VHD with Windows Server 2012 R2 to get you quickly up to speed. I absolutely recommend it), we do not see any BI development tool mentioned in the feature list.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/featureselection.png?mtime=1372362887"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/featureselection.png?mtime=1372362887" alt="" width="858" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">But when we take a look at the prerequisites that are going to be installed, we see the Visual Studio 2010 Shell listed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/readytoinstall.png?mtime=1372363033"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/readytoinstall.png?mtime=1372363033" alt="" width="655" height="557" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">However, this is most likely the shell for SQL Server Management Studio and not for any kind of BI tool. The start menu confirms our suspicion after the installation:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/startmenu.png?mtime=1372362887"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/startmenu.png?mtime=1372362887" alt="" width="910" height="632" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">No BIDS, SSDT or SSDTBI to be seen. But how do we develop our BI solutions in SQL Server 2014 CTP1? Don’t they want us to test SSIS, SSAS or SSRS? Is it only about Hekaton and the updateable columnstore index in this release? Luckily no. When we dig a bit in the MSDN documentation, we find the following quote in the </span><a style="text-align: justify;" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb522628(v=sql.120).aspx">What&#8217;s New in Analysis Services and Business Intelligence</a><span style="text-align: justify;"> page:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>SQL Server Data Tools for Business Intelligence (SSDT BI), previously known as Business Intelligence Development Studio (BIDS), is used to create Analysis Services models, Reporting Services reports, and Integration Services packages. In this pre-release version of SQL Server 2014, SQL Server Setup no longer installs SSDT BI. The Visual Studio 2012 version of SSDT BI is now available as a web download from the Microsoft Download center.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/We-need-to-go-deeper_inception.jpg?mtime=1372362887"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/We-need-to-go-deeper_inception.jpg?mtime=1372362887" alt="" width="400" height="226" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">The point here is, aside from the fact that they forgot to mention SSDTBI was previously known as SSDT before it was previously known as BIDS (inception!), is that you have to download the tool yourself, just as you did for SQL Server 2012 if you wanted to play with the Visual Studio 2012 version. And you can find it </span><a style="text-align: justify;" href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=36843">here</a><span style="text-align: justify;">. It’s only a mere 783MB.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/downloadsize.png?mtime=1372362886"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/downloadsize.png?mtime=1372362886" alt="" width="959" height="45" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">My guess is that a later version of SQL Server 2014 will install some version of the BI development environment. I don’t know how it will be called –most likely still SSDTBI – or if it will be Visual Studio 2012 or Visual Studio 2013. It does mean however that SQL Server 2014 CTP1 has no new BI features for the moment, as you are using the exact same development environment as in SQL Server 2012. Maybe new features are added in a later release of SQL Server 2014, who knows?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One small piece of advice to finish of this blog post: when installing SSDTBI, choose <em>Perform a new installation of SQL Server 2012</em>, not the other one (and ignore the fact you are actually developing for SQL Server 2014).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/setup_ssdtBI_1.png?mtime=1372362887"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/setup_ssdtBI_1.png?mtime=1372362887" alt="" width="569" height="427" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">All the features will be selected for you.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/setup_ssdtBI_2.png?mtime=1372362887"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/setup_ssdtBI_2.png?mtime=1372362887" alt="" width="574" height="435" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">And after the installation, you can finally make some BI solutions on SQL Server 2014!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/ssdtbi_3.png?mtime=1372362887"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SQL2014BIDS/ssdtbi_3.png?mtime=1372362887" alt="" width="750" height="459" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/sql-2014-ctp1-where-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where are the Data Sources and Data Source Views in SSIS 2012?</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/where-are-the-data-sources/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/where-are-the-data-sources/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Axel Achten (axel8s)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connection manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data source view]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server data tools]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/03/where-are-the-data-sources/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I'm still preparing to teach a MS6235A SSIS training I use a SQL 2012 RTM environment to test the demo's. One of the demo's is to show how a Connection Manager is made based on a Data Source View. In BIDS 2008 the Data Sources and Data Source View&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I&#8217;m still preparing to teach a <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/learning/en/us/course.aspx?ID=6235A&amp;locale=en-us">MS6235A SSIS training</a> I use a SQL 2012 RTM environment to test the demo&#8217;s. One of the demo&#8217;s is to show how a Connection Manager is made based on a Data Source View. In BIDS 2008 the Data Sources and Data Source Views are found in the Solution Explorer:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV1.png?mtime=1332152100"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV1.png?mtime=1332152100" width="165" height="157" /></a></div>
<p>To create a new Data Source you right click on the Data Source folder and follow the wizard:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV2.png?mtime=1332152402"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV2.png?mtime=1332152402" width="280" height="177" /></a></div>
<p>Next you would make a Data Source View based on the Data Source just created by right clicking on the Data Source View folder and again following the instructions:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV3.png?mtime=1332152786"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV3.png?mtime=1332152786" width="297" height="188" /></a></div>
<p>In the screen that pop&#8217;s up you get the list of available Data Sources and after selecting one the Connection Manager is created.<br />
The last step is to create the Connection Manager that will be based on the Data Source. This is accomplished by right clicking in the Connection Manager pane and by selecting &#8220;New Connection From Data Source&#8230;&#8221;:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV4.png?mtime=1332153238"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV4.png?mtime=1332153238" width="694" height="363" /></a></div>
<p>To use the Data Source View a &#8220;Data Flow Task&#8221; must be created and in the task an &#8220;OLE DB Source&#8221; is used. When configuring the OLD DB Source you can finally refer to the Data Source View:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV6.png?mtime=1332160446"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV6.png?mtime=1332160446" width="190" height="117" /></a></div>
<p>Now when I try the same scenario with the new &#8220;SQL Server Data Tools&#8221; you can immediatly see that there are no Data Sources and Data Source Views in the solution explorer:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV7.png?mtime=1332165228"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV7.png?mtime=1332165228" width="207" height="174" /></a></div>
<p>What you can see is a Connection Managers folder. Right clicking the folder gives me the option to create a new Connection Manager. In the wizard I connect to my AdventureWorks2012 database and when I complete the wizard my Solution Explorer shows the new Connection Manager:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV8.png?mtime=1332166288"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV8.png?mtime=1332166288" width="209" height="235" /></a></div>
<p>But more important when you look at the Connection Managers pane in the package itself you&#8217;ll see that there is a &#8220;(project)ConnectionManagerName&#8221; added to the package:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV9.png?mtime=1332166495"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/DSV9.png?mtime=1332166495" width="241" height="58" /></a></div>
<p>And this Connection Manager can be used from within an OLE DB Source control.<br />
So with the new Data Tools for SQL Server 2012 it looks like we&#8217;ve lost the Data Source Views for SSIS projects. But creating Data Sources in the project scope stays possible altough it&#8217;s now renamed to Connection Managers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/where-are-the-data-sources/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t install Denali BIDS side by side with a 2008 instance</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/don-t-install-denali-bids-side-by-side-w/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/don-t-install-denali-bids-side-by-side-w/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 16:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ctp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[database]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server denali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/11/don-t-install-denali-bids-side-by-side-w/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you already have a SQL Server 2008 or a SQL Server 2008 R2 instance then do not install SQL Server Denali as a named instance. If you do so then your current SSIS development environment will be broken. There is a reason there are virtual machines, I&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you already have a SQL Server 2008 or a SQL Server 2008 R2 instance then do not install SQL Server Denali as a named instance. If you do so then your current SSIS development environment will be broken. There is a reason there are virtual machines, I recommend using <a href="http://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox</a></p>
<p>With CTP1 of Denali, BIDS is still based on Visual Studio 2008, in a later version it will use the 2010 shell.</p>
<p>Anyway if you do install Denali as a named instance this is what happens when you try to create a new SSIS project</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5151504623/" title="Denali SSIS Error by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1079/5151504623_2289d67254.jpg" width="481" height="201" alt="Denali SSIS Error" /></a></p>
<p>Here is the text</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;<br />
Microsoft Visual Studio<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;<br />
&#8216;C:UsersDenisAppDataLocalTemptemp.dtproj&#8217; cannot be opened because its project type (.dtproj) is not supported by this version of the application. </p>
<p>To open it, please use a version that supports this type of project.<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;<br />
OK   Help<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Here is also a small video I created</p>
[video:youtube:hdNeTWHiwW0]
<p>Click on the <a href="/index.php/All/sql+server+denali:">SQL Server Denali</a> tag to see all our SQL Server Denali related posts</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/don-t-install-denali-bids-side-by-side-w/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Screenshots of the new look and feel of BIDS in Denali</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/screenshots-of-the-new-look-and-feel-of/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/screenshots-of-the-new-look-and-feel-of/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 16:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ctp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[database]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server denali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/11/screenshots-of-the-new-look-and-feel-of/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you are installing SQL Server Denali CTP 1 on a computer which already has SQL Server 2008 or 2008 R2 installed, please read: Don’t install Denali BIDS side by side with a 2008 instance. For CTP 1 BIDS is still based on VS 2008 once they switch to 2010 this won&#8217;t be a problem. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you are installing SQL Server Denali CTP 1 on a computer which already has SQL Server 2008 or 2008 R2 installed, please read: <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DataDesign/don-t-install-denali-bids-side-by-side-w">Don’t install Denali BIDS side by side with a 2008 instance</a>. For CTP 1 BIDS is still based on VS 2008 once they switch to 2010 this won&#8217;t be a problem.</p>
<p>The first thing you will notice is that the icons are new, here is just a simple package that shows some of these icons<br />
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5152114618/" title="SSIS Designer by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1222/5152114618_da34b86292.jpg" width="500" height="445" alt="SSIS Designer" /></a></p>
<p>The toolbox will show you different icons depending on where you are in the designer. If you are in the data flow task you will see these icons, I have split int into 2 images because I couldn&#8217;t fit it on my laptop screen<br />
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5151504507/" title="SSIS ToolBox DataFlow 1 by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1252/5151504507_e6e261b18a.jpg" width="286" height="465" alt="SSIS ToolBox DataFlow 1" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5152114600/" title="SSIS ToolBox DataFlow 2 by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4054/5152114600_9bdede35b2.jpg" width="272" height="490" alt="SSIS ToolBox DataFlow 2" /></a></p>
<p>If you are in a control flow you will see these icons<br />
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5152114558/" title="SSIS ToolBox ControlFlow by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4019/5152114558_954e792f53.jpg" width="239" height="500" alt="SSIS ToolBox ControlFlow" /></a></p>
<p>Click on the <a href="/index.php/All/sql+server+denali:">SQL Server Denali</a> tag to see all our SQL Server Denali related posts</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/screenshots-of-the-new-look-and-feel-of/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
