<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Hardware and Infrastructure Design &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>MSDN giveaway winners</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-giveaway-winners/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-giveaway-winners/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 15:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware and Infrastructure Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msdn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raffle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/07/msdn-giveaway-winners/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The winners of the MSDN Ultimate subscriptions are Emtucifor and Shawson. Originally we were going to select the winner based on comments, we also only had one subscription. Then Ted Krueger donated one of his subscriptions, there was only one comment t&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The winners of the MSDN Ultimate subscriptions are <a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=71">Emtucifor</a> and <a href="http://www.shawson.co.uk/codeblog">Shawson</a>. Originally we were going to select the winner based on comments, we also only had one subscription. Then Ted Krueger donated one of his subscriptions, there was only one comment that stood out and it was Emtucifor&#8217;s. The comment is below</p>
<blockquote><p>I have always dreamed of owning my own software company. A few years back I started doing some database development on the side, but then I got married, had a son, and began having some health challenges which together halted what I&#8217;d been doing.</p>
<p>But there is a special opportunity coming to me this Saturday to get back into the swing of things: my wife and son will be leaving the country for six weeks. I had already been planning to devote myself to developing one of many application ideas, but now:</p>
<p>1) I would use MSDN Ultimate Subscription to build a secure server/file transfer/fetching/archiving/processing/reconciling/user worklist managing/cross-platform system (uncannily and quite coincidentally, exactly what is desperately needed at a company I know). It will help other people&#8217;s lives in several ways: filling a need that many companies are bound to have and for a low price (as initially I will need to build market presence more than profit); increasing the number of small software development businesses out there, proving again that it can be done and providing inspiration for the masses; getting a family&#8217;s Dad home so he can spend more time with them. If it helps, I&#8217;ll blog about the development and growth of my application and business.</p>
<p>2) The functionality I would use that is unique to VS Ultimate is Architecture and Modeling. I believe in &#8220;starting the way you mean to finish.&#8221; So even though I&#8217;ll be a one-man shop at first, that means test-driven design, agile development, automated regression testing, version control, good backups, and all the infrastructure needed to hire employees when the time comes without having to change much. I&#8217;ll be eager to add the layer diagramming abilities of VS Ultimate to this mix.</p>
<p>3. Blogs and technical community activity:</p>
<p>/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&#038;author=71<br />
http://stackoverflow.com/users/57611/emtucifor<br />
http://tek-tips.com/userinfo.cfm?member=emtucifor<br />
http://squaredthoughts.blogspot.com/ (a bit out of date but still representative of my work)<br />
not to mention http://forum.lessthandot.com/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;u=98</p></blockquote>
<p>Not only did we think that the comment was good but apparently someone else as well, he actually used parts of it as his own in Andy Leonard&#8217;s giveaway here: http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andy_leonard/archive/2010/07/03/a-visual-studio-2010-msdn-seeding-card-giveaway-contest.aspx</p>
<p>We decided to raffle of the other subscription by vote..so I already started to put the polls together. During that time David Taylor left a great comment</p>
<blockquote><p>1) Why do you need this &#8211; Because I am a poor, seriously underpaid SQL Server 2008 DBA/Developer who can&#8217;t even afford VS2010 Pro!<br />
What are you going to build with this &#8211; I am going to build practice apps to learn from, as I am relatively new to development<br />
will it help other people&#8217;s lives? It is my hope that training myself will get me into a job in which I am helping other people.</p>
<p>2) What specific functionality that is only part of Ultimate are you going to use? &#8211; Architecture Explorer</p>
<p>3) You need to have a technical blog and provide the URL to that blog, if you are an active member of the technical community (stackoverflow, msdn forums etc etc) then also include those links. &#8211; http://dyfhid.wordpress.com./ Also, I am the Volunteer Coordinator for PASS&#8217; APplication Development Virtual Chapter, located at http://appdev.sqlpass.org/</p></blockquote>
<p>Now we had a dilemma, do we yank the poll and give the award to David or not? We proceeded with the poll. Wouldn&#8217;t you know it, David won Andy&#8217;s contest, because of that I emailed him and we decided that he wouldn&#8217;t be eligible here.</p>
<p>Here are the results of the final poll: http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=121&amp;t=11550</p>
<p>Congratulations to both winners, hopefully they will let us know in a couple of months if this has indeed made their developer life easier</p>
<p>Congratulations again from all of us at Lessthandot.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-giveaway-winners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Final vote for the MSDN giveaway</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/final-vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/final-vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 10:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware and Infrastructure Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msdn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raffle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/07/final-vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are giving away 2 MSDN ultimate subscriptions, for the original announcement see here: MSDN Ultimate Subscription giveaway

We did not include David Taylor because he won this morning at sqlblog: http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andy_leonard/archive/2010/0&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are giving away 2 MSDN ultimate subscriptions, for the original announcement see here: <a href="/index.php/Architect/HardwareInfrastructureDesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway">MSDN Ultimate Subscription giveaway</a></p>
<p>We did not include David Taylor because he won this morning at sqlblog: http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andy_leonard/archive/2010/07/09/and-the-winner-is.aspx and he was fine with us taking him off.</p>
<p>Here are the 6 finalist, I picked the top 3 from each group that people had a chance to vote on: http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=121&amp;t=11533 and http://forum.lessthandot.com/posting.php?mode=edit&amp;f=121&amp;p=56403</p>
<p>This vote will end in 3 hours, at noon Eastern Standard Time (GMT -5)<br />
Here are the candidates and their replies</p>
<p><strong>Shawson</strong><br />
1) I will build games with it. I am getting into indie game development with a view to moving from my current profession of web development into games development. I&#8217;m just completing a browser game using just javascript and the new html5 media and canvas elements, to see whats possible in the near future without flash! So i will be using it for c# xna, as well as javascript and html. I also wish to do some work with the new odata stuff, to deal with the highscores, as well as a chance to use the latest iteration of the entity framework. </p>
<p>2) The historical debugger would be awesome, especially when debugging realtime code which is changing all the time, as you see in game loops. I&#8217;m also interested to see the designer tools letting you visually build systems with UML and have the basic structural code generated for you. </p>
<p>3) http://www.shawson.co.uk/codeblog<br />
http://8weekgame.shawson.co.uk/<br />
http://stackoverflow.com/users/192305/shawson</p>
<p><strong>Roger Pence</strong><br />
1. I need this subscription to help me simplify healthcare-related software. Simpler software is easier to use correctly. Improve record keeping improves lives.<br />
2. Better ALM, Architecture and Modeling, and DB support would help make me a better developer.<br />
3. http://rogerpence.com/blog</p>
<p><strong>Naomi</strong><br />
/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&#038;author=218<br />
http://beyondrelational.com/blogs/naomi/archive/2010/03/22/why-left-join-doesn-t-bring-all-records-from-the-left-table.aspx</p>
<p>Active answerer at many technical sites:</p>
<p>MSDN<br />
ASP.NET/Forums<br />
universalthread.com<br />
tek-ips.com</p>
<p><strong>Dave Ballantyne</strong><br />
1) I am now running my a user group ( http://sqlsocialkent20100818.eventbrite.com/) , so would like to speak with more authority about DataDude and such issues.<br />
2) Intellitrace looks good as do the architecture components.<br />
3) http://sqlblogcasts.com/blogs/sqlandthelike/ , active in SqlServerCentral and msdn online forums, User groups twitter, fingers cross for a session at SqlBits</p>
<p><strong>dennydotnet</strong><br />
1. I am working on a startup idea. Currently using ASP.NET MVC 1, VS 2008. Would love to move up to VS 2010 / .NET 4 and latest MVC version. Idea is around helping people find great deals on products/services.</p>
<p>2. I could certainly use the feature packs / architecture / modeling tools and the latest Visual Studio 2010. I&#8217;d also be interested in playing with Expression Studio Ultimate. Any Windows Phone 7 stuff (if available) would be nice to experiment with as well.</p>
<p>3. http://www.dennydotnet.com/<br />
http://stackoverflow.com/users/113474/dennydotnet<br />
http://forums.asp.net/members/superghost.aspx</p>
<p><strong>Meile Zetstra</strong><br />
1) I&#8217;m currently running VS2010 Premium, but it just lacks the of all the architectural stuff that&#8217;s in the Ultimate version. I&#8217;d use that to build some tooling or VS extension that revolves arround code inspection, code reflection and generations of diagrams from existing assemblies.</p>
<p>2) The architecture and modeling stuff. Also the use of the just released Visualization and Modeling Feature Pack is on my wish-to-use list.</p>
<p>3) My blog: http://blogger.xs4all.nl/mzetstra<br />
http://sequenceviz.codeplex.com/</p>
<p><strong>You can vote here: http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=121&amp;t=11550</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/final-vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vote for the MSDN giveaway winner</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway-winner/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway-winner/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 15:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware and Infrastructure Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msdn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raffle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/07/vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway-winner/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As you might know we are giving away 2 MSDN ultimate subscriptions, for the original announcement see here: MSDN Ultimate Subscription giveaway

We decided on one of the winners already, for the other winner I decided to pull a Pontius Pilate on you s&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As you might know we are giving away 2 MSDN ultimate subscriptions, for the original announcement see here: <a href="/index.php/Architect/HardwareInfrastructureDesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway">MSDN Ultimate Subscription giveaway</a></p>
<p>We decided on one of the winners already, for the other winner I decided to pull a Pontius Pilate on you so that nobody can blame me that they didn&#8217;t win&#8230;.yes I know it sounds like a  cop out&#8230;that is because it is&#8230;and this is more fun.</p>
<p>Here is what I did..I picked the 20 best answers and put them in 2 groups of 10. In each group 3 people will advance to a final vote, you can vote for two people. The results of those two polls will be looked at tomorrow morning around 9 AM EST and then a new poll will be created with the final 6 contestants.</p>
<p>Make sure that you look at every person&#8217;s answer, also check their links so that you can decide who should advance.</p>
<p>The group A people can be found here: http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=121&amp;t=11533<br />
The group B people can be found here: http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=121&amp;t=11532</p>
<p>Good luck everyone</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway-winner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MSDN Ultimate Subscription giveaway +1</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway-2/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Designing Multi-Application Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Designing Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware and Infrastructure Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information and Integration Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Introduction to Architecture and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msdn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual studio 2010]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/07/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway-2/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was fortunate enough to receive MSDN Ultimate Subscriptions as well as SQLDenis.  I Think Denis's idea and contest to see who we can give these to is excellent.  To support Denis and his idea, I'm adding another subscription that will be handed over once we read over the responses.  That means your chances just got much better to enjoy the subscriptions and the benefits Visual Studio 2010 has to offer!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/Architect/msdn_notforresale.gif" alt="" title="" width="250" height="145" align="left" /></div>
<p>I was fortunate enough to receive MSDN Ultimate Subscriptions as well as SQLDenis (<a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=4">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/denisgobo/">Twitter</a>).  I Think Denis&#8217;s idea and contest to see who we can give these to is excellent.  To support Denis and his idea, I&#8217;m adding another subscription that will be handed over once we read over the responses.  That means your chances just got much better to enjoy the subscriptions and the benefits Visual Studio 2010 has to offer!</p>
<p>
</p>
<p>To go over what the response should consist of again…</p>
<ol>
<li>Why do you need this, what are you going to build with this, will it help other people&#8217;s lives?</li>
<li>What specific functionality that is only part of Ultimate are you going to use?</li>
<li>You need to have a technical blog and provide the URL to that blog, if you are an active member of the technical community (stackoverflow, msdn forums etc etc) then also include those links.</li>
</ol>
<p>Leave a comment <a href="/index.php/Architect/HardwareInfrastructureDesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway">here</a>, you will also have to join the forums, that way I will have your email to contact you and I will able to ask you questions about your answers if needed. I created a thread in the forums here: http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=121&amp;t=11456</p>
<blockquote><p><span class="MT_red">Note: Click, <a href="/index.php/Architect/HardwareInfrastructureDesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway">here</a> to leave your comment on the original blog post and add a comment to the forums to indicate you have done so.  Do not put your comment on this blog post</span></p></blockquote>
<p><i>And as in the original blog post, the results will be judged by the LessThanDot owners/management group</i></p>
<p>
These MSDN Subscriptions are more than just something you will leave to start playing with 6 months from now.  I can honestly say, even with the price tag they come with retail on the shelf, they are worth it.  The Visual Studio and .NET Framework product team are really outdoing themselves this time by sending these out to us so we can find community members that will really take advantage of them.
</p>
<p><strong>Good luck and I look forward to reading your responses!</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MSDN Ultimate Subscription giveaway</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 10:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware and Infrastructure Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msdn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/07/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft was kind enough to give me 3 MSDN Ultimate Subscriptions. I gave two of these away already, I have one left for the readers of Lessthandot.com.

Update 
Ted Krueger decided to add one of his, so now there will be two that we will be giving&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4756881779/" title="MSDN Ultimate subscriptions by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4094/4756881779_5f96a7d626.jpg" width="457" height="298" alt="MSDN Ultimate subscriptions" /></a></p>
<p>Microsoft was kind enough to give me 3 MSDN Ultimate Subscriptions. I gave two of these away already, I have one left for the readers of Lessthandot.com.</p>
<p><strong>Update<br />
<a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=68">Ted Krueger</a> decided to add one of his, so now there will be two that we will be giving away&#8230;&#8230;that just doubled your chances  </strong></p>
<p><strong>Update 2<br />
This is now closed, but you can vote for the winner, see here for details: <a href="/index.php/Architect/HardwareInfrastructureDesign/vote-for-the-msdn-giveaway-winner">Vote for the MSDN giveaway winner</a></strong></p>
<p>The list price for this is $11,899, you can see what is all included here: http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/en-us/products/2010-editions/ultimate  You get pretty much everything that Microsoft makes in terms of software. This is a one year subscription and is not restricted to the US only, so if you live outside the US then you can also enter to win.</p>
<p>So what do you need to do to win this? Here is the deal, you will have to answer 3 question in order to win this.</p>
<p>1) Why do you need this, what are you going to build with this, will it help other people&#8217;s lives?<br />
2) What specific functionality that is only part of Ultimate are you going to use?<br />
3) You need to have a technical blog and provide the URL to that blog, if you are an active member of the technical community (stackoverflow, msdn forums etc etc) then also include those links.</p>
<p>Leave a comment here, you will also have to join the forums, that way I will have your email to contact you and I will able to ask you questions about your answers if needed. I created a thread in the forums here: http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=121&amp;t=11456</p>
<p><em>BTW owners/management of Lessthandot are not allowed to enter this giveaway, they will however judge who will get this.</em></p>
<p>We will pick a winner Friday July 9th and announce it in a blog post.</p>
<p>Good luck</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/msdn-ultimate-subscription-giveaway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patterns And Practices Application Architecture Guide 2.0, Something Everyone Should Read</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/patterns-and-practices-application-archi/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/patterns-and-practices-application-archi/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 11:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware and Infrastructure Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheat sheets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design patterns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/03/patterns-and-practices-application-archi/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was listening to show number 426 on dotnetrocks: Rob Boucher on Application Architecture Guidance! They mentioned the Patterns And Practices Application Architecture Guide 2.0, this guide is available for free on codeplex.

Although it is a Microsof&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was listening to show number 426 on dotnetrocks: <a href="http://www.dotnetrocks.com/default.aspx?showNum=426">Rob Boucher on Application Architecture Guidance!</a> They mentioned the <a href="http://www.codeplex.com/AppArchGuide">Patterns And Practices Application Architecture Guide 2.0</a>, this guide is available for free on codeplex.</p>
<p>Although it is a Microsoft technology centric guide, there should be chapters for every developer in your group.<br />
Here is one example from the book</p>
<h3>
Key Design Principles<br />
</h3>
<p>When getting started with your design, bear in mind the key principles that will help you to create architecture that meets “best practices,” minimizes costs and maintenance requirements, and promotes usability and extendibility. The key principles are:
<ul>
<li><b>Separation of concerns</b>. Break your application into distinct features that overlap in functionality as little as possible.</li>
<li><b>Single Responsibility Principle</b>. Each component or a module should be responsible for only a specific feature or functionality.</li>
<li><b>Principle of least knowledge</b>.** A component or an object should not know about internal details of other components or objects. Also known as the Law of Demeter** (LoD).</li>
<li><b>Don’t Repeat Yourself (DRY)</b>. There should be only one component providing a specific functionality; the functionality should not be duplicated in any other component.</li>
<li><b>Avoid doing a big design upfront</b>. If your application requirements are unclear, or if there is a possibility of the design evolving over time, avoid making a large design effort prematurely. This design principle is often abbreviated as BDUF. </li>
<li><b>Prefer composition over inheritance</b>. Wherever possible, use composition over inheritance when reusing functionality because inheritance increases the dependency between parent and child classes, thereby limiting the reuse of child classes.</li>
</ul>
<p>The nice thing is that each chapter has a resource section at the bottom so that you can dive deep into a specific topic mentioned in the chapter itself. This is great stuff and I recommend that you check out this guide. You also might want to listen to the dotnetrocks podcast about this guide: http://www.dotnetrocks.com/default.aspx?showNum=426</p>
<p>Here is a list of all the chapters, make sure you check out the cheat sheets</p>
<h3>
Chapters<br />
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Introduction%20V2&amp;referringTitle=Home">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Architecture%20and%20Design%20Solutions%20At%20a%20Glance&amp;referringTitle=Home">Architecture and Design Solutions At a Glance</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Fast%20Track&amp;referringTitle=Home">Fast Track</a></li>
</ul>
<h4>
Part I, Fundamentals<br />
</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%201%20-%20Architecture%20Fundamentals&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 1 &#8211; Fundamentals of Application Architecture </a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=.NET%20Platform%20Overview%20V2&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 2 &#8211; .NET Platform Overview</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%203%20-%20Architecture%20and%20Design%20Guidelines&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 3 &#8211; Architecture and Design Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
<h4>
Part II, Design<br />
</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%204%20-%20Designing%20Your%20Architecture&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 4 &#8211; Designing Your Architecture</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%205%20-%20Deployment%20Patterns&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 5 &#8211; Deployment Patterns</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%206%20-%20Architectural%20Styles&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 6 &#8211; Architectural Styles</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%207%20-%20Quality%20Attributes&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 7 &#8211; Quality Attributes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%208%20-%20Communication%20Guidelines&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 8 &#8211; Communication Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
<h4>
Part III, Layers<br />
</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%209%20-%20Layers%20and%20Tiers&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 9 &#8211; Layers and Tiers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2010%20-%20Presentation%20Layer%20Guidelines&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 10 &#8211; Presentation Layer Guidelines</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2011%20-%20Business%20Layer%20Guidelines&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 11 &#8211; Business Layer Guidelines</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2012%20-%20Data%20Access%20Layer%20Guidelines&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 12 &#8211; Data Access Layer Guidelines</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2013%20-%20Service%20Layer%20Guidelines&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 13 &#8211; Service Layer Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
<h4>
Part IV, Archetypes<br />
</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2014%20-%20Application%20Archetypes&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 14 &#8211; Application Archetypes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2015%20-%20Web%20Applications&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 15 &#8211; Web Applications</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2016%20-%20Rich%20Internet%20Applications%20%28RIA%29&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 16 &#8211; Rich Internet Applications (RIA)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2017%20-%20Rich%20Client%20Applications&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 17 &#8211; Rich Client Applications</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2018%20-%20Services&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 18 &#8211; Services</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2019%20-%20Mobile%20Applications&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 19 &#8211; Mobile Applications</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2020%20-%20Office%20Business%20Applications%20%28OBA%29&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 20 &#8211; Office Business Applications (OBA)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Chapter%2021%20-%20SharePoint%20LOB%20Applications&amp;referringTitle=Home">Chapter 21 &#8211; SharePoint Line-Of-Business (LOB) Applications</a></li>
</ul>
<h4>
Appendix<br />
</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Pattern%20Catalog%20V2&amp;referringTitle=Home">Cheat Sheet &#8211; patterns &amp; practices Pattern Catalog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Cheat%20Sheet%20-%20Presentation%20Technology%20Matrix&amp;referringTitle=Home">Cheat Sheet &#8211; Presentation Technology Matrix</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Cheat%20Sheet%20-%20Data%20Access%20Technology%20Matrix&amp;referringTitle=Home">Cheat Sheet &#8211; Data Access Technology Matrix</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Cheat%20Sheet%20-%20Workflow%20Technology%20Matrix&amp;referringTitle=Home">Cheat Sheet &#8211; Workflow Technology Matrix</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Cheat%20Sheet%20-%20Integration%20Technology%20Matrix&amp;referringTitle=Home">Cheat Sheet &#8211; Integration Technology Matrix</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>
Errata Page<br />
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apparchguide.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Errata%20Page&amp;referringTitle=Home">Errata Page</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/patterns-and-practices-application-archi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Danger in Design: Why bother with Architecture ?</title>
		<link>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/why-bother-with-architecture/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/why-bother-with-architecture/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 10:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[damber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Designing Multi-Application Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Designing Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware and Infrastructure Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information and Integration Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Introduction to Architecture and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methodologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rationale]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/06/why-bother-with-architecture/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Creativity is a wonderful thing. It&#8217;s also something different for each of us, which is why sometimes our perspectives on the world can produce conflicting ideas on what is the right way and the wrong way to do things. This is a very common facet of the IT world, in particular making computer software, solutions [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Creativity is a wonderful thing.  It&#8217;s also something different for each of us, which is why sometimes our perspectives on the world can produce conflicting ideas on what is the right way and the wrong way to do things.  This is a very common facet of the IT world, in particular making computer software, solutions and services.  </p>
<h1>We don&#8217;t need architects!  &#8230;Do we ?</h1>
<p>It&#8217;s important for us to remember that we develop software to &#8220;do something&#8221; that we want it to do. In which case we need to continually review the success of that software or solution by evaluating it&#8217;s ability to meet our needs.  But who gets to say what those needs are, and how well they are met?  More importantly, what makes IT solutions good or bad ?  Is it how big they are ? Or how easy to use they are ?  Or maybe how efficiently they operate ? Or what about how well measured and managed they are ?  Or even how easy it is to change the way they work ?  What about all of the above, and much more&#8230;?</p>
<p>Getting to a point where a) you understand what success looks like, and b) you have a solution that delivers that success, can be achieved by using an Architect to facilitate and coordinate the construction of a design and resulting solution.  But that&#8217;s not always what happens. Apart from the many varying definitions of an architect&#8217;s role (and the different types of architects.. e.g. Enterprise Architect, Solutions Architect, Application Architect, Technical Architect,etc), there&#8217;s also often a perception from developers that architects are generally away with the fairies, dreaming up blue sky designs that are just not grounded in reality or worthwhile bothering with.  Additionally, a lot of businesses (too many unfortunately), just don&#8217;t understand the value of using an architect&#8230; Why pay someone to design the solution, when you&#8217;ve got business systems analysts and developers that can work it out between themselves ?</p>
<p> </p>
<h1>Winchester Mystery House, San Jose, CA</h1>
<p>Why indeed&#8230;  well, I thought it may be useful to post a little analogy with the &#8216;real world&#8217; &#8211; where architects and builders have been working together for many years to produce wonderful (and not so wonderful) buildings.</p>
<p>Firstly, let me introduce the Winchester Mystery House, of the Winchester Guns family fame:</p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/Architect/images/winchesterhouse.png" alt="" title="" width="440" height="286" /></div>
<p></p>
<h2>Functionally Rich</h2>
<ul>
<li>160 Rooms</li>
<li>47 Fireplaces</li>
<li>17 Chimneys</li>
<li>6 kitchens</li>
<li>10,000 windows</li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<h2>State of the Art Technology (at the time)</h2>
<ul>
<li>Wall Insulation</li>
<li>Push button gas lights</li>
<li>No-clog sink patent</li>
<li>Intercoms</li>
<li>Modern Heating &amp; Sewage</li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<h2>Total Cost</h2>
<p style="font-size: 1em;">$5.5m (~<span style="font-weight:800;">$300m</span> today) over <span style="font-weight: 800;">38 years</span> (1884 &#8211; 1922)</p>
<p></p>
<h2>But&#8230; <span style="color:#ff0000;">No Interoperability</span></h2>
<ul>
<li>65 doors to blank walls</li>
<li>13 abandoned staircases</li>
<li>24 skylights in floors</li>
<li>Rooms &#8220;build-around&#8221; other rooms</li>
<li>Enough keys to fill 2 large buckets</li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p>Ouch.</p>
<p></p>
<h2>Due to the division of labour</h2>
<ul>
<li>Builders: 147</li>
<li>Architects: <span style="font-weight:800;text-decoration:underline;">0</span></li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<h2>Sound Familiar ?</h2>
<p>We&#8217;ve all worked on a project with something like this.  Usually because the system wasn&#8217;t really &#8216;designed&#8217; it just &#8216;happened&#8217;.  Maybe if we spent a little more time designing, and a little less building things would work a little better.  I bet they had some very talented builders working on this too &#8211; but their perspective wasn&#8217;t to make a solid overall design, it was to simply get on and do what they were tasked with.. sound familiar ?  How often do users come to a technical forum and ask for a solution to their problem to be faced with answers like &#8220;you need to normalise your database&#8221; etc, to which they simply retort &#8220;that&#8217;s not part of this project&#8221; ?  Too many, but sadly understandably so.</p>
<p>
A favourite Project Manager quote is &#8220;Failing to Plan is Planning to Fail&#8221;.  And they are generally right &#8211; not having a consistent, well thought out and planned design can lead to very complicated and difficult to manage, change or even use software.  Most architects will have come across solutions or applications that weren&#8217;t &#8216;designed&#8217; and just evolved, and will know just how much of a problem those applications really are.  This is <a href="http://www.sciam.com/article.cfm?id=softwares-dirty-little-secret&amp;sc=rss">Software&#8217;s Dirty Little Secret</a> &#8211; many systems have just &#8220;happened&#8221; without real thought to the design of the software.  And for that matter, haven&#8217;t thought about the application as part of a composite solution either &#8211; this is actually quite rare, even today with all the SOA hype of the last few years.
</p>
<h3>The Architect&#8217;s hand</h3>
<p>
Sometimes it might seem strange to developers that an architect wants to make a project use standards compliant technologies, standardised, re-usable or existing components, such as a Business Rules Engine, Reporting &amp; BI, Service Bus, Messaging Gateway, Portlets, etc &#8211; but this is what architecture is all about &#8211; not thinking about the one, single application or issue, but thinking about it&#8217;s co-existence in a much bigger world &#8211; not just the here and now functional requirements, but tomorrows new direction and demands.  Simplifying and standardising, Rationalising and Re-Using, Conceptualising and Componentising&#8230; the best architectures are easily understood, simple solutions that achieve a kind of elegance in concept and practicality in implementation.
</p>
<p>
There are several methodologies to use for developing an architecture &#8211; personally I use TOGAF which is more for generalist Enterprise &amp; Solutions Architecture development but the <acronym title="Architecture Development Methodology">ADM</acronym> can be applied in concept to designing most solutions/systems/applications.
</p>
<h2>So we do need to &#8220;do architecture&#8221; then?</h2>
<p>In short, Yes.  But how you actually &#8220;do architecture&#8221; depends greatly on the context.  There is a simple lesson here &#8211; architecture is all about simplifying and standardising the problem domain to provide an efficient, re-usable and consistent answer.  The important difference between a formal &#8220;architect&#8221; and a &#8220;builder&#8221; is not of technical expertise, but of perspective, so don&#8217;t assume that your most expert Java Programmer is naturally the architect to your solutions.  This doesn&#8217;t mean that an architect of all types shouldn&#8217;t possess good technical abilities and experience.</p>
<p>There is a nice <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/arcjournal/cc505968.aspx">overview of the different types of Architects</a> at the Microsoft Architecture Journal (which is often surprisingly not MS biased) written by IASA Sweden, however this misses out the technical/infrastructure architect from their Roles diagram, which is a key architect in any IT implementation.  Also, another article on the Architect Journal talks about <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/arcjournal/cc505974.aspx">what an architect actually is</a>, however is a little Software Architect focused.  Both interesting reads, especially for non-architects to understand how to &#8216;use&#8217; an architect (well, work with one effectively at least <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> ). </p>
<h3>Some Exceptions..</h3>
<p>There are times when a formal architecture process is more of a hindrance than a help, and that is in R &amp; D contexts where rapid prototyping and proof of concept solutions are all about unrestricted creativity &#8211; in these cases architecture experience and knowledge is a good backdrop to help organise and focus ideas and channel that creativity into creating something unique.  (But&#8230; Remember that this is not production ready, it is a prototype in need of architectural design to create a production capable solution.  This is where too many rapid prototyping approaches get a bad name.)</p>
<p>
One thing I will write about soon is the risk of &#8216;over-designing&#8217; a solution, because sometimes it is easy to get carried away with design-pattern addiction and framework-itis and actually miss the whole point of the exercise.  Doing &#8216;too much&#8217; architecture can be as bad, and even worse than doing none.
</p>
<h2>And Finally&#8230;</h2>
<p>So&#8230; Yes &#8211; Sometimes it&#8217;s nice to just set out in your car and drive wherever the wind takes you until the fuel runs out.  But other times, and almost always when it is on &#8216;business time&#8217;, wandering aimlessly in the hope of finding something that might be useful is just not acceptable.  Having that vision, aspiration, direction and roadmap an architecture can bring to your project might seem like a chore and &#8220;impossible&#8221; to achieve to some people.. but how else will you get there, without ever actively and knowingly moving toward it ? Chance ?  Good Luck with that&#8230;</p>
<p>So, the next time you think about just winging it, and not bothering with architecture, just think about your software product as your own house that you wish to build &#8211; would you really just start building ?  Or even just draw up your own plans on visio and ask the builders to &#8216;sort it out&#8217; ?  </p>
<p><em>N.B. In the Winchester House example, strange as it may seem, the design actually met the brief &#8211; the needs of the owner weren&#8217;t really to design an architecturally great building, but just to have something creative to do.. it doesn&#8217;t matter that it wasn&#8217;t consistent, or standardised or even usable &#8211; it was the pleasure of doing that was needed, not the objective of greatness in form and function.  But have a think about that&#8230; when was the last time your boss suggested you design something for the fun of it, at the company&#8217;s expense, regardless of whether it results in some sort of throw-away chimera ? </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/architect/hardwareinfrastructuredesign/why-bother-with-architecture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
