<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">XP &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-03-09T12:50:36Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/" />
	<id>/index.php/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/category/sysadmins/os/windows/xp/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Don&#8217;t fall for the social engineering scam that makes you go to ammyy.com]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/security/don-t-fall-for-the/" />
		<id>/index.php/2011/09/don-t-fall-for-the/</id>
		<updated>2011-09-18T12:10:00Z</updated>
		<published>2011-09-18T12:10:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="2003 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Security" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows 7" /><category scheme="/" term="XP" /><category scheme="/" term="scam" /><category scheme="/" term="security" /><category scheme="/" term="social engineering" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am pretty sure that none of our readers would fall for this social engineering scam that would make you share your computer with someone else, I am writing about it because I know of one person who had a call like this but she luckily hung up.

I he&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/security/don-t-fall-for-the/"><![CDATA[<p>I am pretty sure that none of our readers would fall for this social engineering scam that would make you share your computer with someone else, I am writing about it because I know of one person who had a call like this but she luckily hung up.</p>
<p>I heard about this on Twit&#8217;s <a href="http://twit.tv/sn">Security Now</a>( With Steve Gibson and Leo Laporte ). Here is how it works, you will get a call from someone based in India working for Microsoft telling you that your computer is infected. The first thing they do is tell you to go to start/run box, type <em>eventvwr </em>and it will bring up Windows Event Viewer. Now they have you go to the aplication folder and look at all the errors that are there, this is because the computer is infected. </p>
<p>Of course everyone that has been using windows for a while will know that it will always have errors.</p>
<p>The next part is pretty funny&#8230;.</p>
<p>They will tell you to go back to the Run box and type &#8220;inf&#8221;, then they will tell you that inf stands for <strong>infected files</strong>.  They make you go to C:Windowsinf After you are there they will ask you if you can you see a lot of .inf and .pnf files in the INF directory. If you say yes, and you will, they will tell you that those are corrupted files. Next they will tell you to double-click one of the PNF files.  Once you double-click it, you will see an error message like the one below</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/All/pnffile.PNG?mtime=1326496203"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/All/pnffile.PNG?mtime=1326496203" width="412" height="252" /></a></div>
<p>This, they will tell you is proof that your machine is infected.</p>
<p>After that they will tell you that to fix it you need to do the following. Go to the Run box and type www.ammyy.com. Ammyy Admin &#8211; is a popular config-zero free remote desktop sharing software. It&#8217;s used for system administration, webinars and instant remote desktop access. So next they will take over your system by using this tool</p>
<p>Here is a also a video that someone recorded</p>
[video:youtube:cueN1-2lANA]
<p>So if you or any of the people you know get any of these calls, just tell them to hung up.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong> Microsoft dumps partner over support call scam, see here: http://www.pcpro.co.uk/news/370054/microsoft-dumps-partner-over-support-call-scam</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/security/don-t-fall-for-the/#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/security/don-t-fall-for-the/feed/atom/" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Compressing files with NTFS compression by running compact from the command line]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/vista/compressing-files-with-ntfs-compression/" />
		<id>/index.php/2011/06/compressing-files-with-ntfs-compression/</id>
		<updated>2011-06-22T14:11:00Z</updated>
		<published>2011-06-22T14:11:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="2003 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="2008 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Vista" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows 7" /><category scheme="/" term="XP" /><category scheme="/" term="compression" /><category scheme="/" term="ntfs" /><category scheme="/" term="zip" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know that you can right click on a file/folder, select properties, click advanced and then compress contents to save disk space(see image).




Did you know that you can call this from the command line also? I just saw this on  Raymond Chen's b&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/vista/compressing-files-with-ntfs-compression/"><![CDATA[<p>You know that you can right click on a file/folder, select properties, click advanced and then compress contents to save disk space(see image).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5860004203/" title="compress by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5277/5860004203_c847a70cac.jpg" width="394" height="300" alt="compress" /></a></p>
<p>Did you know that you can call this from the command line also? I just saw this on  Raymond Chen&#8217;s blog today: http://blogs.msdn.com/b/oldnewthing/archive/2011/06/22/10177613.aspx</p>
<p>I decided to try it out</p>
<p>The command is compact , here are all the switches</p>
<pre>C:UsersSQLDenis&gt;compact /?
Displays or alters the compression of files on NTFS partitions.

COMPACT [/C | /U] [/S[:dir]] [/A] [/I] [/F] [/Q] [filename [...]]

  /C        Compresses the specified files.  Directories will be marked
            so that files added afterward will be compressed.
  /U        Uncompresses the specified files.  Directories will be marked
            so that files added afterward will not be compressed.
  /S        Performs the specified operation on files in the given
            directory and all subdirectories.  Default "dir" is the
            current directory.
  /A        Displays files with the hidden or system attributes.  These
            files are omitted by default.
  /I        Continues performing the specified operation even after errors
            have occurred.  By default, COMPACT stops when an error is
            encountered.
  /F        Forces the compress operation on all specified files, even
            those which are already compressed.  Already-compressed files
            are skipped by default.
  /Q        Reports only the most essential information.
  filename  Specifies a pattern, file, or directory.

  Used without parameters, COMPACT displays the compression state of
  the current directory and any files it contains. You may use multiple
  filenames and wildcards.  You must put spaces between multiple
  parameters.</pre>
<p>I have a temp folder on my C drive, first I want to see if anything is compressed, I will run <strong>compact /Q</strong> to get some information</p>

<div class="bwp-syntax-block clearfix">
<div class="bwp-syntax-toolbar"><div class="bwp-syntax-control"><a href="javascript:;" class="bwp-syntax-source-switch" title="View Source Code"></a></div></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-wrapper clearfix bwp-syntax-simple"><table class="dos"><thead><tr><td colspan="2"  class="head">DOS</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="li1"><td class="ln"><pre class="de1">1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
</pre></td><td class="de1"><pre class="de1">c:Temp<span class="sy0">&gt;</span>compact /Q
&nbsp;
&nbsp;Listing c:Temp
&nbsp;New files added to this directory will <span class="kw2">not</span> be compressed.
&nbsp;
&nbsp;
Of 8 files within 1 directories
0 are compressed and 8 are <span class="kw2">not</span> compressed.
1,833,822 total bytes of data are stored <span class="kw1">in</span> 1,833,822 bytes.
The compression ratio is 1.0 to 1.</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-source"><pre class="no-parse">c:Temp&gt;compact /Q

 Listing c:Temp
 New files added to this directory will not be compressed.


Of 8 files within 1 directories
0 are compressed and 8 are not compressed.
1,833,822 total bytes of data are stored in 1,833,822 bytes.
The compression ratio is 1.0 to 1.</pre></div></div>

<p>Now, I want to compress those files, I will do that with the <strong>compact /C</strong> command</p>
<pre>c:Temp&gt;compact /C

 Setting the directory c:Temp to compress new files [OK]

 Compressing files in c:Temp

ChartingUsage.abf      352256 :    143360 = 2.5 to 1 [OK]
ipconfig.txt            28482 :      8192 = 3.5 to 1 [OK]
Test.pcf.vpn              982 :       982 = 1.0 to 1 [OK]
test.csv                 8375 :      4096 = 2.0 to 1 [OK]
test.htm                25204 :      8192 = 3.1 to 1 [OK]
test2.csv                8375 :      4096 = 2.0 to 1 [OK]
TestDB.BAK            1395200 :    258048 = 5.4 to 1 [OK]
tshoot.txt              14948 :      8192 = 1.8 to 1 [OK]

9 files within 2 directories were compressed.
1,833,822 total bytes of data are stored in 435,158 bytes.
The compression ratio is 4.2 to 1.</pre>
<p>Now I can run <strong>compact /Q</strong> again to get some information</p>

<div class="bwp-syntax-block clearfix">
<div class="bwp-syntax-toolbar"><div class="bwp-syntax-control"><a href="javascript:;" class="bwp-syntax-source-switch" title="View Source Code"></a></div></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-wrapper clearfix bwp-syntax-simple"><table class="dos"><thead><tr><td colspan="2"  class="head">DOS</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="li1"><td class="ln"><pre class="de1">1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
</pre></td><td class="de1"><pre class="de1">c:Temp<span class="sy0">&gt;</span>compact /Q
&nbsp;
&nbsp;Listing c:Temp
&nbsp;New files added to this directory will be compressed.
&nbsp;
&nbsp;
Of 8 files within 1 directories
8 are compressed and 0 are <span class="kw2">not</span> compressed.
1,833,822 total bytes of data are stored <span class="kw1">in</span> 435,158 bytes.
The compression ratio is 4.2 to 1.</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-source"><pre class="no-parse">c:Temp&gt;compact /Q

 Listing c:Temp
 New files added to this directory will be compressed.


Of 8 files within 1 directories
8 are compressed and 0 are not compressed.
1,833,822 total bytes of data are stored in 435,158 bytes.
The compression ratio is 4.2 to 1.</pre></div></div>

<p>As you can see, the files are compressed and the ratio is 4.2 to 1</p>
<p>Hopefully this will be useful for some of you that copy files and then want to compress files after the copy process is done</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/vista/compressing-files-with-ntfs-compression/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/vista/compressing-files-with-ntfs-compression/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulnerability in Microsoft Video ActiveX control could allow remote code execution]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/vulnerability-in-microsoft-video-activex/" />
		<id>/index.php/2009/07/vulnerability-in-microsoft-video-activex/</id>
		<updated>2009-07-08T11:15:21Z</updated>
		<published>2009-07-08T11:15:21Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="2003 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Operating Systems" /><category scheme="/" term="Security" /><category scheme="/" term="XP" /><category scheme="/" term="activex" /><category scheme="/" term="security" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a bad one if you are running Windows XP or Windows Server 2003 with Internet Explorer. If you are running Windows Vista, Windows 7 or Windows Server 2008 then you are not affected The bad part about this is that all it takes for you is to visit a bad site. If you [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/vulnerability-in-microsoft-video-activex/"><![CDATA[<p>This is a bad one if you are running Windows XP or Windows Server 2003 with Internet Explorer. If you are running Windows Vista, Windows 7 or Windows Server 2008 then you are not affected</p>
<p>The bad part about this is that all it takes for you is to visit a bad site. If you are using Chrome (like me), FireFox or Safari then you are not affected by this. Microsoft really should redesign IE from scratch and get rid of all that ActiveX baggage/nonsense, it is not worth it, it only causes troubles. Almost every IE vulnerability is ActiveX based.</p>
<p><em>Mitigating Factors:</p>
<p>Customers who are using Windows Vista or Windows Server 2008 are not affected because the ability to pass data to this control within Internet Explorer has been restricted.</p>
<p>By default, Internet Explorer on Windows Server 2003 and 2008 runs in a restricted mode that is known as Enhanced Security Configuration. Enhanced Security Configuration is a group of preconfigured settings in Internet Explorer that can reduce the likelihood of a user or administrator downloading and running specially crafted Web content on a server. This is a mitigating factor for Web sites that you have not added to the Internet Explorer Trusted sites zone. See also Managing Internet Explorer Enhanced Security Configuration.</p>
<p>By default, all supported versions of Microsoft Outlook and Microsoft Outlook Express open HTML e-mail messages in the Restricted sites zone. The Restricted sites zone helps mitigate attacks that could try to exploit this vulnerability by preventing Active Scripting and ActiveX controls from being used when reading HTML e-mail messages. However, if a user clicks a link in an e-mail message, the user could still be vulnerable to exploitation of this vulnerability through the Web-based attack scenario.</p>
<p>In a Web-based attack scenario, an attacker could host a Web site that contains a Web page that is used to exploit this vulnerability. In addition, compromised Web sites and Web sites that accept or host user-provided content or advertisements could contain specially crafted content that could exploit this vulnerability. In all cases, however, an attacker would have no way to force users to visit these Web sites. Instead, an attacker would have to persuade users to visit the Web site, typically by getting them to click a link in an e-mail message or Instant Messenger message that takes users to the attacker&#8217;s Web site.</p>
<p>An attacker who successfully exploited this vulnerability could gain the same user rights as the local user. Users whose accounts are configured to have fewer user rights on the system could be less impacted than users who operate with administrative user rights.</em></p>
<p><strong>There are 2 ways to do something about this</strong><br />
1) Visit <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/advisory/972890.mspx">Microsoft Security Advisory (972890)</a> and look in the workaround section where you will find a way so that you can disable attempts to instantiate a COM object in Internet Explorer by setting the kill bit for the control in the registry.</p>
<p>2) Use the fix it button on this page  http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx/kb/972890</p>
<p>Here is a partial list of domains that are exploiting this hole</p>
<p>q23r.cn<br />
wf3gr.8800.org<br />
ads.v8dc.com<br />
name81.8u60.8u.cn<br />
wvg7.cn<br />
ma.o524q.cn<br />
laibuji.w528e.cn<br />
girlfired.d821e.cn<br />
w1.7777ee.com<br />
w2.7777ee.com<br />
w3.7777ee.com<br />
w8.7777ee.com<br />
w9.7777ee.com<br />
milllk.com<br />
haha999b.com<br />
babi2009.com<br />
haha888l.com<br />
xin765.com</p>
<p>A complete list can be found here: http://isc.sans.org/diary.html?storyid=6739</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/vulnerability-in-microsoft-video-activex/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/vulnerability-in-microsoft-video-activex/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
	</feed>
