<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>product selection &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/product-selection/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Product Selection, Reviewing the Process</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-reviewing-the-process/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-reviewing-the-process/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product selection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/03/product-selection-reviewing-the-process/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was a long trip from "I want product ABC" to what we really ended up choosing and implementing. No process is perfect, no meeting goes as planned. After the product selection process is complete it's time to review what went well, what fared poorly, and what we can try to improve the process. There are fifteen other tasks waiting, but taking some time to identify these factors is the first step to evolving our process towards an ultimate goal of less wasted motion in both the short and long terms.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="background-color: #eeeeee; padding: 1em; margin: 1.5em .5em 0em 0em; border: 1px solid #CCCCCC; float: right">
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li>1: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-identifying-needs" title="Read the first entry">Identifying Needs</a></li>
<li>2: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring" title="Read the 2nd entry">Requirements and Scoring</a></li>
<li>3: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-evaluation" title="Read the 3rd entry">Evaluation</a></li>
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold">4: Review</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>It was a long trip from &#8220;I want product ABC&#8221; to what we really ended up choosing and implementing. No process is perfect, no meeting goes as planned. After the product selection process is complete it&#8217;s time to review what went well, what fared poorly, and what we can try to improve the process. There are fifteen other tasks waiting, but taking some time to identify these factors is the first step to evolving our process towards an ultimate goal of less wasted motion in both the short and long terms. Some day we should be able to lift our heads and realize that we are not only selecting the best possible products for our needs, but doing so with less energy and resources then it originally took to simply pick one at random (with the random conversations, arguments, integration losses, and other baggage that incorporate that &#8216;process&#8217;).</p>
<h2> Step 4: Review </h2>
<div style="margin: 1.5em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: right;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ThinkingGuy.jpg" title="Assess and review" style="max-width: 120px" />
</div>
<p>There are a lot of templates out there for reviewing projects and tasks and, like so many areas in our field, there are books upon books upon theories upon methods. Don&#8217;t waste a lot of time trying to find the perfect method, generally any method will get us 80% of the way there. One starting place I like is the <a href="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/09/key-elements-agile-retrospective" title="Agile Retrospectives on InfoQ">Agile Retrospective</a>.</p>
<h3>Hold the Retrospective</h3>
<p>The best retrospectives I have been included in have had a few common factors (this is not to say you can&#8217;t have an excellent one without these factors, I can only speak from my own experience). Prior to the retrospective we should send out a survey for people to fill out and bring to the meeting with them. I have a post-mortem document I borrow questions from and expanded over time, here are some examples (my apologies, I haven&#8217;t tracked all the sources of these questions):</p>
<ul>
<li>Are you proud of the outcome of the project?</li>
<li>What was the single most frustrating part of the project?</li>
<li>What part of the project most contributed to the success?</li>
<li>Given the opportunity, would you take part in this project again?</li>
<li>How could we have improved [name of phase, sub-process, fill in the blank]</li>
<li>Did we include all of the necessary people in the process?</li>
<li>What could we have removed from the process or what was the least useful part of the process?</li>
<li>What information was presented in the poorest or hardest to understand fashion?</li>
</ul>
<p>The purpose is to help people identify significant factors in the process that they felt helped, hurt, or simply caused waste. Areas that are considered wasteful are potential candidates to try living without, negative areas are areas that we should analyze further, and positive areas are things we can thank the team for helping us succeed with.</p>
<h3>Reflect and Assess</h3>
<p>Having the group feedback is important, but the only person that has been present for the entire process has been you. Set aside 30 to 60 minutes to reflect over the process, using materials like meeting requests and early emails to refresh your memory. Try to quickly live back through the process and see what parts could have been improved or were unnecessary now that you have the benefit of hindsight. Ask yourself if you personally felt like the selection was successful, what you would like to have tried differently, and what pieces you think could be improved for the next one.</p>
<h3>Document, Document, Document</h3>
<p>Again with the documentation. I have a poor memory and a dislike for ineffectiveness, so I try to make sure that if I have spent a lot of energy on a project that I have captured the end result as best as I could. Document the results of the retrospective and the self-review and put that document together with the documents you produced for the product selection. This may also be excellent material to use in reviews with your boss as it will provide a lot of input into how you and others felt the process went and also invites them to help provide you with areas or training that can help the next time around be even more effective. Writing all of the information can help reinforce your memory and many times serves as a greater benefit then the end product.</p>
<p>Document only as much as you need and no more. Documenting every last detail is almost as useless as documenting nothing at all. Find a balance.</p>
<h2> And Done! </h2>
<div style="margin: 1.5em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: left;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/success.jpg" title="Success" style="max-width: 120px" />
</div>
<p>We did it. From a general budget line item or CEO query we have evaluated what the company needed, brought all the business owners on board to create requirements and selection criteria, evaluated several products against each other, and executed a lessons learned exercise against our process. Along the way we sidestepped a lot of meetings, reduced a slew of risks, reduced implementation and requirements gaps, and probably saved our company a lot of money they will never know about. </p>
<p>The absolute last step is to write this down for your year end review and to send out a thank you email to everyone that was involved in the process. From the CEO to the business owners, to the implementation team, everyone deserves to enjoy the successes. And a little not-so-secret tip? Success is the best step 0  for your next project. Having a string of success behind you makes it that much easier to root cause people&#8217;s requirements, get them involved in selection, and successfully complete that next project.</p>
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li>1: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-identifying-needs" title="Read the first entry">Identifying Needs</a></li>
<li>2: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring" title="Read the 2nd entry">Requirements and Scoring</a></li>
<li>3: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-evaluation" title="Read the 3rd entry">Evaluation</a></li>
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold">4: Review</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-reviewing-the-process/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Product Selection, Evaluation</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-evaluation/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-evaluation/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product selection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/02/product-selection-evaluation/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Having identified the root needs the product will fulfill, engaging people while selecting criteria, and generating a scorecard to evaluate each contender against, we're ready to get started, right?

Well, almost.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="background-color: #eeeeee; padding: 1em; margin: 1.5em .5em 0em 0em; border: 1px solid #CCCCCC; float: right">
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li>1: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-identifying-needs" title="Read the first entry">Identifying Needs</a></li>
<li>2: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring" title="Read the 2nd entry">Requirements and Scoring</a></li>
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold">3: Evaluation</li>
<li>4: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-reviewing-the-process" title="Read the 4th entry">Review</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>Having identified the root needs the product will fulfill, engaging people while selecting criteria, and generating a scorecard to evaluate each contender against, we&#8217;re ready to get started, right?</p>
<p>Well, almost. </p>
<h2> Step 3: Evaluation </h2>
<p>In order to evaluate and score all of the contending products, we first need some contending products.</p>
<h3> Select Candidates </h3>
<div style="margin: 1.5em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: left;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/doors.png" title="Obligatory picture of 3 doors" style="max-width: 120px" />
</div>
<p>At this point it&#8217;s highly likely we will have one or two products that have been suggested. However those aren&#8217;t the only solutions on the market and armed with our enhanced and comprehensive list of requirement, we ought to be able to find a few more options to evaluate. Even if we have a clear winner at this point, looking at additional options will ensure there wasn&#8217;t anything critical we overlooked and that we can show alignment with the groups interests.</p>
<div style="border: 1px solid #BBBBBB; margin: 0em 1em; padding: 1em; float: right; width: 200px;">
I was once in a process improvement session that was headed towards a solution involving a 3-4 week development project. The operations manager listened to us hash through the problem and requirements, then calmly suggested a solution involving a pack of construction paper and some transparent binder inserts. Not only did it end up filling the need, we were able to implement it that afternoon and it required less work to use.
</div>
<p>While options are good, we want to be wary of the internal development solution. Because the solution is what we make of it and will undoubtedly change over the course of implementation, it is the option that simultaneously has the least and most options, the lowest and highest cost, and the worst and best support. My opinion is to include 2-3 versions including small to large ranges of features and to have each of them quoted separately. We also need to ensure that criteria for implementation time and internal support are evaluated, as a custom development project will have a significant long-term impact on both of these.</p>
<h3> <s>Play with products</s> Evaluate! </h3>
<p>With the exception of the internal development product, it&#8217;s now time to sit down and play with some products. Depending on the size of the purchase and the criticality of the purchase, this could consist of something as light as reviewing published specs to getting full installations or samples and having real users test drive the products. The scorecard is the starting point for these trials, but we want to make sure we also capture additional features and any detrimental factors we run into. </p>
<p>Extra columns or space on the scorecard should be used to reflect software scores. These include things like price tags, annual support costs, average response time, and other similar values. Some of these, like cost, will likely already be strongly represented in our criteria (ie, don&#8217;t spend more than $X), while other may need to be factored in or rated against one another. Don&#8217;t forget to track bonus items, features no one was expecting but might help break a tie.</p>
<h3> Review and Select </h3>
<div style="margin: 1.5em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: left;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/scores2.png" title="Use the scorecard" style="max-width: 120px" />
</div>
<p>Highest score wins, right? Not necessarily.</p>
<p>After all of the evaluations have been completed, we should have a clear set of leaders. With some hands on time, there have likely been some pros and cons discovered that weren&#8217;t on the initial list. These could sway the group to re-evaluate some of their scores. The important part is that the process has given us the information we need to make an informed decision, whereas without it were closer to guessing.</p>
<p>Either individually or in a group we need to determine where the new criteria fall on the scorecard, determine if anything has changed since we started (budget cuts, changing needs, etc), and so on. </p>
<h3>Document, Document, Document</h3>
<p>Document all the factors in the decisions. Promises from vendors, pros and cons of products, changes to the scoring, final selection. In 6 months we need to be able to understand what details led to the decision we made and if a product has failed to fulfill it&#8217;s promises.</p>
<p>The final deliverable of the product selection process is a decision that has clearly included the input of the necessary parties and a decision directly based on our needs and problems.</p>
<h2>Next Steps</h2>
<p>Once the product has been selected, it&#8217;s time to implement. This should include at least a minimal implementation plan, identifying an owner for the implementation, purchasing the software, and so on. This can be a two paragraph note with a bullet list or a fully defined project plan following your methodology of choice (critical path, CCPM, scrum, etc). </p>
<p>Implementing the product is outside the scope of this product selection series, but there is one step beyond implementation that is not. Every process should end in a review.  What worked, what didn&#8217;t work, did we we achieve long term success, and so on. In short, the process is never perfect, some things didn&#8217;t go so well, and there is always too much work. So we&#8217;ll skip past the implementation and head straight to the review.</p>
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li>1: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-identifying-needs" title="Read the first entry">Identifying Needs</a></li>
<li>2: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring" title="Read the 2nd entry">Requirements and Scoring</a></li>
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold">3: Evaluation</li>
<li>4: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-reviewing-the-process" title="Read the 4th entry">Review</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-evaluation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Product Selection, Requirements and Scoring</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product selection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/02/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Once we have the purpose of the product selection defined, it's time to move on to defining the characteristics we need or want from our product. Up until this point in the process we have talked to people one-on-one or in small groups. Now that we have identified the core need or needs the product must fulfill, we are ready to expand that into the list of requirements and features by incorporating input from the wider group of affected people. We can use brainstorming to engage people as well as help them voice their expectations and evaluate the relative priorities of those expectations.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="background-color: #eeeeee; padding: 1em; margin: 1.5em .5em 0em 0em; border: 1px solid #CCCCCC; float: left">
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li>1: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-identifying-needs" title="Read the first entry">Identifying Needs</a></li>
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold">2: Requirements and Scoring</li>
<li>3: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-evaluation" title="Read the third entry">Evaluation</a></li>
<li>4: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-reviewing-the-process" title="Read the 4th entry">Review</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>Once we have the purpose of the product selection defined, it&#8217;s time to move on to defining the characteristics we need or want from our product. Up until this point in the process we have talked to people one-on-one or in small groups. Now that we have identified the core need or needs the product must fulfill, we are ready to expand that into the list of requirements and features by incorporating input from the wider group of affected people. We can use brainstorming to engage people as well as help them voice their expectations and evaluate the relative priorities of those expectations.</p>
<h2>Step 2: Requirements and Features</h2>
<div style="margin: 1.5em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: left;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/List.png" title="Picture of list" style="max-width: 80px" />
</div>
<p>We are going to bring everyone together in a meeting or set of meetings. The end goal is a prioritized list of requirements and features that we can use to evaluate potential products. This prioritized list will simplify the comparison effort and will give us an opportunity to enlist the aid of the people defining requirements to help us prioritize them and determine the line between nice-to-haves and must-haves. In addition it brings together the people with a vested interest in the production selection, engages them in the process, and provides us an opportunity to explain our process to them. This should help to bring up objections and additions sooner, when they can still be incorporated into the process.</p>
<p>In one step we are managing expectations from the beginning of the process, engaging the people that will be most impacted by the decision (which makes buy-in easier), and hopefully settings some people at ease and reducing potential emotional turmoil.</p>
<h3> Preparing </h3>
<p>Prior to holding the meeting, send everyone a brief outline of the project and the needs that were identified in the prior step. Request that people spend 5-10 minutes brainstorming a list of features or ideas they have about the product and bring that to the meeting. It&#8217;s unlikely that everyone will actually create a list, but it will help people get in the right mind-frame and the 2 or 3 people that do bring lists will help get the brainstorming session flowing. In the event that additional needs are brought forward, we will need to evaluate them and determine if they should be added to the list of core needs for the product selection process or if they reflect requirements or potentially an unrelated matter.</p>
<div style="margin: 1.5em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: right;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/clock.png" title="Picture of list" />
</div>
<p>We want to prepare for this meeting. Having a high-level plan doesn&#8217;t mean we have to necessarily stick to it, but it will help us think through what we need to achieve from the meeting as well as provide a tool to help keep the meeting on track. Some highlights of the meeting (or set of meetings) should include:</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em;">
<li>An overview of the purpose of the meeting (get people on track early)</li>
<li>A review of the overall process being followed</li>
<li>A review of the initial purpose of the product selection</li>
<li>A review of the list of needs (including new ones) the product will fulfill</li>
<li>A brainstorming session, preferably on whiteboard or with markers on an easel</li>
<li>A scoring or prioritization session</li>
<li>A closing review and communication of next steps</li>
</ul>
<p>Our preparation should include a clearly defined objective, a high level agenda, and a planned method to reign in extreme digressions or off-topic input. These meetings can go long, so we also want to make sure we have some breaks planned and we add that to our up front communication. If we are intending to have a followup, we should communicate that at the outset when we discuss the goals of this particular session. In some company cultures, using the a different word (such as session) instead of meeting may help attendance or initial attitude, we should use what we think would work best.</p>
<p>An effective meeting is one in which everyone walks away satisfied that the time was well spent and got a lot done. If the company does not provide <a href="http://www.bnet.com/article/how-to-run-an-effective-meeting/61211" title="Good Effective Meeting article to start with">effective meeting</a> training, 10-20 minutes perusing the web can give some good input on how to help the meeting go smoothly. The more effective the meeting, the smoother it will go, the better your gathered requirements will be, and the higher the engagement level will be within the group. </p>
<h3> Brainstorming </h3>
<p>The brainstorming phase is critical because it will provide us with the last raw ingredients we need to create our evaluation checklist. Based on personal experience I have found that using informal materials seems to help people get into the flow quicker. A whiteboard or pad of paper on an easel seems less permanent as a decision-making surface and can help people feel more comfortable about speaking out and making additions.</p>
<div style="margin: 0em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: left;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/words.png" title="Brainstorming picture" />
</div>
<p>Just as we did when determining the needs the product will fulfill, we are going to have some suggestions that need further analysis. Whether they are shared due to a vested interest in specific products or as an attempt to work some extra responsibilities in, we still want to dig into these suggestions and try to find some root criteria. Even if the entire audience is against including the items, this is a brainstorming session and we include all input, even unpopular items. </p>
<p>It&#8217;s up to you whether you allow the brainstorming to continue until it reaches a natural conclusion (the microwave popcorn method) or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeboxing" title="Timeboxing via Wikipedia">timebox</a> it. However it ends, thank everyone for a successful session. This again will help engage them in the process and gives us a moment to help the group notice their own success (and be sincere, how many product selection processes have even made it this far?).</p>
<h3> Scoring/Prioritizing </h3>
<p>Up until now we have hopefully been able to manage the groups emotions fairly well. Everyone&#8217;s input has been welcome, everyone has been included and has had their opinions valued. Unfortunately that may change as we move into prioritizing or assigning scores to all of the suggested criteria. At this point it may be useful to start transferring everything to a spreadsheet on an overhead so that all of the items are visible to the group but can also be re-arranged quickly. </p>
<p>One of the most effective selection tools I have used is a <a href="http://lssacademy.com/2007/06/11/need-help-making-decisions/" title="Read more on Cause and Effect matrix">Cause and Effect Matrix</a>. Often used as a tool to prioritize risks during a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Failure_mode_and_effects_analysis" title="FMEA at Wikipedia">Failure Modes Effect Analysis</a>, a Cause and Effect Matrix helps us score options against a range of criteria that each have a relative weight or priority. For product selection this helps produce a scorecard we can use apply to each product that shows which products score best against the criteria selected by the people in this room.</p>
<div style="margin: .5em .5em .5em 0; padding: .5em; color: #666666; text-align: center; float: left;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/scorecard.png" title="Scorecard picture" />
</div>
<p>To use this tool we will need to go through the criteria the group has brainstormed and assign a relative score to each one. Whether we have the group do this together or return to their desks and submit an individual prioritization is a matter of taste. Working together in the room provides the advantage that people can explain what the criteria meant when they suggested, attempt to influence others, and potentially vote to remove criteria altogether. The potential downside is that we are inviting emotional discourse and there could be some hurt feelings (only a problem if it gets out of hand). Asking people to vote on relative weights or averaging the priority they assign individually should give a weighting to each individual criterion and allow us to build a scorecard.</p>
<p>If the items are scored individually, it is critical to bring everyone back together again to discuss items and to help people communicate their meanings to the wider group. Just as non-IT people will not find it obvious how expensive it could be to buy software for an operating system than IT doesn&#8217;t have the in-house knowledge to support, there is also that same potential to misunderstand the criticality of an item that a marketing, sales, or purchasing agent brings to the table. A follow-up allows people to discuss the items they feel uncomfortable with and attempt to sway the vote towards a more comfortable value.</p>
<p>As before, thank the group and congratulate them on another step successfully completed. </p>
<h2>Next Steps</h2>
<p>We should now have a list of the needs we are trying to fulfill and the criteria and scorecard we are going to use to score candidate products. Our next step is to select and evaluate those candidate products. Along the way we will pick up some missing criteria, identify costs and potential gaps, and hopefully narrow in on one or more solid options using the scoring mechanism the company has defined.</p>
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li>1: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-identifying-needs" title="Read the first entry">Identifying Needs</a></li>
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold">2: Requirements and Scoring</li>
<li>3: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-evaluation" title="Read the third entry">Evaluation</a></li>
<li>4: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-reviewing-the-process" title="Read the 4th entry">Review</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Product Selection, Identifying Needs</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-identifying-needs/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-identifying-needs/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product selection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/02/product-selection-identifying-needs/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Product selection is something we will all run into in our careers, regardless of where we fall in the technical spectrum. Whether we are helping select a tool for end users, new hardware for our servers, or a framework to use in our process, product selection can have far reaching affects and the potential to consume a great deal of time and effort.

The following post is the first of four outlining a four step selection process that attempts to create structure without becoming too heavy to use. There are meetings and details, but only in support of a few key methods (chosen due to their success in my own anecdotal experiences).]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="background-color: #eeeeee; padding: 1em; margin: 1.5em .5em 0em 0em; border: 1px solid #CCCCCC; float: left">
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;">1: Identifying Needs</li>
<li>2: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring" title="Read the 2nd entry">Requirements and Scoring</a></li>
<li>3: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-evaluation" title="Read the third entry">Evaluation</a></li>
<li>4: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-reviewing-the-process" title="Read the 4th entry">Review</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>Product selection is something we will all run into in our careers, regardless of where we fall in the technical spectrum. Whether we are helping select a tool for end users, new hardware for our servers, or a framework to use in our process, product selection can have far reaching affects and the potential to consume a great deal of time and effort.</p>
<p>The following post is the first of four outlining a four step selection process that attempts to create structure without becoming too heavy to use. There are meetings and details, but only in support of a few key methods (chosen due to their success in my own anecdotal experiences). Like any process, this comes with no guarantees. Try the whole thing, takes pieces and incorporate them into your own process or throw the whole thing out and keep your own process. The important thing is to stop shooting from the hip so we can cut out some meetings, reduce surprises, improve integration, and ultimately select a product that does what we need it to do without an emotional and political bloodbath.</p>
<h2>Step 0: Why Do I Need a Process?</h2>
<div style="float: right; margin: .5em; padding: .45em; border: 1px solid #dddddd; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/AorB.jpg" alt="Option A or Option B?" />
</div>
<p>It often starts with &#8220;I need an IDE&#8221; or &#8220;I need ABC, Inc&#8217;s IDE&#8221;. On the one hand, when we pre-select a product we then measure all other potential solutions against that product instead of against our needs. On the other, a vague category fails to provide anything but the most general criterion. Despite their differences, they tent to both lead to a very similar outcome: highly opinionated, emotional selection processes where groups of people end up rallying behind the product they like the best. These methods are extremely variable and, beside creating a lot of dissension and wasted time, often leave us with a product that is missing a number of critical features or capabilities and requires far too long to integrate into our environment. This method may seem faster, but it has a lot of additional costs and can actually take far longer.</p>
<h2>Step 1: Identification</h2>
<p>Whether we have a specific product or type of product in mind, the first thing we should is take a step back and determine what need we are expected to fill. Identifying the needs provides us the most important criteria during product selection and provides a tool to separate the requirements from the nice-to-haves.</p>
<h3>Identify the Need</h3>
<p>Rarely are we asked to look at a product simply because someone wants one more product on the shelf, or needs to waste some money from the budget. Before we start looking at products we need to determine what the root need is for that product selection. Needs should be expressed as barriers that prevent our company from doing it&#8217;s job at a higher level of effectiveness, ongoing problems that are degrading performance or creating additional work, new standards, changes in legal restrictions, etc. </p>
<p>By using <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Root_cause_analysis" title="Root Cause Analysis on Wikipedia">Root cause analysis</a> methods we can dig into the reasons behind the project and determine then actual barriers or needs the business is trying to address. These are often not very clear to the person who initiated the product request, but determining the root need will take us a long way towards succeeding in filling that need.</p>
<h3>&#8220;The CEO Said So&#8221;</h3>
<div style="float: right; margin: .5em; padding: .45em; border: 1px solid #dddddd; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
   <img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/ProductSelection/dashboard.jpg" alt="Dreaming of a dashboard" style="max-width: 200px" /><br />
   Are they really asking for<br />more software?
</div>
<p>Often we will run into reasons such as &#8220;because the CEO said so&#8221; or &#8220;because we budgeted for it&#8221; as needs. We can these items, but we don&#8217;t want to let the position or invocation of a budget keep us from digging into the root cause. Often when a CEO says &#8220;we need a new dashboarding system&#8221; what he is actually doing is communicating a need such as &#8220;I don&#8217;t feel that I have visibility of X and in my past company product Y gave me that visibility&#8221;. While he thinks he is asking us to buy a specific product, what he is actually doing is asking us to to solve his visibility problem using the solution that satisfied him the last time he had this problem. If we determine which capabilities or features he most greatly misses, we can then determine what those features provided at the CEO&#8217;s last job and likely what they feel they are missing now. </p>
<p>Note that this is the same reasoning that our new IT manager uses when he joins the company and starts buying all of the software he used at his last one. He is uneasy or has a need and knows what products made him feel comfortable or worked in a previous environment, so those are what he purchases. Unfortunately, this isn&#8217;t his last position and environments can vary drastically under the surface. Like the CEO, we want to dig into what need or uneasiness they are trying to resolve and use the root needs as criteria or as leads to follow-up with other business owners.</p>
<h3>&#8220;We Always Use Vendor X&#8221;</h3>
<p>Not uncommon, many companies like to use a single vendor or a selection from a known set of vendors. The advantages include the presence of an existing relationship, potential for extra savings, and simpler support plans (the same number and people we already call).</p>
<p>All of which is wasted if what they are selling is different from what we think we are buying.</p>
<p>This is a difficult situation to work with, because often people will see having a selection process to be a waste of effort. However we can play off the fact that there isn&#8217;t a clearly defined need and even if we are purchasing from that vendor, we need to make sure we buy the correct package, support options, and integration services. And in order to do that we need to evaluate our own needs and see what other, similar companies offer to make sure we are getting all of the options we need. And now we&#8217;re back on track, defining a need instead of impulse buying.</p>
<h3>(And Other Tricky Situations&#8230;)</h3>
<p>These are not the only tricky situations, but the key is to use these situations to the opposite effect that people are expecting. If the product selection is a foregone conclusion, then we use the process to select options inside that pool and engage that person or persons in the selection process. If we are seen as protecting their interests and needs (which we are, by the way, just in a broader fashion then they are expecting), then we can spend less time arguing and more time helping them get what they really need.</p>
<h3>Next Steps</h3>
<p>Once we have identified the root needs that need to be resolved we can start to bring together the people that need to be involved. We have a guiding direction, now we need to build a collection of selection criteria, determine which among them are requirements, and determine the relative merits of the remaining nice-to-haves. The goal of our next step will be to produce a scorecard we can apply to all of our prospective products in an objective manner.</p>
<h4>Product Selection:</h4>
<ul style="margin-left: 1em; list-style-type: none; ">
<li style="color: #666666; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;">1: Identifying Needs</li>
<li>2: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-requirements-and-scoring" title="Read the 2nd entry">Requirements and Scoring</a></li>
<li>3: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-evaluation" title="Read the third entry">Evaluation</a></li>
<li>4: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/product-selection-reviewing-the-process" title="Read the 4th entry">Review</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/product-selection-identifying-needs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
