<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>glassfish &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/glassfish/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Oracle Details Its Plans For MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice And Open Source</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 09:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Java EE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glassfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netbeans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openoffice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtualization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oracle has updated the Sun Acquisition FAQ. The FAQ now has Oracle's plans for MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice, Open Source and other things.

Below are the relevant pieces from that document.

What are Oracle’s plans fo&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oracle has updated the <a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/sun/038563.pdf">Sun Acquisition FAQ</a>. The FAQ now has Oracle&#8217;s plans for MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice, Open Source and other things.</p>
<p>Below are the relevant pieces from that document.</p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for the GlassFish Enterprise (Java<br />
EE) Server after the transaction closes?</strong><br />
Oracle plans to continue evolving GlassFish Enterprise Server, delivering<br />
it as the open source reference implementation (RI) of the Java Enterprise<br />
Edition (Java EE) specifications, and actively supporting the large GlassFish<br />
community.  Additionally, Oracle plans to invest in aligning common<br />
infrastructure components and innovations from Oracle WebLogic Server<br />
and GlassFish Enterprise Server to benefit both Oracle WebLogic Server and<br />
GlassFish Enterprise Server customers.</p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for NetBeans?</strong><br />
Oracle has a strong track record of demonstrating commitment to choice for<br />
Java developers. As such, NetBeans is expected to provide an additional open<br />
source option and complement to the two free tools Oracle already offers for<br />
enterprise Java development: Oracle JDeveloper and Oracle Enterprise Pack for<br />
Eclipse. While Oracle JDeveloper remains Oracle’s strategic development tool<br />
for the broad portfolio of Oracle Fusion Middleware products and for Oracle’s<br />
next generation of enterprise applications, developers will be able to use<br />
whichever free tool they are most comfortable with for pure Java and Java EE<br />
development:  JDeveloper, Enterprise Pack for Eclipse, or NetBeans. </p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for MySQL?</strong><br />
Oracle plans to spend more money developing MySQL than Sun does now.<br />
Oracle expects to continue to develop and provide the open source MySQL<br />
database after the transaction closes. Oracle plans to add MySQL to Oracle’s<br />
existing suite of database products, which already includes Berkeley DB, an<br />
open source database. Oracle also currently offers InnoDB, an open source<br />
transactional storage engine and the most important and popular transaction<br />
engine under MySQL. Oracle already distributes MySQL as part of our<br />
Enterprise Linux offering.</p>
<p><strong>What is Oracle’s plan for OpenOffice?</strong><br />
Oracle has a history of developing complete, integrated, and open products,<br />
making integration quicker and less costly for our customers. Based on the<br />
open ODF standard, OpenOffice is expected to create a compelling desktop<br />
integration bridge for our enterprise customers and offers consumers another<br />
choice on the desktop. After the transaction closes, Oracle plans to continue<br />
developing and supporting OpenOffice as open source. As before, some of<br />
the larger customers will ask for extra assurances, support, and enterprise<br />
tools. For these customers we expect to offer a typical commercial license<br />
option.</p>
<p><strong>How does Oracle support open source?</strong><br />
Oracle has long been committed to developing, supporting, and promoting<br />
open source. Oracle has been, and continues to be, committed to offering<br />
choice, flexibility, and a lower cost of computing for end users. Oracle<br />
has invested significant resources in developing, testing, optimizing and<br />
supporting open source technologies such as Linux, PHP, Apache, Eclipse,<br />
Berkeley DB, and InnoDB. Oracle continues to embrace and offer open source<br />
solutions as a viable choice for development and deployment. More information<br />
about Oracle’s support of open source can be found at<br />
oracle.com/opensource. </p>
<p><strong>Will Oracle continue Sun’s virtualization strategy?</strong><br />
Yes, Oracle plans to continue Sun’s “desktop to datacenter virtualization”<br />
strategy and integrate with Oracle’s virtualization products. By unifying<br />
management across desktop virtualization, server virtualization, storage<br />
virtualization, and network virtualization, Oracle and Sun provide<br />
comprehensive, flexible, eco-efficient solutions to maximize utilization,<br />
consolidate to reduce costs, increase productivity, and decrease management<br />
complexity. We expect to continue Sun’s desktop virtualization products:<br />
VDI, Secure Global Desktop, Sun Ray, and VirtualBox.</p>
<p><strong>Delivering increased investment and innovation in Java</strong><br />
Oracle plans to accelerate investment in the Java platform for the<br />
benefit of customers and the Java community. Java is one of the<br />
computer industry’s best-known brands and the Java platform is<br />
one of the industry’s most widely deployed technologies. Oracle has<br />
been a leader in the Java community since the inception of the Java<br />
programming language and already has the world’s largest investment<br />
in the Java platform, which provides the foundation for its Oracle<br />
Fusion Middleware products and its next-generation enterprise<br />
applications.<br />
Oracle plans to not only broaden and accelerate its own investment in the<br />
Java platform, but also plans to increase the commitment to the community<br />
that helps make Java an ubiquitous, innovative platform unified around<br />
open standards. </p>
<p>So what do you think, is there still a reason to fear what will happen to these technologies after this deal closes?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
