<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>book review &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-review-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tableau Dashboard Cookbook by Jen Stirrup</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 08:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DISCLAIMER I received this book through the O’Reilly blogger review program, which I already mentioned in the review of Thinking With Data. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself. TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">DISCLAIMER</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I received this book through the <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/reviews/">O’Reilly blogger review program</a>, which I already mentioned in the review of <a href="/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/">Thinking With Data</a>. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard of Jen Stirrup (<a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/jenstirrup">twitter</a>): she currently holds the PASS board seat for Europe, she has spoken at dozens of different events and has won the PASSion award in 2012. I have watched her speak at the SQL Server Days in Belgium a few times before and this year she will deliver <a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/precon/#jen">a full precon about Power BI and R</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s say I was a little bit excited when I heard she wrote<a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781782177906.do"> a book about Tableau</a>. I had no experience whatsoever with Tableau, but I had seen some demos and visualizations so I was anxious to try out the product. I got myself the book and I downloaded the free trial of <a href="http://www.tableausoftware.com/products/desktop">Tableau Desktop 8.2</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em>Note:</em> the trial is only 10 days, so if you want to finish the entire book in that time period, you better reserve some quality reading time for yourself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2816" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif" alt="tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover" width="180" height="222" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s start with the good stuff. Personally I loved this book and the main reason is because it is very hands-on: there are a lot of examples (or recipes if you follow the cookbook doctrine) that guide you step-by-step through the features of Tableau. For readers inexperienced with Tableau – such as myself – this is a great way to discover the product without being overwhelmed by its many features. Each recipe starts with a short introduction – not too long so it doesn’t get tedious – and then dives directly into the action. At the end there is a small recap of what you just did and how it works and there are optionally some pointers to further references. The book is limited on theory but overloaded with practicalities, which was very appealing to me. I felt I learned a great deal about Tableau by reading this book, but I also realized I just learned the basic functionalities of the product. That’s why this book may not be suited for already advanced users of Tableau; they may not find a lot of new information in this book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">A small disadvantage is that this book is (in theory) already outdated because it deals with Tableau 8.1, while the 8.2 version has just been released. However, I didn’t experience much difficulties over this. The only obvious difference is the import of multiple files, where there is now a much more graphical and easier to use interface to join tables together.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Personally I found that this book is best read from front to back, as the recipes in a single chapter often depend on each other: you start with a blank worksheet and in each recipe you build on top of the other until you end with a working dashboard at the end of the chapter. Also, sometimes chapters depend on the finished dashboard of the previous chapter. This makes it a bit harder to just jump to a chapter in the book and do some recipes. Luckily you can download finished worksheets from the publishers’ website.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What I found a little bit disappointing was the section in the final chapter about R, called <em>Wrapping up with R – dashboards as a tool</em>. I have been toying with the R language lately and I expected to see some cool stuff there. But there was only an introduction on how to install R with a package called Rserve and how to set-up a connection from within Tableau to Rserver. That’s it. No demonstration on how to actually use R with Tableau. I would have liked some more material over there, or maybe something in an addendum. An idea perhaps for a second edition? Anyway, this book is not about R but about Tableau <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Now on to the bad stuff. Quite early on in the book – somewhere in chapter 2 – it became very clear that this book was badly edited. There are no spelling or grammar mistakes – not that I know of – but sometimes screenshots are switched or even wrong. One time a recipe – which is essentially a bulleted list of action points – jumped to the end while skipping a few steps. Sometimes when following the recipe step-by-step, you achieve a different result than what is displayed in a screenshot. Most of the time you can work around those issues by using your mind a bit and by comparing with (hopefully correct) screenshots. It can get annoying after a while, but it didn’t stop me from reading the book (unlike some delicate little flowers who wrote some reviews on Amazon) because there is still very great content inside it. But you would think that with 4 reviewers, 3 proofreaders and 10 (!) editors mistakes like these would have been avoided. I have contacted the author and she told me that the mistakes have been reported and should appear on the Errata page.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">All in all, I recommend this book to people new to Tableau. They will definitely learn enough by this book to take their first steps with Tableau. A job well done by the author, but shame on you Packt Publishing for all those mistakes. Fire those editors please.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">UPDATE: the author (Jen Stirup) has placed <a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/2014/07/packt-tableau-dashboard-cookbook-errata.html">errata about chapter 2 on her blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Naked Statistics</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/naked-statistics/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/naked-statistics/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 12:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naked statistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[statistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I stumbled up on this book review of Naked Statistics by Nathan Yau. The introduction on Amazon promises us the following: Once considered tedious, the field of statistics is rapidly evolving into a discipline Hal Varian, chief economist at Google, has actually called “sexy.” From batting averages and political polls to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">A few weeks ago I stumbled up on this <a href="http://flowingdata.com/2014/05/08/naked-statistics/">book review</a> of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/039334777X">Naked Statistics</a> by <a href="http://flowingdata.com/">Nathan Yau</a>. The introduction on Amazon promises us the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify">Once considered tedious, the field of statistics is rapidly evolving into a discipline Hal Varian, chief economist at Google, has actually called “sexy.” From batting averages and political polls to game shows and medical research, the real-world application of statistics continues to grow by leaps and bounds. How can we catch schools that cheat on standardized tests? How does Netflix know which movies you’ll like? What is causing the rising incidence of autism? As best-selling author Charles Wheelan shows us in Naked Statistics, the right data and a few well-chosen statistical tools can help us answer these questions and more.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify">I decided to take a look at it since I could really use a refresh on my statistics knowledge. As promised, the book is a really basic introduction to some general statistics concepts, such as probability, descriptive statistics, regression, statistical interference, polling and the central limit theorem.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://amzn.to/1HvgVzV"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2641 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Naked-Statistics.jpg" alt="Naked-Statistics" width="166" height="250" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Throughout the book, the author uses compelling anecdotes and use cases that really explain the subject matter at a comprehensible, attractive and accessible level. There are almost no formulas in this book, so you probably don’t want to use this book as reference material, but it keeps the subject matter rather light. It also give you a bunch of fun stories that you can use to explain statistical concepts to others. For me, this was one of the greatest strengths of the book. I have a basic background on statistics (although the course was 10 years ago and it was given by quite a boring professor), but the examples used in the book made more practical sense than the traditional “I’m pulling some colored marbles out of an urn”.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">If you already have quite some background in statistics, this book will be too basic but you can still read it for the funny stories. For everyone else, I absolutely recommend this book, certainly because it sells at a rather low price. What are you waiting for?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/naked-statistics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of The Well-Grounded Java Developer</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/review-of-the-well-grounded/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/review-of-the-well-grounded/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Application Lifecycle Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Java EE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groovy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java functional programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jvm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polyglot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scala]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/01/review-of-the-well-grounded/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a review of The Well-Grounded Java Developer, Vital techniques of Java 7 and polyglot programming. Written by Benjamin J. Evans and Martijn Verburg. The book was published in July, 2012 and it contains 496 pages

This is an excellent&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a review of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290068/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1617290068">The Well-Grounded Java Developer, Vital techniques of Java 7 and polyglot programming</a>. Written by Benjamin J. Evans and Martijn Verburg. The book was published in July, 2012 and it contains 496 pages</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/EnterpriseDev/Denis/evans_cover150.jpg?mtime=1357748948"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/EnterpriseDev/Denis/evans_cover150.jpg?mtime=1357748948" width="150" height="188" style="float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;" /></a>Right from the start I want to say that this is an excellent book and I highly recommend it. One thing you do need to be aware about is that in order to use this book you need to know Java. If you don&#8217;t know Java then this is not the book for you. This book is all about bringing you to the next level as a Java developer by showing you how to do continuous integration, dependency injection, testing, performance tuning, and more.<br />
This book even shows you how to use different languages that run on the JVM. The book is written in a easy and concise style, everything is very clear. I also love the annotations which are sprinkled throughout the book, they give some nice background information. While the chapters on Groovy, Scala and Clojure are not a complete reference for the language, they do provide enough material to form a nice foundation, now you can further explore the language on your own.</p>
<p>The book is split up in four parts, I will list each part with the chapters within that part and will give a brief summary what the part is about</p>
<p><strong>Part 1 Developing with Java 7</strong><br />
Chapter 1 Introducing Java 7<br />
Chapter 2 New I/O</p>
<p>This section shows you what was added in Java 7, for example you can now use strings in switch statements, try-with-resources(similar to a using statement in c#, it frees up the resources after it is done). The Java IO stuff has been rewritten and much easier to use, where you had to write a whole bunch of code before, you can now do the same in much less code. Some things that did not exist in Java in terms of IO but now does exist are explained as well.</p>
<p><strong>Part 2 Vital techniques</strong><br />
Chapter 3 Dependency Injection<br />
Chapter 4 Modern concurrency<br />
Chapter 5 Class files and bytecode<br />
Chapter 6 Understanding performance tuning</p>
<p>This part has a lot of stuff and as a Java developer you should really know how this stuff works if you want to get to the next level. Dependency Injection(DI) and inversion of control (IoC) are covered, Guice 3, the reference implementation for DI in Java is also covered. Concurrency before Java 5 and concurrency now is covered. Concurrency will be a must now that we have multi-CPU and multi-core everywhere, you better get your wits around it. There is a whole chapter on the class files itself and how they are loaded as well as what they compile into. These are fun details and will show you exactly what happens when you compile and execute a class. Evereybody&#8217;s favorite subject performance tuning is covered in this part of the book as well.</p>
<p><strong>Part 3 Polyglot programming on the JVM</strong><br />
Chapter 7 Alternative JVM languages<br />
Chapter 8 Groovy: Java’s dynamic friend<br />
Chapter 9 Scala: powerful and concise<br />
Chapter 10 Clojure: safer programming</p>
<p>This is a very interesting part of the book and I would suggest not to skip it. There are 3 type of languages covered in this part:<br />
Groovy, a dynamic language<br />
Scala, a functional language<br />
Clojure, a Lisp for functional programming</p>
<p>Take a look at these languages and you will be amazed how much Java boilerplate code you can eliminate by using these languages instead. Some of the functional is a little bit of a paradigm shift and you might need some time adjusting. You will also see how you can interoperate between these languages and Java.</p>
<p><strong>Part 4 Crafting the polyglot project</strong><br />
Chapter 11 Test-driven development<br />
Chapter 12 Build and continuous integration<br />
Chapter 13 Rapid web development<br />
Chapter 14 Staying well-grounded</p>
<p>The last part is all about automation and making your life easier. If you are a developer who still deploys stuff by using FTP to move JAR, EAR and WAR files, pay attention. Maven is covered as the build automation tool, Jenkins is the  continuous integration tool. In the Rapid web development chapter Grails is explored.</p>
<hr />
Let me just repeat again that I think this is an awesome book and as a Java developer you have to check it out. The one thing that is missing from the book is ORM, it is covered a little in the testing chapter but if you want to know about ORM, you will need to pick out some other book just for that.</p>
<p>You can download the following chapters to get a feel for the book</p>
<p><a href="http://www.manning.com/evans/TWGJD_sample_ch01.pdf">Sample chapter 1</a><br />
<a href="http://www.manning.com/evans/TWGJD_sample_ch04.pdf">Sample chapter 4</a></p>
<p>Head on over to Amazon for other reviews of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290068/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1617290068">The Well-Grounded Java Developer, Vital techniques of Java 7 and polyglot programming</a><br />
The site for the book can be found here: http://www.manning.com/evans/ </p>
<hr />
Below is the complete table of contents so that you have a little more details about each chapter.</p>
<p><strong>Part 1 Developing with Java 7<br />
Chapter 1 Introducing Java 7<br />
</strong>The language and the platform<br />
Small is beautiful—Project Coin<br />
The changes in Project Coin<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 2 New I/O</strong><br />
Java I/O—a history<br />
Path—a foundation of file-based I/O<br />
Dealing with directories and directory trees<br />
Filesystem I/O with NIO.2<br />
Asynchronous I/O operations<br />
Tidying up Socket-Channel functionality<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Part 2 Vital techniques<br />
Chapter 3 Dependency Injection</strong><br />
Inject some knowledge—understanding IoC and DI<br />
Standardized DI in Java<br />
Guice 3—the reference implementation for DI in Java<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 4 Modern concurrency</strong><br />
Concurrency theory—a primer<br />
Block-structured concurrency (pre-Java 5)<br />
Building blocks for modern concurrent applications<br />
Controlling execution<br />
The fork/join framework<br />
The Java Memory Model (JMM)<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 5 Class files and bytecode</strong><br />
Classloading and class objects<br />
Using method handles<br />
Examining class files<br />
Bytecode<br />
Invokedynamic<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 6 Understanding performance tuning</strong><br />
Performance terminology—some basic definitions<br />
A pragmatic approach to performance analysis<br />
What went wrong? Why we have to care<br />
A question of time—from the hardware up<br />
Garbage collection<br />
JIT compilation with HotSpot<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Part 3 Polyglot programming on the JVM<br />
Chapter 7 Alternative JVM languages<br />
</strong>Java too clumsy? Them’s fighting words!<br />
Language zoology<br />
Polyglot programming on the JVM<br />
How to choose a non-Java language for your project<br />
How the JVM supports alternative languages<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 8 Groovy: Java’s dynamic friend</strong><br />
Getting started with Groovy<br />
Groovy 101—syntax and semantics<br />
Differences from Java—traps for new players<br />
Groovy features not (yet) in Java<br />
Interoperating between Groovy and Java<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 9 Scala: powerful and concise</strong><br />
A quick tour of Scala<br />
Is Scala right for my project?<br />
Making code beautiful again with Scala<br />
Scala’s object model—similar but different<br />
Data structures and collections<br />
Introduction to actors<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 10 Clojure: safer programming</strong><br />
Introducing Clojure<br />
Looking for Clojure—syntax and semantics<br />
Working with functions and loops in Clojure<br />
Introducing Clojure sequences<br />
Interoperating between Clojure and Java<br />
Concurrent Clojure<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Part 4 Crafting the polyglot project<br />
Chapter 11 Test-driven development<br />
</strong>TDD in a nutshell<br />
Test doubles<br />
Introducing ScalaTest<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 12 Build and continuous integration</strong><br />
Getting started with Maven 3<br />
Maven 3—a quick-start project<br />
Maven 3—the Java7developer build<br />
Jenkins—serving your CI needs<br />
Code metrics with Maven and Jenkins<br />
Leiningen<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 13 Rapid web development</strong><br />
The problem with Java-based web frameworks<br />
Criteria in selecting a web framework<br />
Getting started with Grails<br />
Grails quick-start project<br />
Further Grails exploration<br />
Getting started with Compojure<br />
A sample Compojure project—“Am I an Otter or Not?”<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 14 Staying well-grounded</strong><br />
What to expect in Java 8<br />
Polyglot programming<br />
Future concurrency trends<br />
New directions in the JVM</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/review-of-the-well-grounded/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Microsoft SQL Server 2012 T-SQL Fundamentals</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/book-review-microsoft-sql-server-1/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/book-review-microsoft-sql-server-1/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 17:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Axel Achten (axel8s)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t-sql]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/11/book-review-microsoft-sql-server-1/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With a basis as a system engineer, I became a DBA. And DBA's don't often write real DML queries. I can read a query, understand what it's doing but when I need to read one I need BOL the help me out. Taking the 070-457 Transition Your MCTS on SQL Server&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With a basis as a system engineer, I became a DBA. And DBA&#8217;s don&#8217;t often write real DML queries. I can read a query, understand what it&#8217;s doing but when I need to read one I need BOL the help me out. Taking the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/learning/en/us/exam.aspx?ID=70-457">070-457 Transition Your MCTS on SQL Server to MCSA: SQL Server 2012,Part 1</a> exam showed me I&#8217;m strong in database administration but there was room for improvement for my query skills. That&#8217;s why I bought <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0790145321978.do">Microsoft SQL Server 2012 T-SQL Fundamentals</a> by Itzik Ben-Gan (<a href="http://tsql.solidq.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/ItzikBenGan">twitter</a>).</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0790145321978.do"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Axel8s/BRTsql.jpg?mtime=1354044858" width="175" height="214" /></a></div>
<p><b>Chapter 1: Background to T-SQL Querying and Programming</b><br />
When you followed a bunch of trainings and read some books about SQL Server, you will possibly have seen some chapters on the origin and basics of relational databases and the SQL language. But I bet you have never seen a chapter like this one. In a straight and clear way Itzik guides you through the mathematics behind SQL, the flavors and architecture of SQL Server and the definitions of tables en data integrity. Now you&#8217;re ready to stand between other professionals and at least know what they are talking about. For me, they should include these 25 pages in every SQL Server learning book.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 2: Single-Table Queries</b><br />
In the largest chapter of this book, the writer explains every part of the SELECT statement and how these queries are processed by SQL Server. It&#8217;s the basis a user needs to start understanding set-based logic. In the second part of the chapter predicates and operators, CASE expressions, NULL handling, character data, date and time data and even metadata is handled. It might seem overwhelming for starters but all the essentials for writing queries are in this chapter.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 3: Joins</b><br />
I thought I knew how joins work, but after this chapter I know a lot more. All join types are explained in detail including a subchapter Beyond the Fundamentals. And again explained in such a clear way. My students will certainly benefit from this.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 4: Subqueries</b><br />
The chapter starts with the self-contained subqueries, that are easy to understand and moves on to the correlated subqueries and shows the power of them. The EXISTS predicate is also well explained. In the beyond the fundamentals of the chapter some examples are shown on how to build windowing functionality without the windowing functions. The only disadvantage in the chapter is the fact that SOME, ANY and ALL are not covered because they are rarely used. From experience I know they might show up on Microsoft exams.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 5: Table Expressions</b><br />
A beautiful chapter where you will learn to write real powerful queries using derived tables, Common Table Expressions, Views , Functions and the APPLY operator. You&#8217;ll see the true value of these expressions when you see the complex definitions of the exercises and the simple queries you need in the solution.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 6: Set Operators</b><br />
UNION, INTERSECT, EXCEPT will have no more secrets for you, the writer even shows you how to create queries to implement the INTERSECT and EXCEPT ALL operators that are supported in Standard SQL but are not implemented in T-SQL.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 7: Beyond the Fundamentals of Querying</b><br />
Everybody has heard of the new Windowing functions in SQL 2012 but little people can explain it as clear and simple as it&#8217;s written down in this book. Also pivoting is explained again and all the possibilities of groupings and grouping sets are written out in plain T-SQL and with use of the functions so you can really see what the different key words are doing. So the chapter goes indeed beyond the fundamentals, but I would mark it as one of the essentials you should learn about T-SQL</p>
<p><b>Chapter 8: Data Modification</b><br />
The basics of INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE and MERGE, BULK INSERT, Identities and Sequences all well explained. But then UPDATE based on a JOIN, DELETE with TOP and OFFSET-FETCH and off course the OUTPUT clause with all its possibilities. I think a lot of production code will be optimized after reading this chapter.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 9: Transactions and Concurrency</b><br />
The chapter starts with the theory of transactions, locks, blocks and some copy and paste code to start troubleshooting blocking issues on your production servers. But the decent explanation of how the Isolation Levels work with simple examples makes it understandable for everyone.</p>
<p><b>Chapter 10: Programmable Objects</b><br />
The last chapter in the book is about variables, batches, cursors, procedures,etc. &#8230; And because they are not considered as fundamentals you get an overview with decent examples to get you started. </p>
<p><b>Conclusion</b><br />
If you need to write queries with T-SQL, this is a book that will get you started. After every chapter you&#8217;ll find also a number of exercises to test what you have learned.</p>
<p>For me the book is decent value for money, now let&#8217;s see when I can schedule my exam.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/book-review-microsoft-sql-server-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
