<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>BEA WebLogic and Aqualogic &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/enterprisedev/appserver/bea/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Back to Java after an eleven year hiatus, what are some good resources you recommend?</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/back-to-java-after-an/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/back-to-java-after-an/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[BEA WebLogic and Aqualogic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Java EE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Websphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eclipse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netbeans]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/11/back-to-java-after-an/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week eleven coworkers and myself will be in Java training for most of the time, I haven't touched Java since 2001. I did a bunch of research over the 4 day weekend to get a little head start.

I installed Netbeans and Eclipse to see how they are&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mrjoro/22752982/" title="Java Logo by mrjoro, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/17/22752982_28bfc98f68_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" alt="Java Logo" /></a></p>
<p>This week eleven coworkers and myself will be in Java training for most of the time, I haven&#8217;t touched Java since 2001. I did a bunch of research over the 4 day weekend to get a little head start.</p>
<p>I installed Netbeans and Eclipse to see how they are different<br />
I played around with Tapestry and took a look at Struts<br />
I used JUnit to write a couple of tests<br />
I installed Maven and used that to bring down the sample Tapestry project<br />
I installed and configured HyperSQL (with sa and blank password&#8230;  ouch!!!)</p>
<p>It seems to me that there are a whole lot of things that I need to know, twelve years ago none of this stuff existed. I also seems to me that the language itself hasn&#8217;t changed so much compared to C#. I might also take a look at Scala down the road, some of that stuff seems interesting. </p>
<p>When I used Java in 2000 and 2001 it was primarily to do JSP development. The main project at that time was converting a ColdFusion site to JSP. The IDE that we used at that time was Kawa, we also gave Visual Cafe a spin. I must say that the IDE is much much better than what existed twelve years ago. Eclipse has a robust plugin system and computers have advanced in speed over the past twelve years so that Java apps don&#8217;t feels slow on the desktop anymore</p>
<p>Over the next five days, I will blog about what I did and learned, I will also probably put some stuff on our wiki so that I can have it as a reference/cheat sheet</p>
<p>Here is my question to you&#8230;..What are some of your favorite resources for Java and the Java ecosystem? I am looking for blogs to subscribe to, people to follow on twitter, if you have a favorite Java book then tell me about it. My favorite books from 2001 were Core Java, Volume I and II, I am happy to see that the 9th edition is coming out on December 10th: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0137081898/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0137081898&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=sql08-20">Core Java Volume I&#8211;Fundamentals (9th Edition) (Core Series)</a>. If you know of any good podcasts then tell me about those as well</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/back-to-java-after-an/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
