<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: PM vs. BA</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/pm-vs-ba/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/pm-vs-ba/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 12:40:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: imnotted</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/projectmanagement/pm-vs-ba/#comment-5809</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[imnotted]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 11:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/01/pm-vs-ba/#comment-5809</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good analysis, Thx. Touching on the thinking processes - Execution (How) versus Context (Why)- might also help delineate the roles. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
PMs execute a plan, even if they did not create the plan. They understand the sequence of events, needs, resources, etc. even if they do not know the technology, the producer, or the ultimate benefit to the organization. Their skills lye in &quot;how&quot; to get things done.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
BAs plan an execution. They tend to be engaged in plan development to ensure the organization contexts drive the work and match the intended outcomes. They understand &quot;why&quot; the work matters even if they are not sure how it will be accomplished. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Of course as you described, many managers view the roles and the people as interchangeable. This might suggest a managers&#039; need to better understand how and why thinking processes, or it may simply be the limits on organization resources these days.&lt;br /&gt;]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good analysis, Thx. Touching on the thinking processes &#8211; Execution (How) versus Context (Why)- might also help delineate the roles. </p>
<p>PMs execute a plan, even if they did not create the plan. They understand the sequence of events, needs, resources, etc. even if they do not know the technology, the producer, or the ultimate benefit to the organization. Their skills lye in &#8220;how&#8221; to get things done.</p>
<p>BAs plan an execution. They tend to be engaged in plan development to ensure the organization contexts drive the work and match the intended outcomes. They understand &#8220;why&#8221; the work matters even if they are not sure how it will be accomplished. </p>
<p>Of course as you described, many managers view the roles and the people as interchangeable. This might suggest a managers&#8217; need to better understand how and why thinking processes, or it may simply be the limits on organization resources these days.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
