<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	>
	<title type="text">Comments on Virtual Lab: Creating a 2008 R2 Domain Controller</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-02-26T12:40:14Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comments" />
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/feed/atom/" />
	<id>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/feed/atom/</id>
<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<title>By: bearhntr28</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-4919754" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>bearhntr28</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-4919754</id>
		<updated>2016-02-17T02:54:01Z</updated>
		<published>2016-02-17T02:54:01Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-4919754"><![CDATA[<p>Here is my delimma, we have a corporate environment and this DC will be only for the lab. In order for the computer to get to the Internet – I have to use one of the DNS entries from the corp network. I have DNS1 = 127.0.0.1 and DNS2=corp DNS1 from computers. The Time is synching with the corp NNTP server.</p>
<p>It is PRIVATE and is not seen by anyone not on accessing the LAB’s Segment (151.114.20.xxx). We have our own subnet for lab printers and computers and other servers. They are used for testing our software products and attempting to replicate customer issues. We have all addresses from .10-.240 in that segment.</p>
<p>We need access to the following — LDAP, CERT AUTH, AD, EXCHANGE 2013 (I plan to install on the DC), and we have a SQL server which will need to use the AD Accounts from this server once setup.</p>
<p>I have built it once, and could not get anything to properly work — the EVALUATE THIS ROLE would give all sorts of errors. I thought I would try SBS 2011, as we are replacing an SBS 2003 server with this one (it will be retired). I gave with SBS 2011 this weekend, when I could not get it to talk to the Internet without putting a ROUTER on the desk where the server sits and configuring it to be the pass through – as the INET Wizard kept seeing the CORP DHCP and DNS and failing out.</p>
<p>Right now the only ROLE I have on in the server is AD DOMAIN SERVICES and DNS (as I have run DCPROMO already. Eventually I would like to have the following:</p>
<p>1) LDAP capabilities for use on other computers and printers to authenticate and do email addr lookups.</p>
<p>2) CERT AUTH for creating SSL certs to test SSL in the environment.</p>
<p>3) Every user have a HOME FOLDER and EMAIL (Exchange 2013) through Outlook Web.</p>
<p>4) Service accounts and Groups to use for managing users – our old DC everyone knew the DOMAIN ADMIN and LOCAL ADMIN password and trashed the server.</p>
<p>5) I am not seeing a NEW USER WIZARD like in SBS 2011 (and SBS 2003) that can use templates to create a new user with EMAIL and FOLDER and allow you to choose different templates for them which puts them into specific groups.</p>
<p>I am fairly proficient with setting up a DC (have one at home). but I think part of my problem comes from the DC within a corp environment and I have been told that it cannot broadcast DHCP or DNS info to the network. So it needs to be only seen by machines where we set the DNS1 entry to its IP ADDRESS to setup authentication on them, or once the computer is added to the domain (ASCLAB.local).</p>
<p>I have scoured the Internet looking for a walk through to do this, and one was pretty close – but I was getting tons of errors in the ROLE CHECKS. I am not skeerd of Yellow Triangles – it is the Red Circles that get me.  🙂</p>
<p>If anyone has any ideas on how best to get this done – a website, a forum, anything – I would be so grateful.</p>
<p>Curtis</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: mansoor</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2755" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>mansoor</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2755</id>
		<updated>2012-08-16T09:52:02Z</updated>
		<published>2012-08-16T09:52:02Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2755"><![CDATA[<p>Hi i was actually searching for virtual labs where i can implement myself. for example there is a article in this website creatind Domain Controllers. but i want virtual lab where i can do to get experience</p>
<p>thanks in advance</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2754" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2754</id>
		<updated>2011-01-09T11:58:48Z</updated>
		<published>2011-01-09T11:58:48Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2754"><![CDATA[<p>If you are planning on setting up the combined DNS/Domain controller, then you will want to give it a static address so either your switch can reference it and hand it out to DHCP clients or your individual machines can be configured with it manually. Short of  a specialized multi-cast DNS (or zeroconf if it&#8217;s a small network?) setup, you have to have the IP address of a DNS server in order to ask it for name resolution, if it is constantly changing (DHCP) then you will be forced to update all of your other systems regularly with the new address.</p>
<p>Pick an address outside of the dynamic range in your switch and use that one (this will guarantee none of your other systems will accidentally be provided the same address). One digit higher or lower than your switch, or completely opposite (ie .1 and .254) might be easy to remember.</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Prakash Heda</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2753" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Prakash Heda</name>
			<uri>http://www.starinnovative.com/</uri>
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2753</id>
		<updated>2011-01-09T03:25:43Z</updated>
		<published>2011-01-09T03:25:43Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2753"><![CDATA[<p>My home network has defined ranges and already has a DNS server, so these servers will all receive addresses in the 51-99 range and they will have the non-virtual DNS server listed as a secondary DNS. </p>
<p>This is probably why I guess its not working for me&#8230;can you provide details to configure DHCP as well to make this article work on generic scenerio&#8230;thanks ~ Prakash</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2757" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2757</id>
		<updated>2010-06-07T08:13:57Z</updated>
		<published>2010-06-07T08:13:57Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2757"><![CDATA[<p>Sachin, that might be a better question for the forums. When you say the system is not responding, do you mean you can&#8217;t ping it, remote desktop isn&#8217;t work, or you can&#8217;t open the console window (VMWare console, VPC, Virtual Server, &#8230; not sure what you are using). <br />
If you cannot access it on the network then you likely assigned it an IP address that is not on the correct subnet or that is inaccessible from the system you are trying to connect from. If you are trying to connect by name, try using the ip address instead, it may be a DNS resolution issue. Lastly, if you are trying to use the remote console for your virtualization platform, i would need to know which platform you are on before I could make any guesses.<br />
Generally the console for your virtualization product should continue to work, no mater what&#8217;s wrong with the system. Try using that and the administrator account to log into the system and verify the network settings and see if any error entries are showing in the event log.</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Sachin Shah</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2756" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Sachin Shah</name>
			<uri>http://www.sachinshah.in/</uri>
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2756</id>
		<updated>2010-06-07T07:24:03Z</updated>
		<published>2010-06-07T07:24:03Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/#comment-2756"><![CDATA[<p>Hi, </p>
<p>I had followed same steps on my i7 Processor computer. But System is not repsonding after reboot.. What can be issue ??</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2010/05/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/virtual-lab-creating-a-2008-r2-domain-co/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
</feed>
