<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>microsoft &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/microsoft/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Speaking at ITPROceed 2015</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/speaking-at-itproceed-2015/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/speaking-at-itproceed-2015/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 08:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[itproceed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power bi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speaking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3383</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This year I have the opportunity again to speak at ITPROceed, the biggest (Microsoft-related) conference in Belgium for the IT professional. The conference takes place the 11th of June at Utopolis Mechelen. My session is situated in the Data Platform &#38; Internet of Things track and is titled Demystifying Power BI. Basically it introduces the full Power [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year I have the opportunity again to speak at <a href="http://azure.itproceed.be/">ITPROceed</a>, the biggest (Microsoft-related) conference in Belgium for the IT professional. The conference takes place the 11th of June at Utopolis Mechelen. My session is situated in the <em>Data Platform &amp; Internet of Things</em> track and is titled <em><span style="color: #000000">Demystifying Power</span></em><span style="color: #000000"> BI. Basically it introduces the full Power BI stack and highlights what you can use for which purpose in order to get rid of some of the confusion that lives in the market place. The abstract:</span></p>
<p>Is it an on-line cloud BI-platform? Or is it a collection of Excel add-ins? Is it a SharePoint feature? Or an off-line dashboard designer? It’s all that and even more.<br />
Power BI has many faces and this session aims to give a clear overview of what Power BI – Microsoft newest BI offering – is and what it isn’t.<br />
You will learn how you can use Power BI in your environment and how you can bring self-service BI to the next level.</p>
<p>You can check the full agenda <a href="http://azure.itproceed.be/agenda/">here</a>. There is still room available, so hurry up and register <a href="http://azure.itproceed.be/registration/">here</a>. Oh wait, I didn&#8217;t mention the best part yet: the event is totally free!</p>
<p>See you at ITPROceed!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/itproceed.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3384" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/itproceed.png" alt="itproceed" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/speaking-at-itproceed-2015/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rants about Connect</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/rants-about-connect/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/rants-about-connect/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 12:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Excel Reporting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[powerpivot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssas tabular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/07/rants-about-connect/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The site connect.microsoft.com is a wonderful concept: you can provide feedback about the Microsoft products, report bugs and give suggestions directly to the teams responsible for those products. People can vote on items to indicate them as more import&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The site <a href="/connect.microsoft.com">connect.microsoft.com</a> is a wonderful concept: you can provide feedback about the Microsoft products, report bugs and give suggestions directly to the teams responsible for those products. People can vote on items to indicate them as more important.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">At least, that’s the theory. It’s been known that the communication from Microsoft can be improved. For example: bugs that are closed as “by design” of “not reproducible” without any  (or very little) feedback from Microsoft. Don’t get me wrong, also a lot of good stuff happens on that site. But two of these “miscommunications” got a bit on my nerve the last few days.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Prompt pages in Reporting Services</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A few years back I was working with Cognos to develop reports. They have a wonderful concept there, called <em>Prompt Pages</em>. Essentially it is a separate set of report pages which are called before the report is ran. Inside those prompt pages, you can place your various prompts to populate your report parameters. And you have full customizability. You can put everything where you want it, how you want it. Here’s a very basic example I found with a quick Google search:</p>
<p><a href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/ConnectRants/promptpage_example.png?mtime=1375101805"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/ConnectRants/promptpage_example.png?mtime=1375101805" alt="" width="385" height="385" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You can imagine the shock I went through when I first saw the Reporting Services prompts. Anyway, there’s been a Connect item logged to request a similar feature: <a style="text-align: justify;" href="http://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/details/545893/allow-ssrs-parameter-panel-to-be-formatted">Allow SSRS Parameter Panel to be formatted</a>. It has 71 votes at the time of writing, which is quite high for a Connect item. It has been logged in 2010 and Microsoft said a feature like this will be availabe in the next version of Reporting Services.  That’s SQL Server 2012. I don’t see it in this list: <a style="text-align: justify;" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms170438.aspx">What&#8217;s New (Reporting Services)</a>. I guess they were too busy with Power View. That’s cool, new shiny products are nice, but it doesn’t mean you need to neglect your already established widely used products (such as Analysis Services MultiDimensional by the way). Especially not when it is a highly requested feature like this one. So please, go to the Connect item and vote it up so that it might be included in SQL Server 2014!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>The PowerPivot vs SSAS Tabular bug</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There’s a rather nasty bug that pops up when you try to modify a PowerPivot model in Excel 2013 while you have an SSAS Tabular instance running on the same machine. You get this error:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>We couldn’t load the Data Model. This may be because the Data Model in the workbook is damaged.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The solution is quite simple: disable the SSAS Tabular service and you can edit your PowerPivot model. But this isn’t a real solution, isn’t it?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Julie Koesmarno (<a href="http://www.mssqlgirl.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/MsSQLGirl">twitter</a>) has an entire blog post on the subject: <a href="http://www.mssqlgirl.com/powerpivot-2013-error-data-model-damaged.html">PowerPivot 2013 Error: Data Model Damaged</a>. She also logged the Connect item for this bug: <a href="http://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/details/780949/powerpivot-couldnt-load-data-model-when-ssas-tabular-instance-is-running#tabs">PowerPivot couldn&#8217;t load Data Model when SSAS Tabular Instance is running</a>. However, Microsoft closed the Connect item, as it is <em>Not Reproducible</em>, although 2 users have marked this bug as reproducible. I’d appreciate it if you went to Connect and voted this bug up, because this one is driving me mad! Especially when I want to load SSAS Tabular data into a PowerPivot model…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/rants-about-connect/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I prepared myself for the MCSE certification</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/how-i-prepared-mcse/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/how-i-prepared-mcse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[certification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mcsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mcse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/04/how-i-prepared-mcse/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This blog details my preparation for the MCSE - Business Intelligence certification.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">Last week I took the final exam to acquire the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/learning/en/us/mcse-sql-business-intelligence.aspx#fbid=EmSJ9xHTLm0">MCSE – Business Intelligence</a> certification. This blog post describes my preparation for all of the exams. It is not a strict guideline of course, it’s just what suited best for me.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The MCSE certification exists of 5 separate exams, of which the first 3 grant you the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/learning/en/us/mcsa-sql-certification.aspx#fbid=EmSJ9xHTLm0">MCSA SQL Server</a> certification. These are the following:</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify">
<li>70-461: Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012</li>
<li>70-462: Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Databases</li>
<li>70-463: Implementing a Data Warehouse with Microsoft SQL Server 2012</li>
<li>70-466: Implementing Data Models and Reports with Microsoft SQL Server 2012</li>
<li>70-467: Designing Business Intelligence Solutions with Microsoft SQL Server 2012</li>
</ul>
<p><a style="text-align: justify" href="/media/users/koenverbeeck/MCSEPrep/MCSE.jpg?mtime=1365060226"><img style="float: left;margin-left: 10px;margin-right: 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/MCSEPrep/MCSE.jpg?mtime=1365060226" alt="" width="300" height="171" /></a></p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: justify">The MCSA exams are the same for everyone; it doesn’t matter if you are going for the MCSE – Business Intelligence or for MCSE – Data Platform. Personally I like this decision, as everyone with the MCSA has the same common ground in the SQL Server platform. There’s always some overlap between the tasks a specific role is supposed to do. For example, DBA’s need SSIS from time to time to move data around and BI developers might need to set-up replication to feed a reporting database. Forcing everyone to do the same exams ensures certification holders have a certain skill set in the most important aspects of SQL Server.</div>
<p><span style="text-align: justify">Before I started my certification spree on SQL Server 2012, I already had the three MCTS certifications for SQL Server 2008 (BI, DBA en database developer) and the MCITP: Business Intelligence Developer 2008. So I only had to refresh the older material &#8211; especially the DBA stuff – and learn all the new features. Why didn’t I took the upgrade exams? Because I like to challenge myself and I wanted to make sure I learned as much as possible in the progress.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>70-463</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This is the first exam that I took. It deals mostly with SSIS, but has also some sections about DQS, MDS and dimensional modeling. I took this exam a year ago in beta, so there were no preparation materials available. Luckily I consider myself quite proficient in SSIS, so I didn’t need much preparation. After all, if you are going for one of the MCSE certifications, you should have at least one specialization in the SQL Server stack.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I learned about the new SSIS features (which was Denali CTP1 at the time) by giving a session on the Belgian SQL Server Days in 2011:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/video/working-with-the-new-project-deployment-model-in-ssis-for-dummies-smarties.aspx"><em>Working with the New Project Deployment Model in SSIS for Dummies/Smarties</em></a><em> </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">You learn a lot about something by trying to teach others about it. Of course I also read a lot of blog posts about the subject, of which most of them are mentioned in the video. I gave the same presentation again for the SQLLunchUK user group, but this time through a LiveMeeting.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">A few years back I read <a href="http://amzn.to/1fpLRrp">The Data Warehouse Toolkit</a> by Ralph Kimball. Every serious BI professional should read this book, even if you are an adept Inmon follower. This book gives you all the details you need about dimensional modeling: star schemas, slowly changing dimensions, table grains et cetera. Microsoft relies heavily on the Kimball approach, in the data warehouse design but also in Analysis Services Multidimensional.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Regarding Data Quality Services (DQS), I also mastered the basics by giving a session. This time a webinar for the Belgian 12 Hours of SQL:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/video/an-introduction-to-data-quality-services-dqs.aspx"><em>An introduction to Data Quality Services (DQS)</em></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Most information about DQS I got from MSDN articles, such as these <a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sqlserver/jj737674">How-To videos</a>, and from TechEd videos, like this excellent one from Elad Ziklik: <a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/TechEd/NorthAmerica/2011/DBI207">Using Knowledge to Cleanse Data with Data Quality Services</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The last item on the list for this exam is Master Data Services (MDS). Since it only takes a small percentage of the questions and I’m not really convinced by the product – to be honest – I didn’t put much investigation to it. I read the free e-book <a href="http://amzn.to/1LlkyNj">Introducing SQL Server 2012 training kit</a>, so I at least knew how to handle the product.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The exam itself went pretty well, although I struggled a bit with the <a href="http://mediadl.microsoft.com/mediadl/www/l/learning/video/certification/exam/repeated_answer_series.wmv">Repeated Answer Choices</a> questions, since it was the first time I ever saw those type of questions and took a few seconds before I realized what was going on J</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>70-461</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Every person working closely with SQL Server, be it a DBA, a database developer or a BI developer, should know at least the basics of T-SQL. So this exam shouldn’t be too hard for most people. To prepare myself, I read the book <a href="http://amzn.to/1LlkInS">SQL Server 2012 High-Performance T-SQL Using Window Functions</a> by Itzik Ben-Gan to learn more about the windowing functions introduced in SQL Server 2012. I can absolutely recommend this book to everyone to get up to speed with Windowing Functions in SQL Server. Itzik really does a great job by explaining all the concepts very clearly and uses a lot of practical examples. A must-read.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Next I read blog posts and MSDN articles about the new T-SQL functionality, such as TRY_PARSE, THROW and LAG/LEAD. <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/09f0096e-ab95-4be0-8c01-f98753255747">This MSDN page</a> gives a nice overview. Since the exam might contain questions that require you to write code, I refreshed my knowledge on the syntax of the several TSQL statements. Finally I re-read the chapters about T-SQL of the <a href="http://amzn.to/1PmAAUY">training kit for the 70-433 exam</a>, especially the one about XML. Because you know, I use this everyday so I’m an expert at it (uh-hum. Irony).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I passed the exam on the first try, but I have to admit that the code writing questions are harder than it seems when you have no MSDN pages available to check your syntax.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>70-462</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This was the exam I feared the most. I’m certainly no DBA and although I already had the MCTS for administrating SQL Server 2008, I had to relearn almost everything again as I didn’t have much real-time practice regarding administration. So I took my time preparing myself for the exam, going over the <a href="http://amzn.to/1fpNe9s">training kit</a> a few times and watching some TechEd videos on Channel9.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I did all the exercises of the training kit by setting up a virtual environment with a few servers using HyperV and doing all the DBA stuff such as mirroring, replication database, taking back-ups et cetera. The training kit briefly describes how to set this environment up, but it really doesn’t go in too much detail, so you’re pretty much on your own. If you have never heard of differencing disks for virtual machines before – like I did – prepare yourself to do some research. There was especially no information on how to set-up the networking, which appears to be crucial when you went to set-up clustering, as you need to have multiple networks. I briefly go over my set-up in this <a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/Forums/Topic1377933-10-1.aspx#bm1421996">forum thread</a>. The training kit and the matching practice tests also have some errors, so make sure to check out the <a href="http://oreilly.com/catalog/errataunconfirmed.csp?isbn=0790145345134">Errata</a> page of the book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/learning/en/us/certification-exams.aspx#fbid=HsP2QW2phvi">new types of exam questions</a> (check the section <em>Exam formats and question types</em>) also include drag-and-drop questions, so I focused on learning the correct sequence to do something. For example, how to set up mirroring, replication or Availability Groups, how to do a partial restore, how to upgrade a cluster et cetera.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">All in all the training kit did a good job preparing me for the exam, as I passed it on the first try, but my score really wasn’t that impressive. But hey, what do you expect from a BI guy J Finishing this exam gave me the MCSA certification.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>70-466</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">After a few months of well deserved “non-studying for exams” I decided to pick up the pace again and to start preparing for the 70-466 exam. I was in between projects at the time, so it was excellent timing to get some studying done.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I started by reading the excellent book <a href="http://amzn.to/1Lll6Ts">Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Analysis Services: The BISM Tabular Model</a> by SSAS Maestros Chris Webb, Alberto Ferrari and Marco Russo, which comes at a whopping 656 pages. It’s a great book and it will teach you everything you need to know about tabular models and DAX, but actually it’s much too detailed for just exam preparation. But hey, a little too much knowledge doesn’t hurt anyone, right? So if you just want to get up to speed with SSAS tabular you can skip a few chapters, such as DAX Advanced for example.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">For SSAS multidimensional and Reporting Services, I just re-read the relevant chapters of <a href="http://amzn.to/1fpNzJi">the 70-448 training kit</a>, giving more attention to features I don’t use a lot, like pro-active caching, MDX (I know, sorry Chris Webb) and administrating SSAS and SSRS servers. I skipped the data mining chapter, as it apparently didn’t make the exam <em>Skills Measured</em> section. I digged deeper into SSAS and SSRS administration by reading relevant blogs and MSDN articles, such as <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms157403.aspx">Reporting Services Execution and Trace Logging</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The exam went pretty well on the first try and thus I had only one exam left for the MCSE certification!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>70-467</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The exam was really interesting to study for. You can compare it a bit to the MCITP – Business Intelligence exam. What makes it so interesting is that everything comes together in this exam. You need to know about SSIS, SSAS (multidimensional and tabular), SSRS (Report Designer, Report Builder, Power View, PowerPivot and PerformancePoint) and SharePoint integration in order to succeed. Everything just comes together.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">To prepare myself I went over <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/learning/en/us/course.aspx?id=20467a#fbid=HsP2QW2phvi">course 20467A: Designing Business Intelligence Solutions with Microsoft SQL Server 2012</a>, which is a fascinating read. I revisited some chapters about administration for SSRS and SSAS and I dug a bit deeper into SharePoint integration (but let’s face it, I’ll never get that Kerberos authentication thingy).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The exam itself wasn’t that easy, but I managed to get through, so now I’m the proud holder of the MCSE – Business Intelligence certification!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This was my entire preparation. I’m done now with exams for a while J</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">If you have interesting reading materials or videos that can help other preparing themselves for their exams, please share them in the comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/how-i-prepared-mcse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://mediadl.microsoft.com/mediadl/www/l/learning/video/certification/exam/repeated_answer_series.wmv" length="613282" type="video/x-ms-wmv" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Have you Tried Out Microsoft TFS 2010?</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/application-lifecycle-management/have-you-tried-out-tfs2010/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/application-lifecycle-management/have-you-tried-out-tfs2010/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Application Lifecycle Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[team foundation server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tfs 2010]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/05/have-you-tried-out-tfs2010/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Several times I found myself wanting to try out different features of TFS 2010, but my only options appeared to be building a virtual machine (time consuming and requires gobs of money or an MSDN/TechNet subscription) or using a live server as a guinea pig (for some reason admins frown on this). Luckily there's an easier option, I just wasn't aware of it until last week.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several times I found myself wanting to try out different features of TFS 2010, but my only options appeared to be building a virtual machine (time consuming and requires gobs of money or an MSDN/TechNet subscription) or using a live server as a guinea pig (for some reason admins frown on this). Luckily there&#8217;s an easier option, I just wasn&#8217;t aware of it until last week.</p>
<p>Microsoft has virtual machine images for a full TFS 2010 server installation, along with sample labs if you&#8217;re just getting started with TFS.</p>
<p><b>Downloads:</b></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=e0198b64-4acb-4709-b07f-359fb4d523bc" title="Download Hyper-V image">Visual Studio 2010 RTM (Hyper-V)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=509c3ba1-4efc-42b5-b6d8-0232b2cbb26e" title="Download Win 7 Virtual PC Image">Visual Studio 2010 RTM (Windows [7] Virtual PC)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=5e13b15a-fd74-4cd7-b53e-bdf9456855bd" title="Download Virtual PC 2007 Image">Visual Studio 2010 RTM (Virtual PC 2007 SP1)</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/briankel/archive/2011/04/15/getting-started-with-the-team-foundation-server-2010-and-project-server-2010-integration-virtual-machine.aspx">Brian Keller posted more information</a> on the images and what they have included as well as some information to simplify downloading the collection of .rar&#8217;s that compose each image.</p>
<p>Besides trying out the built-in tools, I also intend on playing with some of the additional templates that are out there for project and task management in TFS.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/59ac03e3-df99-4776-be39-1917cbfc5d8e/" title="Download the 1.0 Scrum template">MS Scrum Template 1.0</a></li>
<li><a href="http://scrumforteamsystem.com/" title="Scrum for Team System by EMC">EMC&#8217;s Scrum for Team System</a></li>
</ul>
<p>As if that isn&#8217;t enough, there is a remarkable amount of information at <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/vstudio/ff637362" title="Go to MSDN">MSDN</a> on the test labs, Build process, Branching, Requirements Management, Integration, &#8230; the list goes on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/application-lifecycle-management/have-you-tried-out-tfs2010/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Source Analysis for C# Announced</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/microsoft-source-analysis-for-c-announce/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/microsoft-source-analysis-for-c-announce/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 16:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[C#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/05/microsoft-source-analysis-for-c-announce/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft Source Analysis for C# has been announced. Here is what I found on the Microsoft site: This tool is known internally within Microsoft as StyleCop, and has been used for many years now to help teams enforce a common set of best practices for layout, readability, maintainability, and documentation of C# source code. Source [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Source Analysis for C# has been announced. Here is what I found on the Microsoft site:<br />
<blockquote>This tool is known internally within Microsoft as StyleCop, and has been used for many years now to help teams enforce a common set of best practices for layout, readability, maintainability, and documentation of C# source code.</p>
<p>Source Analysis is similar in many ways to Microsoft Code Analysis (specifically FxCop), but there are some important distinctions. FxCop performs its analysis on compiled binaries, while Source Analysis analyzes the source code directly. For this reason, Code Analysis focuses more on the design of the code, while Source Analysis focuses on layout, readability and documentation. Most of that information is stripped away during the compilation process, and thus cannot be analyzed by FxCop.</p>
<p>The ultimate goal of Source Analysis is to allow you to produce elegant, consistent code that your team members and others who view your code will find highly readable. </p></blockquote>
<p>More info can be found here: http://blogs.msdn.com/sourceanalysis/<br />
Source Analysis for C# can be downloaded here: https://code.msdn.microsoft.com/Release/ProjectReleases.aspx?ProjectName=sourceanalysis.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/microsoft-source-analysis-for-c-announce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
