<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sqlsaturday &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/sqlsaturday/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Announcing SQL Saturday Minnesota #453 Pre-Conference Seminars!</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-453-pre-conference-seminars/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-453-pre-conference-seminars/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Timmerman]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#sqlsat453]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#sqlsatmn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minnesota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pre-cons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlsaturday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3517</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Before we know it, October will be upon us and it will be time for another SQL Saturday Minnesota!  If you have not yet registered for this free day of training on October 10th, please visit the site and sign up now! Since no SQL Saturday Minnesota would be complete without a full slate of pre-cons, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #272727">Before we know it, October will be upon us and it will be time for another <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/453/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQL Saturday Minnesota</a>!  If you have not yet registered for this free day of training on October 10th, please visit the <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/453/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">site</a> and sign up now!</span></p>
<p>Since no <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/453/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank">SQL Saturday Minnesota</a> would be complete without a full slate of pre-cons, <a href="http://passmn.org/" target="_blank">PASSMN</a> and the organizers of SQL Saturday #453 are proud to announce the addition of <strong>four</strong> day long pre-cons to be held on <span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ">Friday, October 9th</span></span> from <span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ">9AM &#8211; 5PM</span></span>. Sessions will once again be held at Dakota County Technical College in Rosemount, MN.</p>
<p>For the low price of only <strong>$99</strong> you could learn how to build a world class data organization from the team at Pragmatic Works, dive into the world of Hadoop with Hortonwork&#8217;s own Bill Preachuk and his PASS Summit 2015 selected pre-con, become a SQL Server security master with Ed Leighton-Dick, or learn everything there is no know about Power BI with Mark Vaillancourt.</p>
<p>Visit the links below to review the complete abstracts for these amazing sessions.</p>
<p>Any one of these sessions represents an amazing value for your training dollars!</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><span style="color: #1155cc"><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday453preconreg/home#PD_BI1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Adam Jorgensen, Jason Strate, Steve Hughes, and Anthony Martin</span></a></span></strong><span style="color: black">: </span><span style="color: #272727">Building World Class Data Organizations</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #1155cc"><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday453preconreg/home#BD1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Bill Preachuk</span></a></span></strong><span style="color: black">: </span><span style="color: #272727">Hadoop Essentials for the SQL Server Professional</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #1155cc"><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday453preconreg/home#DB1" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Ed Leighton-Dick</span></a></span></strong><span style="color: black">: </span><span style="color: #272727">SQL Server Security Master Class</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #1155cc"><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/sqlsaturday453preconreg/home#BI2" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">Mark Vaillancourt</span></a></span></strong><span style="color: black">: </span><span style="color: #272727">Click, Click, WOW: The Exciting World of Power BI</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Upon successful registration, you will receive a confirmation email from the SQLSaturday #453 team within 48 hours.</p>
<p><span style="color: #272727">You may also access this information by visiting the <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/453/eventhome.aspx" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc">SQL </span><span class="aBn"><span class="aQJ"><span style="color: #1155cc">Saturday</span></span></span><span style="color: #1155cc"> #453 homepage</span></a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #272727">Please direct any questions regarding the pre-cons to the SQL Saturday #453 team at </span><a href="mailto:sqlsaturday453@sqlsaturday.com" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc"><span style="color: #1155cc">sqlsaturday453@sqlsaturday.</span>com</span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/announcing-sql-saturday-minnesota-453-pre-conference-seminars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Saturday #46, Raleigh NC</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 10:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlsaturday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/09/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It's been a few days since SQL Saturday 46 and I have finally found some time to jot down my recap. This was the first Raleigh SQL Saturday and it lived up to all of my expectations.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a few days since SQL Saturday 46 and I have finally found some time to jot down my recap. This was the first Raleigh SQL Saturday and it lived up to all of my expectations.</p>
<h2>The Event</h2>
<div style="float: left; margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/volunteers.png" alt="The volunteers that made it happen" /><br />
The excellent group of volunteers <br />that pulled it all together
</div>
<p>There were <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/46/schedule.aspx" title="Check out the full schedule">6 tracks of events</a>, which were balanced more towards the BI and SSIS side of things than the previous events I&#8217;ve attended. Registration was hiccup free (though I was early and missed the rush), rooms were all located in close proximity to one another, and the lunch room flowed pretty quickly despite an early line. The signs and schedule were excellent, with 8.5&#215;11 placards posted for all of the sessions on each room&#8217;s door as well as large grids posted on the wall in two locations, displaying the whole schedule. Once I figured out the room numbering, it was easy to locate the sessions or speakers I was interested in. The event was organized by members of <a href="http://tripass.org/" title="Visit the TriPASS site">TriPASS</a>, the local SQL Server User Group in Raleigh, and I&#8217;m looking forward to getting involved with the next one they put together. If I had to pick one element of the event that characterized it the most, that element would be how smoothly the execution went.</p>
<h2>Sessions</h2>
<div style="float: right; margin: .5em 0 .5em 2em; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/grant.png" alt="Grant Fritchey starting his session" /><br />
Grant Fritchey getting <br /> started on his session
</div>
<p>I started my morning off with Geoff Hiten&#8217;s (<a href="http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/geoffh/default.aspx" title="Geoff Hiten's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/sqlcraftsman" title="SQLCraftsman on Twitter">twitter</a>) &#8220;Clustering for Mere Mortals&#8221; session, which gave me enough basic knowledge that there may be a clustering blog article in the near future. Geoff did an excellent job of communicating a complex task to his audience, balancing just enough background knowledge, direct examples, and good practices from his own experience.</p>
<p>I expanded my CDC knowledge in Chris Skorlinski&#8217;s (<a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/repltalk/" title="Visit Chris's blog">blog</a>) first session, but unfortunately wasn&#8217;t able to make his SSIS + CDC session later in the afternoon (the disadvantage to being in my home town, had to run home to feed the cats). He provided an excellent overview of how CDC works, how to interact with it, and some of the internals behind the magic.</p>
<p>After lunch, I attended Grant Fritchey&#8217;s (<a href="http://scarydba.wordpress.com/" title="Visit Grant's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/GFritchey" title="GFritchey on Twitter">twitter</a>) &#8220;Identifying and Fixing Performance Problems using&#8221; presentation and had a blast (I&#8217;m using the SQL Saturday site-ized version of his presentation name). Despite some demo issues, Grant managed to balance delivery of his presentation with good audience feedback, even taking a 2 minute break in the middle to get everyone up on their feet and fight the post-lunch effects. </p>
<p>After Grant&#8217;s session I caught Andy Leonard&#8217;s (<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andy_leonard/" title="Visit Andy's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/AndyLeonard" title="AndyLeonard on Twitter">twitter</a>) &#8220;SSIS Design Patterns&#8221; session. I was completely out of my depth here, being far more of a beginner in SSIS (it doesn&#8217;t get much more beginner), but I was still able to take away quite a bit of information from the session, including some ideas I will likely try to put into practice in an upcoming project.</p>
<div style="margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/andyquote.png" alt="Andy Leonard Quote" /></div>
<h2>The After-thing</h2>
<p>I managed to run into quite a few of the local members of the user group, who did an excellent job preparing and executing this event. It seemed Janice Lee (<a href="http://janiceclee.com/" title="Visit Janice's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/JaniceLee" title="JaniceLee on Twitter">twitter</a>) and I were constantly running into each other just long enough to share how great our last session was before heading off to two more completely different ones. It was one of these between-session breaks where I got to meet Eric Humphrey (<a href="http://lotsahelp.blogspot.com/" title="Visit Eric's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/lotsahelp" title="Lotsahelp on Twitter">twitter</a>) for the first time, another familiar face from the SQL community on twitter. There were many others I met along the way and at least as many people that I intended to meet but missed (or who snuck out early). </p>
<p>The day ended on a high note, around a table with Grant, Allen White (<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/allen_white/default.aspx" title="Check out Allen's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/sqlrunr" title="SQLRunr on Twitter">twitter</a>), Brent Kremer, and David Elvikis. Stories were traded, good food was eaten (not counting the fried pickles that showed up), and I think we all had a fun time. It was great to find out that Grant and Allen were just two more normal (well, close to normal) people like the rest of us. Somehow I managed to leave owing a round. So the next time we end up at the same event Grant, don&#8217;t be surprised if a drink shows up <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f600.png" alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<div style="margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/scotch.png" alt="Glass of Scotch (The Macallen 12)" />
</div>
<p>Unfortunately I fell down on the job where pictures and tweets were concerned, so there aren&#8217;t as many as there have been for past events. </p>
<p>SQL Saturday 46 was an excellent event and ultimately both a lot of fun and a lot of information, what I have grown to expect from SQL Saturday events. The sessions were great, the event went smoothly, and the networking with the local and greater community was everything I had hoped for. I&#8217;m already looking for to my next one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Saturday 28, Baton Rouge</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 09:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlsaturday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/08/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I'm in the air flying back from SQL Saturday 28 and wanted to capture my thoughts while the event was still fresh. Overall I would have to rate it as a resounding success. Last year the event attracted 200 professionals from Baton Rouge and the surrounding area, this year attendance doubled to 400, with additional interest from about 200 more that weren't able to make it.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m in the air flying back from SQL Saturday 28 and wanted to capture my thoughts while the event was still fresh. Overall I would have to rate it as a resounding success. Last year the event attracted 200 professionals from Baton Rouge and the surrounding area, this year attendance doubled to 400, with additional interest from about 200 more that weren&#8217;t able to make it. </p>
<div style="float: left; margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<a href="http://yfrog.com/jd1bej" title="See the fullsize picture"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat28_2010/patrick_leblanc.png" alt="Patrick LeBlanc (@patrickdba) speaking Friday night" /></a><br />
Patrick LeBlanc (<a href="http://sqldownsouth.blogspot.com/" title="Patrick LeBlanc's Blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/patrickdba" title="Patrick LeBlanc (@patrickdba) on twitter">twitter</a>)<br /> Speaking Friday night
</div>
<p>The event featured <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/28/schedule.aspx" title="Check out the full schedule">8 tracks</a>, including SQL and .Net sessions. Several early-bird sessions kicked off around 7:30AM &#8211; I have to applaud those brave enough to speak in front of a crowd that early, as I was still getting appropriately caffeinated.  In addition, INETA made it possible for Keith Elder (<a href="http://keithelder.net/blog/" title="Keith Elder's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/keithelder" title="@KeithElder on twitter">twitter</a>) to provide a full day&#8217;s &#8220;.Net From Scratch&#8221; training session. Steve Jones (<a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/steve_jones/default.aspx" title="Steve Jones on SQL Server Central">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/way0utwest" title="Steve Jones (@way0utwest) on twitter">twitter</a>) delivered the keynote, starting the day off with commentary on professional development, technical skill, and the importance of enjoying our jobs and finding balance in life. </p>
<p>The dinner the night before was in a large enough venue that we were able to mingle and talk a good bit before the dinner appeared, and the food was both good and plentiful (which worked out well for those of us who had been eating airport fare). Patrick LeBlanc (<a href="http://sqldownsouth.blogspot.com/" title="Patrick LeBlanc's Blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/patrickdba" title="Patrick LeBlanc (@patrickdba) on twitter">twitter</a>) provided our mid-evening entertainment, welcoming everyone to the area and introducing us to the team that had worked so hard to put the event together. Somehow I managed to end up at the <a href="http://www.sparkhound.com/" title="Check out the Sparkhound website">Sparkhound</a> table, but they&#8217;re a friendly group and it made for a fun dinner.</p>
<div style="float: right; margin: 2em; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<a href="http://yfrog.com/83a1rxj" title="See the fullsize picture"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat28_2010/chris_eargle.png" alt="Chris Eargle (@kodefuguru) documenting his audience" /></a><br />
Chris Eargle (<a href="http://www.kodefuguru.com/" title="Chris Eargle's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/KodefuGuru" title="Chris Eargle (@kodefuguru) on twitter">twitter</a>)<br /> Documenting his Audience
</div>
<p>The event took place at LSU in a lecture hall, which meant we had classrooms with integrated power and overheads, simplifying some of the setup. A full size classroom was set aside for the speakers and featured plenty of space for us to get off our feet, plug in, or just get a snack throughout the day.</p>
<p>My session was right after lunch (see the <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DataDesign/creating-a-conceptual-data-model" title="Check out my pre-session post">Conceptual Data Modeling</a> post from last week). Despite speaking with no code examples in an after lunch session, I still managed to draw a number of inquisitive people. Despite ending a few minutes early, we still managed to almost run over due to the great conversation we had at the end. Thomas LeBlanc (<a href="http://thesmilingdba.blogspot.com/" title="Thomas LeBlanc's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/TheSmilingDBA" title="Thomas LeBlanc (@TheSmilingDBA) on twitter">twitter</a>) presented on normalization and data modeling after my session and I stuck around to watch his presentation as well, picking up some ideas for the next version of my presentation.</p>
<p>Of the three SQL Saturday events I attended this year, this one was probably the best represented on twitter during the day. William Assaf (<a href="http://sqltact.blogspot.com/" title="William Assaf's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/william_a_dba" title="William Assaf (@william_a_dba) on twitter">twitter</a>) kept the media flowing, constantly uploading pictures and commentary throughout the day and keeping the <a href="http://twitter.com/SQLSatBR" title="[Sorta] Official SQLSatBR Twitter account">@SQLSatBR</a> account busy.  </p>
<div style="float: left; margin: .5em 2em .5em 0em; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<a href="http://yfrog.com/mcg1sp" title="See the fullsize picture"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat28_2010/sqlsatteam.png" alt="A great team of people" /></a><br />
A great team of people (click for larger)
</div>
<p>As is always the case with the events, the best part was the people. I met a number of new people, at varying places in their respective careers, and had interesting conversations that lasted until the restaurant hosting the after party finally asked the last four of us to leave. I wasn&#8217;t able to work everyone&#8217;s names into the post, but it was a great group and there a lot of names both familiar and new. From what I hear, the planning for next year is already in progress, so maybe I&#8217;ll see you there.</p>
<p>For more pictures, check out <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/willassaf/SQLSaturday28?authkey=Gv1sRgCIDCruLCuNDy4wE&amp;feat=directlink#" title="William A's full Picasa Gallery">William&#8217;s full gallery</a> on Picasa.<br />
<br style="clear: left;" /><br />
And the slide decks for my session <a href="http://tiernok.com/presentation.php" title="Eli's slide decks">are posted now</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Saturday New York City recap</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-new-york-city-recap/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-new-york-city-recap/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 11:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlsaturday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/04/sql-saturday-new-york-city-recap/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday was the first time I attended a SQL Saturday event. The event kicked off with a keynote about SQL Server 2008 R2 by Roger Doherty showing some of the things that are in this new release. The sessions were held in five difference rooms and sometimes it was a tough decision deciding what to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550944858/" title="SQL Saturday NYC by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4017/4550944858_0d98ebf3c4.jpg" width="500" height="203" alt="SQL Saturday NYC" /></a><br />
<br />Yesterday  was the first time I attended a SQL Saturday event. The event kicked off with a keynote about SQL Server 2008 R2 by Roger Doherty showing some of the things that are in this new release.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550945294/" title="SQL Saturday Keynote Roger Doherty by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4067/4550945294_8f17a23600.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="SQL Saturday Keynote Roger Doherty" /></a></p>
<p>The sessions were held in five difference rooms and sometimes it was a tough decision deciding what to attend because there were five concurrent sessions.  I attended five sessions, some sessions were slides only, some were code only but the majority of the sessions were slides and code.<br />
Below are these five sessions and my short review of each</p>
<p><strong>Andy Leonard<br />
Applied SSIS Design Patterns</strong><br />
This session talked about design patterns in SSIS. It was mostly focused on passing variables between parent and child packages and also how events bubble up. It was a very interesting session and Andy showed me some things that I will implement in my packages.<br />
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550945658/" title="Andy Leonard by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4068/4550945658_4fc9d2c66a.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Andy Leonard" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Adam Jorgensen<br />
Performance Tuning Analysis Services</strong><br />
I was very interested in this session, Adam showed some of the things you need to be careful about when building cubes, he also showed what you need to capture with profiler and perfmon.<br />
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550308081/" title="Adam Jorgensen by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4018/4550308081_a184537d2e.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Adam Jorgensen" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550946428/" title="Performance Tuning Analysis Services by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2595/4550946428_5cd90740e0.jpg" width="500" height="406" alt="Performance Tuning Analysis Services" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550308601/" title="Adam Jorgensen Performance Tuning Analysis Services by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4033/4550308601_1beaaed1c5.jpg" width="500" height="345" alt="Adam Jorgensen Performance Tuning Analysis Services" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Kevin Goff<br />
Building OLAP Cubes with SSAS 2008</strong><br />
This was a beginner level session explaining what OLAP is, how data is modeled, he mentioned star and snowflake schemas, differences between fact and dimension tables, role playing dimensions and slowly changing dimensions.</p>
<p><strong>Derek Comingore<br />
Delivering Rapid Business Value with Microsoft BI</strong><br />
This was a high level session giving examples about how you can deliver business value, usually there were pros and cons in the slides to every approach. The  Fast Track Data Warehouse might be something interesting for companies,  it is basically a preconfigured server (or rack of servers). All you have to do is plug it in and you are ready to go, more info about that here: http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/2008/en/us/fasttrack.aspx</p>
<p><strong>Charles Hyman<br />
A Complete BI Solution in 90 minutes</strong><br />
This was my favorite session of the event; it was all code, no slides and lots of fun. Charles basically created a cube from scratch within an hour or so. </p>
<p><strong>The raffle</strong><br />
As usually it ended with the raffle, during the day there was a Kindle giveaway and at the end of the event there were interesting things too. There were PASS 2009 DVDs, a GPS unit, iPod touch, books, software, gift cards etc etc. What was interesting is that a lot of people left by the time the raffle began. In some cases they had to call 8 names before they had someone who was present.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550947872/" title="Raffle2 by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4057/4550947872_3a4e05bc0d.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Raffle2" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/4550309155/" title="Raffle1 by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4071/4550309155_13c0d2b3d8.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Raffle1" /></a></p>
<p>I had a good time at the event, I learned a couple of things and I will play around with some of those things to see how I can incorporate them into my code. Seeing something developed in front of you also makes you grok it faster compared to a book. You can ask the person delivering the session a question and he/she will explain it to you right there and then, you can&#8217;t get something like that out of a book.</p>
<p>I will finish with a big thanks to Melissa Demsak and all the other people involved in making this an awesome event.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-new-york-city-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Saturday 33 &#8211; Charlotte, NC</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-33-charlotte-nc/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-33-charlotte-nc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 20:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlsaturday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlserver]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/03/sql-saturday-33-charlotte-nc/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This weekend was SQL Saturday #33 in Charlotte NC and also the first one I attended. It&#8217;s been a long weekend, but I wanted to get my thoughts down while they&#8217;re still fresh. Be warned, it&#8217;s been a long weekend, so my grammar and attempts to reign in my propensity for verbosity have both gone [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was SQL Saturday #33 in Charlotte NC and also the first one I attended. It&#8217;s been a long weekend, but I wanted to get my thoughts down while they&#8217;re still fresh. Be warned, it&#8217;s been a long weekend, so my grammar and attempts to reign in my propensity for verbosity have both gone out the window.</p>
<h2>Background</h2>
<p>Sorry SQL Saturday? Tarwn and SQL? We have questions and we know how painful it is for you to write short blog posts&#8230;</p>
<h3>SQL What?</h3>
<p><a href="http://sqlsaturday.com/about.aspx" title="More About SQL Saturday (Visit the Site)">SQL Saturday</a> is the name for a series of 40+ SQL events that occur throughout the US. Each event is managed locally by SQL user groups and PASS chapters and sticks to a few guidelines set down by Andy Warren (<a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/andy_warren/default.aspx" title="Andy Warren's blog>blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/SQLAndy" title="Andy Warren on Twitter">twitter</a>), Steve Jones (<a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/steve_jones/default.aspx" title="Steve Jones's blog">blog</a> | <a href="www.twitter.com/way0utwest " title="Steve Jones on Twitter">Twitter</a>), and Brian Knight (<a href="http://www.bidn.com/blogs/BrianKnight" title="Brian Knight's Blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/brianknight" title="Brian Knight on Twitter">twitter</a>), the creators of SQL Saturday. This year the reins for SQL Saturday are being passed to <a href="http://www.sqlpass.org/" title="Visit the  Professional Association for SQL Server website">PASS</a> in order to help manage the logistics of the growth of the events. There is a lot more information available on the <a href="http://sqlsaturday.com/" title="Hit the website">SQLSaturday website</a>, including upcoming dates and locations for more events.</p>
<h3>My Involvement</h3>
<p>So obviously I am not a SQL guy and you may be wondering what I was doing at a SQL Saturday. As you know, LessThanDot has some really good SQL people that frequently write articles, offer support in multiple forums, and support their respective communities. This year we have decided to begin supporting the community in a more active role by supporting SQL Saturday #31 in Chicago. As we continue to grow we hope we will be able to extend our support in other ways, but that&#8217;s less relevant at the moment. I&#8217;ll be present at SQL Saturday #31 to help show support &#8220;(and hopefully sneak into a few sessions as well).</p>
<p>When the local call went out for attendees to SQL Saturday in Charlotte, I jumped on the opportunity to not only meet some of the local(-ish) community, but also to take advantage of the learning opportunities from the sessions and from the event itself. While I was able to dive deeper into a number of topics that interest me I was also able to ask some questions about the logistics of the event and planning. </p>
<h2>The Sessions</h2>
<p>I made it to the following sessions:</p>
<p><b><u><a href="http://thesqlagentman.com/presentationfiles/" title="Click here for Presentation Files">Insight Into Your Indexes with DMVs</a></u><br />
Timothy Ford </b>(<a href="http://thesqlagentman.com/" title="Timothy Ford's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/SQLAgentman" title="Timothy Ford on Twitter">twitter</a>)<br />
An excellent session using DMVs to manage, maintain, and locate unused indexes or potential targets for tuning. This was a good session because I had already used everything he pointed out, but he gave me more depth (as well as a number of tricks) that I didn&#8217;t previously have.</p>
<p><b><u>Is Virtualization a Good Choice for SQL Server?</u><br />
Denny Cherry</b> (<a href="http://itknowledgeexchange.techtarget.com/sql-server/" title="Denny's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/mrdenny" title="Denny Cherry on Twitter">twitter</a>)<br />
Having previous virtualized servers (as well as managed the random set of SQL servers), I was eager to start filling a gap in my education, namely putting the two together. Denny did an excellent introduction into virtualization of SQL Server, critical points that need to be determined when considering virtualization, and a live view into his own, very large environments. </p>
<p><b><u>Powershell Awesomesauce</u><br />
Aaron Nelson</b> (<a href="http://sqlvariant.com/wordpress/" title="Aaron Nelson's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/SQLVariant" title="Aaron Nelson on Twitter">twitter</a>)<br />
I went into Aaron&#8217;s session with almost no knowledge of powershell and came out with some ideas and practical examples of where it could be used to manage environments and automate work. While some of the concepts clicked quickly for me (&#8216;piping&#8217; output is common in Unix-like systems), others were new to me and his examples hit a good balance between brevity in code length and breadth of functionality. He also pointed out a number of good follow-up resources and reading recommendations.</p>
<p><b><u>Maximizing Plan Re-Use</u><br />
Andrew Kelly</b> (<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andrew_kelly/" title="Andrew Kelly's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/gunneyk" title="Andrew Kelly on twitter">twitter</a>)<br />
The concept of executions plans is still fairly new to me, something I had little knowledge on prior to Andrew&#8217;s session. Andrew presented a good mix of knowledge about plans, recompilation of plans, reasons, etc. and active examples to help us tie the concepts to the code. While I&#8217;m by no means an expert after one session, he filled in some critical gaps in my own learning and helped connect some dots from past tuning experiences.</p>
<p><b><u>Storage for the DBA</u><br />
Denny Cherry</b> (<a href="http://itknowledgeexchange.techtarget.com/sql-server/" title="Denny's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/mrdenny" title="Denny Cherry on Twitter">twitter</a>)<br />
As Denny put it in the beginning, often there is a disconnect between DBA&#8217;s and Storage Admins that comes down to some fundamental differences in terminology. This session was a &#8216;How to Speak Storage Admin&#8217; class that walked us trough the basics of terminology, tools and methods to help size your environment, and some advanced tools he uses in his own environment. And excellent session, even if I am a developer and not a DBA <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><b><u><a href="http://kevinekline.com/slides/" title="Kevin's Slides">Top 10 Mistakes on SQL Server</a></u><br />
Kevin Kline</b> (<a href="http://kevinekline.com/" title="Kevin Kline's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/kekline" title="Kevin Kline on Twitter">twitter</a>)<br />
An excellent session from Kevin on the top 10 <u>DBA</u> mistakes he has seen in his experiences. From lack of troubleshooting methodology to not testing backups, he covered a number of assumptions and bad practices that we have probably all been guilty of, at one time or another.<br />
<i>Note: The linked slides page above has the 2005 version of this Top 10&#8230; slides, but not the newer 2008 one he presented yesterday. I assume that will be posted soon, though</i></p>
<h2>The Community</h2>
<p>The community was probably the best part of the event. Beyond getting to learn from so many people (for free!) it was great to actually meet them face to face. Someone repeated the &#8220;Our rockstars are not the same as your rockstars&#8221; comment at one point during the day, and I couldn&#8217;t agree more. It was just downright cool to meet people that previously I had only talked with on twitter and forums, or seen as names on book covers and faces in webinars. The down-to-earth, we&#8217;re-all-part-of-the-same-community feeling was a great change from the larger conferences that (not that I don&#8217;t appreciate those as well). Instead of being a conference event, the day had a more fun, get-together feel to it.</p>
<p>And the fact that Greg (<a href="http://twitter.com/sqlsensei" title="Greg on Twitter">SQLSensei</a>) picked up my bar tab and I got a raffle drawing prize from Kevin (<a href="http://twitter.com/kekline" Title="kevin on Twitter (again)">kekline</a>) definitely didn&#8217;t hurt. Peter (<a href="http://twitter.com/peter_shire" title="Peter on twitter">Peter_Shire</a>), Greg (<a href="http://twitter.com/sqlsensei" title="Greg on Twitter">SQLSensei</a>), and the rest of the group at Charlotte put together an excellent event.</p>
<h2>Final Word</h2>
<p>The event was a resounding success. This was my first SQL Saturday and already I&#8217;m looking forward to my next one, and the one after that. The SQL community is amazing and I think that these events really drive it home. I urge everyone to support your local SQL Server user groups and events like SQL Saturday, as this will only help the community continue growing and continue to be a close-knit and fun community to be a part of. </p>
<p>I have also, after urging from a number of people, started giving thought to offering to speak at few events myself. While I&#8217;m not nearly the SQL guru that the other speakers are, I&#8217;ve been in the trenches for a while, broken my fair share of servers, and could probably find one or two things to pass on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-33-charlotte-nc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
