<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>book &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services Blueprints – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/reporting-services-blueprints/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/reporting-services-blueprints/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blueprints]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reporting services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssrs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/12/reporting-services-blueprints/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ 

Recently Packt Publishing released the book SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services Blueprints authored by Marlon Ribunal (blog&#124;twitter) and Mickey Stuewe (blog&#124;twitter). My former colleague Valentino was the technical reviewer for this piece – he wrote&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image_block"><a href="http://www.packtpub.com/sql-server-2012-reporting-services-blueprints/book?utm_source=mention.com&amp;utm_medium=link&amp;utm_campaign=book_mention.com"><br /><img style="float: left; margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SSRS_blueprints/ssrsblueprints.png?mtime=1386846154" alt="" width="231" height="284" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently <a href="https://www.packtpub.com/">Packt Publishing</a> released the book <a href="http://www.packtpub.com/sql-server-2012-reporting-services-blueprints/book?utm_source=mention.com&amp;utm_medium=link&amp;utm_campaign=book_mention.com">SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services Blueprints</a> authored by Marlon Ribunal (<a href="http://marlonribunal.com/sql-server-express-reporting-data-solutions/">blog</a>|<a href="https://twitter.com/MarlonRibunal">twitter</a>) and Mickey Stuewe (<a href="http://mickeystuewe.com/">blog</a>|<a href="https://twitter.com/SQLMickey">twitter</a>). My former colleague Valentino was the technical reviewer for this piece – he wrote about it <a href="http://blog.hoegaerden.be/2013/11/17/book-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-blueprints/">here</a> – so I was very interested in getting my hands on this book. Luckily Packt was kind enough to provide me with a copy so I could write a review.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-align: justify;">The book itself is advertised as a </span><em>step-by-step, task-driven tutorial</em><span style="text-align: justify;">, a hands-on book with some real-life blueprints which doesn’t waste time with boring introductions and technical obscurities. In my opinion, the book achieves this goal quite well. At no point I had the feeling I was reading dry technical documentation, but rather practical easy-explained tips on how to use Reporting Services. I also have to admit the reviewers really did a great job: the text reads fluently and I believe I didn’t find any spelling mistakes or typos, which are pet peeve of mine (I do hope I didn’t make any myself in this blog post). The book is aimed at people new to Reporting Services, so hardcore BI professionals won’t get much out of it, but I have to admit I learned a few nuggets here and there.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The book tells the journey of John Kirkland, an <em>awesome accidental DBA</em> for Red Speed Bicycle LLC, a company remarkably similar to AdventureWorks, who also happens to become an <em>accidental</em> report developer. Using this story makes the book relatable and more uplifting than most technical books. The first 4 chapters guide John through the basics of creating reports: how to create data sources and data sets, how to use parameters (with a good piece on multivalued parameters), how to format reports, how to use the different actions (learned something about document maps here) and finally how to implement charts. These chapters are the most valuable for beginners of SSRS and they cover a lot of the basic reporting needs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The fifth chapter goes into detail about location based reporting and shows how you can use maps in SSRS. The sixth chapter is quite an important one and deals with Analysis Services as data source for the reports. The first sections of this chapter deal with some administrative issues of SSAS, such as for example setting the firewall and finding the correct port. Personally I found this information superfluous and I would have liked more details on how to create reports on top of SSAS. For example, how to create a report using a parent-child hierarchy, how to use distinct count over a many-2-many dimension and so on. I get it from the point of view from John, the hero of the book who is a DBA and might like all that technical information about SSAS, but maybe an additional appendix would have been better. If you’re going technical though, why not include more technical deep-dives into managing the SSRS server instead of SSAS?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Chapter 7 deals with deployments and everything that comes after: subscriptions, caching, snapshots et cetera. One minor downside is that it only explains deployment from Visual Studio. There’s no explanation on alternatives with scripting. Chapter 8 – the final chapter &#8211; is a bit of the “garbage” chapter, as it covers multiple subjects: SharePoint integration, Power View and Power Pivot. What disappointed me most is the very short introduction to Power View which has no screenshots at all. I repeat: no screenshots at all. Power View is Microsoft’s answer to competitors like QlickView and it is has beautiful, rich and interactive graphics, it’s easy to use and it makes SSRS look pretty bland and boring. But no screenshots. As Power View is officially part of Reporting Services (although it resides in Office and SharePoint) and is another reporting/visualization tool, I’d rather have a full chapter on Power View and less info on the SSAS DBA and the geo reporting stuff.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The book closes with two appendixes: a short one on SSRS best practices and one on using replication to create a separate reporting database.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I really enjoyed the book and I will recommend it to people new to Reporting Services to get up to speed quickly with this tool. It has great examples that you can follow along using provided code snippets. The only downside – but this is my personal opinion – is the lack of Power View goodness. Don’t let this stop you though on adding this title to your library!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/reporting-services-blueprints/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virtual book club.. who is in?</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/virtual-book-club-who-is/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/virtual-book-club-who-is/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/08/virtual-book-club-who-is/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At work we decided to start a book club, we pick a book, every week we decide how much we will read. After the week is over, we meet and then discuss what we read. We discuss what we liked, what we didn't like and also what we learned.



Why should&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At work we decided to start a book club, we pick a book, every week we decide how much we will read. After the week is over, we meet and then discuss what we read. We discuss what we liked, what we didn&#8217;t like and also what we learned.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/9564719333/" title="Book list by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5478/9564719333_3d9b05c893.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Book list" /></a></p>
<p>Why should I have all the fun with this? I figured why not make it a virtual book club, we pick a SQL Server book and then we figure out how much we will read in a week,  after the week is over we can discuss.</p>
<p>I suggest for the first book we start with <strong><a href="http://www.red-gate.com/community/books/sql-server-execution-plans-ed-2">SQL Server Execution Plans, Second Edition</a></strong> by Grant Fritchey. You can buy the book in print format or you can download the book from free by clicking on the title which will bring you to the redgate site</p>
<p>The book has 8 chapters</p>
<p>Chapter 1: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/4/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-1-execution-plan-basics">Execution Plan Basics</a><br />
Chapter 2: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/11/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-2-reading-graphical-execution-plans-for-basic-queries">Graphical Execution Plans for Basic Queries</a><br />
Chapter 3:<a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/17/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-3-text-and-xml-execution-plans-for-basic-queries"> Text and XML Execution Plans for Basic Queries</a><br />
Chapter 4: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/25/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-3-understanding-more-complex-query-plans">Understanding More Complex Query Plans</a><br />
Chapter 5: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/10/7/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-5-controlling-execution-plans-with-hints">Controlling Execution Plans with Hints</a><br />
Chapter 6: Cursor Operations<br />
Chapter 7: Special Datatypes and Execution Plans<br />
Chapter 8: Advanced Topics</p>
<p>One chapter a week should be doable for everyone. I will post my &#8216;review&#8217; on Sunday and then you guys have the whole of next week to do yours in the comments.</p>
<p>After this book is done we can pick the next one, we can use a poll for that.</p>
<p>So who is in, leave a comment if you want to participate?</p>
<p>You can find my reviews here:<br />
Chapter 1: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/4/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-1-execution-plan-basics">Execution Plan Basics</a><br />
Chapter 2: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/11/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-2-reading-graphical-execution-plans-for-basic-queries">Graphical Execution Plans for Basic Queries</a><br />
Chapter 3: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/17/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-3-text-and-xml-execution-plans-for-basic-queries">Text and XML Execution Plans for Basic Queries</a><br />
Chapter 4: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/9/25/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-3-understanding-more-complex-query-plans">Understanding More Complex Query Plans</a><br />
Chapter 5: <a href="http://denis-gobo.squarespace.com/denisgobo/2013/10/7/review-of-sql-server-execution-plans-chapter-5-controlling-execution-plans-with-hints">Controlling Execution Plans with Hints</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/virtual-book-club-who-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of The Well-Grounded Java Developer</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/review-of-the-well-grounded/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/review-of-the-well-grounded/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Application Lifecycle Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Java EE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groovy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java functional programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jvm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polyglot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scala]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/01/review-of-the-well-grounded/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a review of The Well-Grounded Java Developer, Vital techniques of Java 7 and polyglot programming. Written by Benjamin J. Evans and Martijn Verburg. The book was published in July, 2012 and it contains 496 pages

This is an excellent&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a review of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290068/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1617290068">The Well-Grounded Java Developer, Vital techniques of Java 7 and polyglot programming</a>. Written by Benjamin J. Evans and Martijn Verburg. The book was published in July, 2012 and it contains 496 pages</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/EnterpriseDev/Denis/evans_cover150.jpg?mtime=1357748948"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/EnterpriseDev/Denis/evans_cover150.jpg?mtime=1357748948" width="150" height="188" style="float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;" /></a>Right from the start I want to say that this is an excellent book and I highly recommend it. One thing you do need to be aware about is that in order to use this book you need to know Java. If you don&#8217;t know Java then this is not the book for you. This book is all about bringing you to the next level as a Java developer by showing you how to do continuous integration, dependency injection, testing, performance tuning, and more.<br />
This book even shows you how to use different languages that run on the JVM. The book is written in a easy and concise style, everything is very clear. I also love the annotations which are sprinkled throughout the book, they give some nice background information. While the chapters on Groovy, Scala and Clojure are not a complete reference for the language, they do provide enough material to form a nice foundation, now you can further explore the language on your own.</p>
<p>The book is split up in four parts, I will list each part with the chapters within that part and will give a brief summary what the part is about</p>
<p><strong>Part 1 Developing with Java 7</strong><br />
Chapter 1 Introducing Java 7<br />
Chapter 2 New I/O</p>
<p>This section shows you what was added in Java 7, for example you can now use strings in switch statements, try-with-resources(similar to a using statement in c#, it frees up the resources after it is done). The Java IO stuff has been rewritten and much easier to use, where you had to write a whole bunch of code before, you can now do the same in much less code. Some things that did not exist in Java in terms of IO but now does exist are explained as well.</p>
<p><strong>Part 2 Vital techniques</strong><br />
Chapter 3 Dependency Injection<br />
Chapter 4 Modern concurrency<br />
Chapter 5 Class files and bytecode<br />
Chapter 6 Understanding performance tuning</p>
<p>This part has a lot of stuff and as a Java developer you should really know how this stuff works if you want to get to the next level. Dependency Injection(DI) and inversion of control (IoC) are covered, Guice 3, the reference implementation for DI in Java is also covered. Concurrency before Java 5 and concurrency now is covered. Concurrency will be a must now that we have multi-CPU and multi-core everywhere, you better get your wits around it. There is a whole chapter on the class files itself and how they are loaded as well as what they compile into. These are fun details and will show you exactly what happens when you compile and execute a class. Evereybody&#8217;s favorite subject performance tuning is covered in this part of the book as well.</p>
<p><strong>Part 3 Polyglot programming on the JVM</strong><br />
Chapter 7 Alternative JVM languages<br />
Chapter 8 Groovy: Java’s dynamic friend<br />
Chapter 9 Scala: powerful and concise<br />
Chapter 10 Clojure: safer programming</p>
<p>This is a very interesting part of the book and I would suggest not to skip it. There are 3 type of languages covered in this part:<br />
Groovy, a dynamic language<br />
Scala, a functional language<br />
Clojure, a Lisp for functional programming</p>
<p>Take a look at these languages and you will be amazed how much Java boilerplate code you can eliminate by using these languages instead. Some of the functional is a little bit of a paradigm shift and you might need some time adjusting. You will also see how you can interoperate between these languages and Java.</p>
<p><strong>Part 4 Crafting the polyglot project</strong><br />
Chapter 11 Test-driven development<br />
Chapter 12 Build and continuous integration<br />
Chapter 13 Rapid web development<br />
Chapter 14 Staying well-grounded</p>
<p>The last part is all about automation and making your life easier. If you are a developer who still deploys stuff by using FTP to move JAR, EAR and WAR files, pay attention. Maven is covered as the build automation tool, Jenkins is the  continuous integration tool. In the Rapid web development chapter Grails is explored.</p>
<hr />
Let me just repeat again that I think this is an awesome book and as a Java developer you have to check it out. The one thing that is missing from the book is ORM, it is covered a little in the testing chapter but if you want to know about ORM, you will need to pick out some other book just for that.</p>
<p>You can download the following chapters to get a feel for the book</p>
<p><a href="http://www.manning.com/evans/TWGJD_sample_ch01.pdf">Sample chapter 1</a><br />
<a href="http://www.manning.com/evans/TWGJD_sample_ch04.pdf">Sample chapter 4</a></p>
<p>Head on over to Amazon for other reviews of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290068/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1617290068">The Well-Grounded Java Developer, Vital techniques of Java 7 and polyglot programming</a><br />
The site for the book can be found here: http://www.manning.com/evans/ </p>
<hr />
Below is the complete table of contents so that you have a little more details about each chapter.</p>
<p><strong>Part 1 Developing with Java 7<br />
Chapter 1 Introducing Java 7<br />
</strong>The language and the platform<br />
Small is beautiful—Project Coin<br />
The changes in Project Coin<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 2 New I/O</strong><br />
Java I/O—a history<br />
Path—a foundation of file-based I/O<br />
Dealing with directories and directory trees<br />
Filesystem I/O with NIO.2<br />
Asynchronous I/O operations<br />
Tidying up Socket-Channel functionality<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Part 2 Vital techniques<br />
Chapter 3 Dependency Injection</strong><br />
Inject some knowledge—understanding IoC and DI<br />
Standardized DI in Java<br />
Guice 3—the reference implementation for DI in Java<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 4 Modern concurrency</strong><br />
Concurrency theory—a primer<br />
Block-structured concurrency (pre-Java 5)<br />
Building blocks for modern concurrent applications<br />
Controlling execution<br />
The fork/join framework<br />
The Java Memory Model (JMM)<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 5 Class files and bytecode</strong><br />
Classloading and class objects<br />
Using method handles<br />
Examining class files<br />
Bytecode<br />
Invokedynamic<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 6 Understanding performance tuning</strong><br />
Performance terminology—some basic definitions<br />
A pragmatic approach to performance analysis<br />
What went wrong? Why we have to care<br />
A question of time—from the hardware up<br />
Garbage collection<br />
JIT compilation with HotSpot<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Part 3 Polyglot programming on the JVM<br />
Chapter 7 Alternative JVM languages<br />
</strong>Java too clumsy? Them’s fighting words!<br />
Language zoology<br />
Polyglot programming on the JVM<br />
How to choose a non-Java language for your project<br />
How the JVM supports alternative languages<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 8 Groovy: Java’s dynamic friend</strong><br />
Getting started with Groovy<br />
Groovy 101—syntax and semantics<br />
Differences from Java—traps for new players<br />
Groovy features not (yet) in Java<br />
Interoperating between Groovy and Java<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 9 Scala: powerful and concise</strong><br />
A quick tour of Scala<br />
Is Scala right for my project?<br />
Making code beautiful again with Scala<br />
Scala’s object model—similar but different<br />
Data structures and collections<br />
Introduction to actors<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 10 Clojure: safer programming</strong><br />
Introducing Clojure<br />
Looking for Clojure—syntax and semantics<br />
Working with functions and loops in Clojure<br />
Introducing Clojure sequences<br />
Interoperating between Clojure and Java<br />
Concurrent Clojure<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Part 4 Crafting the polyglot project<br />
Chapter 11 Test-driven development<br />
</strong>TDD in a nutshell<br />
Test doubles<br />
Introducing ScalaTest<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 12 Build and continuous integration</strong><br />
Getting started with Maven 3<br />
Maven 3—a quick-start project<br />
Maven 3—the Java7developer build<br />
Jenkins—serving your CI needs<br />
Code metrics with Maven and Jenkins<br />
Leiningen<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 13 Rapid web development</strong><br />
The problem with Java-based web frameworks<br />
Criteria in selecting a web framework<br />
Getting started with Grails<br />
Grails quick-start project<br />
Further Grails exploration<br />
Getting started with Compojure<br />
A sample Compojure project—“Am I an Otter or Not?”<br />
Summary</p>
<p><strong>Chapter 14 Staying well-grounded</strong><br />
What to expect in Java 8<br />
Polyglot programming<br />
Future concurrency trends<br />
New directions in the JVM</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/review-of-the-well-grounded/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of Zero Day by Mark Russinovich</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-of-zero-day-by/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-of-zero-day-by/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber thriller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techno thriller]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/08/review-of-zero-day-by/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a small review of Zero Day: A Novel by Mark Russinovich 
If you are a windows user/developer then the name Mark Russinovich might seem familiar to you, Mark is of course the guy who started Sysinternals, he discovered the Sony rootkit on their&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/6017612547/" title="Zero Day by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6138/6017612547_17c6c6200d_m.jpg" width="180" height="240" alt="Zero Day" /></a><br />
This is a small review of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031261246X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=031261246X">Zero Day: A Novel</a> by Mark Russinovich<br />
If you are a windows user/developer then the name Mark Russinovich might seem familiar to you, Mark is of course the guy who started Sysinternals, he discovered the Sony rootkit on their CDs and is now a technical fellow at Microsoft. In other words, Mark knows what he talks about when writing about zero day attacks. So what does zero day mean anyway? Here is what wikipedia has about zero day</p>
<blockquote><p>A zero-day (or zero-hour or day zero) attack or threat is a computer threat that tries to exploit computer application vulnerabilities that are unknown to others or the software developer, also called zero-day vulnerabilities. Zero-day exploits (actual software that uses a security hole to carry out an attack) are used or shared by attackers before the developer of the target software knows about the vulnerability.<br />
The term derives from the age of the exploit. A &#8220;zero day&#8221; attack occurs on or before the first or &#8220;zeroth&#8221; day of developer awareness, meaning the developer has not had any opportunity to distribute a security fix to users of the software</p></blockquote>
<p>The story is about a terrorist organization that tries to bring the US and European systems down by launching a whole variety of viruses (virii) written by the Russian coder superphreak. Our hero must try to find out what the virus does, who created it and how to stop it. He also warned people about September 11th and nobody listens because he wasn&#8217;t persistent enough, he doesn&#8217;t want to make the same mistake again. Will he succeed? I won&#8217;t spoil it here but the books has some major turns and twist that will make it difficult to put the book down.</p>
<p>The book is written in a style similar to Michael Crichton or Dan Brown, the chapters are fast paced and short. The book is hard to put down, it is a page turner and you will stay past your bed time trying to find out what will happen next.</p>
<p>I liked the book and can highly recommend it, if you liked <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/daemon-by-daniel-suarez-is-a-book-every">Daemon by Daniel Suarez</a>, then you will like this too</p>
<h2>Additional info</h2>
<p>Here is some more info about the book and the author</p>
<p>The trailer for the book<br />
[video:youtube:ucyMBYg9RWU]</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thebigthrill.org/2011/04/zero-day-by-mark-russinovich/">Mark Russinovich&#8217;s interview for The Big Thrill</a><br />
Read Mark&#8217;s interview on Zero Day in the latest issue of The Big Thrill</p>
<p>Podcast with Herding Code: http://herdingcode.com/?p=320</p>
<p>Check out the Amazon reviews: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031261246X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=031261246X">Zero Day: A Novel</a> by Mark Russinovich</p>
<p>If you know of similar cyber-thriller books like Zero Day or <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0451228731?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0451228731">Daemon</a> and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0525951571?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0525951571">Freedom(tm)</a> leave me a comment, I am interested in checking those out</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-of-zero-day-by/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Physics of the Future: How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100 by Michio Kaku</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-physics-of-the-future/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-physics-of-the-future/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nanobots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/06/review-physics-of-the-future/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I picked up the book Physics of the Future: How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100 mainly to see what is in store for humanity in the year 2100. Having read Ray Kurzweil's 3 books on a similar subject, this was of inte&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5825886374/" title="Physics of the Future How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100 by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5197/5825886374_e89ee3e4bc_m.jpg" width="240" height="240" alt="Physics of the Future How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100" /></a><br />
I picked up the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0385530803/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217153&amp;creative=399349&amp;creativeASIN=0385530803">Physics of the Future: How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0385530803&amp;camp=217153&amp;creative=399349" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /> mainly to see what is in store for humanity in the year 2100. Having read Ray Kurzweil&#8217;s 3 books on a similar subject, this was of interest to me. When people predict the future they usually underestimate the pace of progress, just imagine when you looked at CPUs between 1980 and 1985, you would never think that we would have quadcore CPUs in our laptops, these quadcore CPUs would outperform those clunky machines by such a factor that it is almost impossible to put it on the same graph.</p>
<p>There were some interesting things in this book, one of them is Optogenetics,<br />
<blockquote>Optogenetics is the combination of genetics and optics to control well-defined events within specific cells of living tissue. It includes the discovery and insertion into cells of genes that confer light responsiveness; it also includes the associated technologies for delivering light deep into organisms as complex as freely moving mammals, for targeting light-sensitivity to cells of interest, and for assessing specific readouts, or effects, of this optical control.</p></blockquote>
<p> To learn more about Optogenetics , you can check out this Scientific American article: <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=optogenetics-controlling">Optogenetics: Controlling the Brain with Light [Extended Version]</a> and of course, there is always wikipedia: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optogenetics</p>
<p>What about having <em>retinal display</em> contact lenses? These lenses would connect directly to the internet. I guess it would be fine for certain things but for most things it would be a big distraction.</p>
<p>The book also mentions driverless cars, of course Google already showed that after the book was published so this is only a matter of time.</p>
<p>Will the robots take over is explored in this book, the singularity is also discussed.</p>
<p>In terms of medicine, nanobots that go through our veins and zap cancerous cells will be here, your doctor might be a robot.</p>
<p>Clothing will be smart, if you get injured, your clothes will make a diagnose of your condition and together with your gps location they will send a signal to the nearest hospital.</p>
<p>All in all, I found this book very interesting and very entertaining. for some people all these thing will be scary and they will be scared of it, for other people it will be exciting and they will embrace these changes.  Michio Kaku has already seen some of these inventions already as proto types being tested right now. You don&#8217;t need to be a science buff to understand this book, it is dumb down to appeal to the masses.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-physics-of-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Quality and Master Data Management with Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 book available as a free download</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/data-quality-and-master-data/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/data-quality-and-master-data/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 08:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data quality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/06/data-quality-and-master-data/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dejan Sarka and Davide Mauri have made available the book Data Quality and Master Data Management with Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 as a free download on their site

Here is a little blurb about the book
This book deals with master data. It explains&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dejan Sarka and Davide Mauri have made available the book <em>Data Quality and Master Data Management with Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2</em> as a free download on their site</p>
<p>Here is a little blurb about the book</p>
<blockquote><p>This book deals with master data. It explains how we can recognize our master data. It stresses the importance of a good data model for data integrity. It shows how we can find areas of bad or suspicious data. It shows how we can proactively enforce better data quality and make an authoritative master data source through a specialized Master Data Management application. It also shows how we can tackle the problems with duplicate master data and the problems with identity mapping from different databases in order to create a unique representation of the master data.</p>
<p>For all the tasks mentioned in this book, we use the tools that are available in the Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 suite. In order to achieve our goal—good quality of our data—nearly any part of the suite turns to be useful. This is not a beginner’s book. We, the authors, suppose that you, the readers, have quite good knowledge of SQL Server Database Engine, .NET, and other tools from the SQL Server suite.</p></blockquote>
<p>You can download the book here: http://www.solidq.com/ce-en/News/Pages/Data-Quality-and-Master-Data-Management-with-Microsoft-SQL-Server-2008-R2.aspx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/data-quality-and-master-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Eli&#8217;s Shelves: Books for IT Management</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/from-elis-shelves-it-management/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/from-elis-shelves-it-management/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/05/from-elis-shelves-it-management/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So everything is going fine, then *wham* you're in charge. Maybe it's responsibility for a small part of the infrastructure or a single system, maybe it's for a whole department. Unfortunately that switch doesn't come with any instructions, and most managers and team leads are left on their own to figure out what those instructions would have been, had they actually existed.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So everything is going fine, then *wham* you&#8217;re in charge. Maybe it&#8217;s responsibility for a small part of the infrastructure or a single system, maybe it&#8217;s for a whole department. Unfortunately that switch doesn&#8217;t come with any instructions, and most managers and team leads are left on their own to figure out what those instructions would have been, had they actually existed.</p>
<p>This week we are looking at a couple books for team leads and managers.</p>
<h2>IT Management</h2>
<p>Managing IT programs, leading IT teams, and managing IT departments are similar in many ways, despite the difference in goals and resources. All three have responsibility for a technical area, all three tend to tend to be given little direction or training, and all three are actually responsible for people, not technology. </p>
<p>The IT Program manager or owner is responsible for the people that consume the products, managing their expectations, helping the understand what they need, and then ultimately helping other implement those needs. The team lead is responsible for helping a team of (usually highly opinionated) individuals to start paddling in the same direction, with an ultimate goal of delivering features or products. The IT Manager is responsible for understanding the needs of the people and business, being the interface to the business, building and sustaining a of people that can ultimately meet and exceed those needs, and thus bears responsibility for the technology meeting the needs of the ultimate end user.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not about the computers, it&#8217;s about the people, both those inside and outside the group. </p>
<div style="float: left; padding: .5em; width: 170px; margin: 0em .5em .5em 0px; border: 1px solid #dddddd; color: #666666; font-size: .8em; text-align: center; position: relative;">
   <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Peopleware-Productive-Projects-Teams-Second/dp/0932633439" title="Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams"><img src="http://tiernok.com/_n_images/books/pppat.jpg" alt="Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams" /></a><br />
   Peopleware
</div>
<h3><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Peopleware-Productive-Projects-Teams-Second/dp/0932633439" title="Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams as Amazon">Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams</a><br />Tom DeMarco, Timeothy Lister</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s said that at one point every new manager at Microsoft, when walking into their office for the first time, would find this book waiting for them. I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s true or not, but I like to think that it was. Peopleware was first published in 1987 and was updated in 1999. The core premise of the book is that people are not modular cogs and we really ought to stop treating them as such. From building teams to selecting the furniture, to the idea that work can be fun, rather than just onerous, the authors cover a lot of ground without stretching the book into 800 pages.  <br style="clear: left" /></p>
<div style="float: left; padding: .5em; width: 170px; margin: 0em .5em .5em 0px; border: 1px solid #dddddd; color: #666666; font-size: .8em; text-align: center; position: relative;">
   <a href="http://www.amazon.com/World-Class-Businesses-Succeed-Triumphs/dp/0470450185/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1266457090&amp;sr=1-1" title="World Class IT: Why Businesses Succeed When IT Triumphs at Amazon"><img src="http://tiernok.com/_n_images/books/wci.jpg" alt="World Class IT: Why Businesses Succeed When IT Triumphs" /></a><br />
   World Class IT
</div>
<h3><a href="http://www.amazon.com/World-Class-Businesses-Succeed-Triumphs/dp/0470450185/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1266457090&amp;sr=1-1" title="World Class IT: Why Businesses Succeed When IT Triumphs">World Class IT: Why Businesses Succeed When IT Triumphs</a><br />Peter A. High</h3>
<p>As we move from the team to the department level, we adopt a greater number of unknowns. No longer responsible for a group of individuals with a goal, we are instead &#8216;in charge&#8217; of some amorphous group of technologies and people, with an almost constant stream of absolutely critical requests being thrown over the wall from the business. At this point we have either two options, get stuck trying to catch up or focus on the whole picture. In &#8220;World Class IT&#8221;, Peter High offers a model he has used to help bring structure, measurement, and opportunities to many environments. He walks us through the 5 main principles of his model, each focusing on a portion of the IT Environment, it&#8217;s importance, what it means to be world class, and sample measurements one could use along the way. While this book is aimed at the CIO, the structure of the model and example metrics are useful at multiple levels.</p>
<p>These two books are only a very small sample of those available for IT Managers and Team Leads and I would hope that both roles had read the first and most managers had read one or more books like the second. The challenge with reading for an IT Lead or IT Manager role is that, beyond just leadership or IT Management books, you need to be reading material on the processes you are following and the business you are in. This means understanding your processes (project management and business architecture books are in the near future) as well as your business.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/from-elis-shelves-it-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review &#8211; NHibernate 3.0 Cookbook</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/book-review-nhibernate-3-0-cookbook/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/book-review-nhibernate-3-0-cookbook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 14:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Ullrich]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhibernate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/11/book-review-nhibernate-3-0-cookbook/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just finished reading the NHibernate 3.0 Cookbook, part of Packt Publishing&#8217;s Open Source series, and I&#8217;ve been really impressed. The book is written by Jason Dentler, whose blog I&#8217;m sure anyone doing frequent searches for NHibernate has run across once or twice in their travels. What really stood out to me about this book [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just finished reading the <a href="https://www.packtpub.com/nhibernate-3-0-cookbook/book">NHibernate 3.0 Cookbook</a>, part of Packt Publishing&#8217;s Open Source series, and I&#8217;ve been really impressed.  The book is written by <a href="http://jasondentler.com/blog/">Jason Dentler</a>, whose blog I&#8217;m sure anyone doing frequent searches for NHibernate has run across once or twice in their travels.</p>
<p>What really stood out to me about this book was how easy it was to read.  You can tell that Jason went out of his way to make the book approachable for people unfamiliar with the concepts (without dumbing down the content) and in my opinion it really paid off.  It makes for a much lighter and more enjoyable read than most technical books (I could routinely knock out 40-50 pages in a 45 minute train ride).  I think it also makes it easier to grasp the concepts as well (at least this was true for the topics I was less familiar with).  </p>
<p>The book is broken up into chapters representing the cornerstones of NHibernate, each chapter containing a handful or two of recipes illustrating solutions to commonly encountered problems.  The chapters are broken out as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Models And Mappings</li>
<li>Configuration And Schema</li>
<li>Sessions And Transactions</li>
<li>Queries</li>
<li>Testing</li>
<li>Data Access Layer</li>
<li>Extending NHibernate</li>
<li>NHibernate Contribution Projects</li>
</ul>
<p>I view most of these as <strong>essential</strong> knowledge for people developing with NHibernate, and I have trouble thinking of an essential topic that is left off the list.  The book is intended as a quick reference containing solutions to common problems, but because of the way it is written and the breadth of the content it could serve as a good introduction for a newcomer as well. It would be impossible to cover <strong>everything</strong> about NHibernate in a book twice as long as this one, but I think there is enough here to leave the reader in a good place to be able to solve any other problems they run into (with some help from the internets of course).</p>
<p>I learned a few new things over the course of reading the book.  The first was in the recipe about configuring NHibernate from code (in the Configuration and Schema chapter).  It discusses the NHibernate.Cfg.Loquacious namespace, which offers a much better way to configure NHibernate in code than the normal configuration namespace.  I typically use Fluent NHibernate lately, so I may never have come across this had I not read the book.  I&#8217;m certainly glad that I know it&#8217;s there now.  Other things the book turned me on to included <a href="http://code.google.com/p/codeconform/">ConfORM</a>, a very cool take on automapping and <a href="http://nhibernatespatial.codeplex.com/">NHibernate.Spatial</a>, both of which I will need to give a try at some point in the not too distant future.</p>
<p>There were a lot of things to like about the book, but I&#8217;d have to say my favorite was the chapter dedicated to the various contribution projects.  Some of these libraries really help NHibernate stand out from other ORMs, but they aren&#8217;t always that well documented (I guess this is a problem with OSS in general).  They address many common needs, but because of the lack of documentation (or maybe because people don&#8217;t always know where to look) I&#8217;ll sometimes encounter people trying to recreate something (like caching) that the contribution projects have quite well covered.  To see a book like this spreading the word about these libraries makes me smile.  In addition to making me smile, this chapter offers a great intro to NHibernate.Caches, and probably the best example of setting up NHibernate.Search with Lucene.net that I&#8217;ve come across.</p>
<p>I also like that it uses a consistent domain model throughout the book.  You could certainly get the same experience by scouring the interwebs and working through examples, but I suspect some of the lessons would be lost to the tedious act of setting up the domain objects used in each example.  Keeping the model used consistent allows the reader to really focus on the core subject of each recipe.</p>
<p>I think this book would be a good read for experienced NHibernate users trying to get up to speed on version 3 quickly, or for anyone looking for a quick reference that cuts right to the heart of common problems.  I&#8217;m not sure about how brand new NHibernate users would like it, but I have a feeling that it would work well for the type of users that learn best by doing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/book-review-nhibernate-3-0-cookbook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with me about the chapters I wrote for the SQL Server Deep Dives book</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/interview-with-me-about-the-chapters-i-w/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/interview-with-me-about-the-chapters-i-w/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 11:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/03/interview-with-me-about-the-chapters-i-w/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The folks at http://sqlperspectives.wordpress.com/ are reviewing the SQL Server Deep Dives book a chapter at a time (one chapter per week). The review is usually done by more than one person, so far there are already 8 chapters reviewed. I think that this is a very cool idea, it is almost like a book club. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The folks at http://sqlperspectives.wordpress.com/ are reviewing the  SQL Server Deep Dives book a chapter at a time (one chapter per week). The review is usually done by more than one person, so far there are already 8 chapters reviewed. I think that this is a very cool idea, it is almost like a book club.</p>
<p>Since they reviewed my chapter about the <em>minimally logged bulk insert</em>, they asked me to do an interview. You can find that interview here:  http://sqlperspectives.wordpress.com/2010/03/26/an-interview-with-denis-gobo/</p>
<p>You can also find the reviews by Richard Rodriguez, Chris Shaw and Jeremy Lowell here: http://sqlperspectives.wordpress.com/category/chapter-8/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/interview-with-me-about-the-chapters-i-w/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with Brent Ozar about the book Professional SQL Server 2008 Internals and Troubleshooting</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/interview-with-brent-ozar-about-the-book/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/interview-with-brent-ozar-about-the-book/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 19:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performance tuning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/01/interview-with-brent-ozar-about-the-book/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I noticed Brent Ozar worked on a SQL book titled: Professional SQL Server 2008 Internals and Troubleshooting. This book is now available and I decided to ask Brent some questions about this book. This interview was conducted by email, enjoy. Denis: Is the book geared towards a beginner/intermediate level user or do you have to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I noticed Brent Ozar worked on a SQL book titled: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0470484284?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0470484284">Professional SQL Server 2008 Internals and Troubleshooting</a>. This book is now available and I decided to ask Brent some questions about this book. This interview was conducted by email, enjoy.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Is the book geared towards a beginner/intermediate level user or do you have to be an advanced user to really utilize the information in this book?</strong></p>
<p>I like to think that the reader is somebody who&#8217;s been managing SQL Servers for a year or two and is getting frustrated.  He doesn&#8217;t understand what&#8217;s going on inside the engine when a query runs.  He&#8217;s not satisfied with just creating more indexes or running sp_who2 &#8211; he wants to know what&#8217;s actually happening under the hood.  He can&#8217;t afford top-notch consultants, or he can&#8217;t get good ones locally, or he wants to BECOME a top-notch consultant.</p>
<p>This book covers so many gray areas that traditional books haven&#8217;t covered.  CPUs matter.  Memory matters.  Storage matters.  Latching matters.  Traditional SQL books haven&#8217;t dived deeply enough into these subjects, and I think this book does.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: What are the most important things a person can do to master SQL troubleshooting?</strong></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t change anything you don&#8217;t fully understand, and don&#8217;t take anybody&#8217;s word for anything.  Just because you read a recommendation in a forum that your server will go faster when MAXDOP is set to 1 doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s going to work in your individual situation.  Just because MAXDOP = 1 makes one of your servers faster doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;ll make them all faster.  When you change settings, you change the way SQL Server behaves, and you should understand the ramifications.</p>
<p>One of the first things I do when I&#8217;m troubleshooting a server is find out all of the non-default settings.  Don&#8217;t assume AUTO_CLOSE is turned off &#8211; people do crazy things.  I make a list of everything that isn&#8217;t set at factory defaults, and I start asking why.  Don&#8217;t get me wrong &#8211; there&#8217;s some easy knobs to turn in order to make SQL Server go faster, like Instant File Initialization, but there&#8217;s not a lot of surefire tweaks that work in every single situation.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: With the addition of Dynamic Management Views is it now easier to find bottlenecks than before?</strong></p>
<p>Without a doubt.  Whenever I present on DMVs, I hear a chorus of questions asking how to get that same information in SQL Server 2000.  DMVs are without a doubt the most helpful thing in my troubleshooting and tuning.  Managing a SQL Server without querying the DMVs is like trying to bake a cake without knowing how the oven temperature control works.  Your results will definitely vary from cake to cake.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: What is your favorite Dynamic Management View to troubleshoot performance?</strong></p>
<p>sys.dm_db_missing_index_details, I wish I could quit you.</p>
<p>I do &#8220;weekend&#8221; performance tuning on the side, so when I troubleshoot performance, I&#8217;m usually looking at a database I&#8217;ve never seen before.  Indexing is tough to do right, and easy to do wrong.  I can usually get huge performance improvements by tweaking the index strategy.  The missing index DMVs give me a starting point without having to run traces.  They&#8217;re still not a silver bullet &#8211; they&#8217;re like the Index Tuning WIzard or Database Tuning Advisor in that they can give some pretty nasty advice.  When used properly, though, they can give huge performance boosts. </p>
<p><strong>Denis: Is there a place for Solid State Drives, perhaps for tempdb or is it still too early for mission critical servers?</strong></p>
<p>Last year when I spoke about performance tuning at a Quest event in California, there were already several folks there using SSD drives packaged in PCI Express cards like Fusion-io, and they were using it for more than just TempDB too.  When you&#8217;re really desperate for performance, like when your app just won&#8217;t scale and you&#8217;re out of space for more SAN gear, you get desperate, and you&#8217;ll try those cutting-edge technologies before the rest of us.  Those people are out there already, dancing on the edge, and I&#8217;m hearing good reports back.</p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s a bad idea for mission critical servers because truly mission critical databases should be on clusters, and most SANs don&#8217;t take solid state drives yet.  I think the best use for SSDs in SANs is for automated tiering systems where the SAN controller automatically moves data around based on how often it&#8217;s accessed.  Data that&#8217;s very, very frequently read can get migrated onto SSD.  That&#8217;s still a high-end SAN feature though, not mainstream.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Should we be looking at Page Life Expectancy or Buffer Cache Hit Ratio and why?</strong></p>
<p>We should be looking at Page Life Expectancy, but only in combination with all of the metrics packaged together.  I talked about this in my blog post, Bottlenecks and Bank Balances:</p>
<p>http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2009/10/bottlenecks-and-bank-balances/</p>
<p>At the end of the day, does it really matter whether your Page Life Expectancy is 70 or 700 or 7000?  Is that your biggest bottleneck, and are the application users satisfied with performance?  I&#8217;ve managed servers with abysmal Page Life Expectancy numbers (like below 60) that the business was completely satisfied with.  Some applications just aren&#8217;t important or aren&#8217;t worth spending extra money/time/resources on.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: What part of SQL troubleshooting do people struggle the most with?</strong></p>
<p>Reading execution plans and doing something about it.  I bought Grant Fritchey&#8217;s book, SQL Server 2008 Query Performance Tuning Distilled, for that exact reason &#8211; I just couldn&#8217;t read the plans well enough, and the question comes up so gosh-darned often.  I&#8217;m working with a company now that sends me execution plans so large that I would need to print them out on wallpaper and paste it up in a conference room.  There comes a point where you have to draw the line and say, &#8220;It&#8217;s not a matter of tuning this query &#8211; it&#8217;s a matter of dumping this query and asking what the user is really trying to accomplish, and how we can meet their needs.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Can you name some tools that will help with troubleshooting performance?<br />
</strong><br />
I work for Quest Software, but even if I didn&#8217;t, I&#8217;d name-drop Foglight Performance Analysis.  It samples SQL Server&#8217;s memory space, captures performance data without requiring a trace, and gives you a gorgeous slice &amp; dice user interface to quickly find the nastiest queries, applications, and users.  There&#8217;s flat-out nothing like it on the market.</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t imagine performance tuning without Bill Graziano&#8217;s fantastic utility ClearTrace.  If you don&#8217;t have Foglight PA, you&#8217;ll be running traces to capture queries, and ClearTrace really helps you make sense of trace file contents.  I can fire up ClearTrace and find problem queries very fast.</p>
<p>In the book, I wrote the Performance Dashboard chapter, and I&#8217;d highly recommend that for anybody who has zero budget for SQL Server tools.  It&#8217;s not perfect &#8211; it&#8217;s far from it &#8211; but it&#8217;s one heck of a big leap forward when you&#8217;re stumbling around in the dark trying to find bottlenecks.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: What are some of the biggest mistakes people make when setting up a new server in terms of performance?</strong> </p>
<p>Not using Instant File Initialization, not aligning their partitions, and remote desktopping into the server to run things like SQL Server Management Studio.  STOP remote controlling your servers.  SSMS burns up memory that should be dedicated to the database engine.  I&#8217;ve got a setup checklist on my site, too:</p>
<p>http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2008/03/sql-server-2005-setup-checklist-part-1-before-the-install/</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Which chapter was the hardest to write and can you explain why?<br />
Both of them.</strong></p>
<p>Lemme make one thing perfectly clear: I am the dumbest author involved in this book.  For real.  When I first got the chance to be involved with this book, I looked at the available chapter list and said, &#8220;I&#8217;ll take storage and the Performance Dashboard.&#8221;  I took storage because I loooooove storage, and I took the Performance Dashboard because I thought it would be easy.</p>
<p>The storage chapter was hard because I wanted to keep working on it forever.  One of my coauthors said he spent 1,200 hours on one chapter, and I can see how that would happen.  As I was writing and editing the storage chapter, I just kept thinking of more and more things I wanted to throw in there, but when you&#8217;re writing, you have to make sure you&#8217;re covering each subject well enough.  I didn&#8217;t want to do a half-ass job covering a million topics.  I eventually had to cut myself off to do my day job, and I&#8217;m still killing myself over things I didn&#8217;t get to include.  I didn&#8217;t include the infamous 15-second IO warning events, for example.  I&#8217;m hoping we get to do a SQL 2008 R2 version so I can expand it.</p>
<p>The Performance Dashboard chapter was hard because I wrote it and then said, &#8220;Okay, this is not nearly enough information.&#8221;  I dove into creating new reports because really, if you&#8217;re going to go down the Performance Dashboard route, you&#8217;re going to want to roll your own stuff too.  I didn&#8217;t originally sign onto the project to write an SSRS book (because I&#8217;m an SSRS noob) but I had to include some stuff on it, and that made me nervous.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Will you write another book?</strong><br />
Originally I said no.  I yelled no from the mountaintops.  Now, wouldn&#8217;t you know it, I&#8217;m finishing an ebook as we speak.  This one&#8217;s on Twitter though.  I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ll do another ground-up from-scratch technical book.  I have amazing respect for guys like Ross Mistry who keep banging out books.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: What SQL books are on your bookshelf?</strong></p>
<p>SQL Server Query Performance Tuning Distilled by Grant Fritchey<br />
SQL Server 2005 Performance Tuning by Steven Wort, Christian Bolton, Justin Langford, and more<br />
Inside SQL Server 2008 T-SQL Querying by Itzik Ben Gan and others<br />
Oracle and VMware by Bert Scalzo<br />
The Wine Trials 2010 by Robin Goldstein and Alexis Herschkowitsch (databases and drinks go together like developers and cursors)<br />
And tons more, but that&#8217;s a good start.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Who are your favorite authors?</strong></p>
<p>I really like reading James Rowland-Jones&#8217; chapter on Latching in our book.  He has a really good sense of humor that plays well in print.</p>
<p>I like that Kevin Kline writes like he talks &#8211; he makes complex topics deceptively simple.  Anybody can sandblast you with fifty-cent words, but Kevin distills things down in a way that&#8217;s easy to read quickly.</p>
<p>Tim Ford spends entirely too much time writing his next book and needs to blog more, because he&#8217;s hilarious, and I&#8217;m going through withdrawal.</p>
<p>My favorite authors of all time, though, would be Dave Eggers, Douglas Adams, and Garrison Keillor &#8211; and the poet W. H. Auden for good measure.  I&#8217;m no Paul Randal &#8211; I think I read maybe 10 books in 2009, and I don&#8217;t see that changing in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: How are you involved with SQLServerpedia?</strong></p>
<p>There&#8217;s only two of us really heavily involved on a day-to-day basis.  Brett Epps handles everything technical &#8211; if it involves PHP, graphics, MySQL, anything like that, that&#8217;s his full time job.  (I&#8217;m thankful for him, because when I was the guy doing that, the site looked bad and performed worse.)  I handle everything else &#8211; working with the bloggers, checking article submissions, planning promotions, coming up with what we&#8217;re going to do next.  I get a lot of logistical support from a bunch of Questies &#8211; Christian Hasker, Andy Grant, Betsy Mendenhall, Heather Eichman, and Stephanie McCulloch &#8211; but most of the work is still me.</p>
<p>I love it.  I really wish I had more hours in the day to spend on SQLServerPedia.  We&#8217;ve got a million cool ideas, and it just comes down to manpower.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Where can we expect to see you in 2010? Any conferences, seminars, trade shows or classrooms perhaps?</strong></p>
<p>EVERYWHERE, MUHAHAHA.  Okay, maybe not.  I&#8217;ll be at the WorkTamer conferences in Canada, the Microsoft MVP Summit in Seattle, SQLSaturday Chicago, the PASS Summit in Seattle, and maybe the European one as well.  I&#8217;m aiming for the Microsoft Certified Master program in March, and if that happens, I&#8217;ll be off the radar for a few weeks.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve got a day-long free virtual event coming in February with Kevin Kline and Ari Weil, too &#8211; we&#8217;ll be talking DMVs all day long.  More news soon&#8230;</p>
<p>That is it,  thanks to Brent for the interview, you can visit Brent&#8217;s site here: http://www.brentozar.com/ and you can follow him on twitter here: http://twitter.com/brento</p>
<p>To check out the book, visit the wrox site here: http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Professional-SQL-Server-2008-Internals-and-Troubleshooting.productCd-0470484284.html or Amazon here: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0470484284?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0470484284">Professional SQL Server 2008 Internals and Troubleshooting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/interview-with-brent-ozar-about-the-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
