<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>community &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>T-SQL Tuesday #42: The Long and Winding Road</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/t-sql-tuesday-42/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/t-sql-tuesday-42/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 06:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlfamily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsql tuesday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/05/t-sql-tuesday-42/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s the second Tuesday of the month, which means it’s time again for #TSQL2sday! It is the 42nd installment of this blog post series and the subject is not about the Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything as I hoped it wo&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://wendyverse.blogspot.be/2013/05/its-time-for-t-sqltuesday-42-long-and.html"></a></p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://wendyverse.blogspot.be/2013/05/its-time-for-t-sqltuesday-42-long-and.html" target="_blank"><img style="float: left;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/TSQL2sday37/TSQL2sday.PNG?mtime=1355209029" alt="" width="133" height="134" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It’s the second Tuesday of the month, which means it’s time again for #TSQL2sday! It is the 42<sup>nd</sup> installment of this blog post series and the subject is not about the <em>Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything</em> as I hoped it would be, but about <a href="http://wendyverse.blogspot.be/2013/05/its-time-for-t-sqltuesday-42-long-and.html">the long and winding road</a> that is our work life and which technologies were key to our interests and successes. In this blog post I’ll talk about how I got where I am now and how SSIS played a major role in it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">About exactly 4 years ago I suddenly found myself out of a job during the financial crisis. I was an IT consultant with no specialization and little experience. Luckily I quickly found a new job through one of my ex-colleagues (always maintain your network people!) at a local BI consulting firm. I didn’t know a thing about Business Intelligence (I had a bit of data mining and data warehousing in a course at university, but I can’t really say it sticked), but fortunately the company was willing to invest in junior people. This is a really amazing thing to do, especially in times of crisis and I’m very grateful for the opportunity they gave me. So the first thing they did was sending me to a couple of Microsoft trainings. I followed one on Analysis Services and I was really amazed by the product. I took another one about Integration Services and I was … not so amazed. I don’t really recall why, but the product just didn’t strike a chord with me.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A few weeks later I was on my first BI project and my first assignment was: make some SSIS packages. I dreaded the task, but trying to make the most of it I dove into SSIS. And after I made my hands dirty with it and got over the initial learning curve, I suddenly fell in love with SSIS! I saw the possibilities the product has to offer and what amazing stuff you can do with it and I lost all the prejudices I had earlier. After some time I really wanted to expand my knowledge on SSIS, so I had the idea of answering questions about SSIS on forums. Because you learn the most about a subject by “teaching” it. By chance I noticed the SQLServerCentral newsletter in one of my colleagues’ inbox, so I thought: “Why not that forum? Let’s try it out.” I went to SSC, registered myself and started answering questions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Fast forward a few years. I switched jobs in the meantime but still work quite a lot with SSIS. Thanks to my involvement in SSC, I got to learn a lot of interesting people in the SQL Server community. I started giving sessions at conferences about SSIS, writing articles about it, giving trainings about it and as of late, writing blog posts about it. In a way, my passion for SSIS made me what I am today (in a professional way I mean). I still love SSIS and I like very much what Microsoft did with it in SQL Server 2012, but recently I’m realizing writing ETL isn’t the only thing that matters. I’m slowly diving into the front-end of the BI solution, which is very interesting to work with. Right now I’m learning more and more about SharePoint BI – PowerPivot and Power View – and my focus of blog posts is shifting in that direction. My next session I will give at an event will not be about SSIS, but about data visualization. In other words, I might be in yet another bend in the long and winding road that is my career in business intelligence. I’m very curious to what the future will bring…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/t-sql-tuesday-42/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Advent 2012 Day 9: Reinventing the wheel</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-advent-2012-day-10/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-advent-2012-day-10/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/12/sql-advent-2012-day-10/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is day nine of the SQL Advent 2012 series of blog posts. Today we are going to look at something called reinventing the wheel. Just in case your are not familiar with this metaphor or maybe you are not a native English speaker, I will use wikipedia&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is day nine of the <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBProgramming/sql-advent-2012-here-is">SQL Advent 2012 series</a> of blog posts. Today we are going to look at something called <em>reinventing the wheel</em>. Just in case your are not familiar with this metaphor or maybe you are not a native English speaker, I will use wikipedia&#8217;s description of what <em>reinventing the wheel</em> means.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ciphershot/7139384947/" title="#124 Reinventing the Wheel by Ciphershot, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8166/7139384947_e4f67ac7ba_n.jpg" width="213" height="320" alt="#124 Reinventing the Wheel" style="float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;" /></a> From wikipedia: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinventing_the_wheel</p>
<p><em>To <strong>reinvent the wheel</strong> is to duplicate a basic method that has already previously been created or optimized by others.<br />
The inspiration for this idiomatic metaphor lies in the fact that the wheel is the archetype of human ingenuity, both by virtue of the added power and flexibility it affords its users, and also in the ancient origins which allow it to underlie much, if not all, of modern technology. As it has already been invented, and is not considered to have any operational flaws, an attempt to reinvent it would be pointless and add no value to the object, and would be a waste of time, diverting the investigator&#8217;s resources from possibly more worthy goals which his or her skills could advance more substantially.</em></p>
<p>So now that you have read the paragraph above, how many times did you write some code only to find out that it already exists in the language as part of some library or function. How many times have you written code that you could have easily grabbed from GitHub, CodePlex and other repositories for your own use?</p>
<p></p>
<h2>Why write your own solution when you can use something that is robust and tested?</h2>
<p>Find out who the community leaders are for a particular skill set that you are interested in, start following these people, follow them on twitter, subscribe to their blogs and podcasts. Go to their presentations, talk to them, find out what they use, find out if they have made code available for the public to use. You will find out that a good percentage of these people have made available a whole bunch of libraries, stored procedures, functions, maintenance routines and much more for you to use and it is all free. <br />
Don&#8217;t be scared to ask for help on twitter, if you don&#8217;t know any of the SQL Server tweeple, use the #sqlhelp hash tag and ask for help, here is an example of what it looks like <a href="https://twitter.com/search/realtime?q=%23sqlhelp&amp;src=typd">#sqlhelp</a></p>
<p>Here is an image of the replies on twitter after I asked a question with the #sqlhelp tag</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Denis/ADvent/sqlhelp.PNG?mtime=1355070897"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Denis/ADvent/sqlhelp.PNG?mtime=1355070897" width="516" height="438" /></a></div>
<p>Some commercial firms will also have community editions of code and tools for you to use. Take advantage of this, these are great, if you like the tools then maybe you will find a need for the pro editions, these have more bells and whistles and are not limited.</p>
<p>Some examples of available solutions.<br />
<strong>Index maintenance</strong><br />
Do you have scripts that do index maintenance, do you have to modify these scripts often because of bugs or changing requirements? Take a look at <a href="http://ola.hallengren.com/sql-server-index-and-statistics-maintenance.html">SQL Server Index and Statistics Maintenance</a> by <a href="http://ola.hallengren.com/">Ola Hallengren</a></p>
<p>Also check out this index defrag script by <a href="http://sqlfool.com/">Michelle Ufford</a> <a href="http://sqlfool.com/2011/06/index-defrag-script-v4-1/">Index Defrag Script, v4.1</a></p>
<p><strong>SQL Server activity</strong><br />
Want to know what is going on right now? Try <a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic/default.aspx">Adam Machanic&#8217;s</a> procedure <a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic/archive/2012/03/22/released-who-is-active-v11-11.aspx">Who Is Active</a></p>
<p><strong>The state of your SQL Server</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.brentozar.com/">Brent Ozar Unlimited</a> has a neat proc you can run which will give you a fast health check, get it here: <a href="http://www.brentozar.com/blitz/">sp_Blitz</a>. There is also a video showing how to use this proc</p>
<p><strong>Potential problems in your SQL Server database</strong><br />
Try our own <a href="http://sqlcop.lessthandot.com/">SQLCop</a> tool, this tool was written by <a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=10">George Mastros</a> and will highlight potential problems</p>
<p><strong>Execution Plans</strong><br />
SQL Sentry has a free version of <a href="http://www.sqlsentry.net/plan-explorer/sql-server-query-view.asp">SQL Sentry Plan Explorer</a>. This plan explorer does much more than the one that comes with SQL Server Management Studio</p>
<h2>Get involved</h2>
<p>If you have created some cool code and you know there is nothing similar, why now give back to the community? Put it out there, solicit feedback and in the end the code will be better because more eyes will have looked at it. Accept contributions as well. All of these things will make the community as a whole grow, if the community grows then the platform will grow as well. When the platform grows, this means there will be more demand for someone with your skill set. You are responsible that your community doesn&#8217;t turn into a ghost town.</p>
<h2>Do you know of great SQL Server tools/scripts/procs</h2>
<p>If you feel that there is great code/tools out there for SQL Server that I did not mention, leave me a comment and I will check it out and add it to this post</p>
<p>That is all for day nine of the <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBProgramming/sql-advent-2012-here-is">SQL Advent 2012 series</a>, come back tomorrow for the next one, you can also check out all the posts from last year here: <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DataDesign/sql-advent-2011-recap">SQL Advent 2011 Recap</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-advent-2012-day-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ada Lovelace Day..Do you remember which women have influenced you over the years?</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/ada-lovelace-day-do-you/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/ada-lovelace-day-do-you/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lovelace]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/10/ada-lovelace-day-do-you/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Someone posted an Ada Lovelace day message in our forum. Here is what it said

This Ada Lovelace Day on October 7, share your story about a woman — whether an engineer, a scientist, a technologist or mathematician — who has inspired you to become who&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Someone posted an <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewtopic.php?f=100&amp;t=15486">Ada Lovelace day message in our forum</a>. Here is what it said</p>
<blockquote><p>This Ada Lovelace Day on October 7, share your story about a woman — whether an engineer, a scientist, a technologist or mathematician — who has inspired you to become who you are today. Write a blog post, record a podcast, film a video, draw a comic, or pick any other way to talk about the women who have been guiding lights in your life. Give your heroine the credit she deserves!</p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>More information can be found here: http://findingada.com/</p>
<p>
After thinking a little, I realized that I am not doing what I am doing because of any man or woman, but I am better at what I do thanks to a woman&#8230;.</p>
<p>This person is of course <strong>Kalen Delaney</strong>. It started all with the Inside SQL Server books for me..I still have the hardcover 2000 edition at home and will keep it for sentimental reasons (same is true for Ken Henderson&#8217;s guru books)</p>
<p>Kalen makes a lot of information available through her <a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/kalen_delaney/">blog</a>, her training, the contributions to SQL Server magazine and of course her books. The book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735626243/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=0735626243">Microsoft® SQL Server 2008 Internals</a> that she co-authored is a must have if you want to get to the next level of SQL Server knowledge</p>
<p>After reading the Inside SQL book certain things about SQL Server made a lot more sense to me, for example the fact that you couldn&#8217;t fit more than 8060 bytes in a row, well this is because the pages were 8K. There were many more examples like that.</p>
<p>Kalen is also involved with the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290475/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399373&amp;creativeASIN=1617290475">SQL Server MVP Deep Dives Vol. 2</a> book, just like with the previous version all author royalties will be donated to charity.</p>
<p>Thank you Kalen for providing all that wonderful information in a variety of formats&#8230;the SQL community is thankful!!</p>
<p>So my readers, which women have influenced you over the years? Leave me a comment or blog about it and drop me a link in the comments&#8230;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/ada-lovelace-day-do-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Saturday #46, Raleigh NC</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 10:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlsaturday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/09/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It's been a few days since SQL Saturday 46 and I have finally found some time to jot down my recap. This was the first Raleigh SQL Saturday and it lived up to all of my expectations.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a few days since SQL Saturday 46 and I have finally found some time to jot down my recap. This was the first Raleigh SQL Saturday and it lived up to all of my expectations.</p>
<h2>The Event</h2>
<div style="float: left; margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/volunteers.png" alt="The volunteers that made it happen" /><br />
The excellent group of volunteers <br />that pulled it all together
</div>
<p>There were <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/46/schedule.aspx" title="Check out the full schedule">6 tracks of events</a>, which were balanced more towards the BI and SSIS side of things than the previous events I&#8217;ve attended. Registration was hiccup free (though I was early and missed the rush), rooms were all located in close proximity to one another, and the lunch room flowed pretty quickly despite an early line. The signs and schedule were excellent, with 8.5&#215;11 placards posted for all of the sessions on each room&#8217;s door as well as large grids posted on the wall in two locations, displaying the whole schedule. Once I figured out the room numbering, it was easy to locate the sessions or speakers I was interested in. The event was organized by members of <a href="http://tripass.org/" title="Visit the TriPASS site">TriPASS</a>, the local SQL Server User Group in Raleigh, and I&#8217;m looking forward to getting involved with the next one they put together. If I had to pick one element of the event that characterized it the most, that element would be how smoothly the execution went.</p>
<h2>Sessions</h2>
<div style="float: right; margin: .5em 0 .5em 2em; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/grant.png" alt="Grant Fritchey starting his session" /><br />
Grant Fritchey getting <br /> started on his session
</div>
<p>I started my morning off with Geoff Hiten&#8217;s (<a href="http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/geoffh/default.aspx" title="Geoff Hiten's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/sqlcraftsman" title="SQLCraftsman on Twitter">twitter</a>) &#8220;Clustering for Mere Mortals&#8221; session, which gave me enough basic knowledge that there may be a clustering blog article in the near future. Geoff did an excellent job of communicating a complex task to his audience, balancing just enough background knowledge, direct examples, and good practices from his own experience.</p>
<p>I expanded my CDC knowledge in Chris Skorlinski&#8217;s (<a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/repltalk/" title="Visit Chris's blog">blog</a>) first session, but unfortunately wasn&#8217;t able to make his SSIS + CDC session later in the afternoon (the disadvantage to being in my home town, had to run home to feed the cats). He provided an excellent overview of how CDC works, how to interact with it, and some of the internals behind the magic.</p>
<p>After lunch, I attended Grant Fritchey&#8217;s (<a href="http://scarydba.wordpress.com/" title="Visit Grant's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/GFritchey" title="GFritchey on Twitter">twitter</a>) &#8220;Identifying and Fixing Performance Problems using&#8221; presentation and had a blast (I&#8217;m using the SQL Saturday site-ized version of his presentation name). Despite some demo issues, Grant managed to balance delivery of his presentation with good audience feedback, even taking a 2 minute break in the middle to get everyone up on their feet and fight the post-lunch effects. </p>
<p>After Grant&#8217;s session I caught Andy Leonard&#8217;s (<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/andy_leonard/" title="Visit Andy's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/AndyLeonard" title="AndyLeonard on Twitter">twitter</a>) &#8220;SSIS Design Patterns&#8221; session. I was completely out of my depth here, being far more of a beginner in SSIS (it doesn&#8217;t get much more beginner), but I was still able to take away quite a bit of information from the session, including some ideas I will likely try to put into practice in an upcoming project.</p>
<div style="margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/andyquote.png" alt="Andy Leonard Quote" /></div>
<h2>The After-thing</h2>
<p>I managed to run into quite a few of the local members of the user group, who did an excellent job preparing and executing this event. It seemed Janice Lee (<a href="http://janiceclee.com/" title="Visit Janice's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/JaniceLee" title="JaniceLee on Twitter">twitter</a>) and I were constantly running into each other just long enough to share how great our last session was before heading off to two more completely different ones. It was one of these between-session breaks where I got to meet Eric Humphrey (<a href="http://lotsahelp.blogspot.com/" title="Visit Eric's blog">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/lotsahelp" title="Lotsahelp on Twitter">twitter</a>) for the first time, another familiar face from the SQL community on twitter. There were many others I met along the way and at least as many people that I intended to meet but missed (or who snuck out early). </p>
<p>The day ended on a high note, around a table with Grant, Allen White (<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/allen_white/default.aspx" title="Check out Allen's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/sqlrunr" title="SQLRunr on Twitter">twitter</a>), Brent Kremer, and David Elvikis. Stories were traded, good food was eaten (not counting the fried pickles that showed up), and I think we all had a fun time. It was great to find out that Grant and Allen were just two more normal (well, close to normal) people like the rest of us. Somehow I managed to leave owing a round. So the next time we end up at the same event Grant, don&#8217;t be surprised if a drink shows up <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f600.png" alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<div style="margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat46_2010/scotch.png" alt="Glass of Scotch (The Macallen 12)" />
</div>
<p>Unfortunately I fell down on the job where pictures and tweets were concerned, so there aren&#8217;t as many as there have been for past events. </p>
<p>SQL Saturday 46 was an excellent event and ultimately both a lot of fun and a lot of information, what I have grown to expect from SQL Saturday events. The sessions were great, the event went smoothly, and the networking with the local and greater community was everything I had hoped for. I&#8217;m already looking for to my next one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/sql-saturday-46-raleigh-nc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Saturday 28, Baton Rouge</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 09:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlsaturday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/08/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I'm in the air flying back from SQL Saturday 28 and wanted to capture my thoughts while the event was still fresh. Overall I would have to rate it as a resounding success. Last year the event attracted 200 professionals from Baton Rouge and the surrounding area, this year attendance doubled to 400, with additional interest from about 200 more that weren't able to make it.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m in the air flying back from SQL Saturday 28 and wanted to capture my thoughts while the event was still fresh. Overall I would have to rate it as a resounding success. Last year the event attracted 200 professionals from Baton Rouge and the surrounding area, this year attendance doubled to 400, with additional interest from about 200 more that weren&#8217;t able to make it. </p>
<div style="float: left; margin: .5em 2em .5em 0px; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<a href="http://yfrog.com/jd1bej" title="See the fullsize picture"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat28_2010/patrick_leblanc.png" alt="Patrick LeBlanc (@patrickdba) speaking Friday night" /></a><br />
Patrick LeBlanc (<a href="http://sqldownsouth.blogspot.com/" title="Patrick LeBlanc's Blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/patrickdba" title="Patrick LeBlanc (@patrickdba) on twitter">twitter</a>)<br /> Speaking Friday night
</div>
<p>The event featured <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/28/schedule.aspx" title="Check out the full schedule">8 tracks</a>, including SQL and .Net sessions. Several early-bird sessions kicked off around 7:30AM &#8211; I have to applaud those brave enough to speak in front of a crowd that early, as I was still getting appropriately caffeinated.  In addition, INETA made it possible for Keith Elder (<a href="http://keithelder.net/blog/" title="Keith Elder's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/keithelder" title="@KeithElder on twitter">twitter</a>) to provide a full day&#8217;s &#8220;.Net From Scratch&#8221; training session. Steve Jones (<a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/steve_jones/default.aspx" title="Steve Jones on SQL Server Central">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/way0utwest" title="Steve Jones (@way0utwest) on twitter">twitter</a>) delivered the keynote, starting the day off with commentary on professional development, technical skill, and the importance of enjoying our jobs and finding balance in life. </p>
<p>The dinner the night before was in a large enough venue that we were able to mingle and talk a good bit before the dinner appeared, and the food was both good and plentiful (which worked out well for those of us who had been eating airport fare). Patrick LeBlanc (<a href="http://sqldownsouth.blogspot.com/" title="Patrick LeBlanc's Blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/patrickdba" title="Patrick LeBlanc (@patrickdba) on twitter">twitter</a>) provided our mid-evening entertainment, welcoming everyone to the area and introducing us to the team that had worked so hard to put the event together. Somehow I managed to end up at the <a href="http://www.sparkhound.com/" title="Check out the Sparkhound website">Sparkhound</a> table, but they&#8217;re a friendly group and it made for a fun dinner.</p>
<div style="float: right; margin: 2em; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<a href="http://yfrog.com/83a1rxj" title="See the fullsize picture"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat28_2010/chris_eargle.png" alt="Chris Eargle (@kodefuguru) documenting his audience" /></a><br />
Chris Eargle (<a href="http://www.kodefuguru.com/" title="Chris Eargle's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/KodefuGuru" title="Chris Eargle (@kodefuguru) on twitter">twitter</a>)<br /> Documenting his Audience
</div>
<p>The event took place at LSU in a lecture hall, which meant we had classrooms with integrated power and overheads, simplifying some of the setup. A full size classroom was set aside for the speakers and featured plenty of space for us to get off our feet, plug in, or just get a snack throughout the day.</p>
<p>My session was right after lunch (see the <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DataDesign/creating-a-conceptual-data-model" title="Check out my pre-session post">Conceptual Data Modeling</a> post from last week). Despite speaking with no code examples in an after lunch session, I still managed to draw a number of inquisitive people. Despite ending a few minutes early, we still managed to almost run over due to the great conversation we had at the end. Thomas LeBlanc (<a href="http://thesmilingdba.blogspot.com/" title="Thomas LeBlanc's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/TheSmilingDBA" title="Thomas LeBlanc (@TheSmilingDBA) on twitter">twitter</a>) presented on normalization and data modeling after my session and I stuck around to watch his presentation as well, picking up some ideas for the next version of my presentation.</p>
<p>Of the three SQL Saturday events I attended this year, this one was probably the best represented on twitter during the day. William Assaf (<a href="http://sqltact.blogspot.com/" title="William Assaf's blog">blog</a>|<a href="http://twitter.com/william_a_dba" title="William Assaf (@william_a_dba) on twitter">twitter</a>) kept the media flowing, constantly uploading pictures and commentary throughout the day and keeping the <a href="http://twitter.com/SQLSatBR" title="[Sorta] Official SQLSatBR Twitter account">@SQLSatBR</a> account busy.  </p>
<div style="float: left; margin: .5em 2em .5em 0em; color: #666666; font-size: 80%; text-align: center;">
<a href="http://yfrog.com/mcg1sp" title="See the fullsize picture"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/sqlsat28_2010/sqlsatteam.png" alt="A great team of people" /></a><br />
A great team of people (click for larger)
</div>
<p>As is always the case with the events, the best part was the people. I met a number of new people, at varying places in their respective careers, and had interesting conversations that lasted until the restaurant hosting the after party finally asked the last four of us to leave. I wasn&#8217;t able to work everyone&#8217;s names into the post, but it was a great group and there a lot of names both familiar and new. From what I hear, the planning for next year is already in progress, so maybe I&#8217;ll see you there.</p>
<p>For more pictures, check out <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/willassaf/SQLSaturday28?authkey=Gv1sRgCIDCruLCuNDy4wE&amp;feat=directlink#" title="William A's full Picasa Gallery">William&#8217;s full gallery</a> on Picasa.<br />
<br style="clear: left;" /><br />
And the slide decks for my session <a href="http://tiernok.com/presentation.php" title="Eli's slide decks">are posted now</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-saturday-28-baton-rouge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Being a finalist for the Exceptional DBA of the Year</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/exceptional-dba/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/exceptional-dba/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 16:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy and Standards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exceptional dba of the year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/exceptional-dba/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week brought one of the highest achievements in my career and community work.  On June 23rd it was announced by Red Gate and SQL Server Central that I had made it into the finalists for the Exceptional DBA of the Year award.  WOW!  Every time I say it, I still get that feeling in my gut only certain things that you are truly emotional about can bring.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/dba_year.gif" alt="" title="" width="180" height="79" /></div>
<p>This week brought one of the highest achievements in my career and community work.  On June 23rd it was announced by Red Gate and SQL Server Central that I had made it into the finalists for the Exceptional DBA of the Year award.  WOW!  Every time I say it, I still get that feeling in my gut only certain things that you are truly emotional about can bring.  </p>
<p><strong>June 23rd, 2010</strong></p>
<p>The morning that the announcement went out I was completely blown away, not only by the nomination, but by the reactions and support from the SQL Community.  Twitter, personal email, IM, Facebook, Linkedin and every other online communication method had messages congratulating me on this remarkable accomplishment and wishes for luck on winning. </p>
<p>This was also the day I was able to see who the other finalists were.  I was more than pleased to see Jorge Segarra (<a href="http://sqlchicken.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/sqlchicken">Twitter</a>) and Jonathan Kehayias (<a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jonathan_kehayias/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/sqlsarg">Twitter</a>) in the final six.  Jorge is a leader in the SQL Community.  I could easily see that from the creation of SQL University and when I was lucky enough to have him come speak at SQL Saturday in Chicago.  Jonathan is another person that the word exceptional fits with without a doubt.  I’ve been very fortunate over the last few months to get to know him better and, for my part, call him a friend.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m still reading about Kevan Riley, John Burnette and Tracy Hamlin.  I can guarantee that these other three finalists are nothing short of exceptional simply by making it to this accomplishment as well.  I hope to meet all of them at PASS or in their local areas during SQL Saturday’s or SSUG’s. </p>
<p><strong>How did I get here?</strong></p>
<p>I have to thank Rose Waters (<a href="http://twitter.com/sqlrose">Twitter</a>) dearly.  Rose works on my team as a SQL Developer, and she is a great one at that.  She nominated me for this award which means more to me than I can express in a blog.  The one thing I strive for is to help the people around me, and try to create an atmosphere that we all want to come into daily.  The fact that Rose did this for me means I’m doing a good job at that goal.  Every time I hear Rose is attending User Groups meetings, posting on <a href="http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23sqlhelp">#SQLHELP</a> and interacting with the community I get a huge smile.  To help Rose and others get involved in this awesome community is the most important goal I have and can accomplish for myself. </p>
<p align="center"><strong>Thanks Rose!!!!</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/thanks.gif" alt="" title="" width="200" height="133" /></div>
</p>
<p><strong>The week in play</strong></p>
<p>The week following the announcement has been nonstop jaw dropping events.  The next day, my Google alerts had blown up on me and I was off looking at how big this nomination was.  Several news sites had announced the start of the community voting process, and many of the people I look up to and have a very high level of respect for had blogged on the announcement.  I found that even CNBC had the announcement the next day.  Each day brought another jaw dropping moment.  Thursday, I received a call from my local news paper.  The reporter had found out about the award and nomination, and wanted to report on the news in the weekends publications.  At this point I’m still just amazed at this entire nomination. </p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.red-gate.com/">Red Gate</a> and <a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/">SQL Server Central</a></strong></p>
<p>I feel the Exceptional DBA of the Year award that Red Gate and SQL Server Central have created is the utmost prestigious award in the SQL Server field.  To be a finalist is an honor and accomplishment.  The part of this nomination that is most special to me is that my peers are doing the nominating and voting.  There is no more gratifying feeling and reward than knowing your hard work is respected by so many others and you have helped them with their own growth in the community and personal careers.    That is, without a doubt in my mind, the power of the SQL Community.  We stand together and support each other no matter who the other person is.  In my mind, we are all exceptional in that way. </p>
<p><strong>Cast Your Vote!</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/vote.gif" alt="" title="" width="200" height="168" align="left" /></div>
<p></p>
<p>Winning this award would be one of the highest accomplishments possible in my career. I’d love to say, “Vote for me!” But, what I sincerely would like everyone to do is take a few minutes and read about all of the finalists. If you don’t know one of them from the community or personally, take a few minutes to research and find out what they have accomplished in their career. They have made it this far, and deserve the attention and recognition. Each of these DBAs is exceptional. It’s a hard decision, but do your best to vote for the person you truly feel is the most exceptional.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/exceptional-dba/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Community Services &#8211; Resources everywhere!</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-help-and-resources/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-help-and-resources/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 16:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/sql-help-and-resources/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the last day of Community Service week for SQL University.  Before we get started, I’d like to say it has been nothing short of a pleasure writing the last two weeks for SQL University.  All of the discussions and topics we a lot of fun to go over and I’m looking forward to hearing from everyone how they were able to use them.  Don’t forget to pass SQL University and the community itself on to the person to your side that may not be aware of them.  Let’s keep building this community together!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the last day of Community Service week for <a href="http://sqlchicken.com/sql-university">SQL University</a>.  Before we get started, I’d like to say it has been nothing short of a pleasure writing the last two weeks for SQL University.  All of the discussions and topics were a lot of fun to go over and I’m looking forward to hearing from everyone how they were able to use them.  Don’t forget to pass SQL University and the community itself on to the person to your side that may not be aware of them.  Let’s keep building this community together!</p>
<p><strong>The last one means, TEST!</strong></p>
<p>Today being our last day of community service week, we’re going to take a quiz.  </p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/quiz.gif" alt="" title="" width="160" height="201" /></div>
<p>Kidding!!!  (I think an apple just whizzed by my head)</p>
<p><strong>Resources</strong> are up to bat and we have a plethora of them available to us in the community.   Between Jes, Coach LaRock and I authoring community service week, we have covered a ton of community information.  </p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/2010/06/14/meet-the-sql-server-community/">Meet the SQL Server Community! </a>– (6/14) by Jes Borland</li>
<li><a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/sql-community-tech-forums">SQL Server Forums-Helping to Build a Knowledge Base </a>(6/15) by Ted Krueger </li>
<li><a href="http://thomaslarock.com/2010/06/sql-university-community-service-week/">DBA Coach LaRock: Community Service Week </a>(6/16)</li>
<li><a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/2010/06/17/sql-community-professional-association-of-sql-server/">SQL Community: Professional Association of SQL Server</a> – (6/17) by Jes Borland</li>
<li><a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/sql-community-blogging">Let’s Blog!</a> &#8211; (6/17) by Ted Krueger</li>
</ul>
<p>You could almost take what we’ve gone over and spend the next 2 years diving into just those topics.  There is one other corner of the community that I find to be exceptional that cannot go without discussion.  That is, the companies that stand behind us. </p>
<p>If you are reading this and have been part of a SQL Saturday, SQL Server User Group, Pod cast or any type of resource that requires funds, you already know exactly how devoted SQL related companies are to supporting the SQL Community.  Quest, Red-Gate, Pragmatic Works, Confio, Idera…the list goes on and on.  These companies all sell products that help us make life easier for a DBA or DB Developer.   As many say, they help us be lazy database administrators.</p>
<p>These companies take the vast amount of resources and pour them into building the community.  </p>
<p>Quest Software is a great example.  Quest has not only been a major sponsor for dozens of SQL events but also spends a great deal of resources on providing things like, &#8220;<a href="http://sqlserver.quest.com/kbcategory.jspa?categoryID=291">The pain of the week</a>&#8221; to the community.   <a href="http://sqlserverpedia.com/">SQLServerPedia</a> is a huge resource powered by Quest with Mr. Ozar leading the way.  You could without a doubt spend a month reading, watching and learning from <a href="http://sqlserverpedia.com/">SQLServerPedia</a>. </p>
<p>Red-Gate is another great company supporting the community in a number of ways,  from the <a href="http://www.exceptionaldba.com/">Exceptional DBA of the Year</a> recognition that is going on right now, to the work that Steve Jones (<a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/steve_jones/default.aspx">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/way0utwest">Twitter</a>)and Brad McGehee (<a href="http://www.bradmcgehee.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/bradmcgehee">Twitter</a>) do for the community backed by Red-Gate.  Red-Gate stands behind the community and does a great deal for us all.  And did I mention the SQL Tools rock?</p>
<p>Pragmatic Works is one of my favorite online free resources in the community.  There are so many <a href="http://www.pragmaticworks.com/Resources/webinars/Default.aspx">webinars</a> provided to the community to build on, you could spend another month just watching them to catch up.  Pragmatic Works has an entire <a href="http://www.pragmaticworks.com/Resources/Default.aspx">resource page</a> devoted to the webinars, whitepapers, articles and my personal favorite, the SSIS Cheat Sheet.  Pragmatic Works is a resource that is valued and highly recommended to everyone that touches anything SQL Server related.</p>
<p>I hardly even scratched the surface of these companies&#8217; devotion and support of the SQL Community.   There are dozens of others that I could sit down and praise for everything they do daily.  I&#8217;ve been fortunate to have worked with some of them during SQL Saturdays and User Groups and sat down to talk with them.  If you have a chance to find them at one of these events or meetings, stop by and get to know them.  You will be amazed at just how much they are involved in the community and the passion that comes out for it.  </p>
<p><strong>Don’t forget these resources</strong></p>
<p>Having lunch at your desk today while we talk about all these cool resources we have?  Good!  We can talk about <a href="http://www.sqllunch.com/">SQL Lunch</a>.  SQL Lunch is another resource that is absolutely free and invaluable.   SQL Lunch is composed of the entire world as a location.  There are speakers from all over that take their time out to hold sessions during the lunch hour (in some time zones).  I know I can’t think of a better way to spend my lunch.  And I know if you are a DBA or DB Developer, you are eating at your desk just as often as I do.</p>
<p>SQL Share is another virtual training resource.  SQL Community leaders such as <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/13986/JessicaMoss.aspx">Jessica Moss</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/1379/Jonathan-Kehayias.aspx">Jonathan Kehayias</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/7/Brian-Knight.aspx">Brian Knight</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/18/Andy-Warren.aspx">Andy Warren</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/2626/Grant-Fritchey.aspx">Grant Fritchey</a> and many more are all part of providing this free resource.  These are web casts that focus on SQL Server topics and get right down to it.  They have an amazing talent for making the difficult topics very easy so you pick them up fast and do them the right way.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.simple-talk.com/sql/">Simple-Talk</a>: Do I need to say more?  I spend a lot of time on Simple-Talk.  The amount of knowledge that is held in this resource is almost frightening.  If you sat back and thought of trying to build a knowledge base and author listing like the one on this site, you would think it is impossible.  But it is there and if you don’t use it, you need to start.</p>
<p><strong>Scratched it</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/scratch.gif" alt="" title="" width="250" height="245" align="left" /></div>
<p>Yes, I scratched again.  I’ve only named a handful of places you can find resources to build your knowledge and networking in the SQL Community.  <strong>There is an enormous amount the SQL Community has to offer</strong>.  The homework for everyone is to go out and find people that do not know about the SQL Community and make them aware.  Nothing is ever perfect and everything can build higher and out farther.  The SQL Community has a lot of space to grow and growing with it is the reward we all shall share.</p>
<p>I’ve had a great time doing SQL University the last two weeks.  I hope everyone enjoyed it as much as I have.  As with all of the sessions, I welcome your suggestions on making things better for all of us.  If you would, please take the time to fill out the <a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/a/sqlchicken.com/viewform?hl=en&amp;formkey=dDBoSW02QldrTTc2dER3WVZheUlEX3c6MQ#gid=0">SQL University Course Evaluation</a>.</p>
<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-help-and-resources/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL University &#8211; Let&#8217;s blog</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-blogging/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-blogging/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 16:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/sql-community-blogging/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SQL University is one of the greatest concepts I've seen in the SQL Community.  Thanks to Jorge for coming up with it and organizing it.  Today we are going to talk about something dear and close to the concept of SQL University.  Blogging!  Blogs are an important part of the concept of SQL University.  With them we can easily bring this wealth of knowledge in the course syllabus format with writers from the SQL Community in a vast geographical range and range of expertise.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://sqlchicken.com/sql-university/">SQL University</a> is one of the greatest concepts I&#8217;ve seen in the SQL Community.  Thanks to Jorge Segarra (<a href="http://sqlchicken.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/SQLChicken">Twitter</a>)for coming up with it and organizing it.  Today we are going to talk about something dear and close to the concept of SQL University.  Blogging!  Blogs are an important part of the concept of SQL University.  With them we can easily bring this wealth of knowledge in the course syllabus format with writers from the SQL Community in a vast geographical range and range of expertise.  </p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/blog.gif" alt="" title="" width="296" height="280" /></div>
<p>Getting your day-to-day experiences and knowledge out to the community can be tough sometimes.  We can share what we know and what we learn with the teams we work in, but the walls of our building keep that from going far.  Blogging removes the wall and much does much more for our personal growth.  </p>
<p>Promoting and sharing blogs doesn’t only bring with it satisfaction of sharing what you’ve learned but also allows you to help everyone in the community so we can all build our knowledge base.</p>
<p><strong>My own personal story of blogging</strong></p>
<p>
I wrote my first blog in November of 2008.  The title was, &#8220;<a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBAdmin/MSSQLServerAdmin/user-to-schema-to-roles-for-controlling-">User to Schema to Roles for controlling security</a>&#8220;.  I won’t lie; I have learned an enormous amount about how to blog since then.  I’ve learned more about writing period!  Writing is an art form and catching the audience’s attention is important when you write your blogs.  The best part of blogging and writing in general is that everyone has their own way of getting the audience’s attention with humor, technical skills and just downright talent.  You hold that talent inside you, but you need to try it to find it and build on it. </p>
<p>In the SQL Community, we have hundreds (if not thousands) of bloggers out there writing daily and providing step-by-step articles that help us learn new things, fix old things and become better DBA’s all around.   So why write your own if the wealth of knowledge exists and is still pouring out of all of these SQL Community members?</p>
<p><i>If it is written already, I don’t need to write it.</i>  <-- Horrible statement! 


<p>The one reason I can give you to not hold back on starting up your own blog and sharing your SQL Server trials is: everyone sees a situation differently and replays that situation to an audience in many different ways.  Your way (yes, yours) can be the way that a hundred people grasp while other perspectives leave them with questions.  That reason alone takes, &#8220;it&#8217;s already done&#8221; and throws it down the truncate statement.  (Haha! SQL nerd humor is awesome!)  </p>
<p><strong>Let people review them</strong></p>
<p>Letting your guard down and sending your drafted blogs to friends and peers in the SQL Community can be hard.  No one likes to be marked by a red pen or be told that the entire blog may need a new direction.  In some cases, technical reviews find errors and mistakes all over the entire process and even directions describing why what you are telling everyone might not be the best way to do it.</p>
<p>A perfect example is a blog on using TRUNCATE_ONLY.   SHRINK and TRUNCATE_ONLY are just bad.  (Paul Randal (<a href="http://sqlskills.com/blogs/paul">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/paulrandal">Twitter</a>) <a href="http://www.sqlskills.com/blogs/paul/post/backup-log-with-no_log-use-abuse-and-undocumented-trace-flags-to-stop-it.aspx">says so</a>.) Very bad!  Google TRUNCATE_ONLY log and you will find plenty of bad advice, unfortunately.  The use of this option and action is really not a good thing to do on your SQL Servers.  We do see a lot of blogs going out on the topic though, and complete step-by-step instructions on how to do it.  If these blogs were placed under a technical review, the author may have gotten this reply:</p>
<blockquote><p><i>&#8220;Ted, I hate to say it but the blogs needs a lot of help in the technical realm.   Your steps are perfect and solid for anyone to take and get a shrinkfile working.  No doubt about that!  The problem is, you don’t say anything about why shrinkfile is not good and when to use it.  Just says: do it!  I could see how that might lead to a DBA putting a shrinkfile (or database) into a job and running it endlessly.  I would definitely add a description of the action and emergencies where it really is only called on.&#8221;</i></p></blockquote>
<p>I can also honestly say that most of the SQL Community and bloggers we have would be polite and respectful in while doing a review like this.  </p>
<p>While on this topic; thanks to Jes Borland (<a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/grrl_geek">Twitter</a>) for reviewing this blog and adding to it.  </p>
<p><strong>Practice if you are unsure</strong></p>
<p>Are you still unsure about blogging?  Practice a few blogs.  Write them and save them in a lost sea of folders in your Documents.  When you do that, keep your eyes and ears open in the community.  I can pretty much guarantee you that at some point, someone is going to mention the situation you wrote about either happened to them or they need help on it.  Then scramble to get your blog up and give it to them! </p>
<p><strong>Which blogs should I read?</strong></p>
<p>There are leaders in the SQL Community and those leaders all actively blog (and blog a lot).   The list could go on forever if we put them into this lesson, but luckily enough we have PASS to the rescue as always.  PASS collected a list of community bloggers and <a href="http://www.sqlpass.org/Community/BlogDirectory.aspx">posted it</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Still not convinced?</strong></p>
<p>Mike Walsh contributes a lot to the SQL Community.  A little while ago Mike spent the time writing a series on blogging.  The blog series starts with a <a href="http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2009/12/interview-with-mike-walsh-about-blogging/">video chat session with Brent Ozar</a> on experiences with blogging.  Then the series goes into, &#8220;<a href="http://www.straightpathsql.com/archives/2009/12/why-should-i-blog/">Why I should blog</a>&#8220;, &#8220;<a href="http://www.straightpathsql.com/archives/2009/12/how-should-i-blog/">How should I blog</a>&#8221; and the second part of the <a href="http://www.straightpathsql.com/archives/2009/12/blogging-tips-brent-ozar-mike-walsh-interview/">interview with Brent</a>.  The series is excellent and answers a lot of questions and pumps you up to get into blogging SQL Server and about the community.  If I haven’t convinced you how blogging can be extremely gratifying, Mike will.  </p>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to attend another SQL University course! Please take the time to fill out the <a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/a/sqlchicken.com/viewform?hl=en&amp;formkey=dDBoSW02QldrTTc2dER3WVZheUlEX3c6MQ#gid=0">SQL University Course Evaluation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-blogging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Server Forums – Helping to build a knowledge base</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-tech-forums/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-tech-forums/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 16:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/sql-community-tech-forums/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We're devoting an entire class to technical forums this week.  Forums have been around as long as most of the online community services have been.  They offer (mostly) unsolicited help at (mostly) no charge to the person requesting the help.  The word mostly worked its way into that last statement quite a bit.  There are resources out there that will allow the solicitation of the members and will charge for help.  This class is not going to discuss any of those services.  Why?  Because we are discussing the SQL community and this community truly puts itself out in front of everyone in need without asking for much of anything in return.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/sqlu_tiny.gif" alt="" title="" width="54" height="60" align="left" /></div>
<p>Welcome to another day of the Community Service week for <a href="http://sqlchicken.com/sql-university">SQL University</a>.  Jes Borland (<a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/grrl_geek">Twitter</a>) wrote an <a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/2010/06/14/meet-the-sql-server-community/">excellent class</a> yesterday on the SQL Community and areas that help connect us all.  Today we&#8217;re going to move on into the service parts of the SQL community and show how we can keep building the community.  I’d like to thank Jes again for helping author todays topic on technical forums.  </p>
<p>As with all SQL University weeks, please take a moment to rate us by filling out the <a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/a/sqlchicken.com/viewform?hl=en&amp;formkey=dDBoSW02QldrTTc2dER3WVZheUlEX3c6MQ#gid=0">SQL University Course Evaluation</a>.  We greatly appreciate your feedback so we can all become better.  </p>
<p>We&#8217;re devoting an entire class to technical forums this week.  Forums have been around as long as most of the online community services have been.  They offer (mostly) unsolicited help at (mostly) no charge to the person requesting the help.  The word mostly worked its way into that last statement quite a bit.  There are resources out there that will allow the solicitation of the members and will charge for help.  This class is not going to discuss any of those services.  Why?  Because we are discussing the SQL community and this community truly puts itself out in front of everyone in need without asking for much of anything in return.  The community devotes countless hours to supporting the strong foundation that it has constructed over the years.  Rarely will you find a part of it in which a request for money, goods or payback will be requested or expected.  In most cases, the gratitude of the solution being worked out amongst ourselves is the reward and payback.   The community takes that to heart and it is why you may not find another group like the SQL community.</p>
<p><strong>All bases covered</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/big _circle.gif" alt="" title="" width="645" height="504" /></div>
<p>SQL Server has grown to cover a wide flavor of specialized fields over the last decade.  Business Intelligence, CLR specialists, Tuning Experts, Mud Wrestling administrators, SAN Experts, Broker Experts, Full Text Search Experts, T-SQL Experts…the list goes on and on.  A lot of these experts fit into groups such as the BI group, the SQL Programming group and the DBA group.  In each of these groups you will find leaders that jump at the opportunity to throw what they know out into the public to help with any problems, new development or implementations.  These members of the community often are referred to as answerers.  And even the answerers turn to the others for help in the time of need, so we all become answerers in the community. </p>
<p><strong>The list</strong></p>
<p>How do you find these leaders and others that devote even minutes of their day to helping?</p>
<p>Below is a list of some sites that I, and other authors this semester, visit daily or hourly,  or sometimes lurk at with their finger on the refresh button:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/en/category/sqlserver/">MSDN SQL Forums</a></li>
<li><a href="http://serverfault.com/">Serverfault</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/Forums/">SQLServerCentral Forums</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sqlteam.com/forums/">SQL Team Forums</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=14&amp;sid=95273364bfa1d4cbee1b6a2bf998431b">LessThanDot.com SQL Forums</a></li>
</ul>
<p>These forums are available for free and are a resource that should not be set to the side lightly.  The members of these forums all have a great deal of unique, real-life experiences to share, and will help in building your own knowledge.   If everyone in the community helps build the forums, the knowledge base that can be composed is truly infinite in nature. </p>
<p><strong>Reward yourself by giving back</strong></p>
<p>When asking questions in forums around the SQL community, there is one way that you will find even more value in the resource.  Start answering the questions and helping others!  No one knows the answer to everything!  What will often happen is that you can assist in searching other resources, testing on your resources that may not be available to the other people asking for help or simply work through the problem and troubleshoot in your unique way.  This builds both sides in learning more about SQL Server and everyone benefits. </p>
<p>Never feel uncomfortable helping others.  Helping is one of the foundations of increasing your knowledge of SQL Server.  Everyone won’t run into the same problem in our careers working on SQL Server, so we may never be exposed to specific situations.  By giving back on these forums and working through issues that you may not have come across, you benefit by learning the situation, path to recovery and complete solution.  Imagine the power behind that knowledge if the same problem comes up in your own environment someday!  So when you ask a question on one of these SQL Server forum resources, think about looking around to see if you might be able to help out and give a little back.  You may just become addicted like many of us have over the years.</p>
<p><strong>Obligation</strong></p>
<p>It is absolutely critical to understand that the members in these forums do not have a binding agreement to help nor are they obligated in any way to stick through it.  Usually, the members helping will go to great lengths to solve the problems.  If a person does not stick through it though, becoming frustrated with them is usually not the best reaction.  The member helping may have had a problem of their own come up, or had to leave their computer for a time.  Every reply is given for free and as-is.  Reacting negatively when a member that is helping you leaves abruptly may cause repercussions in the future, when you have another question. </p>
<p>When every resource fails you: Books Online, real books, your secret cube buddy that knows how to write SELECT *, the help desk solution of reboot doesn’t work &#8211; give the technical forums a try.  When you get an answer and are sitting back relaxing, push the chair back to the keyboard and see if you can return the favor by helping on the next thread under yours.</p>
<p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/crazy_hair_puller.gif" alt="" title="" width="101" height="160" align="left" /></div>
<p>There is no need to pull your hair out at the roots; no need to call the CTO and tell them you quit before they fire you for not being able to fix it; no need to literally break down.  Give it a try and post your situation on a SQL Server forum.  I think you will be pleasantly surprised at the results you receive.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-tech-forums/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Connections Suburban Chicago Wrap Up</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sqlconns-presentation/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sqlconns-presentation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 11:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssug]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/05/sqlconns-presentation/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tuesday marked the day that I presented on SSIS basics.  The night went really good and the group and I had a great time during the discussion.  Kim Young (needs to be on twitter) started us off with stored procedures and error handling and moved into Wendy plugging PASS and the community.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Tuesday marked the day that I presented on SSIS basics.  The night went really good and the group and I had a great time during the discussion.  Kim Young (needs to be on twitter) started us off with stored procedures and error handling and moved into Wendy (<a href="http://wendyverse.blogspot.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/wendy_dance">Twitter</a>) plugging PASS and the community.
</p>
<p>
The group I presented to was about the best group you could get in front of you.  Several questions were asked along the way and several attendees jumped in with their own real-life experiences and tips to SSIS trials and successes.  SSIS basics itself is a difficult session to fit in one night.  From the feedback I received after the session, I was glad to hear that several were going to do just that and jump right in.  A few attendees stayed after asking many questions about SQL Server internals and some other things they had in their own installations.  If you are attending one of these sessions, don’t hesitate to do the same.  I know I truly enjoy helping in any way and getting the one on one discussions going is great for all of us to gain more knowledge.
</p>
<p>
The slides that were used for the session can be downloaded below.  I’ve also included the SSIS package and test import file that the group and I went through while learning some things about SSIS.  If you download the package, all you need to do to get it to work with your own test lab and instance is fill in the variables, sqlconn and dbname respectfully.   Then place the import.txt on your C drive and away you go!
</p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/sqlconns.gif" alt="" title="" width="448" height="196" /></div>
<p>
<a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt//SQL Server Integrated Services 90 Minutes.pdf" title="">Slides</a><br />
<br />
<a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt//SSUG Demo.zip" title="">DTSX and Import File</a></p>
<p>
If you have any problems or questions, feel free to jump into the LessThanDot forums and ask away.  The site is all yours and we’re sitting here waiting to throw a helping hand all the time.<br />
<br />
I can’t wait to have the opportunity to jump back in with this group and present again!  </p>
<p>I&#8217;d also liked to thank &#8220;Everyone&#8221; that pitched in and gave Wendy, Aaron and I the gift for putting on SQL Saturday in Chicago.  That was way over the top thoughtful!  Thank you!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sqlconns-presentation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
