<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>productivity &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/productivity/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Productivity Is Not The Only Measurement</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/itprocesses/productivity-is-not-the-only/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/itprocesses/productivity-is-not-the-only/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[measurement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[screamy people]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/06/productivity-is-not-the-only/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Measurements have value. Measure something over time and we have a baseline. Monitor that measurement and we can see problems before they become obvious. Experiment with minor changes, and we can compare to the baseline to tell if we have improved or hurt our performance. Collect enough measurements and trends will emerge, exposing a layer of information we didn't have access to before.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Measurements have value. Measure something over time and we have a baseline. Monitor that measurement and we can see problems before they become obvious. Experiment with minor changes, and we can compare to the baseline to tell if we have improved or hurt our performance. Collect enough measurements and trends will emerge, exposing a layer of information we didn&#8217;t have access to before.</p>
<p><quote style="text-align: center; display: block; font-size: 110%">&#8220;If you cannot measure it, you cannot improve it&#8221; &#8211; Lord Kelvin</quote></p>
<p>But this isn&#8217;t just relevant to our servers, our software, and our support systems, it&#8217;s also relevant to ourselves and our work.</p>
<h2>Ongoing Measurements</h2>
<p>Often the first measurement we consider, when looking to measure our work, is a productivity measure. How many tickets did we close in a day, how many lines of code did we produce, how many hours did we spend doing a vital task. But productivity is just one option available to us.</p>
<h3>Productivity</h3>
<p>The overwhelming positive for measuring productivity is that everyone will understand what we&#8217;re measuring. They may argue the unit, the targets we chose, the brand of graph paper we drew on, but they understand that we are attempting to show a number that represents how much we are working and getting done.</p>
<p><b>Examples:</b></p>
<ul style="margin-left: 2em">
<li>Tech: How many help tickets we completed</li>
<li>Developer: How many lines of code we wrote</li>
<li>BA/Product Owner: How many features/user stories/contracts we defined</li>
<li>SQL Admin: How many restores were tested</li>
<li>Sys Admins: How many vendor calls were dodged (hehe)</li>
<li>Manager: How many roadblocks were cleared for staff</li>
</ul>
<p>Productivity is the easiest measure.</p>
<h3>Effectiveness</h3>
<p>What&#8217;s a better measure than how much work we get done? How about the amount of work that was completed the first time? Or the amount of work that went beyond the surface problems? Or the effect that prior work has? Measuring effectiveness can be tricky, but it&#8217;s basically the opposite of busy work and in some cases it might even be a measure of several ongoing types of work.</p>
<p><b>Examples:</b></p>
<ul style="margin-left: 2em">
<li>Tech: Average number of repeat/follow-up tickets on the same problem</li>
<li>Dev: End user features completed and signed off</li>
<li>BA: End user features completed and signed off</li>
<li>Sys Admin: Rate of critical failures/server over time</li>
<li>Manager: Average tenure of staff</li>
</ul>
<p>When we measure effectiveness, we look at the result instead of the work. We create a definition for positive results (fewer outages/server, fewer tickets/problem, less rework and higher customer acceptance, etc) and then measure our impact against those goals. It&#8217;s a shift from measuring what we&#8217;re doing to measuring what we&#8217;re achieving.</p>
<h3>Estimate Variability</h3>
<p>What&#8217;s the impact of taking twice as long as originally estimated to get a task done? Yeah, screamy people. When we provide estimates for people, they have a tendency to make their own plans based on those estimates. The further from the estimate we get, the more it costs for them to change their plans, disrupting estimates they provided to others. On-time delivery is not just a FedEx measure, it&#8217;s also a measure of how well we work to our own estimates and reinforces the trust the receiver extended to us.</p>
<p><b>Examples:</b></p>
<ul style="margin-left: 2em">
<li>Tech: Completion of PC builds on time</li>
<li>Developer: Completion of features to the estimated time</li>
<li>Project Manager: Completion deliverables or phases on time/budget</li>
<li>SQL Admin: Completion of new environments to estimated time</li>
<li>Sys Admins: Completion of upgrade outages to estimated time</li>
<li>Manager: Ongoing execution against financial budget</li>
</ul>
<p>Variability is about trust and the snowball effect. When we finish too early, people are not ready and will likely look late in their own tasks, even if they are perfectly on time. Too late and we drive all later tasks to be late as well. In both cases we have affected how people will see our future estimates and how they will trust our ability to deliver on time. The more consistently we deliver against our estimates, the less risky it is for the stakeholders to build their own plans around that delivery and the less time will be required to ensure and reassure them that we are on schedule still (meetings, meetings, graphs, and meetings), ultimately saving us even more time.</p>
<h3>Lead Time</h3>
<p>Lead time is the average time elapsed from receiving a request to delivering the completed work. How long do people need to wait in order to get what they need? This is another measurement that could be recorded in number of screamy people/task.</p>
<p><b>Example:</b></p>
<ul style="margin-left: 2em">
<li>Tech: Average lifetime of request tickets</li>
<li>Developer: Average time to correct application bugs</li>
<li>Project Manager: Average time to answer questions about the project or project status</li>
<li>SQL Admin: Average time to respond to new requests</li>
<li>Sys Admin: Average time time to deliver a new service</li>
<li>Manager: Average time to deliver budgeted estimates for work requests</li>
</ul>
<p>Lead time measures how quickly we respond and is an excellent number to use when it comes to improvement measures. When lead times get long, you start hearing about how unresponsive the IT department is, how they never get anything done. Short lead times and the IT department is responsive, friendly, busy. Quick lead times also reduce the occurrences of shadow IT and prevalence of do-it-yourself-ers. </p>
<h2>Measure twice&#8230;</h2>
<p>Often when we decide we need measurements, we stop at &#8220;how much work is getting done&#8221;, but Productivity is not the only measure. Selecting the right measurements depends on our environment, business, and what we intend to achieve.</p>
<p><quote style="text-align: center; display: block; font-size: 110%">&#8220;What gets measured, gets managed&#8221; &#8211; Peter Drucker</quote></p>
<p>Measuring our progress or current state can be difficult, often those numbers are less than spectacular. Poor numbers can make us feel worse about the current state. The state hasn&#8217;t changed, we&#8217;ve simply gotten a clearer picture of it. All of the area above that measurement is opportunity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/itprocesses/productivity-is-not-the-only/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>There Is Never Time For &#8230; (Part 1)</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/there-is-never-time-for-part-1/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/there-is-never-time-for-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 10:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy and Standards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cost reduction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initiative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/04/there-is-never-time-for-part-1/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is never time for training, or to make sure the servers have the right background image, or to make a monitoring script to send emails when certain schema changes occur in the database, or to improve the feedback loop on quarterly goals, or to change that dreadful change management form to streamline the process. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is never time for training, or to make sure the servers have the right background image, or to make a monitoring script to send emails when certain schema changes occur in the database, or to improve the feedback loop on quarterly goals, or to change that dreadful change management form to streamline the process. Unfortunately the deep, dark secret is that in 6 months we&#8217;re going to be saying the same thing, &#8220;There isn&#8217;t time now, we&#8217;ll do it later&#8221;.</p>
<p><em>This is the first article in a three part series on major gaps that we continue to put off until we have &#8220;time&#8221;, a magical state that never seems to occur on it&#8217;s own. Each article is based on one high-level subject and provides ideas on how to gain individual and group level traction and make now that &#8220;time&#8221;.</em></p>
<h2>Training and Development</h2>
<p>Training and development seem to be the easiest items to put off until later. Training in our field is critical in timing and content. If we are not constantly honing and growing our skills then we are actually degrading in both ability and the level of opportunity we provide our companies. What&#8217;s worse, you&#8217;re not only performing at lesser levels, but everything you produce with degraded skills is going into production with higher maintenance costs, is not likely to be redone in a hurry with newer technology, and is possibly putting you at a competitive disadvantage. </p>
<p>Times are tough right now and there are still many businesses that don&#8217;t understand the speed with which our various technical landscapes are changing. Instead of waiting for your company to provide training, here are some other ideas on how to improve your skills without breaking the bank:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Lunch and Learn</dt>
<dd>Lunch and Learns don&#8217;t have to be official and don&#8217;t have to be large. Get sign off from your manager, gather some co-workers, and take a slightly longer lunch once every week or two. Take turns researching a new topic and presenting it to the group. Extra technology lpus presentation practice, double win. Out of ideas or research time occasionally? Webinars are occurring on every topic imaginable> Watch in a group, discuss, and try along with the video as ateam.</dd>
<dt>Webinars</dt>
<dd>Can you say free training from top-level talent? More obscure interests may be harder to find specific webinars for, but Microsoft has tons of saved videos, <a href="http://www.sqlpass.org/" title="Visit the PASS website">PASS</a> virtual chapters offer webinars every week or two, and so on.</dd>
<dt>Experimentation</dt>
<dd>Make a list of 5 major new technologies and take it to your boss. Explain that you would like to spend 4 hours a month (or a week, or whenever) working in a lab environment. It might take some negotiation, so make sure you bring some articles of companies that are making a great deal of money off those technologies, saw savings in time or resources from the technologies, or lost vast tracts of their business from diving on a technology without researching it first. Make sure you aren&#8217;t just playing with these new toys, try to solve actual problems with them or create new services for existing products.</dd>
<dt>Articles</dt>
<dd>Have you set up an RSS feed reader? Drowned in the results and stopped reading? Time to try again. Instead of trying to read everything new that comes in, give yourself a goal of reading 1-2 articles a day. Read those one or two then mark everything else as read and repeat the next day. The goal isn&#8217;t to read everything published every minute of every day, it&#8217;s to find 1-2 good articles each day that make you think, expand your skills, or simply present a different outlook or opinion. One article a day is five articles in a work week, is 20 articles a month. Set a goal and achieve it, don&#8217;t let the feeds drown you.</dd>
<dt>Forums</dt>
<dd>This was my secret weapon 7-8 years ago. I had a technical forum account and I started by answering beginner and mid-level questions. As I saw other questions come up I would be interested in their answers or in finding the answers myself. I pace setup on a home PC to try out potential answers I found and answers others suggested. Like a workout routine, I set time aside to visit and answer questions and grew my knowledge incrementally. Also like a workout routine, this doesn&#8217;t have to be a daily habit, just a regular one.</dd>
<dt>Peer Review</dt>
<dd>Some developers already do this and it&#8217;s a tactic we can all take advantage of. That co-worker beside you? yeah, they know something you don&#8217;t know. And guess what, you probably know something they don&#8217;t know. Convince them to sit behind you for a little while, and vice versa. They are going to not only point out that you hit the backspace key 50 times per minute, but also that they do certain tasks slightly differently, or had a different understanding. And while it may seem slower to have someone sit behind you for a few hours insteda of working on their own, keep in mind that if they come up with one shortcut that saves you 10 minutes a day, you just bought an entire extra week of productivity a year (~48 weeks * 5 days * 10 minutes / 60 minutes = 40 hours).</dd>
<dt>Blogging</dt>
<dd>&#8220;Wait, writing stuff makes me better? That seems backwards.&#8221; Starting to write regular blog entries on technology or your professional interests will force you to focus your thoughts and find new ways to present them. You will end up doing random internet searches that provide you with more knowledge, you will work harder to form your thoughts and experiences into words that other people can (hopefully) understand. In short, you will be getting more out of the experiences and knowledge you already have and keeping those skills sharpened even when you aren&#8217;t actively using them.</dd>
</dl>
<h2>Initiative</h2>
<p>These are just a few ideas, I&#8217;m sure if you spent a few minutes you could expand on them and even come up with others that I didn&#8217;t think of. The key factor, though, is that you have to take the initiative to make these happen. Waiting for someone to budget some extra training time or to setup one of these programs for you is likely going to leave you exactly where you are right now. Pick one of these that seems easy, determine your next step and commit. Now write it on a post-it, tell a co-worker, heck post it down below and tell us all what you will start doing in the next 24 hours (or 6, or now) to keep and improve your edge.</p>
<h2>Next &#8211; Part 2</h2>
<p>We can&#8217;t keep waiting for a CPU to fry from a failed fan, a 3AM outage from a full disk drive, or for database to corrupt before we find out no one has been switching out the tapes. Get your training and developmental tasks started, the next article is going to bring another gap&#8230;and another challenge.</p>
<p>Miss an article in the series?<br />
There Is Never Time For &#8230; <em>Part 1: Training and Development</em><br />
There Is Never Time For &#8230; <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/there-is-never-time-for-part-2">Part 2: Standard Processes</a><br />
There Is Never Time For &#8230; <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITServiceManagement/there-is-never-time-for-part-3">Part 3: Process Improvement</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/there-is-never-time-for-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trying the Stand-Up Desk</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/itprocesses/trying-the-stand-up-desk/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/itprocesses/trying-the-stand-up-desk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sore feet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work area]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/02/trying-the-stand-up-desk/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week was my first week trying the stand-up desk concept. While I had read of many people converting their office, I'm going to be reporting directly from the trenches, after spending a week in a cubicle with a stand-up desk and a list of architectu&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week was my first week trying the stand-up desk concept. While I had read of many people converting their office, I&#8217;m going to be reporting directly from the trenches, after spending a week in a cubicle with a stand-up desk and a list of architecture and development tasks that kept me tied to my desk, all day, every day.</p>
<h2>The Desk</h2>
<p>The last few months I have seen several posts about stand-up desks, with Ron Pereira showing <a href="http://lssacademy.com/2009/11/15/my-new-stand-up-desk/">his new setup</a>, Kevin Mayer discussing <a href="http://www.evolvingexcellence.com/blog/2010/01/accessories-for-the-stand-up-desk.html">accessorizing his work area</a>, and Jon Miller taking the concept <a href="http://www.gembapantarei.com/2009/11/how_to_build_the_road_warriors_stand_up_desk.html">on the road</a>. The thought intrigued me, but I wasn&#8217;t sure how I could implement it in a cubicle environment.</p>
<p>My three requirements were ease of implementation, ease of modification, and low initial investment. I considered stacking boxes, raising the brackets holding the desk, and even looked at <a href="http://www.grahampeterson.com/">purpose-built desks</a>, but none of these options satisfied my requirements. After thinking about it a couple weeks, I decided to invest in some build-your-own shelving products from the local Lowes. I had previously used some custom shelving components to build a dual-computer platform for my home office, but I couldn&#8217;t recall what the expense had been. For about $30 I purchased 4 16&#8243;x16&#8243; platforms, 2 12&#8243;x24&#8243; platforms, and several lengths of connecting rods. This gave me enough materials to build the platforms for my desk, with several extra lengths of connecting rod for flexibility in the design process. An extra benefit was that the pieces could be reconfigured to provide additional shelving at home if the standing concept fell through.</p>
<div style="text-align: center; font-style: italic;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/desk_1.0.jpg" alt="My Standing Desk, v1.0 " /><br />
My Standing Desk, v1.0
</div>
<h2>The First Week</h2>
<p>Before the first day was out, I realized I was feeling more energized and engaged in my tasks. The feeling of standing was keeping me sharper and more focused on the tasks at hand, in a way I had rarely felt while sitting down. The standing desk caught people&#8217;s attention early and many of them took a few minutes to come by and ask about it, but even the higher-than-average number interruptions did not seem to derail me the way they did while I was sitting. </p>
<p>The first issue that came up was that I had underestimated the height of the keyboard. Also, while I had initially thought it would be difficult to judge the height of the monitors, it took me less than an hour to decide the taller monitor felt more comfortable. On Tuesday I brought in some more lengths of connecting rod and re-arranged the platforms.</p>
<div style="text-align: center; font-style: italic;">
<img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/desk_1.1.jpg" alt="My Standing Desk, v1.1 " /><br />
My Standing Desk, v1.1
</div>
<p>Unfortunately I also wore my favorite, though less comfortable, shoes on Tuesday. I learned the difficult lesson that my feet were not as accustomed to sustained standing as they had been when I was younger. For the remainder of the week I borrowed a tall directors chair, allowing me to sit every few hours, and wore my oxfords.</p>
<h2>Why a Stand-up Desk?</h2>
<p>My initial reasons for trying the stand-up desk were to (hopefully) increase my metabolic rate a little, decrease my <a href="http://news.discovery.com/human/sitting-health-hazard.html">sitting-related health risks</a>, strengthen my core and back muscles, and test the claims of <a href="http://www.fitbuff.com/i-cant-stand-my-stand-up-desk/">improved productivity</a> and <a href="http://webworkerdaily.com/2009/03/28/how-to-build-a-standing-desk/">creativity</a>. While I can&#8217;t speak to the medical or metabolic points, I can say that the claims of increased focus are true, and that I had muscle soreness early in the week that spoke to getting worked in a way it wasn&#8217;t accustomed to. Walking up to my desk is like turning a switch, I&#8217;m on task and ready to go.</p>
<p>So far there aren&#8217;t many cons to the setup. I still need to find a way to keep my coffee closer to hand (opportunity) and I hope that my feet will continue to acclimate to the standing so I don&#8217;t have to give up my favorite pair of shoes. </p>
<h2>Next Week?</h2>
<p>Perhaps the oddest feeling is that, while I have only been doing this a week, I am already convinced that I couldn&#8217;t go back to sitting all day. Whether this stems from some subconscious agreement that standing is a better working method for me or if it&#8217;s simply because I don&#8217;t want to carry all of those desk parts back down three stories, it looks like I will be standing for a while longer.</p>
<p><i>Continued the following year <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/ITProcesses/the-stand-up-desk-year-2">with a more permanent desk</a></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/itprocesses/trying-the-stand-up-desk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Use Filters in SSMS to only see the things that are of interest to you</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/use-filters-in-ssms-to-only-see-the-thin/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/use-filters-in-ssms-to-only-see-the-thin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 18:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/02/use-filters-in-ssms-to-only-see-the-thin/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now that all my server are SQL Server 2008 I use SSMS with SSMS Toolpack and Toad. I don&#8217;t really use Query Analyzer anymore. The other day I found out that you can hide objects you don&#8217;t want to see in SSMS by using filters. Let&#8217;s first look at some code. Create a new database [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now that all my server are SQL Server 2008 I use SSMS with SSMS Toolpack and Toad. I don&#8217;t really use Query Analyzer anymore. The other day I found out that you can hide objects you don&#8217;t want to see in SSMS by using filters. </p>
<p>Let&#8217;s first look at some code. Create a new database named test, create a new schema named Denis and then add 3 tables to the dbo schema and 3 tables to the Denis schema. Just run the code below</p>

<div class="bwp-syntax-block clearfix">
<div class="bwp-syntax-toolbar"><div class="bwp-syntax-control"><a href="javascript:;" class="bwp-syntax-source-switch" title="View Source Code"></a></div></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-wrapper clearfix bwp-syntax-simple"><table class="tsql"><thead><tr><td colspan="2"  class="head">T-SQL</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="li1"><td class="ln"><pre class="de1">1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
21
22
23
</pre></td><td class="de1"><pre class="de1"><span class="kw1">create</span> <span class="kw1">database</span> test
go
&nbsp;
<span class="kw1">use</span> test
go
&nbsp;
<span class="kw1">create</span> <span class="kw1">schema</span> Denis
go
&nbsp;
<span class="kw1">create</span> &nbsp;<span class="kw1">table</span> Test1<span class="br0">&#40;</span>id <span class="kw1">int</span><span class="br0">&#41;</span>;
go
<span class="kw1">create</span> &nbsp;<span class="kw1">table</span> Test2<span class="br0">&#40;</span>id <span class="kw1">int</span><span class="br0">&#41;</span>;
go
<span class="kw1">create</span> &nbsp;<span class="kw1">table</span> Test3<span class="br0">&#40;</span>id <span class="kw1">int</span><span class="br0">&#41;</span>;
go
&nbsp;
&nbsp;
<span class="kw1">create</span> &nbsp;<span class="kw1">table</span> Denis.<span class="me1">Test1</span><span class="br0">&#40;</span>id <span class="kw1">int</span><span class="br0">&#41;</span>;
go
<span class="kw1">create</span> &nbsp;<span class="kw1">table</span> Denis.<span class="me1">Test2</span><span class="br0">&#40;</span>id <span class="kw1">int</span><span class="br0">&#41;</span>;
go
<span class="kw1">create</span> &nbsp;<span class="kw1">table</span> Denis.<span class="me1">Test3</span><span class="br0">&#40;</span>id <span class="kw1">int</span><span class="br0">&#41;</span>;
go</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-source"><pre class="no-parse">create database test
go

use test
go

create schema Denis
go

create  table Test1(id int);
go
create  table Test2(id int);
go
create  table Test3(id int);
go


create  table Denis.Test1(id int);
go
create  table Denis.Test2(id int);
go
create  table Denis.Test3(id int);
go</pre></div></div>

<p>Now in SSMS you will see the following if you expand the tables folder</p>
<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt//AllTables.PNG" alt="" title="" width="195" height="199" /></div>
<p>What if I only want to see the tables that belong to the Denis schema? Here is how you can setup the filter. Right click on the tables folder, select Filter and then Filter settings.</p>
<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt//FilterSettings.PNG" alt="" title="" width="403" height="196" /></div>
<p>That will pop up a window that looks like the image below</p>
<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt//Filters.png" alt="" title="" width="559" height="448" /></div>
<p>For the Schema property select equals for the operator and type Denis as value. Click OK and now you will see the following when you navigate to the tables folder.</p>
<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt//FilteredView.PNG" alt="" title="" width="187" height="146" /></div>
<p>If you want to remove the filter, just right click on the folder, select Filter and then Remove Filter.</p>
<p></p>
<p>If you work in a team and you created several tables that all start with Report then you can create a new filter and just show these objects. This way you don&#8217;t need to see any tables that your team members created. Below is a screen shot of a filter like that.</p>
<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/NewSnip.PNG" alt="" title="" width="538" height="96" /></div>
<p>Another cool feature is that you can filter on Creation Date, this gives you the ability to filter all that old <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brownfield_(software_development)">Brownfield</a> stuff that nobody maintains anyway because if you change one thing it will break everything else <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>So are you using filters in SSMS?</p>
<p>*** <strong>Remember, if you have a SQL related question, try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/use-filters-in-ssms-to-only-see-the-thin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
