<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>datallegro &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/datallegro/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL Server Fabric and DATAllegro demo at PASS, SQL Data Services Public CTP Available</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-fabric-and-datallegro-demo-at/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-fabric-and-datallegro-demo-at/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datallegro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kilimanjaro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql data services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server fabric]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/11/sql-server-fabric-and-datallegro-demo-at/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has shown DATAllegro at the PASS conference. They have removed Linux, the database it was running on and also the old file system. DATAllegro is running on Windows with NTFS and SQL2008 now. Can&#8217;t wait for the Kilimanjaro CTP 🙂 Another thing shown at PASS is SQL Server Fabric. SQL Server Fabric gives you [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has shown DATAllegro at the PASS conference. They have removed Linux, the database it was running on and also the old file system. DATAllegro is running on Windows with NTFS and SQL2008 now. Can&#8217;t wait for the Kilimanjaro CTP  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Another thing shown at PASS is SQL Server Fabric.  SQL Server Fabric gives you the ability to manage your SQL Server environment as a whole. Inside SQL Server Management Studio there will be a new view named Fabric Explorer connecting to a Fabric Control Point. The Dashboard will show the overal health</p>
<p><strong>SQL Data Services Public CTP</strong><br />
SQL Data Services (SDS) are highly scalable, on-demand data storage and query processing utility services. Built on robust SQL Server database and Windows Server technologies, these services are designed to provide high availability, security and support standards-based web interfaces for easy programming and quick provisioning. Currently these services are only available in pre-release beta form</p>
<p>Signup here: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=133905&amp;clcid=0x409</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-server-fabric-and-datallegro-demo-at/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>DATAllegro acquisition to enable SQL Server to scale into hundreds of terabytes of data</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/datallegro-acquisition-to-enable-sql-ser/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/datallegro-acquisition-to-enable-sql-ser/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 15:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehousing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datallegro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scaling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/datallegro-acquisition-to-enable-sql-ser/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft just announced that they have finalized the DATAllegro acquisition: Microsoft Closes Acquisition of DATAllegro Some interesting thing in this press release: Microsoft will offer a new solution based on DATAllegro’s technology that extends Microsoft SQL Server to scale into hundreds of terabytes of data. The company will begin giving customers and partners early access [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft just announced that they have finalized the DATAllegro acquisition: <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/press/2008/sep08/09-16DAPR.mspx?rss_fdn=Press%20Releases">Microsoft Closes Acquisition of DATAllegro</a></p>
<p>Some interesting thing in this press release:<br />
<blockquote>Microsoft will offer a new solution based on DATAllegro’s technology that extends Microsoft SQL Server to scale into hundreds of terabytes of data. The company will begin giving customers and partners early access to the combined solution through community technology previews (CTPs) within the next 12 months, with full product availability scheduled for the first half of calendar year 2010.<br />
“Microsoft recently launched SQL Server 2008, which is already attracting a great deal of attention thanks to all of the new functionality for mission-critical data management and business intelligence — in fact, it’s been downloaded more than 500,000 times,” said Ted Kummert, corporate vice president of the Data and Storage Platform Division at Microsoft. “These capabilities, combined with DATAllegro’s ability to scale to hundreds of terabytes, present an extremely powerful solution set for customers and partners, and we are committed to getting it in their hands as soon as possible.”<br />
“SQL Server has already brought so much value to our organization, whether it’s giving us more insight into our data, reducing demands on our hardware or simply speeding up the performance of our applications,” said Ron Van Zanten, directing officer of Business Intelligence, Premier Bankcard Inc. “Perhaps more important, it’s delivered all of these benefits without requiring changes to our existing infrastructure. DATAllegro’s technology is a natural complement to SQL Server, so we are excited about the possibilities this acquisition will bring.”</p>
<p>Already a recognized leader in data warehousing and business intelligence (BI), SQL Server 2008 is the only solution in the industry that includes comprehensive, tightly integrated functionality for data management and advanced BI out of the box. Microsoft is positioned in the Leaders quadrant in Gartner Inc.’s Magic Quadrant for the Business Intelligence Platforms1 and the Magic Quadrant for Data Warehouse Database Management Systems2 and in the Visionaries quadrant in Gartner’s Magic Quadrant for CPM Suites, 2007.3 Together, we believe that these placements validate the importance of Microsoft’s overall BI vision — to provide all individuals, teams and entire organizations with BI solutions that drive bottom-line performance and operational excellence. By extending SQL Server with DATAllegro’s technology, Microsoft will now be able to offer customers and partners one of the highest scales of data warehousing.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here are some interesting things about DATAllegro itself:</p>
<blockquote><p>DATAllegro v3 performs table scans between 0.5TB/minute and 10.5TB/minute. DATAllegro v3 offers new capabilities to handle complex workloads that are a mixture of near real-time loads, long analytical queries and short quick-hit queries. Improved workload management gives queries with low workloads higher priority, reducing the overall workload on the server. DATAllegro also provides a comprehensive architecture with a high-speed loader performing loads at rate of over 1TB/hour. The loading server or landing zone within the high-speed appliance network is used to provide a loading services with a minimal impact to queries being run.</p></blockquote>
<p>Visit the DATAllegro site for some more info http://www.datallegro.com/v3/index.asp</p>
<p>Meanwhile I will be marking my calendar for those community technology previews <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/datallegro-acquisition-to-enable-sql-ser/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
