<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	>
	<title type="text">Comments on Bad Medicine &#8211; How Prescription Becomes a Problem in User Stories</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-02-26T12:40:14Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comments" />
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/feed/atom/" />
	<id>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/feed/atom/</id>
<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Alex Ullrich</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5074" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Alex Ullrich</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5074</id>
		<updated>2012-02-13T00:12:02Z</updated>
		<published>2012-02-13T00:12:02Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5074"><![CDATA[<p>We are supposed to have such people, but they&#8217;ve kind of gone silent.  To be honest, I think personality issues being forced on the product team are a big part of the problem here.  We just had someone move from the QA department to a more product-focused role, and let&#8217;s just say he is very strong willed.  I get the impression from all the interaction I have with our real business analysts that he just grinds them down, because he thinks as a former tester he knows how to use the app better than anyone.</p>
<p>I actually won&#8217;t disagree, but I think that there is a big difference between knowing what buttons to push for X result and knowing the larger business problem our software is intended to solve.</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Erik</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5073" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Erik</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5073</id>
		<updated>2012-02-12T22:55:47Z</updated>
		<published>2012-02-12T22:55:47Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5073"><![CDATA[<p>I like what you&#8217;re saying. You need confidence that what you&#8217;re building will do the job, but then they tell you what to build.</p>
<p>You need descriptive, not prescriptive. But &#8220;of what&#8221; really matters, too. Is there any one person or team that has the top-to-bottom picture who can help make better decisions about implementation through better understanding the business rules, events, and values?</p>
<p>At the risk of using a cliche, you don&#8217;t need the drill, you need the hole. But why do you need the hole and are you positioned so that someone could recognize that a completely different solution&#8211;perhaps to a completely different part of the system&#8211;would do the job better?</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Alex Ullrich</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5072" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Alex Ullrich</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5072</id>
		<updated>2012-02-07T09:43:25Z</updated>
		<published>2012-02-07T09:43:25Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5072"><![CDATA[<p>The acceptance criteria is absolutely a win &#8211; we&#8217;ve been fighting for it forever.  I initially thought it might have been a &#8216;be careful what you wish for&#8217; type of thing but that was before I started delineating prescription and precision in my head.</p>
<p>Its not a matter of over precision either.  We certainly get that at times, but I think we&#8217;ve dealt with it well.  What we are seeing is more &#8216;users need to be able to apply concept X to these objects&#8217; &#8211; how the problem is solved is starting to become a requirement.</p>
<p>Finally, I know product should be writing the acceptance criteria, but we&#8217;ll take what we can get 🙂</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5071" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5071</id>
		<updated>2012-02-07T09:29:17Z</updated>
		<published>2012-02-07T09:29:17Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/#comment-5071"><![CDATA[<p>Are they gaining too much detail on what is expected or are they actually starting to include how to do it? In my mind, acceptance criteria are the voice of the user (or product owner). Not all companies have ready access to their users or have a product owner, but maybe part of the issue is that you are receiving them from QA?</p>
<p>The reason I asked about which type of detail they are receiving is because the first is too much depth (ie, there will be a button that is exactly this shade, located 5 pixels from the left edge, font size 8, etc) but still understandable by an end user and the second is outside the scope of acceptance criteria (you will have a button that calls this method that performs this series of transactions).</p>
<p>I suspect this is actually a sign of your success. You have managed to get your QA group to buy into the acceptance criteria to such a level that they are trying to build more and more into it (and probably enjoying the act of creation). They are engaged, they are just pointed at the wrong target. Originally it was enough to just point them at the idea of making acceptance criteria, now that they have gotten that far it&#8217;s time to refine it so they will focus on not going so deeply and getting it done sooner. </p>
<p>Visibility could help, maybe start displaying a metric for how much of the backlog is ready for estimation? Maybe once I&#8217;ve had some more coffee I&#8217;ll have some other suggestions 🙂</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2012/02/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" href="/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/bad-medicine-how-prescription-becomes/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
</feed>
