<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book Review &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/itprofessionals/book-review/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 11:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization cookbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After my review of Tableau Dashboard Cookbook, I read another book about Tableau, namely Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook by Ashutosh Nandeshwar. The book is published by Packt but I am relieved to say this time there were no significant editing issues. In fact it is quite well written and as far as I could tell [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">After my review of <a href="/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/">Tableau Dashboard Cookbook</a>, I read another book about Tableau, namely <a href="http://amzn.to/1RzPjkU">Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook</a> by Ashutosh Nandeshwar. The book is published by Packt but I am relieved to say this time there were no significant editing issues. In fact it is quite well written and as far as I could tell there were no spelling mistakes or typos (yeah those things can really bug me out when reading a book).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The book promises “Over 70 recipes for creating visual stories with your data using Tableau”. That sounds like a lot and it is, because the book (the actual content, not counting preface, indexes …) is about 150 pages long. In other words, a little over 2 pages per recipe. In fact, I actually counted them (I have apparently nothing better to do). There are 74 recipes spread out over 147 pages, so 1.986 pages per recipe. Those are not long recipes. Some other numbers: the shortest recipe is 2 bullet points. It’s about adding a wildcard filter on a worksheet, but it actually builds upon a previous recipe, so it doesn’t count. The following scatter plot (created with Tableau of course) gives an overview of the various lengths of the recipes encountered in the book:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2898" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png" alt="scatterplot" width="500" height="598" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png 573w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot-250x300.png 250w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are quite a few very short recipes, which can easily be verified with a histogram:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2897" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png" alt="histogram" width="500" height="521" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png 725w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram-288x300.png 288w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">As you can notice, the distribution is a little bit skewed to the left (sorry for the sarcasm). Recipes with a length of 6 or shorter make up over 50% of the book. More statistics can be deduced from this box and whisker plot:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2899" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png" alt="boxwhiskerplot" width="800" height="146" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What is my point in all this (aside from me giving the opportunity to myself to exercise creating some charts in Tableau)? The point is that this book is short and the recipes are too basic. 74 recipes in 150 pages, clearly the choice for quantity over quality has been made. It would have been much better if the bulk of those recipes were bundled into a few recipes who were longer but also more complex and challenging. Now most of the recipes just scratch the surface of a feature and never go into any depth. They are the equivalent of a recipe for boiling potatoes:</p>
<ol style="text-align: justify">
<li>Peel potatoes.</li>
<li>Throw them in boiling water.</li>
<li>Wait for 10 to 20 minutes, depending on type of potatoes.</li>
<li>Bon appétit.</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: justify">Maybe in another chapter you get a recipe for cooking vegetables and in another for grilling meat, but you don’t get instructions to cook a lovely meal with all of the ingredients (and now I’m hungry…). There are three chapter dealing with almost the same basic stuff: creating visualizations with one measure, creating visualizations with two measures and finally creating visualizations with multiple measures. Those should be combined in one single chapter with just a couple of interesting recipes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Another issue is that the author sometimes doesn’t bother to give more information on how the resulting visualization should be interpreted (from time to time the resulting visualization looks nice, but is rubbish from a business perspective becomes it doesn’t really give useful insights). Anyway, this is just a detail. The author does include a lot of links to reference material however, which is certainly a big plus. He also gives some good advice about the different types of charts, for example what the downsides are of pie charts and stacked area charts and how to avoid them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The book is way too basic and this because of the overly simplistic recipes. Get this book only if you are an absolute beginner in Tableau and have never read anything about this tool or if you are an absolute novice in data visualizations tools. In my opinion, the <a href="/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/">Tableau Dashboard Cookbook</a> by Jen Stirrup offers considerable more depth (despite the editing issues) and you’ll learn more tricks than in this book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Modeling the Agile Data Warehouse with Data Vault – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/modeling-the-agile-data-warehouse-with-data-vault-review-2/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/modeling-the-agile-data-warehouse-with-data-vault-review-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 11:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data modeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data vault]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few months ago I followed an introductory course about the data vault modeling technique for data warehouses at a local training provider. As part of the training, I received the book Modeling the Agile Data Warehouse with Data Vault written by Hans Hultgren who also is an instructor for the official data vault certification. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">A few months ago I followed an introductory course about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Vault_Modeling">the data vault modeling</a> technique for data warehouses at a <a href="https://www.infosupport.com/">local training provider</a>. As part of the training, I received the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Modeling-Agile-Warehouse-Vault-Volume/dp/061572308X/ref=tmm_pap_title_0?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1405584375&amp;sr=8-2">Modeling the Agile Data Warehouse with Data Vault</a> written by <a href="http://hanshultgren.wordpress.com/">Hans Hultgren</a> who also is an instructor for the official data vault certification. This blog post is a review of this book; I will not introduce the concepts of data vault modeling.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/datavault.jpg"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2841 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/datavault-200x300.jpg" alt="datavault" width="200" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/datavault-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/07/datavault.jpg 231w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">First of all I am glad I received this book for “free” (read: it was most likely included in the price of the training), because the book has a list price of a whopping $95 (Amazon fortunately gives a steep discount on the paperback edition). No, the 434-page book is not made of pure gold, as you might think, but there are quite a lot of pages in color. There are 212 figures in color in the book, so I guess this contributes to the total price, but <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Information-Dashboard-Design-At---Glance/dp/1938377001/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1405585061&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=information+dashboard+design&amp;dpPl=1">Information Dashboard Design</a> is also in color and has a list price of $40, less than half of the data vault book. This is of course only relevant to printed copies, where they have to cut down trees and use quite some ink, but the Kindle edition is even more expensive and is yours for a mere $84.09. Sense, it makes none. To top it off, the book unfortunately has a bit of an amateur look-‘n-feel. The cover art and the pictures used at the start of each section aren’t exactly world class. Anyway, you can’t judge a book by its cover, so we’ll take a look at the content itself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I have to say, this books reads like a breeze. I finished the book in a couple of days, despite being over 400 hundred pages. This is due to the writing style of the author but also because there are 31 (!) chapters in this book. That’s about 14 pages average for one chapter only. But as I said before, there are 212 figures and each chapter has its own title page (so 31 pages less to read) and usually some white space at the end. Because each chapter finished so quickly, you have the feeling you advance really fast through the book. There are a few spelling mistakes and typos here and there, but nothing too worse. The only thing that irritated me some times is the way the author emphasizes words. A hint: he emphasizes a lot. In almost every paragraph, there is something underlined, in italic or in bold or every possible combination of those three. This gives you the feeling you are reading a high-school text book or a supermarket tabloid. And <a href="http://practicaltypography.com/underlining.html">underlining is not done</a> (yes, I am painfully aware that the URL hyperlink is underlined). Any decent editor should have paid attention to that. Another point is that the author frequently repeats itself. I guess this is because he really wants to make a point (how fantastic data vault is compared with 3NF and dimensional modeling in some aspects), but after a few times I already got the point. No need in repeating it in almost every chapter. This is also the case for figures. There’s this one particular figure that I’ve encountered about 11 times throughout the book (sometimes in very slight variations). That is being thorough all right.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">OK, so there may be some improvements possible for form and layout, but what about the data vault stuff itself? Well, it is explained pretty well. If you have had no exposure to data vault yet, this book will teach you a solid understanding of its principles (I consider myself to this category of readers). I guess if you are a more advanced data vault modeler, there is some nuggets here and there to pick up or you can use the book as a reference.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The first section (Data Vault Ensemble, which teaches you why data vault is what it is) and the third section (Working with Data Vault) really dive into data vault and how you should design such a model, but there’s a large section in the middle – Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence – which is a bunch of loosely tied chapters about a variety of subjects. Some of these chapters are in my opinion not needed to explain data vault or agile modeling. They are filler and can easily be omitted from the book. It would have made the book at least 100 pages thinner (and probably a bit cheaper in price). At the back cover Hans says “This is a guide to data vault modeling and at the same time an exploration of the broader concepts surrounding data warehousing &amp; business intelligence today”, so I should not have been that surprised about those chapters, but on the other hand, if the book contains the words “agile data warehouse” and “data vault”, I expect a deep dive into both subjects. The problem is that because of all those <em>broader concepts</em>, these two subjects don’t get the attention they deserve. Especially the agile part. From time to time the author mentions agile and how data vault can quickly adapt to changes and how fast it can be loaded because of parallelism and how agile all of this is, but it never goes any deeper. There is no treatment on how to develop the data vault in an agile project setting. How to deal with scrum or sprints or whatever. None of that. But I can still live with it, I read the book to learn more about data vault and the book succeeded in that goal. It seems the word agile is just thrown into the title to serve as link bait.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">However, I would have liked some more detailed examples. Most of the time it is a really easy example about customers and customers classes and in some cases there is also a sale, products and employees involved, but nothing more complicated than that. This is in my opinion the biggest downside of the book. I really would have liked to see for example a whole transactional process modeled in 3NF, how it is ported into data vault and how at the end the (dimensional) data marts are generated. The book stays too basic. The last chapter of the book – titled Comparison Example – shows some tables with actual rows and data and how they are transformed. I was looking forward to that chapter while reading through the book because I hoped it would finally give a thorough hands-on example. Alas, it was the same customer table used in any other example. This book is not enough hands-on. I guess you have to follow the (paid) courses to get more hands-on material.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The conclusion. I may have sounded a bit harsh in the previous paragraphs, but don’t get me wrong. I liked reading the book and I definitely learned a lot about data vault. I just wished the book got more hands-on examples (and maybe a decent editor). I do recommend this book to everyone who wants a solid introduction to data vault (there are not that many alternatives to be honest).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/modeling-the-agile-data-warehouse-with-data-vault-review-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tableau Dashboard Cookbook by Jen Stirrup</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 08:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DISCLAIMER I received this book through the O’Reilly blogger review program, which I already mentioned in the review of Thinking With Data. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself. TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">DISCLAIMER</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I received this book through the <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/reviews/">O’Reilly blogger review program</a>, which I already mentioned in the review of <a href="/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/">Thinking With Data</a>. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard of Jen Stirrup (<a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/jenstirrup">twitter</a>): she currently holds the PASS board seat for Europe, she has spoken at dozens of different events and has won the PASSion award in 2012. I have watched her speak at the SQL Server Days in Belgium a few times before and this year she will deliver <a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/precon/#jen">a full precon about Power BI and R</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s say I was a little bit excited when I heard she wrote<a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781782177906.do"> a book about Tableau</a>. I had no experience whatsoever with Tableau, but I had seen some demos and visualizations so I was anxious to try out the product. I got myself the book and I downloaded the free trial of <a href="http://www.tableausoftware.com/products/desktop">Tableau Desktop 8.2</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em>Note:</em> the trial is only 10 days, so if you want to finish the entire book in that time period, you better reserve some quality reading time for yourself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2816" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif" alt="tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover" width="180" height="222" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s start with the good stuff. Personally I loved this book and the main reason is because it is very hands-on: there are a lot of examples (or recipes if you follow the cookbook doctrine) that guide you step-by-step through the features of Tableau. For readers inexperienced with Tableau – such as myself – this is a great way to discover the product without being overwhelmed by its many features. Each recipe starts with a short introduction – not too long so it doesn’t get tedious – and then dives directly into the action. At the end there is a small recap of what you just did and how it works and there are optionally some pointers to further references. The book is limited on theory but overloaded with practicalities, which was very appealing to me. I felt I learned a great deal about Tableau by reading this book, but I also realized I just learned the basic functionalities of the product. That’s why this book may not be suited for already advanced users of Tableau; they may not find a lot of new information in this book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">A small disadvantage is that this book is (in theory) already outdated because it deals with Tableau 8.1, while the 8.2 version has just been released. However, I didn’t experience much difficulties over this. The only obvious difference is the import of multiple files, where there is now a much more graphical and easier to use interface to join tables together.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Personally I found that this book is best read from front to back, as the recipes in a single chapter often depend on each other: you start with a blank worksheet and in each recipe you build on top of the other until you end with a working dashboard at the end of the chapter. Also, sometimes chapters depend on the finished dashboard of the previous chapter. This makes it a bit harder to just jump to a chapter in the book and do some recipes. Luckily you can download finished worksheets from the publishers’ website.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What I found a little bit disappointing was the section in the final chapter about R, called <em>Wrapping up with R – dashboards as a tool</em>. I have been toying with the R language lately and I expected to see some cool stuff there. But there was only an introduction on how to install R with a package called Rserve and how to set-up a connection from within Tableau to Rserver. That’s it. No demonstration on how to actually use R with Tableau. I would have liked some more material over there, or maybe something in an addendum. An idea perhaps for a second edition? Anyway, this book is not about R but about Tableau <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Now on to the bad stuff. Quite early on in the book – somewhere in chapter 2 – it became very clear that this book was badly edited. There are no spelling or grammar mistakes – not that I know of – but sometimes screenshots are switched or even wrong. One time a recipe – which is essentially a bulleted list of action points – jumped to the end while skipping a few steps. Sometimes when following the recipe step-by-step, you achieve a different result than what is displayed in a screenshot. Most of the time you can work around those issues by using your mind a bit and by comparing with (hopefully correct) screenshots. It can get annoying after a while, but it didn’t stop me from reading the book (unlike some delicate little flowers who wrote some reviews on Amazon) because there is still very great content inside it. But you would think that with 4 reviewers, 3 proofreaders and 10 (!) editors mistakes like these would have been avoided. I have contacted the author and she told me that the mistakes have been reported and should appear on the Errata page.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">All in all, I recommend this book to people new to Tableau. They will definitely learn enough by this book to take their first steps with Tableau. A job well done by the author, but shame on you Packt Publishing for all those mistakes. Fire those editors please.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">UPDATE: the author (Jen Stirup) has placed <a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/2014/07/packt-tableau-dashboard-cookbook-errata.html">errata about chapter 2 on her blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Naked Statistics</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/naked-statistics/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/naked-statistics/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 12:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naked statistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[statistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I stumbled up on this book review of Naked Statistics by Nathan Yau. The introduction on Amazon promises us the following: Once considered tedious, the field of statistics is rapidly evolving into a discipline Hal Varian, chief economist at Google, has actually called “sexy.” From batting averages and political polls to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">A few weeks ago I stumbled up on this <a href="http://flowingdata.com/2014/05/08/naked-statistics/">book review</a> of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/039334777X">Naked Statistics</a> by <a href="http://flowingdata.com/">Nathan Yau</a>. The introduction on Amazon promises us the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify">Once considered tedious, the field of statistics is rapidly evolving into a discipline Hal Varian, chief economist at Google, has actually called “sexy.” From batting averages and political polls to game shows and medical research, the real-world application of statistics continues to grow by leaps and bounds. How can we catch schools that cheat on standardized tests? How does Netflix know which movies you’ll like? What is causing the rising incidence of autism? As best-selling author Charles Wheelan shows us in Naked Statistics, the right data and a few well-chosen statistical tools can help us answer these questions and more.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify">I decided to take a look at it since I could really use a refresh on my statistics knowledge. As promised, the book is a really basic introduction to some general statistics concepts, such as probability, descriptive statistics, regression, statistical interference, polling and the central limit theorem.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://amzn.to/1HvgVzV"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2641 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Naked-Statistics.jpg" alt="Naked-Statistics" width="166" height="250" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Throughout the book, the author uses compelling anecdotes and use cases that really explain the subject matter at a comprehensible, attractive and accessible level. There are almost no formulas in this book, so you probably don’t want to use this book as reference material, but it keeps the subject matter rather light. It also give you a bunch of fun stories that you can use to explain statistical concepts to others. For me, this was one of the greatest strengths of the book. I have a basic background on statistics (although the course was 10 years ago and it was given by quite a boring professor), but the examples used in the book made more practical sense than the traditional “I’m pulling some colored marbles out of an urn”.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">If you already have quite some background in statistics, this book will be too basic but you can still read it for the funny stories. For everyone else, I absolutely recommend this book, certainly because it sells at a rather low price. What are you waiting for?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/naked-statistics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thinking with Data by Max Shron</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 11:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[o'reilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2445</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DISCLAIMER I recently enrolled myself in the O’Reilly Blogger Review program, which basically allows me to get one O’Reilly eBook for free per month so I can review it on my blog. This works in both ways of course: I get free eBooks while they’re still hot from the press (figuratively speaking of course) and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify"><b>DISCLAIMER</b></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I recently enrolled myself in the O’Reilly Blogger Review program, which basically allows me to get one O’Reilly eBook for free per month so I can review it on my blog. This works in both ways of course: I get free eBooks while they’re still hot from the press (figuratively speaking of course) and the books get some extra coverage on social media. A nice bonus is that Microsoft Press books are also published through O’Reilly, so it is possible I can get my hands early on new SQL Server books.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">They do encourage you to do honest reviews, so don’t expect every review to go like “OMG this is the bestest most awesomesauce book I have ever read!”. It might though if it is an actual great book, but if it isn’t, I will surely mention it in the review.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><b>THINKING WITH DATA</b></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The first book I got my hands on is <i>Thinking with Data – How to Turn Information into Insigths</i> by Max Shron. In this book, Max describes a framework and methodology on how to approach data science projects. Instead of diving straight into a project by applying your favorite tools and techniques on a giving data set, the author explains it is more useful and productive to stop and think a while about the <i>why </i>before the <i>how</i>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920029182.do"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2447" alt="thinkingwithdata" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/thinkingwithdata.gif" width="180" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The first chapters explain how to set the scope – context, need, vision and outcome – and show you how to refine the scope even further, using for example scaffolding. Then you get an introduction on how to construct arguments, using claims, evidence, justifications and rebuttals. Using other fields like philosophy and mathematics, patterns of reasoning are explained (the most interesting chapter in my opinion), followed by a deep-dive into causality. The final chapter puts it all together by two elaborate case studies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Personally I liked this book. Although it is focused on data science projects, there are plenty nuggets of wisdom that can be ported to the realm of business intelligence. The book isn’t too long – a mere 93 pages – which makes it easily digestible. If the book would have been longer, it might get a bit boring to read. The author has a pleasant writing style and uses examples throughout the book. Without the examples, the concepts would have been much harder to grasp. I would recommend this book to anyone who works with data professionally. It will help you to structure your thoughts before diving into the next project.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Master Data Services (Second Edition) – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/master-data-services-second-edition-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/master-data-services-second-edition-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 13:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master Data Services (MDS)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master data services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2329</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the preparation of my upcoming talk about SQL Server 2012 Master Data Services on the Microsoft Business Analytics Day (hosted by my company element61), I read the book Master Data Services 2nd edition by Tyler Graham. I had almost no prior experience with MDS up to this point (I very quickly glanced over it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">For the preparation of my upcoming talk about SQL Server 2012 Master Data Services on the <a href="http://www.element61.be/e/newsevt-detail.asp?ResourceId=721">Microsoft Business Analytics Day</a> (hosted by my company <a href="http://www.element61.be/">element61</a>), I read the book <a href="http://amzn.to/1Oeichj">Master Data Services 2<sup>nd</sup> edition</a> by Tyler Graham.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I had almost no prior experience with MDS up to this point (I very quickly glanced over it in preparation for the 70-463 exam and I guess I didn’t answer a lot of questions about MDS correctly), so I needed a book that could introduce me to the concepts of MDS and how I can effectively manage master data using this tool.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/MDS_book2_banner.png"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-2331" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/MDS_book2_banner.png" alt="MDS_book2_banner" width="207" height="228" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Tyler Graham was part of the development team of SQL Server Master Data Services right from the start, so if anyone is qualified about writing a book about MDS it’s probably him. You can notice his profound knowledge throughout the book, as he frequently delves deeper in the MDS web service (I didn’t even know there was one) and references hidden stored procedures and views to make MDS do your bidding. The book accomplishes its goal: I know have a good working knowledge of the tool and if I have to use it in a project tomorrow, I know where to start.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The book starts with an introduction to manager master data in general, which is very welcome for someone new to the field, just like me. The book then thoroughly explains how to install and configure MDS. In the next chapter, the business use case used throughout the book is introduces and in the following chapter you learn about creating models.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Chapter 5 explains how you can import data into MDS, using the various staging tables. I would have put this chapter later in the book, because the examples show you how to populate objects you have never even heard of and you don’t exactly know what they represent or how you can use them. A bit confusing. The author talks how you can automate the import process using stored procedures – very useful when you plan on using SSIS to load MDS – and he says he will explain them in the next section. However, the next section is about web services and he never mentions the stored procedures again. A missed opportunity…</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WhereAreTheStoredProcedures.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2332" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WhereAreTheStoredProcedures-300x237.png" alt="WhereAreTheStoredProcedures" width="300" height="237" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WhereAreTheStoredProcedures-300x237.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WhereAreTheStoredProcedures.png 724w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The next chapters explain how to create hierarchies, collections, business rules and so on. The whole time the same business case is used for the examples: a clothing company managing financial and product data with MDS. The examples are real-life and they help you to understand how to work with the product.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Then there’s a whole chapter on using Excel as the front-end for MDS. This is great, as this really opens up MDS for the business user, which gives MDS an advantage over its competitors. However, the book uses a sample workbook you can supposedly download from <a href="http://www.mdsuser.com/">mdsuser.com</a>. But the Excel is nowhere to be found in this site. The book also mentions another site you can download samples from, but that site doesn’t even exist anymore.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">At that point we’re at chapter 11, which is a long chapter on how to implement security. The author goes into great detail to explain how it works in MDS. This chapter is certainly useful as a reference when you are implementing permissions in MDS. Chapter 12 shortly explains how to create subscription views so that you can extract data from the system (which is basically the point of a master data implementation, otherwise it wouldn’t be a much use). The next chapter is all about web services, so I gladly skipped that one. The last chapter talks about advanced modelling, but is just a few pages with a few tips and a few reminders of what not to do with MDS. Very interesting though was the authors take on MDS and slowly changing dimensions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">All in all this was a very decent book that showed me how to work with Master Data Services and how to get the most out of it. The author always explains the differences between the previous version and also warns you about what will not work (well) in MDS and how you can possibly circumvent it by fiddling around in the database.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The biggest downside – for me personally – is something that is probably out of control of the author: the format of the eBook. The book was purchased on ebooks.com in PDF format, but the PDF look like some poorly converted eBook format (epub or mobi or something like that). There were no page numbers, no headings or footers and every page just went to the next one, leading to awkward section endings. There were also no margins, which makes it difficult to decently print a page. The book is supposed to be 416 pages long, but the PDF has only 337 pages. Quite a difference. Maybe ebooks.com throw the section about stored procedures away with their lousy conversion. Bad ebooks.com.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WorstFormatEver.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2333" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WorstFormatEver-300x124.png" alt="WorstFormatEver" width="300" height="124" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WorstFormatEver-300x124.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/WorstFormatEver.png 755w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">This might be normal for an actual eBook for reading on a Kindle or a tablet (I have no idea, I own neither of both), but when I buy a PDF I expect it to look like the actual book. Again, this has nothing to do with the efforts of the author: he wrote an excellent book on Master Data Services. The samples are OK with this book, but a few more effort could be put into them. All in all I recommend this book to everyone who wants to learn more about SQL Server 2012 Master Data Services. Just don’t buy it from ebooks.com.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/master-data-services-second-edition-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Star Schema The Complete Reference – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/star-schema-the-complete-reference-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/star-schema-the-complete-reference-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 15:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dimensional modelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star schema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I finished my first book of this year and here’s the review! After I finished the newest edition of Ralph Kimball’s Data Warehouse Toolkit, a senior colleague of mine recommended the book Star Schema The Complete Reference by Christopher Adamson. To be honest, I had never heard about it. But was I wrong: this book [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">I finished my first book of this year and here’s the review! After I finished the newest edition of Ralph Kimball’s Data Warehouse Toolkit, a senior colleague of mine recommended the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Star-Schema-The-Complete-Reference/dp/0071744320">Star Schema The Complete Reference</a> by Christopher Adamson. To be honest, I had never heard about it. But was I wrong: this book is an absolute must read for every data warehouse professional who takes himself/herself seriously. The book is extremely well written and it explains the concepts of star schemas (hence the title of course) very thoroughly with great detailed examples. I would even go as far by proclaiming that I like this book better than the “Toolkit”. If I had to choose only one book to take with me on new projects, it would be this one.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">One of the strengths of this book is that it is vendor independent and also architecture independent. The book begins by introducing how dimensional modelling is used in the methodologies used by Inmon and Kimball and it debunks quite a few myths that exist about both methodologies. It also explains the concept of stand-alone data marts and which advantages and especially which disadvantages this technique has. Throughout the book, the author explains how the different methodologies can have an impact on how certain concepts are implemented.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Another great piece was the explanation of drilling-across and the importance of it for cross analysis of different process. While reading Kimball’s book, I didn’t pick up the significance of this, but because of the attention Christopher gives to conformed dimensions – a whole chapter – I could really put it in perspective. The different types of conformity are well explained and are illustrated with clear examples. The book also gives different ways of drilling across and provides a few code samples.</p>
<p><a href="http://amzn.to/1fJVq5q"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2317 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/bookcover-241x300.jpg" alt="bookcover" width="241" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/bookcover-241x300.jpg 241w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/bookcover.jpg 322w" sizes="(max-width: 241px) 100vw, 241px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are the usual chapters that you expect from a book like this: dimension design, slowly changing attributes, snowflaking, different kinds of fact tables et cetera. But there is the occasional deep dive: multi-valued dimensions/ attributes and how they relate to bridge tables, type-specific stars, recursive hierarchies and so on. He even explains how to handle all these exotic features when there are slowly changing attributes, but unfortunately he doesn’t back it up with detailed examples. It’s the only weak point of the book, but making the book too detailed would perhaps make it too long and harder to read. And hopefully we never have to implement a slowly changing many to many relationship.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are also some chapters on performance enhancements, such as derived tables and aggregates. These solutions might become somewhat obsolete in the past years thanks to hardware advancements and the introduction of columnar and in-memory databases, but since not every company has Enterprise edition these tools might still be very useful.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The last three chapters are more about how to design the ETL, how to work with BI tools and how to document models. Personally I found those less interesting, but there’s still some value in it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><b>Conclusion</b></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It’s a great book about designing data warehouses using star schemas. Buy it, read it and take it with you on every data warehouse project you encounter. You won’t regret it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/star-schema-the-complete-reference-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/book-review-inside-the-sql/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/book-review-inside-the-sql/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 20:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jes Borland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/12/book-review-inside-the-sql/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Want to take the "black box" mystique out of the query optimizer?]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="bText">
<div class="bText">
<p><img style="float: left;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/grrlgeek/1175-QueryOptimizerCover_200h.jpg?mtime=1387829859" alt="" />I’ve had Benjamin Nevarez’s <a href="https://www.simple-talk.com/books/sql-books/inside-the-sql-server-query-optimizer/">Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer</a> sitting on my bookshelf for a couple of years. I recently pulled it off    the shelf to read it cover-to-cover, to see what new things I could    learn.</p>
<p>This book is supposed to take the “magic black box” feel out of the    query optimizer. Chapters range from an introduction to optimization,  to   index selection, to hints.</p>
<p>I remember my first introduction to the parts of the query optimizer –    I was at SQL Saturday Chicago and <a href="http://scarydba.com/">Grant Fritchey</a> was giving a    presentation to a packed room. He mentioned terms like “parsing” and    “binding”. I thought it was interesting, but most of my work with    queries was more practical – how do I make them suck less? (Fortunately,    in the past four years, I’ve gotten a lot better at making queries  run   better.) Now, I’m interested in more details around this process.</p>
<p>The book starts with a discussion of what a query optimizer is, and    what it does. For those of us without computer science degrees, it’s a    great introduction to the history of optimization, core fundamentals,    and challenges. It sets a good foundation for the information that is    covered in the rest of the book.</p>
<p>What’s the difference between a scan and a seek? What is a lookup?    What are the differences between the nested loops, hash, and merge    joins? How can you give SQL Server the information it needs to make the    most efficient decision on which to use? The second chapter covers  some   of the most-frequently seen operators in execution plans.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/grrlgeek/index scan.JPG?mtime=1387830757" alt="" /><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/grrlgeek/index seek.JPG?mtime=1387830757" alt="" /><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/grrlgeek/Key lookup.JPG?mtime=1387830757" alt="" /></p>
<p>How does the optimizer make its decisions? It’s based on query cost    estimates. How does it get information about costs? It looks at the    statistics on indexes. The next chapter covers what statistics are, how    they are calculated, and how to keep them up to date. I have a few    sections highlighted here for future reference.</p>
<p>Then, he dives into indexes – how your queries are written and how    your indexes are created can make or break a determination by the    optimizer. Knowing how it will search for indexes to use will help you    create better indexes. Two tools for discovering better indexes – the    DTA and DMVs are covered. (Secret? I don’t like the DTA. I’d rather you    know how to use the index DMVs.)</p>
<p>In chapter five, Ben starts digging into the inside of the optimizer.    I learned some new things about the sys.dm_exec_query_optimizer_info    and sys.dm_exec_query_transformation_stats DMVs. Transformation rules    are covered, which reminded me of some high school math classes. To  me,   it’s interesting to know how the optimizer handles this, but not    something I would touch very often.</p>
<p>Different phases of optimization are covered as well. It’s good to    know the difference between trivial and full – it’s helped me understand    why SQL Server picked a specific plan time sometimes. It’s also good   to  understand the phases of full.</p>
<p>The next couple of chapters cover a hodge-podge of topics. How are    updates (which can be an insert, update, or delete) different from a    select? How does SQL Server prevent rows from being updated multiple    times? What is parameter sniffing, and how can you work with it? What    are query, join, and table hints, and what do you need to know before    using them?</p>
<p>If you are used to reading execution plans and are looking for a bit    more understanding of how things work, this is a good book to pick up.    Keep in mind that as things change with SQL Server 2014 coming out,  you   might not see some of the same behaviors on newer versions, but  the   information is solid nonetheless.</p>
<p>Thank you, Ben, for distilling what could be a complicated technical discussion into easily-understandable pieces!</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/book-review-inside-the-sql/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Visualization – Book Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/data-visualization-book-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/data-visualization-book-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/07/data-visualization-book-review/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To prepare myself for my session Data Visualization Tips &#38; Tricks, I read a few books. In this blog post, I’ll give a short review for each one of them.
Information Dashboard Design
This book, written by Stephen Few, was the first one I read. And&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">To prepare myself for my session <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/business-intelligence-1/data-visualization-tips-tricks">Data Visualization Tips &amp; Tricks</a>, I read a few books. In this blog post, I’ll give a short review for each one of them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Information Dashboard Design</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://amzn.to/1J0ZLfO"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/DataVizBookReview/informationdashboarddesign.png?mtime=1372771566" alt="" width="186" height="219" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify">This book, written by <a href="http://www.perceptualedge.com/blog/">Stephen Few</a>, was the first one I read. And it was a fascinating read! I went through the book in one long haul. It’s very well written and the design of the book is very well done. A big plus is that the printed version of the book is in color.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><span style="text-align: justify">The essence of the book is on how to design dashboards properly. In the first chapter, you obviously get an introduction and a few examples of poorly designed dashboards. In the second chapter, Stephen defines the concept of a dashboard and the different variations that exist. For example: how does an operational dashboard look like in contrast with an analytical dashboard. The third chapter goes into detail about what you should not do when designing a dashboard by presenting 13 common mistakes. Chapter 4, one of the most interesting chapters delves into visual perception and explains what you can do to draw attention to certain parts of a dashboard. This involves a wee bit of psychology and worth knowing when designing dashboards.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Chapter 5 demonstrates the principle of eloquence through simplicity, or in other words: keep it simple stupid. It talks about how to reduce the “noise” in a dashboard so that only the important aspects remain. Chapter 6 gives an overview of available chart/display types and presents the bullet graph – invented by Stephen himself – which is a very efficient display medium. Chapter 7 talks about usability of your dashboards and chapter 8 brings it all together. In this final chapter Stephen gives a few examples of how to design a few command dashboards according to his vision. Here he also gives yet another few examples of very bad designed dashboards to illustrate his points.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I absolutely recommend this book to anyone who considers reading about data visualization in general. Every self-respecting BI professional should have read this book. The only criticism I can come up with is that the book focuses a lot on “the bad”, or how not to do things. Perhaps a little bit more focus on how to design properly would have been welcome. But overall, a very great book. In August 2013 <a href="http://www.perceptualedge.com/blog/?p=1656">a second edition of the book</a> should launch, and I definitely will keep my eye on that one.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Data Visualization: a successful design process</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://amzn.to/1TD1cUR"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/DataVizBookReview/datavisualizationprocess.png?mtime=1372771564" alt="" width="178" height="219" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify">The second book I read was written by Andy Kirk (<a href="http://www.visualisingdata.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/visualisingdata">twitter</a>), who also gives training classes about data visualization. In contrast with the previous book, this one talks about the design approach on how to create visualizations. In other words, it describes a project-based methodology on how to tackle the process of creating a visualization. This might make the book a bit more “dry” to read, but that doesn’t make it less interesting.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><span style="text-align: justify">The first chapter deals about the context of data visualizations and serves as a general introduction. Chapter 2 talks about setting the scope – or intent – of your visualization project and the different roles that exist in such a project. The 3</span><sup>rd</sup><span style="text-align: justify"> chapter is about finding the right story (editorial focus) and explains the importance of preparing your data. Chapter 4 delves into various design choices, such as choosing the right visualization method and goes for example into detail about color usage. This chapter has quite some similarities with some chapters of Stephen Few’s book. Chapter 5 gives a very extensive overview of different chart/visualization types. The final part, chapter 6, touches the concept of evaluating data visualizations and gives a whole bunch of links to designing tools, resources about data visualization et cetera.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">It was a nice book to read and because of the process-based approach of the book it’s something completely different then <em>Information Dashboard Design</em>. So it is very well worth the effort to read both books. My main criticism about this book is that it is not in color, which is a pity since it’s about data visualization. Some examples were not clear as you could not make any distinction between the colors. Perhaps the e-book version is in color, but I haven’t been able to look into that one, so it is probably worth checking out the e-book instead of the printed version.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Say it with Charts</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://amzn.to/1M6gzDc"><img class="alignnone" style="float: left;margin: 0px 10px 0px 10px" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/DataVizBookReview/SayItWithCharts.jpg?mtime=1372771569" alt="" width="172" height="224" /></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify">During the dry-run of my data visualization session a BI manager of my company recommended me this book. It’s written by Gene Zelazny, a consultant by McKinsey. It is quite an old book, initially written in 1985 and already in its fourth edition! However, it still talks about some universal concepts of data visualization which still hold firm today. As with the other two books, there are not a lot of pages so you’ll breeze through it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><span style="text-align: justify">The book is divided 4 large sections. The first section introduces you to charts. First it gives an example of a guy giving a presentation and of course doing everything wrong. It presents you with 5 basic chart types – pie chart, bar chart, column chart, line chart and dot chart – which are according to the book the only ones you’ll ever need. A bit short-sighted, but probably due to the age of the book. With all the designer tools and computing power we have nowadays, there are certainly more chart types available which are also efficient in its communication.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The second section gives 80 examples of every possible combination of those 5 basic charts. This is very good introduction to people new to charts and it is also a good source for inspiration. The third section talks about concepts and metaphors and is in my opinion worthless. It’s over 60 pages full of outdated sketches. For example on how to use arrows to symbolize process or interrelationships. Basically a lot of PowerPoint/Visio/Clip Art objects. This section was written in a time with no Internet so I get the idea, giving the people some inspiration, but it should’ve been thrown out in later editions. The last edition was published in 2001 and surely there was already some digital revolution going on. Speaking of, the last section goes into detail about the wonders that this revolution has given us. It was added in the latest edition and it is the only one in color. It talks about how computers simplify the development of visualizations and what powerful/beautiful creations can be made with all this new technology. However, it is already 12 years old and it looks – again – very outdated and to be honest, ugly as well. There are a few design errors which the other two books warn about. This section is in serious need of an update. It even talks about animation and gives examples, which is a bit pointless in a written medium such as a book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Is this a bad book? No. Skipping the last two sections and focusing only on the first two, you got yourself a very nice introduction to charts. A very quick one as well, as this reduces the book to a mere 128 pages. There are also some exercises in this book (get out your pencil) to get you started about thinking how to use charts. Conclusion: still worth the read, even if it is just to laugh with the old technology J.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/data-visualization-book-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Pro SQL Server 2008 Failover Clustering</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/book-review-pro-sql-server-2/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/book-review-pro-sql-server-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 12:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jes Borland]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/06/book-review-pro-sql-server-2/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is the most comprehensive look at Windows and SQL Server failover clustering that exists. In this book, Allan Hirt, a clustering expert and Microsoft MVP, lays a solid foundation for all aspects of clustering.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite having worked with SQL Server clusters for years, I didn&#8217;t pick up the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Server-Failover-Clustering-Experts-Voice/dp/1430219661">Pro SQL Server 2008 Failover Clustering</a> and read it cover-to-cover until recently. This is the most comprehensive look at Windows and SQL Server failover clustering that exists. In this book, Allan Hirt (<a href="http://www.sqlha.com/blog/">b</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/SQLHA">t</a>), a clustering expert and Microsoft MVP, lays a solid foundation for all aspects of clustering.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/51ET4iyVwSL.jpg" alt="" width="185" height="250" /></p>
<p>The book covers four main areas – the basics of failover clustering, clustering Windows Server 2008, clustering SQL Server 2008, and administration of a clustered SQL Server 2008 instance.</p>
<p>(Yes, this edition is focused on Windows Server 2008 and SQL Server 2008. <a href="http://www.sqlha.com/2013/06/03/announcement-day-windows-server-2012-r2-sql-server-2014-and-my-mission-critical-book/">Allan is working on an updated version</a>!)</p>
<h3>High Availability 101</h3>
<p>The basics of high availability are covered in the first chapter. Why do you need HA? What HA methods and technologies are available? Failover clustering, log shipping, database mirroring, and replication are discussed here, with great illustrations. It’s important to understand the differences between the methods. A comparison of these methods can help you determine, “Is this right for my company, my application, and my budget?”</p>
<h3>Clustering Windows Server</h3>
<p>The next section is all about clustering Windows Server. If you’re a DBA thinking, “I don’t worry about that, I let my server administration team take care of it”, you have the wrong attitude. You will not succeed in today’s technological landscape with a narrow focus. You need to have at least a basic understanding of how all the parts of your applications, your servers, and your network work together. This is even more important because SQL Server failover clustering is entirely dependent on Windows Server clustering. If you don’t cluster Windows, you can’t cluster SQL Server.</p>
<p>Allan takes a comprehensive look at what is involved in server clustering. You need to choose supported hardware. You have to set up accounts. The networking components must be configured. The concept of quorum is explained – and Windows Server 2008 includes new models, so even if you’re familiar with disk or majority node set, there are new things to learn.</p>
<p>He then gives an overview of preparing Windows Server. There is a step-by-step walkthrough of installing and configuring the network, features and roles, disks, domain tasks, and configuration. My favorite part of this book is the in-depth walk-throughs. There are step-by-step screenshots from the GUI, along with command line or PowerShell scripts if applicable.</p>
<p>The next walk-through is on clustering Windows. Validation must be performed first, and then the cluster can be created. Important post-installation checks and verification are included. The steps here are very comprehensive.</p>
<h3>Clustering SQL Server</h3>
<p>The next two chapters are dedicated to preparing to cluster SQL Server, then actually doing it. He reviews which components of SQL Server can be clustered, and which can’t. Planning needs to be thorough and well-thought-out, especially as you move beyond a two-node cluster. Which disks will host the quorum, data, and log files? Which instances will be installed on which nodes? How will you manage memory? After these things have been determined, then you can proceed with installing SQL Server, node by node.</p>
<p>There is a new method for SQL Server installation, cluster preparation, which is also covered. Each node can have some information configured on it, then, when you are ready, in a few short steps, you can finish installation on the nodes.</p>
<p>There is a section dedicated to upgrading to SQL Server 2008 failover clustering. As with any upgrade, there are business and technical challenges to be considered, including testing and a rollback plan. The steps to do an in-place upgrade are covered from start to finish.</p>
<h3>Administration and Virtualization</h3>
<p>Administration is not overlooked. There are some tasks that are unique to failover clusters, such as adding or removing nodes, or putting disks in maintenance mode. You should read this chapter before clustering, so you know what you can do, and keep it as a reference for after your clusters are installed, in case a problem arises.</p>
<p>Last but not least, there’s a discussion about clusters and virtualization. Face it, virtualization is here to stay. This is another area where DBAs need to expand their skillset. Understanding how clusters will behave on virtual instances – the performance impact, the HA impact – is very important if you’re faced with this in your environment. The best part? Allan shows you how to set up a clustered instance using VMware Workstation – which can help you build a virtual lab to play with!</p>
<p>This book is a must-have for the DBA’s bookshelf. If you aren’t working with failover clusters now, there is a good chance you will at a future point in your career. Even though terms and options may change in new versions of Windows Server and SQL Server, you should work to understand the concepts now.</p>
<p>I can’t wait for the next version!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/book-review-pro-sql-server-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
