<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	>
	<title type="text">Comments on Serverless HTTP + Kinesis Lambdas with Offline Development</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-02-26T12:40:14Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/#comments" />
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/feed/atom/" />
	<id>/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/feed/atom/</id>
<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/#comment-5977400" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/?p=8865#comment-5977400</id>
		<updated>2018-01-17T17:26:37Z</updated>
		<published>2018-01-17T17:26:37Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/#comment-5977400"><![CDATA[<p>I assume you mean &#8220;Why not use kestrel instead of an HTTP Lambda?&#8221;?</p>
<p>If I wanted to put something up quickly that could receive web hook callbacks, the 3 files (package.json, serverless.yml, eventsHttp.js) would be sufficient, and maybe overkill, to easily deploy it and have the service definition and code in git. I could also build a microservices using logs and a variety of storage and ML services this way and it still be about as simple as deploying a single web app to Heroku or Azure. And it would automatically scale based on demand, rather than requiring me to pay a fixed price for fixed resources that would be too little one moment and too much the rest. Also, HTTP events are one type of things Lambdas/Functions can handle, they also provide simplified consumer logic for things like Kinesis and EventHubs and other services. Operating on a file dropped into Dropbox in Azure is pretty much just as easy as the HTTP Handler above, but something that takes some work to implement as part of a website (and I&#8217;d go so far as to say that a website is the wrong kind of tool to build this).</p>
<p>The example above (package.json, serverless.yml, eventsHttp.js) is only lacking AWS account credentials to be 100% complete. I personally love Azure, so if I was deploying something that would be more of a site with consistent usage then I&#8217;d probably shift from functions to Azure Web Sites (probably with MVC) . From there if I needed specific assemblies or to deploy lots of inter-related sites I&#8217;d consider Kubernetes, if I wanted something more ActorModel and to give up some of the niceties of modern web servers I could switch to ServiceFabric, and then finally there is probably still reason I would consider physical servers but I can&#8217;t think of any offhand.</p>
<p>So I don&#8217;t look at FaaS as a replacement for some flavor of website on the Paas/IaaS/Hardware options, just another circle in the Venn diagram that gives us a different set of capabilities and tradeoffs in our toolbelt. I probably could have talked more to that in the post above, but I felt like a bunch of those posts had been written already better than I could and really was focused on helping folks with the specific case of &#8220;how do you have a good local development experience w/ Kinesis functions&#8221; since that was pretty painful for me.</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/?p=8865#comment-5977280" href="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/#comment-5977280" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Peter</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/#comment-5977280" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Peter</name>
			<uri>http://www.sapec.nl/</uri>
		</author>

		<id>/?p=8865#comment-5977280</id>
		<updated>2018-01-17T15:06:37Z</updated>
		<published>2018-01-17T15:06:37Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/#comment-5977280"><![CDATA[<p>Why wouldnt you use kestrel to create code that can be called by web/api plain http or something RESTfull ?.</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/?p=8865" href="/index.php/enterprisedev/cloud/serverless-http-kinesis-lambdas-with-offline-development/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
</feed>
