<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>science &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/science/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Review: Physics of the Future: How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100 by Michio Kaku</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-physics-of-the-future/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-physics-of-the-future/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nanobots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/06/review-physics-of-the-future/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I picked up the book Physics of the Future: How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100 mainly to see what is in store for humanity in the year 2100. Having read Ray Kurzweil's 3 books on a similar subject, this was of inte&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5825886374/" title="Physics of the Future How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100 by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5197/5825886374_e89ee3e4bc_m.jpg" width="240" height="240" alt="Physics of the Future How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100" /></a><br />
I picked up the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0385530803/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217153&amp;creative=399349&amp;creativeASIN=0385530803">Physics of the Future: How Science Will Shape Human Destiny and Our Daily Lives by the Year 2100</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0385530803&amp;camp=217153&amp;creative=399349" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /> mainly to see what is in store for humanity in the year 2100. Having read Ray Kurzweil&#8217;s 3 books on a similar subject, this was of interest to me. When people predict the future they usually underestimate the pace of progress, just imagine when you looked at CPUs between 1980 and 1985, you would never think that we would have quadcore CPUs in our laptops, these quadcore CPUs would outperform those clunky machines by such a factor that it is almost impossible to put it on the same graph.</p>
<p>There were some interesting things in this book, one of them is Optogenetics,<br />
<blockquote>Optogenetics is the combination of genetics and optics to control well-defined events within specific cells of living tissue. It includes the discovery and insertion into cells of genes that confer light responsiveness; it also includes the associated technologies for delivering light deep into organisms as complex as freely moving mammals, for targeting light-sensitivity to cells of interest, and for assessing specific readouts, or effects, of this optical control.</p></blockquote>
<p> To learn more about Optogenetics , you can check out this Scientific American article: <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=optogenetics-controlling">Optogenetics: Controlling the Brain with Light [Extended Version]</a> and of course, there is always wikipedia: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optogenetics</p>
<p>What about having <em>retinal display</em> contact lenses? These lenses would connect directly to the internet. I guess it would be fine for certain things but for most things it would be a big distraction.</p>
<p>The book also mentions driverless cars, of course Google already showed that after the book was published so this is only a matter of time.</p>
<p>Will the robots take over is explored in this book, the singularity is also discussed.</p>
<p>In terms of medicine, nanobots that go through our veins and zap cancerous cells will be here, your doctor might be a robot.</p>
<p>Clothing will be smart, if you get injured, your clothes will make a diagnose of your condition and together with your gps location they will send a signal to the nearest hospital.</p>
<p>All in all, I found this book very interesting and very entertaining. for some people all these thing will be scary and they will be scared of it, for other people it will be exciting and they will embrace these changes.  Michio Kaku has already seen some of these inventions already as proto types being tested right now. You don&#8217;t need to be a science buff to understand this book, it is dumb down to appeal to the masses.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/review-physics-of-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book review: Quantum Man: Richard Feynman&#8217;s Life in Science</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/book-review-quantum-man-richard/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/book-review-quantum-man-richard/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feynman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/06/book-review-quantum-man-richard/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I picked up the book Quantum Man: Richard Feynman's Life in Science because I wanted to learn more about Richard Feynman and what he accomplished. Even though it is not a computer book, I decided to still review the book here because most scientists use&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/5800154040/" title="Quantum Man: Richard Feynman's Life in Science by Denis Gobo, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3208/5800154040_86eb3785c2.jpg" width="160" height="250" alt="Quantum Man: Richard Feynman's Life in Science" /></a> I picked up the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0393064719/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217153&amp;creative=399349&amp;creativeASIN=0393064719">Quantum Man: Richard Feynman&#8217;s Life in Science</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0393064719&amp;camp=217153&amp;creative=399349" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /> because I wanted to learn more about Richard Feynman and what he accomplished. Even though it is not a computer book, I decided to still review the book here because most scientists use computers.</p>
<p>The book is written in a clear format and all the technical stuff is explained in laymen terms. You don&#8217;t have to be a science superhero to understand the material in this book. Here is for example something that most people won&#8217;t understand<br />
<img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/math/3/c/8/3c875a8953e43bd678967f55e67e02b1.png" alt="second order processes in QED" title="second order processes in QED" /></p>
<p>Richard Feynman was an interesting person, he wasn&#8217;t satisfied with just the answer from himself or other people, he wanted to do all the calculations himself to get to the answer. Sometimes he would instinctively know what the answer should be yet he would still do all the calculations to get to the answer. Another interesting fact was that he would seek inspiration in strip joints when he got stuck on a problem. I wonder if he did his research for gravity there <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Richard Feynman was also one of the first scientists to conceive the possibility of quantum computers. He was very interested in computers and while participating in the Manhattan Project—the wartime U.S. Army project at Los Alamos developing the atomic bomb, he first started to use IBM computers. He helped assemble these computers, the IBM people sent to assemble these computers were amazed that Feynman &amp; Co assembled these themselves</p>
<p>Richard Feynman is known for the following things<br />
Feynman diagrams<br />
Feynman point<br />
Feynman–Kac formula<br />
Wheeler–Feynman absorber theory<br />
Feynman sprinkler<br />
Feynman Long Division Puzzles<br />
Hellmann–Feynman theorem<br />
Feynman slash notation<br />
Feynman parametrization<br />
Sticky bead argument<br />
One-electron universe<br />
Quantum cellular automata</p>
<p>He received the following notable awards<br />
Albert Einstein Award (1954)<br />
E. O. Lawrence Award (1962)<br />
Nobel Prize in Physics (1965)<br />
Oersted Medal (1972)<br />
National Medal of Science (1979)</p>
<p>You can check out the <a href="http://www.feynmanlectures.info/">The Feynman Lectures on Physics</a> site to learn more about Feynman&#8217;s work. It has <a href="http://www.feynmanlectures.info/stories.html">stories about the influence of The Feynman Lectures on Physics on people&#8217;s lives</a> and <a href="http://www.feynmanlectures.info/exercises.html">exercises and solutions to math/physics problems</a>.</p>
<p>I highly recommend this book, I enjoyed it, you will enjoy it too!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/book-review-quantum-man-richard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
