<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Operating Systems &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-03-09T12:50:36Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/" />
	<id>/index.php/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/category/sysadmins/os/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jes Borland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Never drag and drop files between servers again!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/never-drag-and-drop-files-between-servers-again/" />
		<id>/?p=4388</id>
		<updated>2016-02-19T15:22:55Z</updated>
		<published>2016-02-19T15:22:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Management" /><category scheme="/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[IT professionals (and amateurs), it&#8217;s time we had a chat. It&#8217;s time to stop dragging and dropping (or copying and pasting) files between servers and/or workstations. It&#8217;s clumsy. It&#8217;s childish. It uses memory on the server. Oh, and there&#8217;s a really easy tool to copy files built into Windows &#8211; Robocopy. Here&#8217;s the basic premise: you [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/uncategorized/never-drag-and-drop-files-between-servers-again/"><![CDATA[<p>IT professionals (and amateurs), it&#8217;s time we had a chat. It&#8217;s time to stop dragging and dropping (or copying and pasting) files between servers and/or workstations.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s clumsy. It&#8217;s childish. It uses memory on the server.</p>
<p>Oh, and there&#8217;s a really easy tool to copy files built into Windows &#8211; <a href="https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc733145.aspx" target="_blank">Robocopy</a>.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the basic premise: you open a PowerShell window (or command prompt, but let&#8217;s join the 21st century), and enter</p>
<pre>robocopy &lt;source directory&gt; &lt;destination directory&gt; &lt;optional: file name&gt; /&lt;options&gt;</pre>
<p>The file(s) are copied, with progress shown. A few things I love about this:</p>
<ul>
<li>I can specify a network location or a local directory for either the source or the destination.</li>
<li>I can copy one backup file, or every transaction log backup in the directory.</li>
<li>I can use the /z option to tell Robocopy that if the transfer gets interrupted, pick back up when it gets reconnected.</li>
<li>I can see the progress, in terms of actual bytes, not just Windows&#8217;s &#8220;45%&#8221; that runs for three hours.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are a couple examples.</p>
<p>I want to move the files from my Extended Events folder on AG1 to AG 2. Command:</p>
<pre>robocopy "C:\Users\a-jes\Documents\SQL Server Management Studio\Extended Events" "\\SQL2014AG2\C$\Users\a-jes\Documents\SQL Server Management Studio" /z</pre>
<div id="attachment_4389" style="width: 885px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-4389 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/robocopy-1.png" alt="All sorts of goodness!" width="875" height="647" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/robocopy-1.png 875w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/robocopy-1-300x221.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 875px) 100vw, 875px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">All sorts of goodness!</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s say I wanted to move all the .xml.gz files from one directory to another. Command:</p>
<pre>robocopy "C:\Users\a-jes\Documents" "\\SQL2014AG2\C$\Users\a-jes\Documents" *.xml.gz /z </pre>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4390 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/robocopy-2.png" alt="robocopy 2" width="883" height="645" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/robocopy-2.png 883w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/robocopy-2-300x219.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 883px) 100vw, 883px" /></p>
<p>That&#8217;s a very quick look at Robocopy. I suggest you know it, use it, and love it!</p>
<p>(Inspired by<a href="https://twitter.com/sqlagentman" target="_blank"> Tim Ford</a>&#8216;s <a href="http://thesqlagentman.com/2016/01/entry-level-content/" target="_blank">call to blog about #entrylevel topics</a> that I #wanttoshare.)</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/uncategorized/never-drag-and-drop-files-between-servers-again/#comments" thr:count="12"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/uncategorized/never-drag-and-drop-files-between-servers-again/feed/atom/" thr:count="12"/>
		<thr:total>12</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tahir Khalid</name>
						<uri>http://www.vurso.co.uk/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 10, how I doth hateth thee mostest]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/" />
		<id>/?p=4121</id>
		<updated>2015-08-26T03:15:19Z</updated>
		<published>2015-08-25T16:00:15Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="IT Professionals" /><category scheme="/" term="Microsoft Technologies" /><category scheme="/" term="System Admins" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows 8" /><category scheme="/" term="windows" /><category scheme="/" term="windows 10" /><category scheme="/" term="windows 8.1" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[How&#8217;s it going folks, thought I&#8217;d get another post written up before I switch over to video logs in the future (watch this space). So I don&#8217;t really need to do a big introduction to Windows 10, there was a lot of buzz going about the internet not least due in part to the upgrade [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/"><![CDATA[<p>How&#8217;s it going folks, thought I&#8217;d get another post written up before I switch over to video logs in the future (watch this space).</p>
<p>So I don&#8217;t really need to do a big introduction to Windows 10, there was a lot of buzz going about the internet not least due in part to the upgrade icon that appeared in the notification tray (from Windows 7 to Windows 8.1) and like many people I became curious as to what exactly Windows 10 would mean to me and the rest of the world. I hadn&#8217;t looked at the beta and the RC releases that came out for Windows 10 even through they were available to developers about a year ago but this was mostly because I had made the jump from Windows 7 to Windows 8 (ouch) and then to Windows 8.1 Professional (easily the best version to date but more on this later).</p>
<p>I remember some of the early hype surrounding Windows 10 namely around the technology and what it would offer (the same sort of hype that appeared before Windows 7 was released to the wild) but the biggest one was how it would revolutionise the Windows desktop and make development more exciting with the introduction of dedicated tools for Universal App&#8217;s &#8211; great I thought this could be a step in the right direction. We had seen some of the buzz already with the announcement of ASP.NET 5 and related technologies such as .NET Core as well as releasing chunks of the code to the community via github (<a title="Announcing ASP.NET 5" href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/AnnouncingNET2015NETAsOpenSourceNETOnMacAndLinuxAndVisualStudioCommunity.aspx" target="_blank">ASP.NET 5</a>).  Along with this news we saw Visual Studio Community Edition and Visual Studio Code hinting at a future where we would not be tied down to a Windows desktop and could code on anything from Linux to OS X  &#8211; more cool stuff! So I bought into the hype and I reserved my copy and while I did not have a compelling reason to upgrade from a rock solid Windows 8.1 Professional platform (running on an HP Elitebook 8560w Mobile Workstation) I was hopeful that Windows 10 would build on the great work of Windows 8.1 (wishful thinking I know).</p>
<p>Before I hear &#8220;ah but Windows 8 was crap dude it was the Vista of this generation!&#8221;, yes true but Windows 8.1 for me was the saving grace, they got it right but due to some negligence or poor marketing most of the general public had no clue that Windows 8.1 was an entirely different product, better in a million ways (and most still don&#8217;t know this) so they chose to ignore it and stick to Windows 7 (which still ins&#8217;t a bad move). I have to give it to Microsoft, they generated the right buzz by allowing people to reserve their digital download of Windows 10.  Word-of-mouth is powerful marketing tool and that&#8217;s exactly what happened here (albeit through the power of social media like Twitter, Facebook and Email) and in this case it was enough to get people to want to get their digital copy of Windows 10 and install it including myself where I couldn&#8217;t wait so I went ahead and downloaded <a title="Windows 10 Download Toolkit" href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windows10" target="_blank"><strong>this</strong></a> toolkit from Microsoft to create my own ISO locally.</p>
<p>After following the instructions to create the external media, I selected ISO and waited while the toolkit proceeded to download the necessary files and create an ISO for me (I recommend you go make a cup of tea at this point).  After the ISO was created I extracted the files to a folder on my C:\ drive and then ran the setup and followed the on-screen instructions to upgrade Windows 8.1 to Windows 10 (choosing to retain my Data &amp; Apps).   This was quite a smooth process all but 1 of my applications worked however here is where the fun started&#8230; We are led to believe that the upgrade process is seamless however its was anything but, I had to reinstall all my drivers for them to work again (even though Windows 10 reported everything as being functional) and if you don&#8217;t do this you will start experiencing strange problems from your SSD drive not running at full speed, CPU running in a stepped state to sound being 50% of its actual volume.</p>
<p>About an hour later I was up and running properly and Windows 10 started to behave, initially very impressed, loved the subtle desktop UI design touches and this time almost everything has a WPF interface to it which is great (to a point) but again Microsoft screwed up here as some screens are just not thought out properly where a typical WinForms dialog has not been thoughtfully transformed over to it&#8217;s WPF counterpart or rather it&#8217;s been over engineered and what should be a simple interface becomes a multi-screen click nightmare (more on this later). Then we have the issue with the CPU running hot. On my humble HP Mobile Workstation I have to keep an eye on the CPU temp as it can run hot (as it&#8217;s meant to) but I had it set up a particular way in Windows 8.1 (using a combination of <a title="Core Temp" href="http://alcpu.com/CoreTemp/" target="_blank">Core Temp </a>and the awesome <a title="Notebook FanControl" href="https://github.com/hirschmann/nbfc" target="_blank">Notebook FanControl</a> by <span style="font-weight: bold">Stefan Hirschmann) </span>so that the system ran cool and quiet more often however the same did not transfer over to Windows 10 so easily and I found for whatever reason the CPU was running at least 5% hotter than on Windows 8.1 and more often (and this seems to be a common problem where many notebook users have reverted back to Windows 7 due to this issue). So what would be causing this problem and why?</p>
<p>Try as I might I could not pin point the issue and Windows 10 would not give up any clues suggesting everything was idle when it obviously wasn&#8217;t and the CPU was busy doing something in the background.  Eventually I found the culprit but try to remedy the problems actually broke Windows 10 functionality and let me explain how. The reason the CPU was running hotter is because it was actually busy doing some work for Cortana, the humble Paperclip evolved through AI, sex change acquiring a female voice and making you believe it can do anything (no Cortana&#8217;s last name is not Jenner, I did check). I saw this before, in Windows 7 a long time ago and some people caught on to what Microsoft was up to and these invisible background processes were removed form subsequent service pack releases.</p>
<p>In the case of Windows 10 you are literally lied to, nothing is reported as running, the event viewer screen doesn&#8217;t record any activity yet when you fire up Systools Process Monitor there is a feint trace of activity &#8211; this behavior is the same as what malware and malicious applications have, not good Microsoft! So to follow up on my hunch I disabled the search features of Cortana complete, opted out of the other sub features and while this reduced the CPU activity (and heat) it did not completely remedy the problem as the CPU was still obviously doing something causing it to heat up &#8211; one idea could be drivers but surely Microsoft would have had plenty of time to sort this out especially for something as common as an i7 QuadCore sandybridge CPU.</p>
<p>But that wasn&#8217;t the last of my issues either; At this point I was quite satisfied I had remedied the teething problems (to be expected with a new system) and was willing to give Windows 10 another go (heck I had been praising it on Twitter for days) but then I was horrified to find the system had been crippled because I had disabled Cortana and the other sub features but we are never made aware of this and Microsoft for obvious reasons didn&#8217;t announce this fact either. So what are the symptoms?  Firstly you will notice the new Start panel doesn&#8217;t work properly, some tiles don&#8217;t appear, some apps won&#8217;t show up on the search and fundamental core applications simply disappear unless you enable search features again&#8230;why would Microsoft do this, what a shitty thing to do!</p>
<p>So this obviously had me concerned as did the fact that Cortana wanted to know EVERYTHING about me, intercept everything I did, socially and via messaging to which said &#8220;YOU&#8217;RE HAVING A LAUGH MATE!&#8221; and promptly renamed Cortana to something else beginning with C and ending with Face. I had a moan on Twitter obviously at this point and to be fair Microsoft Support were quick to respond asking me to try using the built-in feedback and support application, cool&#8230;hold on you muppets that won&#8217;t work because I disabled Cortana so that native application doesn&#8217;t appear anymore but wait there is more bullcakes to follow.</p>
<p>I then followed the link in Windows 10 to join some program that lets me get early releases of updates and software which in turn also enables the feedback feature however this is stuck in an infinite loop of death and you never ever get the feedback app or get to actually provide any feedback &#8211; dipshits! To add insult to injury I was then tweeted to use their support website but get this, I have to pay for that support &#8211; really WTF?!  I had a total nerd rage at this point and told Microsoft to do one and promptly wiped windows 10 and went back to Windows 8.1 Professional, peace at least (for a while). <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter.png"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4122" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter-229x300.png" alt="windows-10-twitter" width="229" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter-229x300.png 229w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter.png 683w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /></a></p>
<p>So I was going to mention a bunch of other crap with Windows 10? Well here is a list:</p>
<ul>
<li>DPI sucks big time, wtf were Microsoft thinking, just give us proper DPI control over the screens (why do I have to go search the internet for a registry hack)</li>
<li>Key power features hidden or removed like Group Policy Editor that you as an administrator can&#8217;t administer</li>
<li>Windows Themes: You have to go through a convoluted series of screens to something called slideshow to then go to a Windows 7 personalisation screen that has key controls missing!!!</li>
<li>Can&#8217;t use older applications at all, Windows 10 will block them even though they WILL work fine (only way round is to hack the registry again)</li>
<li>Some registry changes/hacks are overridden by Windows 10 and restored to default settings wiping your FIXES</li>
<li>You CANNOT opt out of Automatic Updates and this is wrong, period</li>
</ul>
<p>The biggest issue for me is that Windows 10 is essentially a full blown anti-privacy tool and there is no way to opt out of this.  Free is most certainly not free here and I would advise people to read the terms and conditions that we all click through without noticing because there is some scary stuff in there like Microsoft being able to access your mic, camera and data on your Windows 10 OS as they see fit whenever they want, no thanks. Here is an interesting video for you guys: <a title="Do not install Windows 10" href="https://youtu.be/tWs6mk-HWLk" target="_blank">https://youtu.be/tWs6mk-HWLk</a> Finally if you do downgrade like I did, you need to be aware that Microsoft will attempt to force Windows 10 on you so you need to remove some things using <a title="Remove GWA" href="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/get-rid-windows-10-upgrade-notification-windows-7-8/" target="_blank"><strong>this guide</strong></a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Brian Davis</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Enabling Hyper-V Platform in a Windows 8.1 VM]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/" />
		<id>/index.php/2013/12/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/</id>
		<updated>2013-12-22T03:23:00Z</updated>
		<published>2013-12-22T03:23:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows 8" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This weekend I decided to take advantage of the Windows Phone Preview Program for Developers and update my Lumia 920 to Update 3 for WP8.  While Update 3 was downloading and installing on my phone, I decided to install the Windows Phone SDK 8.0 which;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend I decided to take advantage of the <a href="http://dev.windowsphone.com/en-us/featured/update3">Windows Phone Preview Program for Developers</a> and update my Lumia 920 to Update 3 for WP8.  While Update 3 was downloading and installing on my phone, I decided to install the Windows Phone SDK 8.0 which includes Visual Studio Express for Windows Phone on a Win 8.1 VM that I use for development purposes.</p>
<p>Installation was quick and painless until the very end when I received a message stating that the installation was unable to enable Hyper-V.  When I tried to enable it manually by going into Control Panel -&gt; Programs &amp; Features -&gt; Turn Windows Features On or Off, the Hyper-V Platform checkbox was grayed out.  Upon hovering over the check box I received a tool tip stating &#8220;Hyper-V cannot be installed: A Hypervisor is Already Running&#8221;.</p>
<p>At this point I was confused as I had previously installed VS Express for Windows Phone on another VM and had successfully run it along with the emulator (the emulator runs in Hyper-V).  Because of this I knew the VM host machine was correctly setup to allow VM Workstation to run virtualized environments within VM&#8217;s.  I then compared the two VM&#8217;s and found there were a few differences:</p>
<ul>
<li>Original install was an older version of VS Express for Windows Phone</li>
<li> Original install was on a Windows 8 VM </li>
<li>New install was the latest version of VS Express for Windows Phone </li>
<li>New install was on a Windows 8.1 VM </li>
<li>Both VM&#8217;s are running on VM Workstation 9.0.1 </li>
</ul>
<p>After reviewing the two VM&#8217;s I realized there must be something different with either the latest version of VS Express for Windows Phone, Windows 8.1, or both. Doing a little more research I found there were two things I needed to do:</p>
<ol>
<li>Enable &#8220;Virtualize Intel VT-x/EPT or AMD-V/RVI&#8221; in the settings of the VM
<div class="image_block"><a href="/media/users/brian78/HyperV/VMSettings.png?mtime=1387680976"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/brian78/HyperV/VMSettings.png?mtime=1387680976" alt="" width="362" height="140" /></a></div>
</li>
<li>Open the .vmx file for the virtual machine in a text editor and add the following lines to the end of it
<ol>
<li>hypervisor.cpuid.v0 = &#8220;FALSE&#8221;</li>
<li>mce.enable = &#8220;TRUE&#8221;</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>After doing both of these I started the VM and intended to go back in and turn on Hyper-V, however, when I got back to the settings I was happy to see that &#8220;Hyper-V Platform&#8221; was already enabled.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/media/users/brian78/HyperV/WinFeatures.png?mtime=1387680966"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/brian78/HyperV/WinFeatures.png?mtime=1387680966" alt="" width="415" height="364" /></a></div>
<p>ï¿½</p>
<p>With Hyper-V successfully enabled and running I was then able to run VS Express for Windows Phone along with the Windows Phone Emulator.</p>
<p>By the time I was finished with this, Update 3 had successfully installed on my phone and I was ready to go.  Now, not only do I not have to wait for AT&amp;T to release updates, but I can start developing apps for my phone as well.  Now I just need to find the spare time and start developing!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tahir Khalid</name>
						<uri>http://www.vurso.co.uk/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Developer, can do new tricks, require good home]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/hi-i-m-a-developer/" />
		<id>/index.php/2013/02/hi-i-m-a-developer/</id>
		<updated>2013-02-03T16:56:00Z</updated>
		<published>2013-02-03T16:56:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Operating Systems" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows 7" /><category scheme="/" term=".net" /><category scheme="/" term="oracle" /><category scheme="/" term="oracle client" /><category scheme="/" term="programming" /><category scheme="/" term="software developer" /><category scheme="/" term="system administration" /><category scheme="/" term="visual studio" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world of development is an interesting one where creativity comes alive through code to produce wonderful programs that do lots of cool stuff.
Okay that's the Wizard of Oz intro over, is it really that rosy?
It seems the world of development has c&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/hi-i-m-a-developer/"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">The world of development is an interesting one where creativity comes alive through code to produce wonderful programs that do lots of cool stuff.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Okay that&#8217;s the Wizard of Oz intro over, is it really that rosy?</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">It seems the world of development has changed a great deal and gone are the days when you could just be a code cutter (though such roles do exist and are required), it seems a developer has to now master a wide array of skills and do battle with various foes like the Windows Operating System (<em>level 72 elite boss for those that are keeping track&#8230;</em>) as well trying to do their day job (<em>which in itself now consists of different minion roles</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">With the advances in .NET development there are a wide range of Frameworks, Tools and Add-Ons that can be worked with, installed and generally cried over (<em>a black hole in which I have been sucked into, the crying bit&#8230;</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/coders.jpg?mtime=1359936989" alt="Coders" width="282" height="202" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Now I can hear you say, that&#8217;s all good but we don&#8217;t have those problems, we have a <strong>Textbook Development Team</strong> with a <strong>Textbook It Support Team</strong> in a <strong>Textbook Office</strong> but that is not quite the real world and you will often have boundaries between teams becoming thinner or more common now, the lack of resources and/or teams (<em>leaving the task of taking on those roles and their responsibilities up to the individuals in the department and organisation</em>).</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">But then the question has to be asked, just how efficient and proficient can you be as an individual, a team and a department if you are spending a percentage of your available resource and effort performing other duties, often to prepare something prior to performing your actual task or after the event where you still need to perform a multitude of other tasks (<em>covering various roles like administration etc.</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">And this is where my hell begins&#8230;</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;">Now don&#8217;t get me wrong, I enjoy the techie element of my role, I feel I fulfil the developer title more fully by being able to flex my many different skills (<em>making me adaptable for almost any occasion</em>), a result of accumulating experience in a wide range of sectors starting from my humble beginnings as an IT Support guy, moving into a System Administration role, sideways across into Application Support, Technical Project Lead, Solution Architecture and back into Software Development in my current role as an Senior .NET Enterprise Developer (</span><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><em>not Star Trek&#8230;I wish it was, but it&#8217;s not and I have to live with that disappointment for the rest of my career life&#8230;I tried do the Spock hand thing, got strange looks from the others in the developer forum&#8230;</em></span><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;">).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">In the company where I work now, my team is fairly self-sufficient and that often means we do a lot of the stuff ourselves (<em>whilst still going through proper channels as required</em>) which is great as it means we can quickly prototype solutions through a Virtual Machine on our PC or install a particular tool we need to perform some task &#8211; all of this means that we generally have control over our own PC&#8217;s (<em>as all developers should&#8230;but they don&#8217;t unfortunately</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">But it&#8217;s a double edged sword as I found out the past few days and while being able to administer your own PC&#8217;s and Server&#8217;s is great it can quickly become a bottomless pit that you simply can&#8217;t escape no matter how many Bear Ghryll&#8217;s episodes you have watched (<em>some English guy on the TV that does cool stuff to survive, like James Bond for the wild</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">So begins my particular episode&#8230;</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I have a pretty snazzy developer PC inherited from my predecessor, a rather cool Hewlet Packard Z600 Workstation specced up to the hilt with serious &#8216;Uber&#8217; hardware (<em>dual quad Xeon&#8217;s, stupid amount of memory, SSD&#8217;s, drool&#8230;</em>) and thankfully I have complete control over it (<em>mostly</em>) so I had the chance to configure my PC the way I wanted it to do the development I needed to do.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I have the usual culprits on there, Visual Studio 2010 Premium SP1, MSSQL Server 2008 R2, VMware, lots of useful tools (<em>Notepad++, Red Gate, Solitaire</em>) all running on a Windows 7 Professional 64 bit&#8230;nothing out of the ordinary there I hear you say, ah I haven’t told you about that little evil gremlin called Oracle, more specifically Oracle 64 bit and 32 bit clients on a 64 bit operating system (<em>yes, that combination should cause you to feel nauseous</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">The goal was simple, get the latest version of a large .NET Enterprise project, build it, tweak it, break it and glue it back together.  However there was one caveat, I needed to then install the following in some order (<em>mostly like this one</em>):</span></span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;"> </span></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Install the Oracle 64 bit Client for Windows</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;"> </span></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Install the 64 bit ODAC stuff (<em>for some nice ODACness</em>), the Xcopy version btw</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;"> </span></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Install the 32 bit Client (ODT with ODAC)</span></span></li>
</ul>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Simple enough I thought, having virtual zero Oracle skills I was up for the challenge and felt confident I had the knowhow and experience (<em>plus large balls</em>) to deal with any issues that might crop up and like a true techie I refused to read the manual (<em>text file in the case of Oracle products</em>)…I was in for a bumpy ride it seems.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">* It should be noted here, if you do happen to install the 32 bit client first and/or the Oracle Developer Tools and ODAC (32 bit), you will have seriously random Installation problems trying to install Oracle 64 bit Client (<em>the solution is to follow the instructions further down in this post to remove and clean up your PC</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I went ahead and installed the 64 bit Client, in this case I used the client installation that came provided with the Oracle 11g database installation CD (<em>supplied by the tech support guys</em>), selected <strong>Administrator</strong> as the installation type, pointed the installer to where I wanted the files to go, set the Oracle Home directory and went ahead with the installation (<em>no problems here</em>).</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/oracle-installer.jpg?mtime=1359936990" alt="Oracle Installer" width="399" height="274" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">All good so far, put my <strong>TNSNAMES.ORA</strong> file into the  <strong>{Oracle_Home}Product11.2.0Client_X64NetworkAdmin</strong> folder, fired up a Command console and used Sqlplus to connect to an Oracle 11g database server that was supplied by the tech support team, worked like a charm.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">After doing this I installed the Xcopy version of the 64 bit ODAC libraries and tools which can only be installed by the command prompt so you need to run a command similar to this in the installation directory:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="background-color: #000000;"><span style="color: #ffffff;"><span style="font-family: 'courier new', courier;">install.bat all c:oracle OracleHome_Client1 </span></span></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Or something similar to the above command which should go ahead and install the required ODAC bits into the proper place (<em>you need to ensure you specify the Oracle Home directory</em>).  Again this went fairly smoothly as well with no hick-ups so up next was the 32 bit client and here you need to make sure you install the Oracle Developer Tools with ODAC which includes the 32 bit client otherwise you will experience much pain as I did (<em>where I installed the 32 bit client, then ODAC and other bits which caused no end of pain due to path problems, mismatched versions of dll’s etc</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">The above allows you to correctly use PL/SQL Developer (<em>if you have this cool application installed</em>) as long as you remember to go into the <strong>Tools &gt; Preferences &gt; Connection</strong> section and set the OCI Library to the correct location (<em>e.g. {oracle_home}product11.2.0client_1oci.dll or client_1binoci.dll depending on your version</em>) and any other application that requires the 32 bit Oracle Client.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Now the above hard work should be adequate to get a working Developer Workstation with both 64 bit and 32 bit Oracle Clients and Developer Tools however there is always a but…what I didn’t tell you was the amount of pain I went through to get the above installation list right, and believe me it was extremely painful and as I have found out after posting this blog page, there a few other client combinations that can work e.g. having a primary 32 bit Oracle Client installation with the developer tools and a 64 bit Instant Client installation (<em>will save this for a future post</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I spent an awfully long time getting my workstation working and when things did go wrong (<em>which they did a lot, just Google the various issues people have had trying to install and use Oracle clients with their Visual Studio developer machines</em>) I barely got any work done which prompted my colleague to say:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="background-color: #ffff99;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><strong>“We have to do so much administration work, just to get to a solution developed and delivered”</strong></span></span></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Which got me thinking, this is very true and probably becoming the norm now with modern development, more so in my case due to the nature of the team I am in i.e. we develop lots of bespoke solutions, integration various systems together, sometimes involving small pieces of development to large scale projects.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">What I haven’t shared is the nightmare scenario I ended up in with a totally messed up pair of gac’s (<em>32 bit and 64 bit</em>) and problems compiling any of our projects because they all used one combination or another of the Oracle client (<em>mostly 64 bit now</em>).  So if anyone has had this problem here is the proper way to deal with it…</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Open Command Prompt and change to the directory containing your Oracle client installation and run the deinstall.bat batch script:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="background-color: #000000;"><span style="color: #ffffff;"><span style="font-family: 'courier new', courier;">{oracle_home}product11.2.0Client_X64Deinstalldeinstall.bat</span></span></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Once the de-installation (<em>uninstall to you and me…Oracle people…</em>) is complete you need to run the Oracle Universal Installer (<em>semi-cool Java tool…Java is not cool, the app is however</em>).  When this app fires up you have the option to Deinstall any installations on your system:</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/oracle-installer-deinstall.jpg?mtime=1359936990" alt="Oracle Deinstall" width="372" height="270" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Select all the products and then click on Remove to uninstall (<em>deinstall</em>) the products:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/oracle-installer-deinstall-inventory.jpg?mtime=1359936991" alt="Inventory" width="150" height="245" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">If you have no issues with the uninstallation of the Oracle Client stuff you will need to go into the Windows Registry to make sure you remove any references to an Oracle installation otherwise your future Oracle Client installation exercises will result in broken installations and more headaches.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Edit the registry (click START &gt; type regedit32) and start with the following registry location:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINESOFTWARE</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Find the Oracle Key and delete it, do the same for the HKEY_CURRENT_USER and HKEY_USERS (<em>you will need to go through the various sub parent keys and find any Oracle sub Keys and delete them</em>). </span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Don&#8217;t forget to clear the gac&#8217;s (both 32 bit and 64 bit), I found this the simplest way of doing it:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Start Command Prompt for Visual Studio 32 bit</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Type gacutil /l &gt; c:gac32list.txt</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Open the gac32list.txt file and find the word Oracle</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">In the Command Prompt window type the following commands: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">gacutil /u Oracle.DataAccess</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">gacutil /u Oracle.Database.Extensions</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">gacutil /u Oracle.Web</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Close the Command Prompt window</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Start Command Prompt for Visual Studio 64 bit</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Repeat the above commands</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Close the Command Prompt window</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">This should give you a clean installation and hopefully allow you to get a working installation of the Oracle clients on your .NET Developer Workstation.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">So back to the question at hand, just what kind of developer does a developer need to be?  Someone who is comfortable at administering their local, virtual and remote computers?  And just how much effort should be made before you require assistance (<em>and will that not take more effort</em>) but what if you work in an environment where the resources are not available and you have to <strong>“man up”</strong> (<em>so to speak</em>) and take the reins, do you factor that into any and every piece of work and project you do?</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Well in an ideal world you would minimize the effort required for each subsequent piece of work and/or project however you cannot avoid the moments when you will simply have to dig into the trenches and get your hands dirty so be prepared to lose half your estimated time (<em>if not more</em>) battling system incompatibilities, software bugs, assembly hell and those gremlins that keep causing you to see spots on your screen (<em>honest</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Set aside time to climb a difficult mountain and get your hands cut, you will need to work out the many holes in your nice setup and as more and more technical requirements popup don’t expect everything to work well together the first time (<em>you have to integrate your own development environment first</em>). </span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">So key here is to develop the expertise if you don’t have it at hand, become adaptable but remain honest to yourself (<em>you will have to go through some pain to get to the fruits of your labour</em>).  Use knowledge base tools (<em>Wiki</em>) to record your efforts, communicate your findings with your colleagues and attempt to automate and make reusable as much of what you use as possible.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">This will help you better deal with those moments when you have to spend most of your effort on the administration of your development work as appose to the actual developing and as a bonus increase your skills repertoire which every modern developer shouldn’t shy away from (<em>becoming more agile in nature by having a can-do attitude</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/mememe.jpg?mtime=1359936991" alt="mememe" width="98" height="156" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I dedicate my first LTD blog post to Chrissie1.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">References:</span></strong></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/enterprise-edition/downloads/index.html"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Oracle 11g Database Download (includes the clients)</span></a></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/windows/downloads/index-090165.html"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">ODAC Xcopy 64 bit Download</span></a></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/topics/dotnet/utilsoft-086879.html"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Oracle Developer Tools with ODAC 32 bit</span></a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/hi-i-m-a-developer/#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/hi-i-m-a-developer/feed/atom/" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Axel Achten (axel8s)</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting remote Mount Point information with PowerShell]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-mount-point-information/" />
		<id>/index.php/2012/11/getting-remote-mount-point-information/</id>
		<updated>2012-11-29T11:27:00Z</updated>
		<published>2012-11-29T11:27:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="2003 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="2008 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="2012 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="diskspace" /><category scheme="/" term="mount point" /><category scheme="/" term="powershell" /><category scheme="/" term="remote" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a previous post I showed how to get remote disk information with PowerShell. The script works nice untill you execute it on a server with Mount Points. When executing the following script on a server with Mount Points:

Get-WmiObject win32_logicald&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-mount-point-information/"><![CDATA[<p>In a previous post I showed how to <a href="/index.php/SysAdmins/OS/Windows/getting-remote-disk-information-with">get remote disk information with PowerShell</a>. The script works nice until you execute it on a server with Mount Points. When executing the following script on a server with Mount Points:</p>
<pre>Get-WmiObject win32_logicaldisk -computer &lt;computername&gt; | 
select-object DeviceID, VolumeName, @{Name="Size";Expression={$_.Size/1GB}},@{Name="FreeSpace";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/1GB}},
@{Name="PCTFreeSpace";Expression={
$_.FreeSpace/$_.Size*100}}|Sort-Object -descending PCTfreespace|format-table</pre>
<p>I get the following result:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP1.JPG?mtime=1354195164"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP1.JPG?mtime=1354195164" width="977" height="144" /></a></div>
<p>Knowing the sizes of my databases, I knew the numbers were wrong. So I opened a RDP session to the server and found this picture in Disk Management:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP2.JPG?mtime=1354195179"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP2.JPG?mtime=1354195179" width="810" height="530" /></a></div>
<p>At that moment I realized I wasn&#8217;t getting the information from the Mount Points, just from the Disks that had a drive letter assigned to them.<br />
So let&#8217;s find out how we can get that information with Windows PowerShell. I still need the wmiobject but instead of the win32_logicaldisk I&#8217;m going to use the win32_volume. I also replace the DeviceID and VolumeName objects with Name and Label:</p>
<pre>get-wmiobject win32_volume -computer &lt;computername|
select name, label, driveletter</pre>
<p>The result looks like this:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP3.JPG?mtime=1354195191"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP3.JPG?mtime=1354195191" width="733" height="200" /></a></div>
<p>As you can see, the drive letter properties are empty for my Mount Points and in the name column I can find the file and folder where they are mounted.<br />
So let&#8217;s find the space, free space and percentage free space of the volumes. I can use the calculations from my previous script only Size needs to be replaced with Capacity:</p>
<pre>get-wmiobject win32_volume -computer &lt;computername|
select name, label, @{Name="Capacity (GB)";Expression={$_.Capacity/1GB}},@{Name="FreeSpace (GB)";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/1GB}},
@{Name="FreeSpace (PCT)";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/$_.Capacity*100}} |
format-table</pre>
<p>The result now shows the drives and Mount Points with all the requested information:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP4.JPG?mtime=1354195223"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/FSMP4.JPG?mtime=1354195223" width="964" height="186" /></a></div>
<p>To be able to reuse the script I do what I did in the other two PowerShell post:</p>
<pre>param(
	[string] $compname = $(Throw "Provide a Server name as first parameter")
)
Get-WmiObject win32_volume -computer $compname |
select name, label, @{Name="Capacity (GB)";Expression={$_.Capacity/1GB}},
@{Name="FreeSpace (GB)";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/1GB}},
@{Name="FreeSpace (PCT)";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/$_.Capacity*100}} |
format-table</pre>
<p>End that&#8217;s it, the next request for free disk space is a matter of seconds again.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-mount-point-information/#comments" thr:count="5"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-mount-point-information/feed/atom/" thr:count="5"/>
		<thr:total>5</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Axel Achten (axel8s)</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting remote SQL Service information with Windows Powershell]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-sql-service-information/" />
		<id>/index.php/2012/10/getting-remote-sql-service-information/</id>
		<updated>2012-10-11T07:37:00Z</updated>
		<published>2012-10-11T07:37:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="powershell" /><category scheme="/" term="service" /><category scheme="/" term="sql server" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every DBA managing multiple SQl Servers with multiple instances will know the issues with developpers, project managers and others that don't know the importance of the instancename when they request you to take some action.
So you can start some e-mai&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-sql-service-information/"><![CDATA[<p>Every DBA managing multiple SQL Servers with multiple instances will know the issues with developers, project managers and others that don&#8217;t know the importance of the instance name when they request you to take some action.<br />
So you can start some e-mail ping pong to get the instance name, open the server documentation or RDP to the server to find the installed instances. But in the time you would need to do this you can write yourself a PowerShell script to get the remote service information.<br />
First step getting remote services information:</p>
<pre>Get-Service -ComputerName &lt;SQLServerHostName&gt;</pre>
<p>This gives you all the information you need:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService1.PNG?mtime=1349948019"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService1.PNG?mtime=1349948019" width="646" height="278" /></a></div>
<p>But since I only need SQL Server information I will filter out all the other services using the Where-Object and the like operator:</p>
<pre>Get-Service -ComputerName &lt;SQLServerHostName&gt; -name "MSSQL*"</pre>
<p>As you can see we can now see the installed instances of SQL Server on our remote server. Only if the Instance name is too long you will see &#8230; at some point:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService2.PNG?mtime=1349948026"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService2.PNG?mtime=1349948026" width="575" height="138" /></a></div>
<p>Since we only need the Name and ass a surplus the Status of our SQL Server Services we can format the output:</p>
<pre> Get-Service -ComputerName &lt;SQLServerHostName&gt; -name "MSSQL*"|Format-Table -Property Name, Status</pre>
<p>And now we have only the information we need:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService3.PNG?mtime=1349948035"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService3.PNG?mtime=1349948035" width="983" height="136" /></a></div>
<p>Like in my <a href="/index.php/SysAdmins/OS/Windows/getting-remote-disk-information-with">previous post</a> I will put the command in a PS1 script using a parameter and a Throw to be able to reuse the script:</p>
<pre>param(
	[string] $compname = $(Throw "Provide a SQL Server name as first parameter")
)
Get-Service -ComputerName $compname -name "MSSQL*"|Format-Table -Property Name, Status, DisplayName</pre>
<p>Executing the script will look like this:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService4.PNG?mtime=1349948043"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSSQLService4.PNG?mtime=1349948043" width="983" height="253" /></a></div>
<p>Et voila, another point I can take of my list of items I can&#8217;t do on a Server Core&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-sql-service-information/#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-sql-service-information/feed/atom/" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Axel Achten (axel8s)</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting remote disk information with Windows PowerShell]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-disk-information-with/" />
		<id>/index.php/2012/10/getting-remote-disk-information-with/</id>
		<updated>2012-10-04T11:44:00Z</updated>
		<published>2012-10-04T11:44:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="disk usage" /><category scheme="/" term="powershell" /><category scheme="/" term="remote admin" /><category scheme="/" term="wmi" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple of weeks ago someone asked me why they should upgrade to MS SQL Server 2012. I named a bunch of reasons and only remembered afterwards that the possibility to use Windows Server Core could also be a surplus. Just 2 days later this Case for Core&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-disk-information-with/"><![CDATA[<p>A couple of weeks ago someone asked me why they should upgrade to MS SQL Server 2012. I named a bunch of reasons and only remembered afterwards that the possibility to use Windows Server Core could also be a surplus. Just 2 days later this <a href="http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2012/09/case-for-core/">Case for Core</a> post from Jeremiah Peschka (<a href="http://www.brentozar.com/archive/author/jeremiah-peschka/">blog </a>| <a href="https://twitter.com/peschkaj">twitter</a>) made me realize there was a lot of work for me before I could say that running MS SQL Server 2012 on Windows Server Core. I already read the book <a href="http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Microsoft-SQL-Server-2008-Administration-with-Windows-PowerShell.productCd-0470477288.html">Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Administration with Windows PowerShell</a> and reviewed it <a href="http://axel8s.wordpress.com/2012/01/20/book-review-microsoft-sql-server-2008-administration-with-windows-powershell/">here</a>.So I decided to try to avoid the usage of Remote Desktop as much as possible and finally start to use PowerShell on a daily basis. One of the first things I needed to do was the restore of a database on another server. So before I could start the restore I needed to check the servers&#8217; disk configuration and available space. So let&#8217;s see how to do this with PowerShell.<br />
To get information about disks we use the win32_logicaldisk wmiobject and with the -computer parameter we specify our server name:</p>
<pre>GET-WmiObject win32_logicaldisk -computer &lt;computername&gt;</pre>
<p>The result looks like this:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo1.PNG?mtime=1349357595"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo1.PNG?mtime=1349357595" width="232" height="536" /></a></div>
<p>As you can see, the requested information is there and if I only need to do this just once it&#8217;s fine but I&#8217;m going to need this information several times on different servers so let’s make the result more user friendly.<br />
First things first, let&#8217;s just select the data I need, with a pipe I pass the input from the Get-WmiObject to the second part of my command and there I use the Select-Object to specify the object that I want:</p>
<pre>Get-WmiObject win32_logicaldisk -computer &lt;computername&gt; | select-object DeviceID, VolumeName,Size,FreeSpace</pre>
<p>This looks better:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo2.png?mtime=1349357671"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo2.png?mtime=1349357671" width="964" height="110" /></a></div>
<p>Next step is to see the percentage free space. Using @{Name=&#8221;&#8221;,Expression={}}:</p>
<pre>Get-WmiObject win32_logicaldisk -computer &lt;computername&gt; | select-object DeviceID, VolumeName,Size,FreeSpace,@{Name="PCTFreeSpace";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/$_.Size*100}}</pre>
<p>The code works but now I have to scroll again to see all the disk info:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo3.png?mtime=1349357695"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo3.png?mtime=1349357695" width="275" height="458" /></a></div>
<p>I add a second pipe and specify that I want my result formatted as a table, I also make sure the size and free space make more sense:</p>
<pre>Get-WmiObject win32_logicaldisk -computer &lt;computername&gt; | 
select-object DeviceID, VolumeName, @{Name="Size";Expression={$_.Size/1GB}},@{Name="FreeSpace";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/1GB}},
@{Name="PCTFreeSpace";Expression={
$_.FreeSpace/$_.Size*100}}|format-table</pre>
<p>Better no?</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo4.png?mtime=1349357709"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo4.png?mtime=1349357709" width="964" height="141" /></a></div>
<p>Now you can save this script to a text file, rename the file extension to .ps1 and edit the file every time you need to query another server. Or you can use a parameter. I named my file GetDiskUsage.ps1 and started the script with param([Datatype] $Variablename):</p>
<pre>param(
	[string] $compname )
Get-WmiObject win32_logicaldisk -computer &lt;computername&gt; | 
select-object DeviceID, VolumeName, @{Name="Size";Expression={$_.Size/1GB}},@{Name="FreeSpace";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/1GB}},
@{Name="PCTFreeSpace";Expression={
$_.FreeSpace/$_.Size*100}}|Sort-Object -descending PCTfreespace|format-table</pre>
<p>Now I can execute the script with the following command:</p>
<pre>.Getdiskusage &lt;Computername&gt;</pre>
<p>Notice that I also added a Sort-Object before the format to be able to see what disk has the most available free space first:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo5.png?mtime=1349357719"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo5.png?mtime=1349357719" width="964" height="103" /></a></div>
<p>To finish things up a use a Throw in my parameter definition to avoid an ugly error message when I execute the script without specifying a parameter value:</p>
<pre>param(
	[string] $compname = $(Throw "Provide a Server name as first parameter") )
Get-WmiObject win32_logicaldisk -computer &lt;computername&gt; | 
select-object DeviceID, VolumeName, @{Name="Size";Expression={$_.Size/1GB}},@{Name="FreeSpace";Expression={$_.FreeSpace/1GB}},
@{Name="PCTFreeSpace";Expression={
$_.FreeSpace/$_.Size*100}}|Sort-Object -descending PCTfreespace|format-table</pre>
<p>When I now execute the script without specifying a computer name:</p>
<pre>.Getdiskusage</pre>
<p>I see I have to specify a computer name:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo6.png?mtime=1349357734"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/axel8s/PSDiskInfo6.png?mtime=1349357734" width="953" height="72" /></a></div>
<p>I know there are alternatives to write this wmi query. This is just a way that works for me and does the trick now. Feel free to comment and/or correct me if there are better solutions.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-disk-information-with/#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/getting-remote-disk-information-with/feed/atom/" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SQLArcher</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The 5 minute guide to get started with Windows 8]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/the-5-minute-guide-to/" />
		<id>/index.php/2012/09/the-5-minute-guide-to/</id>
		<updated>2012-09-10T06:35:00Z</updated>
		<published>2012-09-10T06:35:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Operating Systems" /><category scheme="/" term="Windows 8" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 8 has been a hot topic of late - especially getting started with it. We already had a post from our very own Denis Gobo (@denisgobo) in how to shut down Windows 8. This led me to write a quick post on some features you may or may not know of.

Wi&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/the-5-minute-guide-to/"><![CDATA[<p>Windows 8 has been a hot topic of late &#8211; especially getting started with it. We already had a post from our very own Denis Gobo (<a href="http://www.twitter.com/denisgobo">@denisgobo</a>) in <a href="/index.php/SysAdmins/windows-8/how-to-shutdown-windows-8">how to shut down Windows 8</a>. This led me to write a quick post on some features you may or may not know of.</p>
<p>Windows 8 has a great design for touch screens, and some great shortcuts for the PC User as well. I&#8217;ve been using it since Consumer Preview and to be honest &#8211; it did take a week or so to get used to the new interface. There are one or two tricks, that when you know them, make it a lot easier to work with as a PC User.</p>
<p>To start of with, I am going to talk a bit about charms. Charms is the new &#8220;navigation&#8221; for Windows 8 &#8211; it appears on the right hand side whenever you move your mouse to either the top right, or bottom right corners of the screen.</p>
<p>This will bring up the following:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/Charms_Menu.jpg?mtime=1347266235"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/Charms_Menu.jpg?mtime=1347266235" width="270" height="1079" /></a></div>
<p>In order they are:</p>
<p>1. Search<br />
2. Share<br />
3. Windows 8 UI<br />
4. Devices<br />
5. Settings</p>
<p>There is one thing about charms which is a very subtle yet powerful feature&#8230; it is context sensitive! Depending which application is active, will depend what charms enables you to do. Some of you might have downloaded the Wikipedia app (for example) from the store; good looking, side scrolling; so how do you search? With the charms menu, just open it up and search whatever you&#8217;re looking for. For those of you which lives in a suffocated broadband area like me &#8211; this is also where you go to limit the amount of data which live tiles uses in the Win8UI (this however is only from RTM onwards).</p>
<p>Another handy feature is Flip-2D &#8211; better known as the 3D Aero flip in Windows Vista/7. This is done by moving your mouse to the top left corner of the screen, or pressing WIN + Tab.</p>
<p>It looks similar to this:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView.jpg?mtime=1347266256"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView.jpg?mtime=1347266256" width="441" height="524" /></a></div>
<p>When it is fully expanded it will look like this (this one is cropped, at the bottom you will have the link to the Win8UI):</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView_2.jpg?mtime=1347267039"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView_2.jpg?mtime=1347267039" width="187" height="374" /></a></div>
<p>A big question would be why to use this one instead of ALT + Tab? While ALT + Tab cycles through both the desktop apps and your Win8 apps, the WIN + Tab allows you to select an individual application and pin it either side of your screen directly if you do not want to close your active application. Apart from this, the only other difference is that it does not cycle through desktop applications.</p>
<p>The last quick feature is the poweruser menu, which is accessible by right clicking on the Win8UI shortcut on the bottom left of the screen:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/PowerUser.jpg?mtime=1347266245"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/PowerUser.jpg?mtime=1347266245" width="351" height="395" /></a></div>
<p>This gives you quick access to control panel, command line, etc. which is very useful.</p>
<p>The last most notable feature is Hyper-V which is available in Windows 8 Pro and Enterprise editions, with the limit being an x64 edition with a SLAT capable CPU. This is very handy especially when you build and destroy multiple virtual machines and do not want to install a Server edition on your Computer/Laptop or if you do not have access to a separate virtual environment. This is enabled via the add/program features.</p>
<p>One last shortcut that I find extremely useful when working with SQL Server Data Tools, Management Studio, etc. is CTRL + Shift. When holding these two keys and launching an application from Win8UI, this immediately launches the application in Administrator Mode.</p>
<p>If there is any features you find handy, feel free to leave a comment.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/the-5-minute-guide-to/#comments" thr:count="5"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/the-5-minute-guide-to/feed/atom/" thr:count="5"/>
		<thr:total>5</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 8, Visual Studio 2012 and Windows Server 2012 released to manufacturing]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/windows-8-releases-to-manufacturing/" />
		<id>/index.php/2012/08/windows-8-releases-to-manufacturing/</id>
		<updated>2012-08-01T14:10:00Z</updated>
		<published>2012-08-01T14:10:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="Windows" /><category scheme="/" term="windows 8" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft just released a press release announcing that Windows 8 has been released to manufacturing (RTM)

Here are the important dates

August 15th: Developers will be able to download the final version of Windows 8 via your MSDN subscriptions.&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/windows-8-releases-to-manufacturing/"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft just released a press release announcing that Windows 8 has been released to manufacturing (RTM)</p>
<p>Here are the important dates for us developers</p>
<p><strong>August 15th</strong>: Developers will be able to download the final version of Windows 8 via your MSDN subscriptions.</p>
<p><strong>August 15th</strong>: IT professionals testing Windows 8 in organizations will be able to access the final version of Windows 8 through your TechNet subscriptions.</p>
<p><strong>August 16th</strong>: Customers with existing Microsoft Software Assurance for Windows will be able to download Windows 8 Enterprise edition through the Volume License Service Center (VLSC), allowing you to test, pilot and begin adopting Windows 8 Enterprise within your organization.</p>
<p><strong>August 16th</strong>: Microsoft Partner Network members will have access to Windows 8.</p>
<p><strong>August 20th</strong>: Microsoft Action Pack Providers (MAPS) receive access to Windows 8.<br />
September 1st: Volume License customers without Software Assurance will be able to purchase Windows 8 through Microsoft Volume License Resellers.</p>
<p>As you can see, you only need to wait 15 days before you can download Windows 8 RTM from MSDN</p>
<p>Rest of the press release can be found here: http://windowsteamblog.com/windows/b/bloggingwindows/archive/2012/08/01/windows-8-has-reached-the-rtm-milestone.aspx</p>
<p><strong>Windows Server 2012</strong> is also released, see here for more info: http://blogs.technet.com/b/windowsserver/archive/2012/08/01/windows-server-2012-released-to-manufacturing.aspx<br />
September 4 is when Windows Server 2012 will be generally available for evaluation and purchase by all customers around the world</p>
<p><strong>Visual Studio 2012</strong> is also done, see here for more info: http://blogs.msdn.com/b/somasegar/archive/2012/08/01/visual-studio-2012-and-net-4-5-complete.aspx<br />
For MSDN Subscribers, the bits will be available for download on August 15th</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/windows-8-releases-to-manufacturing/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/windows-8-releases-to-manufacturing/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Worm: The First Digital World War by Mark Bowden]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/security/review-worm-the-first-digital/" />
		<id>/index.php/2012/04/review-worm-the-first-digital/</id>
		<updated>2012-04-22T17:34:00Z</updated>
		<published>2012-04-22T17:34:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="/" term="2003 Server" /><category scheme="/" term="Security" /><category scheme="/" term="conficker" /><category scheme="/" term="virus" /><category scheme="/" term="worm" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worm: The First Digital World War by Mark Bowden

Do you still remember  Conficker, also known as Downup, Downadup and Kido? Conficker infected between 9 million and 15 million PCs
Here are just some examples that I pulled down from wikipedia

  In&#8230;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/sysadmins/security/review-worm-the-first-digital/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0802119832/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0802119832">Worm: The First Digital World War</a> by Mark Bowden</p>
<p>Do you still remember  <a href="/index.php/SysAdmins/OS/win32-conficker-b-also-known-as-downadup">Conficker, also known as Downup, Downadup and Kido</a>? Conficker infected between 9 million and 15 million PCs<br />
Here are just some examples that I pulled down from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conficker#Impact_in_Europe">wikipedia</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Intramar, the French Navy computer network, was infected with Conficker on 15 January 2009. The network was subsequently quarantined, forcing aircraft at several airbases to be grounded because their flight plans could not be downloaded.</li>
<li>
The United Kingdom Ministry of Defence reported that some of its major systems and desktops were infected. The virus has spread across administrative offices, NavyStar/N* desktops aboard various Royal Navy warships and Royal Navy submarines, and hospitals across the city of Sheffield reported infection of over 800 computers.</li>
<li>
On 2 February 2009, the Bundeswehr, the unified armed forces of Germany reported that about one hundred of their computers were infected.</li>
<li>
An infection of Manchester City Council&#8217;s IT system caused an estimated £1.5m worth of disruption in February 2009. USB flash drives have since been banned, as this was believed to be the vector for the initial infection.</li>
</ul>
<p>I noticed the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0802119832/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0802119832">Worm: The First Digital World War</a> by Mark Bowden and decided to check it out since I already read <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142000957/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0142000957">Killing Pablo</a> which was written by Mark Bowden as well</p>
<p>The book is written for people who are not familiar with all the terms that most IT people know. Things like TCP/IP, ports, RPC and buffer overflow are all explained in very simple ways, an IT person might think that this book is too simple for him or her. The part of the book which I found of most interest is the infighting between the members of the <a href="http://www.confickerworkinggroup.org/wiki/">Conficker Cabal</a> (later renamed to the Conficker Working Group). The cluelessness from the US government was interesting as well.</p>
<p>The book takes you through how the Conficker worm started to infect computers to the cat and mouse game that followed between the Conficker creator and the Conficker Cabal. Also covered is a general history of worms and viruses/virii so that you can see that each virus is based on some elements of the previous one.</p>
<p>The book is only 245 pages and it is a very easy read with a nice size font. If you don&#8217;t know anything about Conficker, I think this is a good book to read. If you already know about Conficker and followed it then I don&#8217;t think you will find a lot of new things in this book that have not been discussed before, however I think that this book will still be of interest to you, the Conficker Cabal stuff was the most interesting part to me</p>
<p>In the end I would recommend this book and I think you will enjoy it.</p>
<p>To see all the books I have read so far in 2012 visit my pinterest board here: http://pinterest.com/denisgobo/books-i-read-in-2012/</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="/index.php/sysadmins/security/review-worm-the-first-digital/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/sysadmins/security/review-worm-the-first-digital/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
		</entry>
	</feed>
