<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>goals &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/goals/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Better Late Than Never, My 2011 Goals</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/better-late-than-never-my/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/better-late-than-never-my/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/01/better-late-than-never-my/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another year done and another year to look forward to. Last year I focused on the long term, refining an amorphous long term picture into something with a bit more substance. Along the way I began some good habits and succeeded in a number of near term goals. This year the theme is continued development and new beginnings. With the birth of my son on January 14th, my focus will be less on big achievements and more on items I can work on in small chunks of time (possibly at 4AM with one arm otherwise occupied by baby).]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="border: 1px solid #AAAAAA; float: right; font-size: 80%; color: #666666; text-align: center; padding: 8px; margin: 8px;"><img src="http://tiernok.com/LTDBlog/01152011484_sm.jpg" alt="Baby Ian - Picture Copyright: Eli, 2011" style="padding-bottom: 5px;" /><br /> Baby Ian</div>
<p>Another year done and another year to look forward to. Last year I focused on the long term, refining an amorphous long term picture into something with a bit more substance. Along the way I began some good habits and succeeded in a number of near term goals. This year the theme is continued development and new beginnings. With the birth of my son on January 14th, my focus will be less on big achievements and more on items I can work on in small chunks of time (possibly at 4AM with one arm otherwise occupied by baby).</p>
<h2 style="clear: left;">2010 Goals</h2>
<p>My original 2010 goals were light so I expanded the list fairly early. I did not end up achieving the whole list. There may be a lesson there.</p>
<dl>
<dt>Read 15-30 Articles/Week</dt>
<dd>According to Google Reader I read 2785 items (~53/week) last year. It&#8217;s not even worth estimating non-RSS articles, I reached this goal easily. Success.</dd>
<dt>Read 12 on-topic Books</dt>
<dd>My professional reading included 20 books this past year and there are several more I was in the process of reading when the year rolled over. Success.</dd>
<dt>Blog Weekly</dt>
<dd>I published 28 blog entries in 2010. Not a bad number, but also far short of my original goal. Being a generalist that only dives deeper into most of these topics on my own time, it can be hard to find material for blogging at times. I am happy with how much I completed and will use this as a baseline for my 2011 goals.</dd>
<dt>Attend 2 Events</dt>
<dd>As part of the 2010 goal setting process at work,  I had a goal of attending one process improvement and one technical event. I achieved the technical side (4 SQL Saturdays, 1 Code Camp) but did not attend a process improvement (agile, lean, etc) event.</dd>
</dl>
<p>Some additional achievements from the past year that were not part of my goals include:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Speaking</dt>
<dd>I presented at SQL Saturday Baton Rouge on data modeling and the RDU Code Camp on unit testing</dd>
<dt>Leadership</dt>
<dd>I created, sold, and lead an ongoing Technical Lunch and Learn program at work with goals to introduce new technologies and practices into the company, challenge and grow our standards, and kindle greater interest in continued learning</dd>
</dl>
<h2>2011 Goals</h2>
<p>I&#8217;m starting with a larger number of goals this year. The numbers are based on last year as a baseline. I&#8217;ve attempted to keep them from being too aggressive as my son will put a lot of new and interesting demands on my time.</p>
<p>Topics this year are similar to last year:</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 2em">
<li>Technical Focus: SQL, .Net, one non-MS (TBD) language, HTML 5</li>
<li>Architecture Focus: Application and Integration (maybe some Enterprise as well)</li>
<li>Usability, Design</li>
<li>Business and Business Analysis</li>
<li>Process: Lean, Agile, Lean Startup, etc</li>
</ul>
<p>And my goals for 2011:</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 2em">
<li>35 Blog Entries </li>
<li>Speak at 2 Events (.Net or SQL)</li>
<li>Read 30 articles/week in topics above</li>
<li>Read 12 books in the topics above</li>
<li>Setup a PHP/MySQL Dev environment again so I can assist with LTD development and maintenance</li>
<li>Finish one release of a personal project (which is amazingly relevant to this post)</li>
</ul>
<p>I suspect the reading goals will be low again, even with a newborn in the house (counting pleasure reading, I purchased over 50 books last year and likely read twice that). Which brings me to my biggest goal for 2011:</p>
<p>Be a good first-time dad AND don&#8217;t fall of the internet at the same time.</p>
<p>Here we go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/better-late-than-never-my/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of my 2010 goals</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/review-of-my-2010-goals/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/review-of-my-2010-goals/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 17:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/12/review-of-my-2010-goals/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The end of the year 2010 is coming up, this is an excellent time to review my 2010 goals. In this post 2010 Goals For SQLDenis I have outlined a couple of things I wanted to accomplish in 2010. Here is a list of those goals

Upgrade our servers to SQL&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The end of the year 2010 is coming up, this is an excellent time to review my 2010 goals. In this post <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/goals-for-2010-for-sqldenis">2010 Goals For SQLDenis</a> I have outlined a couple of things I wanted to accomplish in 2010. Here is a list of those goals</p>
<p>Upgrade our servers to SQL Server 2008<br />
Read 2 books per month<br />
Be more active in the SQL community<br />
Watch more television<br />
Play more computer games</p>
<p>Now let&#8217;s see how I did</p>
<p>
<h2>Upgrade our servers to SQL Server 2008</h2>
<p>This was done and we are all on SQL Server 2008 now. No more replication, we can now use all the fancy T-SQL&#8230;.everyone is happy</p>
<h2>Read 2 books per month</h2>
<p>I didn&#8217;t quite make it but I also read parts of technical books, I decided not to include those since I didn&#8217;t finish those. Here is the list of books that I did finish.</p>
<p><strong>Stephen King</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1416586652?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1416586652">Just After Sunset</a><br />
This is a collection of short stories, the stories I liked the most were The Gingerbread Girl, Graduation Afternoon and Stationary Bike. I liked the book and I recommend it</p>
<p><strong>Stephen King</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1416524517?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1416524517">The Cell</a><br />
This book is about cell phones turning people into zombies. The story is okay, a little too long in my opinion</p>
<p><strong>Daniel Suarez</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0451228731?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0451228731">Daemon</a><br />
I liked this book a lot and have even blogged about it here: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/daemon-by-daniel-suarez-is-a-book-every">Daemon by Daniel Suarez is a book every programmer will love</a></p>
<p><strong>Daniel Suarez</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0525951571?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0525951571">Freedom</a><br />
Freedom is the follow up to Daemon and has all the elements that made Daemon such a great book. This is the first book I read on my Nook Color and I finished it in two days..highly recommended..you do need to read Daemon first, otherwise you will be missing parts of the story</p>
<p><strong>Dan Brown</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0385504225?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0385504225">The Lost Symbol</a><br />
This is probably the best book by Dan Brown. It has a very interesting ending, highly recommended.</p>
<p><strong>Michael Pollan</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143114964?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0143114964">In Defense of Food: An Eater&#8217;s Manifesto</a><br />
Read this on my way to the 2010 MVP summit. If people would read this book they wouldn&#8217;t eat all that modified stuff that the stores are filled with nowadays</p>
<p><strong>Stephenie Meyer</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316038377?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0316038377">Twilight</a><br />
Stephenie Meyer: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316024961?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0316024961">New Moon</a><br />
Stephenie Meyer: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316027650?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0316027650">Eclipse</a><br />
Stephenie Meyer: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316067938?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0316067938">Breaking Dawn</a></p>
<p>Why oh why did I start this series, the first two books were fine but then it became ridiculous. Renesmee really&#8230;? Renesmee is a vampire/human hybrid member of the Olympic Coven. She is the daughter of Edward Cullen and Bella Swan, and the imprintee of Jacob Black<br />
Of course after I &#8216;invested&#8217; all the time into the books so far I had no choice to finish it. I do not recommend this</p>
<p><strong>Peter Benchley</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1400064562?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1400064562">Jaws</a><br />
The movie was good, the book is even better. The book has a chapter which is not in the movie, in this chapter Brody&#8217;s wife and the scientist have an affair. I highly recommended this book.</p>
<p><strong>Steven D. Levitt and Stephen J. Dubner</strong>:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060731338?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0060731338"> Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side of Everything</a><br />
Steven D. Levitt and Stephen J. Dubner: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060889578?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0060889578">SuperFreakonomics: Global Cooling, Patriotic Prostitutes, and Why Suicide Bombers Should Buy Life Insurance</a></p>
<p>These two books are very similar, an interesting read, check it out if you are bored.</p>
<p><strong>Ian Ayres</strong>: <a href=""http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0553384732?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0553384732">Super Crunchers: Why Thinking-By-Numbers is the New Way To Be Smart</a><br />
Interesting book, it shows you all the different ways that companies use numbers/statistics to make decisions. Recommended. </p>
<p><strong>John M. Barry</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143036491?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0143036491">The Great Influenza: The story of the deadliest pandemic in history </a><br />
This was very interesting, the book has a nice history about medicine and hospitals in the US in addition to covering the plague. Highly recommended.</p>
<p><strong>Max Brook</strong>:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307346617?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0307346617"> World War Z: An Oral History of the Zombie War</a><br />
A fun book if you want to escape from reality.</p>
<p><strong>Frank W. Abagnale</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0767906845?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0767906845">The Art of the Steal: How to Protect Yourself and Your Business from Fraud, America&#8217;s #1 Crime</a><br />
Frank Abagnale is the person who wrote &#8220;Catch me if you can&#8221;. This book details how fraud happens and what can be done to stop it. Now more important than ever with identity theft and lost data all over the place. A must read.</p>
<p><strong>Ron Suskind</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001DYVL96?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B001DYVL96">The Way of the World: A Story of Truth and Hope in an Age of Extremism</a><br />
This was an interesting story about culture clashes, cover ups, infiltration and manipulation. If you are into politics then I would say that you should read this book.</p>
<p><strong>Geoff Colvin</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001HD8NZ8?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B001HD8NZ8">Talent Is Overrated: What Really Separates World-Class Performers from Everybody Else</a><br />
A very interesting book, yes Tiger Wood is good..not because he has talent but because he started playing and practicing while he could barely walk. The same is of course true for programming..the people who are in front of the computer 16 hours a day solving problems will be many times better than the ones that just do a 9 to 5 stint. I recommend this book!</p>
<p><strong>Bill Bryson</strong>: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060920084?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0060920084">The Lost Continent: Travels in Small-Town America</a><br />
I love Bill Bryson&#8217;s writing. The first book I read by Bill Bryson was A walk in the woods and I loved it. This book is funny, it is entertaning and you will also learn some facts about the USA. Highly recommended.</p>
<p><strong>Ian Stirk</strong>: <a href=""http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1935182730?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1935182730">SQL Server DMVs in Action: Better Queries with Dynamic Management Views</a><br />
If you want to learn about DMVs then this is the book for you, I have been reading this book while it was being written, it is not released yet.</p>
<p>
<h2>Be more active in the SQL community</h2>
<p>I wrote only 76 blog posts this year but I did write a bunch of Wiki articles, here are 2 examples <a href="http://wiki.lessthandot.com/index.php/Store_More_SQL_Agent_Job_History_Than_The_Default">Store More SQL Agent Job History Than The Default</a> and <a href="http://wiki.lessthandot.com/index.php/How_to_prevent_a_trigger_from_firing_when_doing_an_insert_into_a_table_in_SQL_Server">How to prevent a trigger from firing when doing an insert into a table in SQL Server</a><br />
I was also active in the forums on this site and also on StackOverflow, my stats can be found here: http://stackoverflow.com/users/740/sqlmenace</p>
<p>
<h2>Watch more television</h2>
<p>I did watch more television this year. I watched the following series<br />
Spartacus<br />
True Blood<br />
Dexter<br />
Californication<br />
The Event (even though some people did not recommend it)<br />
<span class="MT_smaller"><span class="MT_smaller">Big Brother</span></span> (Who put that here?)<br />
Boardwalk Empire</p>
<p>My favorite show is probably Boardwalk Empire</p>
<p>
<h2>Play more computer games</h2>
<p>Here I failed miserably..pretty much the only game I played this year was Angry Birds on my wife&#8217;s Droid X<br />
<br />
So that is what I accomplished, I will put up my 2011 goals by January 3rd<br />
<br />
So now it is time to tag some people to see how they did with their goals. I am tagging <a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=68">Ted Krueger</a>, <a href="http://www.brentozar.com/">Brent Ozar</a>, <a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/aaron_bertrand/default.aspx">Aaron Bertrand</a> and you the reader of this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/review-of-my-2010-goals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2010 Goals for Eli (Tarwn)</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/2010-goals-for-eli-tarwn/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/2010-goals-for-eli-tarwn/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 20:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/01/2010-goals-for-eli-tarwn/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was recently tagged to share my 2010 Goals by Ted (blog &#124; Twitter) in his 2010 goals post. I want to thank him for that, as I believed I had a good long term goal until I went to write down my goals for this year and realized that all I had was a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was recently tagged to share my 2010 Goals by Ted (<a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=68" title="Posts by Ted">blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/onpnt" title="Ted's Tweets">Twitter</a>) in <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/goals-for-2010" title="Go check it out">his 2010 goals post</a>. I want to thank him for that, as I believed I had a good long term goal until I went to write down my goals for this year and realized that all I had was a vision without a plan. The initial act of thinking up a career goal is difficult, and after I completed that goal I fell into the trap that so many businesses do: I forgot to communicate and build plans for that vision. A well communicated vision allows everyone in a company to start facing the same general direction, but only provides a direction to wander towards, not a driving force or well-planned route. I believe there is a similarity with career goals, having only a vision means I will consider opportunities that come to me in light of my future goals, while a plan forces me to build or seek opportunities that will help me achieve my goal instead of relying on chance opportunities.</p>
<p>What this all means is that I am once again using solutions from one problem space (business) and applying them to another (my goals).</p>
<h2>Vision</h2>
<p>	To become responsible for a diverse set of business and technology challenges that will require me to develop and implement strategic solutions while continuing to execute or drive improvement at the operational level.</p>
<p>	 I believe the common career paths that would allow me to reach this vision are the Executive IT and Enterprise Architect career paths, though having concisely worded my vision I now have the ability to go see what other options would satisfy it.</p>
<h2>Strategic Goals for 2010</h2>
<p>	I&#8217;m not going to come up with a plan on a Sunday morning while typing a blog article, and randomly creating strategic goals does not help me any more than it did the dozens of companies that have gone out of business recently. Instead I am going to focus on building the steps I need to better understand my vision, my current state, and some potential strategic goals that would help me achieve that clearer state from where I am now. In short, I am going to build the plan I should have built but haven&#8217;t.</p>
<h3>2010 Strategic Goals: Analysis and Planning</h3>
<dl>
<dt>Current State Analysis</dt>
<dd>Just as I have done in business situations, determine the current state of my career, skills and experiences</dd>
<dt>Revise Vision</dt>
<dd>Go through a process of brainstorming, then refine the results back down to a single sentence to create a revised and more accurate vision</dd>
<dt>Research and Plan</dt>
<dd>I am not the first person that has decided to go down this career route, add a few items to my reading list on the careers of others and on career paths in general</dd>
</dl>
<p>	By accomplishing these goals I feel that I will be making a major step towards my long term goals and towards creating the next set of strategic steps necessary to reach those goals.</p>
<h2>Process Changes for 2010</h2>
<p>	An article I read recently describes the importance of staying &#8220;tech savvy&#8221; as an IT Executive (<a href="http://www.peterkretzman.com/2009/11/09/keeping-a-semblance-of-staying-tech-savvy-as-a-cio/">Fits and starts: staying “tech savvy” as a CIO</a> by <a href="http://www.peterkretzman.com/about-peter-kretzman/">Peter Kretzman</a>). I believe this carries further than the IT executive role and really includes any technology role in an organization. Technology is a major business driver and, if your role is to communicate or provide technology solutions, than staying up to date on technology is critical. I also believe that the concepts of Process Improvement, Business Analysis and Business Architecture are important to achieving and executing my goals. My current position has a much narrower scope and area of responsibility (for the moment, at least) than prior positions, allowing me to focus on career and life goals, but I cannot allow myself to stop practicing skills that were once part of my day-to-day environment.</p>
<p>	Areas of focus: Business and Enterprise Architecture, Lean and Process Improvement, Business Analysis, IT Management, Management and Leadership<br />
	Read 15-30 blog technical or focus articles weekly<br />
	Read 6 in-depth books on technology, architecture, lean, or other similarly useful topics<br />
	Re-Read 6 previously purchased books from above</p>
<h2>Measurement</h2>
<p>	The last part is the hardest to consider. If I build some measurements around the items above, then I will know if I am achieving them or how well I am achieving them. And the lazy, procrastinator part of me dislikes the idea of actually having to follow through on some sort of regular scheduled task. With a business or software solution I would be among the first driving to put some measurements or a visual process in place, so my immediate goal for this week is to find a method to track the articles and books I read against my process goals above, and build more defined and measurable goals for the strategic items.</p>
<h2>Outgoing Challenges</h2>
<p>I am going to challenge Alex (<a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=5" title="Alex's posts">blog | <a href="http://twitter.com/AlexCuse" title="Alex's Tweets">Twitter</a>) and Remou (<a href="/index.php/All/?disp=authdir&amp;author=11" title="See Remou's Posts">blog</a>) to follow back up with their 2010 goals. I expect to see plans for doctorates and MS Access world domination, so hopefully they won&#8217;t let us down.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/2010-goals-for-eli-tarwn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2010 Goals For SQLDenis</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/goals-for-2010-for-sqldenis/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/goals-for-2010-for-sqldenis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 17:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/01/goals-for-2010-for-sqldenis/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was tagged by onpnt in his 2010 Goals post. So here is my short list of goals that I would like to accomplish in 2010 Upgrade our servers to SQL Server 2008 This is an easy one since it already happened this week. We went to new machines from machines that were 6 years [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was tagged by <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/what-was-your-first-computer-and-what-we">onpnt</a> in his <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/goals-for-2010">2010 Goals</a> post. So here is my short list of goals that I would like to accomplish in 2010</p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/logo-header-sql08-dg.gif" alt="Upgrade our servers to SQL Server 2008" title="Upgrade our servers to SQL Server 2008" width="363" height="75" /></div>
<h2>Upgrade our servers to SQL Server 2008</h2>
<p>This is an easy one since it already happened this week. We went to new machines from machines that were 6 years old. I now have 16 times more RAM than previously. Instead of 4 HT CPUs I now have 8 CPUs and finally I am no longer on SQL Server 2000 at all. I really am glad that we upgraded; now I can use built in partitioned functions instead of the partitioned views I had to create to made that old box perform as well as it did. There is a ton of other stuff that we utilize now, here is just a tip of the iceberg: mirroring, date datatype, compression.</p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3121/3167236184_4c5385c657_m.jpg" alt="Read 2 books per month" title="Read 2 books per month" /></div>
<h2>Read 2 books per month</h2>
<p>There was a time when I commuted to NYC from Princeton and would read between 50 and 60 books per year. Now that my commute is mostly walking I don’t read that much, I like to increase that. So far I already have finished one book, this book is called Deamon and I already blogged about it here: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/daemon-by-daniel-suarez-is-a-book-every">Daemon by Daniel Suarez is a book every programmer will love</a><br />
One way to read more is by using audio books, this way you can listen at the gym, while you are walking around etc etc. Audio books are sometimes read by really good people. A couple of audio books I really enjoyed are: Angels and Demons, Digital Fortress, and Daemon. Audio books really add another dimension to an already interesting book. For example those creepy synthetic voices in Daemon really bring the book to life. Some of the books that are on my list for this year are below.</p>
<p>Stephen King: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1416586652?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1416586652">Just After Sunset</a><br />
Christiane F: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0553208977?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0553208977">Wir Kinder vom Bahnhof Zoo</a> (I have this book in Croatian)<br />
Dan Brown: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0009SS00A?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0009SS00A">Digital Fortress</a> (I have the Dutch version titled Het Juvenalis Dilemma)<br />
Michael Pollan: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143038583?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0143038583">The Omnivore&#8217;s Dilemma: A Natural History of Four Meals</a><br />
Roy Osherove: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1933988274?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1933988274">The Art of Unit Testing</a><br />
David Allen: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142000280?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0142000280">Getting Things Done</a><br />
Daniel Suarez: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0525951571?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0525951571">Freedom</a><br />
Lou Schuler/Alwyn Cosgrove: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1583332383?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1583332383">New Rules of Lifting</a></p>
<p>Since it is only January I am sure that some SQL Server 2008 R2 Analysis books that deal with PowerPivot will be added to this list. Also after Visual Studio 2010 comes up I will pick up some C# 4.0 and .NET 4.0 books</p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3143/2595051813_c4bba49555_m.jpg" alt="Be more active in the SQL community" title="Be more active in the SQL community" /></div>
<h2>Be more active in the SQL community</h2>
<p>I am pretty active with blogging and on twitter but I took somewhat a hiatus in regards to answering questions in newsgroups forums/fora. This will change; starting next week I will pick up the slack again. I will also commit to writing 2 blog posts per week. Right now I have 247 blog posts on this site; it should be at 350 by the end of this year.</p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/50/116136642_1a928c013a_m.jpg" alt="Watch more television" title="Watch more television" /></div>
<h2>Watch more television</h2>
<p>For some people this might seem strange because they would probably want to decrease the amount of television that they watch. I really watch maybe 2 or 3 hours of television a week and even then it is just mostly flipping channels. The show I watch most is House hunters International on HGTV. Just to show you how little television  I watch, here is a list of show I have never even seen one episode of<br />
Simpsons, Family guy, Lost, CSI (any flavor), Seinfeld, Baywatch, X files, 24, Frazier and this list goes on and on.<br />
When I do watch shows it is mostly on HBO or Showtime, I love Sopranos, Oz, True Blood, Dexter, Californication…basically shows that run for 13 weeks and that don’t skip 2 months like for example Jericho. Jericho was of course the one network show I truly like and it was cancelled.</p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/103/300654059_1e473fcb1e_m.jpg" alt="Play more computer games" title="Play more computer games" /></div>
<h2>Play more computer games</h2>
<p>There was a time when I played games on the computer at least a couple of day a week, this is when I had my Commodore 128 in the 1980s, I blogged about that here: <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/what-was-your-first-computer-and-what-we">What was your first computer and what were some of your favorite games? </a><br />
These days I think the games are too complicated or you need to spend several hours just to learn how to play this game. I like my games to be simple..I have a weapon..you move ..I shoot. Games should be to relax not a commitment, if you don&#8217;t play for a week suddenly a whole bunch of people have higher levels than you in WoW.</p>
<p>So that is it&#8230;nothing major really&#8230;I decided not to tag anyone since it is already practically the middle of January.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/goals-for-2010-for-sqldenis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daemon by Daniel Suarez is a book every programmer will love</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/daemon-by-daniel-suarez-is-a-book-every/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/daemon-by-daniel-suarez-is-a-book-every/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/01/daemon-by-daniel-suarez-is-a-book-every/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was tagged by onpnt in his Goals for 2010 post. One of my resolutions goals of this year is to read more books. Right now I am in the middle of reading Daemon by Daniel Suarez.

According to his bio Daniel Suarez is an independent systems consultant&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/da.jpg" alt="" title="" width="150" height="227" /> I was tagged by <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/?disp=authdir&amp;author=68">onpnt</a> in his <a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/goals-for-2010">Goals for 2010</a> post. One of my <del>resolutions</del> goals of this year is to read more books. Right now I am in the middle of reading <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0451228731?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0451228731">Daemon</a> by Daniel Suarez.</p>
<p>According to his bio Daniel Suarez is an independent systems consultant to Fortune 1000 companies. He has designed and developed enterprise software for the defense, finance, and entertainment industries. An avid gamer and technologist. </p>
<p>You can tell that this book was actually written by a person who worked as a programmer, it wasn&#8217;t just written by someone who did some research about technology. Interestingly Daemon was originally self-published in 2006 under the name Leinad Zeraus. </p>
<p>Here is in short what the book is about: Gaming genius Matthew Sobol, the 34-year-old head of CyberStorm Entertainment, has just died of brain cancer, but death doesn&#8217;t stop him from initiating an all-out Internet war against humanity. When the authorities investigate Sobol&#8217;s mansion in Thousand Oaks, Calif., they find themselves under attack from his empty house, aided by an unmanned Hummer that tears into the cops with staggering ferocity. Sobol&#8217;s weapon is a daemon, a kind of computer process that not only has taken over many of the world&#8217;s computer systems but also enlists the help of superintelligent human henchmen willing to carry out his diabolical plan.</p>
<p>I only read about half of the book and I can already recommend it to all our readers here; if you like technology you will love this book. If you like to read Michael Crichton books then you will love this even more because this book goes into so much more detail than Crichton ever did. The characters are more complex and real and the storyline is much richer. If you have read Dan Brown&#8217;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0312944926?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0312944926">Digital Fortress</a> then you will like this also better. Digital Fortress is a book I actually liked but it has some horrible reviews and the ending was really weak in my humble opinion.</p>
<p>Daniel Suarez has signed a deal with DreamWorks for the film rights, hopefully the movie will be as good as the book.</p>
<p>The first 7 chapters of Daemon are available here: http://thedaemon.com/daemonpreview.html</p>
<p>A interesting talk by the author is available here:  <a href="http://fora.tv/2008/08/08/Daniel_Suarez_Daemon_Bot-Mediated_Reality">Daniel Suarez &#8211; Daemon: Bot-Mediated Reality</a></p>
<p>Wired Magazine also has a nice article &#8211; <a href="http://www.wired.com/culture/culturereviews/magazine/16-05/pl_print">How Debut Daemon Earned Serious Geek Cred</a></p>
<p>The follow-up to Daemon titled Freedom has also just been published, you can find that book here: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0525951571?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0525951571">Freedom</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/daemon-by-daniel-suarez-is-a-book-every/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
