<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mysql &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/mysql-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL Injection Pocket Reference for MySQL, SQL Server and Oracle</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-injection-pocket-reference-for/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-injection-pocket-reference-for/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 08:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MySQL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MySQL Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oracle Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql injection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/07/sql-injection-pocket-reference-for/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a nice SQL Injection Pocket Reference up on Google Docs

Here is what is covered

MySQL
Default Databases
Comment Out Query
Testing Injection
Strings
Numeric
In a login
Testing Version
MySQL-specific code
Database Credentials
Data&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is a nice <a href="https://docs.google.com/Doc?docid=0AZNlBave77hiZGNjanptbV84Z25yaHJmMjk&amp;pli=1#Allowed_Intermediary_Character_30801873723976314">SQL Injection Pocket Reference</a> up on Google Docs</p>
<p>Here is what is covered</p>
<p><strong>MySQL</strong><br />
Default Databases<br />
Comment Out Query<br />
Testing Injection<br />
Strings<br />
Numeric<br />
In a login<br />
Testing Version<br />
MySQL-specific code<br />
Database Credentials<br />
Database Names<br />
Tables &amp; Columns<br />
Finding out number of columns<br />
Retrieving Tables<br />
Retrieving Columns<br />
PROCEDURE ANALYSE()<br />
Retrieving Multiple Tables/Columns at once<br />
Find Tables from Column Name<br />
Find Column From Table Name<br />
Avoiding the use of single/double quotations<br />
String concatenation<br />
Privileges<br />
FILE privilege<br />
MySQL 4/5<br />
MySQL 5<br />
Out Of Band Channeling<br />
Timing<br />
DNS (requires FILE privilege)<br />
SMB (requires FILE privilege)<br />
Reading Files (requires FILE privilege)<br />
Writing Files (requires FILE privilege)<br />
Stacked Queries with PDO<br />
User Defined Functions<br />
Fuzzing and Obfuscation<br />
Allowed Intermediary Characters<br />
Allowed Intermediary Characters after AND/OR<br />
Operators<br />
Constants<br />
MySQL Functions()<br />
MySQL Password Hashing<br />
MySQL Password() Cracker</p>
<p><strong>MSSQL</strong><br />
Default Databases<br />
Comment Out Query<br />
Testing Version<br />
Database Credentials<br />
Database Server Hostname<br />
Database Names<br />
Tables &amp; Columns<br />
Retrieving Tables<br />
Retrieving Columns<br />
Retrieving Multiple Tables/Columns at once<br />
OPENROWSET Attacks<br />
System Command Execution<br />
SP_PASSWORD (Hiding Query)<br />
Stacked Queries<br />
Fuzzing and Obfuscation<br />
Encodings<br />
Allowed Intermediary Characters<br />
Allowed Intermediary Characters after AND/OR<br />
MSSQL Password Hashing<br />
MSSQL Password Cracker</p>
<p><strong>ORACLE</strong><br />
Default Databases<br />
Comment Out Query<br />
Testing Version<br />
Database Credentials<br />
Database Names<br />
Current Database<br />
User Databases<br />
Tables &amp; Columns<br />
Retrieving Tables<br />
Retrieving Columns<br />
Finding Tables from Column Name<br />
Finding Column From Table Name<br />
Fuzzing and Obfuscation<br />
Avoiding the use of single/double quotations<br />
Out Of Band Channeling<br />
Time Delay<br />
Heavy Query Time delays</p>
<p>You can find it here: <a href="https://docs.google.com/Doc?docid=0AZNlBave77hiZGNjanptbV84Z25yaHJmMjk&amp;pli=1#Allowed_Intermediary_Character_30801873723976314">SQL Injection Pocket Reference</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/sql-injection-pocket-reference-for/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Announces SQL Server Migration Assistant for MySQL</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/microsoft-announces-sql-server-migration/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/microsoft-announces-sql-server-migration/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MySQL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MySQL Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/01/microsoft-announces-sql-server-migration/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is just a quick post letting you know that Microsoft has announced the SQL Server Migration Assistant for MySQL This tool is available for download now. 

Microsoft SQL Server Migration Assistant (SSMA) 2008 is a toolkit that dramatically cuts th&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is just a quick post letting you know that Microsoft has announced the SQL Server Migration Assistant for MySQL This tool is available for download now. </p>
<p>Microsoft SQL Server Migration Assistant (SSMA) 2008 is a toolkit that dramatically cuts the effort, cost, and risk of migrating from MySQL to SQL Server 2008 and SQL Azure. SSMA 2008 for MySQL v1.0 CTP1 provides an assessment of migration efforts as well as automates schema and data migration.</p>
<p><strong>Supported Operating Systems: </strong><br />
Windows 7; Windows Server 2003; Windows Server 2008; Windows Server 2008 R2; Windows Vista; Windows XP<br />
SSMA 2008 for MySQL v1.0 CTP1 is designed to work with MySQL 4.1, 5.0 and 5.1 and all editions of SQL Server 2008 or SQL Azure.</p>
<p><strong>Requirements for the SSMA for MySQL client: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft Windows Installer 3.1 or a later version </li>
<li>The Microsoft .NET Framework version 2.0 or a later version. The .NET Framework version 2.0 is available on the SQL Server 2008 product media. You can also obtain it from the .NET Framework Developer Center. </li>
<li>MySQL Connector/ODBC v5.1.</li>
<li>Access to and sufficient permissions on the computer that hosts the target instance of SQL Server 2008 or SQL Azure database.</li>
<li>1 GB RAM.</li>
<p>You can download the SQL Server Migration Assistant for MySQL here: http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/en/details.aspx?FamilyID=69739c8c-ac82-41de-b9e6-8fa5ae2594d9&amp;displaylang=en</ul>
<p>*** <strong>Remember, if you have a SQL related question try our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=17">Microsoft SQL Server Programming</a> forum or our <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=22">Microsoft SQL Server Admin</a> forum</strong><ins></ins></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/microsoft-announces-sql-server-migration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oracle Details Its Plans For MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice And Open Source</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 09:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Java EE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glassfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netbeans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openoffice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtualization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/10/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oracle has updated the Sun Acquisition FAQ. The FAQ now has Oracle's plans for MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice, Open Source and other things.

Below are the relevant pieces from that document.

What are Oracle’s plans fo&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oracle has updated the <a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/sun/038563.pdf">Sun Acquisition FAQ</a>. The FAQ now has Oracle&#8217;s plans for MySQL, Java, Virtualization, NetBeans, Glassfish, OpenOffice, Open Source and other things.</p>
<p>Below are the relevant pieces from that document.</p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for the GlassFish Enterprise (Java<br />
EE) Server after the transaction closes?</strong><br />
Oracle plans to continue evolving GlassFish Enterprise Server, delivering<br />
it as the open source reference implementation (RI) of the Java Enterprise<br />
Edition (Java EE) specifications, and actively supporting the large GlassFish<br />
community.  Additionally, Oracle plans to invest in aligning common<br />
infrastructure components and innovations from Oracle WebLogic Server<br />
and GlassFish Enterprise Server to benefit both Oracle WebLogic Server and<br />
GlassFish Enterprise Server customers.</p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for NetBeans?</strong><br />
Oracle has a strong track record of demonstrating commitment to choice for<br />
Java developers. As such, NetBeans is expected to provide an additional open<br />
source option and complement to the two free tools Oracle already offers for<br />
enterprise Java development: Oracle JDeveloper and Oracle Enterprise Pack for<br />
Eclipse. While Oracle JDeveloper remains Oracle’s strategic development tool<br />
for the broad portfolio of Oracle Fusion Middleware products and for Oracle’s<br />
next generation of enterprise applications, developers will be able to use<br />
whichever free tool they are most comfortable with for pure Java and Java EE<br />
development:  JDeveloper, Enterprise Pack for Eclipse, or NetBeans. </p>
<p><strong>What are Oracle’s plans for MySQL?</strong><br />
Oracle plans to spend more money developing MySQL than Sun does now.<br />
Oracle expects to continue to develop and provide the open source MySQL<br />
database after the transaction closes. Oracle plans to add MySQL to Oracle’s<br />
existing suite of database products, which already includes Berkeley DB, an<br />
open source database. Oracle also currently offers InnoDB, an open source<br />
transactional storage engine and the most important and popular transaction<br />
engine under MySQL. Oracle already distributes MySQL as part of our<br />
Enterprise Linux offering.</p>
<p><strong>What is Oracle’s plan for OpenOffice?</strong><br />
Oracle has a history of developing complete, integrated, and open products,<br />
making integration quicker and less costly for our customers. Based on the<br />
open ODF standard, OpenOffice is expected to create a compelling desktop<br />
integration bridge for our enterprise customers and offers consumers another<br />
choice on the desktop. After the transaction closes, Oracle plans to continue<br />
developing and supporting OpenOffice as open source. As before, some of<br />
the larger customers will ask for extra assurances, support, and enterprise<br />
tools. For these customers we expect to offer a typical commercial license<br />
option.</p>
<p><strong>How does Oracle support open source?</strong><br />
Oracle has long been committed to developing, supporting, and promoting<br />
open source. Oracle has been, and continues to be, committed to offering<br />
choice, flexibility, and a lower cost of computing for end users. Oracle<br />
has invested significant resources in developing, testing, optimizing and<br />
supporting open source technologies such as Linux, PHP, Apache, Eclipse,<br />
Berkeley DB, and InnoDB. Oracle continues to embrace and offer open source<br />
solutions as a viable choice for development and deployment. More information<br />
about Oracle’s support of open source can be found at<br />
oracle.com/opensource. </p>
<p><strong>Will Oracle continue Sun’s virtualization strategy?</strong><br />
Yes, Oracle plans to continue Sun’s “desktop to datacenter virtualization”<br />
strategy and integrate with Oracle’s virtualization products. By unifying<br />
management across desktop virtualization, server virtualization, storage<br />
virtualization, and network virtualization, Oracle and Sun provide<br />
comprehensive, flexible, eco-efficient solutions to maximize utilization,<br />
consolidate to reduce costs, increase productivity, and decrease management<br />
complexity. We expect to continue Sun’s desktop virtualization products:<br />
VDI, Secure Global Desktop, Sun Ray, and VirtualBox.</p>
<p><strong>Delivering increased investment and innovation in Java</strong><br />
Oracle plans to accelerate investment in the Java platform for the<br />
benefit of customers and the Java community. Java is one of the<br />
computer industry’s best-known brands and the Java platform is<br />
one of the industry’s most widely deployed technologies. Oracle has<br />
been a leader in the Java community since the inception of the Java<br />
programming language and already has the world’s largest investment<br />
in the Java platform, which provides the foundation for its Oracle<br />
Fusion Middleware products and its next-generation enterprise<br />
applications.<br />
Oracle plans to not only broaden and accelerate its own investment in the<br />
Java platform, but also plans to increase the commitment to the community<br />
that helps make Java an ubiquitous, innovative platform unified around<br />
open standards. </p>
<p>So what do you think, is there still a reason to fear what will happen to these technologies after this deal closes?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/jee/oracle-details-its-plans-for-mysql-java/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Interview With Kevin Kline About SQL In A Nutshell Third Edition</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/an-interview-with-kevin-kline-about-sql/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/an-interview-with-kevin-kline-about-sql/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 12:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MySQL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postgresql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/an-interview-with-kevin-kline-about-sql/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Most of the database developers these days don&#8217;t work with just one RDBMS, a large percentage will work with at least two of them. SQL In A Nutshell will help you with that, no longer do you have the need for two or more books open at the same time. I asked Kevin Kline if [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most of the database developers these days don&#8217;t work with just one RDBMS, a large percentage will work with at least two of them. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596518846?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0596518846">SQL In A Nutshell</a> will help you with that, no longer do you have the need for two or more books open at the same time. I asked Kevin Kline if he would be interested in an interview and as you can see he said yes.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Is the book geared towards a beginner/intermediate level user or do you have to be an advanced user to really utilize the information in this book?</strong></p>
<p>KK> This book is more of an intermediate + book, since it is a syntax reference.  For example, the book assumes you know what command you want to look up and doesn&#8217;t spend a lot of time educating you as to which command you should use for a given business requirement, as is the case with most O&#8217;Reilly books from the &#8220;In a Nutshell&#8221; series.  For beginning SQL, I recommend &#8220;Learning SQL&#8221; also published by O&#8217;Reilly &amp; Associates.</p>
<p><strong>Denis:  What are the most important things a person can do to master SQL?</strong></p>
<p>KK> Practice!  You simply cannot expect to master SQL, or any programming language for that matter, without doing a lot of it.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: What part of SQL do people struggle the most with?</strong></p>
<p>KK> There are a couple areas that tend to be programmatic for those who are new to SQL.  But I&#8217;d say that the biggest area of struggle, far and away, is getting used to Set Theory.  Set theory governs how data is managed in large sets of records.  It&#8217;s the way that relational databases manipulate data, but most people especially those who&#8217;ve programmed in other popular languages are used to thinking about data one row at a time.  This lead to performance problems.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Between the second edition and the third edition of your book, from a pure SQL standpoint which RDBMS has added the most features?</strong></p>
<p>KK> If I&#8217;m measuring the most progress against the ANSI standard, I&#8217;d have to say that MySQL has added the most new SQL features.  On the other hand, MySQL started from a deficit, meaning that in early editions of my book, MySQL didn&#8217;t meet the ANSI standard for many commands and functions.  So just by complying with the ANSI standard in their latest release, they&#8217;ve added the most new features.  If I&#8217;m measuring by the most new features regardless of the ANSI standard, I&#8217;d have to say that Microsoft SQL Server has made the most progress with their many new data types and commands.  By comparison, Oracle tends to add new features via add-on products outside of the main relational engine which you must buy separately, while SQL Server adds them at no added charge right in the box.  An example of this might include the spatial data type, in the box with SQL Server, but a separate bolt-on with Oracle.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: From each RDBMS covered in your book can you name your favorite feature which is unique to that RDBMS?</strong></p>
<p>KK> I cover fewer database in the 3rd edition than in the 2nd edition since few readers expressed an interest in continuing coverage of IBM&#8217;s DB2 UDB or Sybase&#8217;s Adaptive Server.  Having said that, we still cover the ANSI standard plus the four most popular database &#8211; Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, and PostgreSQL.  For Oracle, I love the incredibly powerful MODEL statement and the DECODE function.  They rock!  For SQL Server, I enjoy the PIVOT and UNPIVOT statements and its XML handling features.  MySQL has a very nifty capability of utilizing several different transaction processing engines, such as InnoDB and MyISAM, some of which focus on raw processing power by dispensing with the niceties.  And I really, really like PostgreSQL unwaivering support of the ANSI standard in all of their SQL statements.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Should people write pure ANSI SQL or are there times when it is okay to write proprietary SQL?</strong></p>
<p>KK> I&#8217;m a big believer in going for performance, and that means writing proprietary code.  Most internal IT shops should usually go with the proprietary code since the application will be for an internal customer who will run the application on only one database platform.  On the other hand, most ISV&#8217;s write their database applications for multiple database platforms to support the widest possible customer base and, invariably, these applications are always performance wastelands.  ANSI SQL is the place to get your fundamental schooling from, but in my opinion, it should not be the destination to take your application to.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Is there a large percentage of people who work with more than one RDBMS at the same time?</strong></p>
<p>KK> We&#8217;d seen a long time span from the late 1990&#8217;s til late in this decade where most database professionals focused on only one database.  However, something that has happened in the last two years is a major upsurge in corporate mergers and acquisitions.  As a result, many more people are being asked to take on a database platform outside of their comfort zone.  I&#8217;d say that the percentages have shifted from about 15% of multi-platform enterprise DBAs a few years ago to as much as 25% today.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: What SQL books are on your bookshelf?</strong></p>
<p>KK> I still keep a copy of SQL99: Complete &#8211; Really! as well as the ANSI 2006 SQL standard.  I have Celco&#8217;s SQL for Smarties, Feuerstein&#8217;s PL/SQL Programming, and Ben-Gan&#8217;s Inside Transact-SQL Programming and Inside Transact-SQL Queries.  In addition, I&#8217;ll always keep a copy of my late friend Ken Henderson&#8217;s The Guru&#8217;s Guide to Transact-SQL for sentimental reasons.  I also have general database books about all the database platforms.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Why do you write technical books?</strong></p>
<p>KK> It started out with a bit of an ironic twist.  When I wrote my first book in the early 1990&#8217;s, I was planning on completing a master&#8217;s degree with a thesis.  I pitched the thesis abstract to a book publishing company and was surprised when the accepted it.  And the simple truth is that I always wanted to write and enjoy writing.  That&#8217;s why I still do it today.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Which chapter was the hardest to write and can you explain why?</strong></p>
<p>KK> There&#8217;s no doubt that the section of SQL in a Nutshell that covers ALTER, CREATE, and DROP statements was the most difficult.  And I fully blame Oracle for this.  Here&#8217;s an example derived from the vendor documentation.  The CREATE TABLE statement for MySQL and PostgreSQL runs to about 25 pages each.  The same statement has more variations on Microsoft SQL Server and so runs to about 55 pages in their documentation.  But on Oracle, the CREATE TABLE statement runs well over 160 pages with more variation, permutations, and sub-permutations than is imaginable.  No offense to the vendors here, but there is such a thing as overloading a statement or function with too much weight.  So you can imagine how much time and energy it took to distill these statements down to a digestable size!</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Who are your favorite authors?</strong></p>
<p>KK> In the database world, my two favorite authors are Kalen Delaney of Inside SQL Server fame and Steven Feuerstein, author of PL/SQL Programming and many other excellent Oracle books and a fine blog as well.  Outside of the database world, I&#8217;m a voracious reader on all topics, both fiction and non-fiction.  However, I will always read anything put out by two non-fiction writers &#8211; Jared Diamond, author of Guns, Germs and Steel, and Michael Pollan, author of The Omnivore&#8217;s Delimma.</p>
<p><strong>Denis: Where can we expect to see you in 2009? Any conferences, seminars, trade shows or classrooms perhaps?</strong></p>
<p>KK> It&#8217;s no secret that the economy has taken a downturn.  So it&#8217;s almost a certainty that I&#8217;ll speak at fewer local user groups this year than in years past.  However, I&#8217;m sure to be at TechEd this May and at the PASS 2009 Summit in Seattle this fall.  I hope to see you there!</p>
<p>Thanks goes out to Kevin Kline for doing the interview, here is some info on the book and I also provided an Amazon link, make sure to check it out</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596518846?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0596518846">SQL in a Nutshell, Third Edition A Desktop Quick Reference Guide</a><br />
By Kevin Kline, Daniel Kline, Brand Hunt<br />
Published: November 2008<br />
Pages: 591<br />
Series: In a Nutshell</p>
<p>Description<br />
The essential reference to the SQL language used in today&#8217;s most popular database products, this new edition of SQL in a Nutshell clearly documents every SQL command according to the latest ANSI standard. It also details how these commands are implemented in the Microsoft SQL Server 2008 and Oracle 11g commercial database packages, and the MySQL 5.1 and PostgreSQL 8.3 open source database products.</p>
<p>If you are interested in Kevin Kline&#8217;s blog, you can find that here: http://sqlblog.com/blogs/kevin_kline/default.aspx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/an-interview-with-kevin-kline-about-sql/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>CentOS, Postfix, MySQL and a Typo</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/linux/centos-postfix-mysql-and-a-typo/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/linux/centos-postfix-mysql-and-a-typo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 20:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[damber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RHEL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[centos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mail server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postfix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[typo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/centos-postfix-mysql-and-a-typo/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A little lesson in typo-trauma Today I finally got round to doing some admin on my primary home server, which (amongst many things) is my main mail server. After dusting a few cobwebs away, checking nobody had broken any of the furniture and such, I decided to run yum to get the latest updates (it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>A little lesson in typo-trauma</h1>
<p>Today I finally got round to doing some admin on my primary home server, which (amongst many things) is my main mail server.  After dusting a few cobwebs away, checking nobody had broken any of the furniture and such, I decided to run yum to get the latest updates (it had been almost a month since the last time I checked 88| but still, at least now it was about to be updated to all the shiny sparkly new things that CentOS had released for me&#8230;</p>
<p>And it did, it came up with about 5 or 6 updates, including an update to postfix. Great.  So, it finished in about a minute or two and I went on about my evening.  All was happy in the land of the ignorant.</p>
<p>Ignorant, that is, until I decided to send an email to my dear old mum to give her an update on the list of laptops I was recommending for her (I know, I&#8217;m so thoughtful :D).  At which point my squirrelmail (webmail) froze.. you see, I&#8217;m currently re-decorating my study, so have moved my main workstation into another room, and as such it&#8217;s not in use.. and my other non-work laptop is, er, recovering from, er, how do you say it? A little &#8216;rinse&#8217; in the bath&#8230; so, work laptop it is, and webmail access only&#8230; </p>
<p>I thought maybe it was my damn windows wifi connection at first because it has been such a problem the last few days.. (I can&#8217;t wait to get back to my linux environments, this windows only stuff is giving me a serious heart condition.)  Anyway, after a prod and a poke it seemed that it might be the mail server&#8230;</p>
<h2>Determining the problem</h2>
<p>So, I checked the mail server logs and discovered&#8230;</p>

<div class="bwp-syntax-block clearfix">
<div class="bwp-syntax-toolbar"><div class="bwp-syntax-control"><a href="javascript:;" class="bwp-syntax-source-switch" title="View Source Code"></a></div></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-wrapper clearfix bwp-syntax-simple"><table class="text"><thead><tr><td colspan="2"  class="head">Text</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="li1"><td class="ln"><pre class="de1">1
2
3
4
5
</pre></td><td class="de1"><pre class="de1">[root@phantom ~]# tail /var/log/maillog
...
...
phantom postfix/smtpd[8736]: fatal: unsupported dictionary type: mysql
...</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-source"><pre class="no-parse">[root@phantom ~]# tail /var/log/maillog
...
...
phantom postfix/smtpd[8736]: fatal: unsupported dictionary type: mysql
...</pre></div></div>

<p>mmmm&#8230; now, that looks familiar.. wasn&#8217;t that a problem I faced when setting up this mail server?  The problem that centos repositories only provide the standard postfix rpm which doesn&#8217;t have mysql support compiled in?  But, it has been working for ages.. why is it failing now ?  Hold on.. let me check what exactly was updated again recently&#8230;</p>

<div class="bwp-syntax-block clearfix">
<div class="bwp-syntax-toolbar"><div class="bwp-syntax-control"><a href="javascript:;" class="bwp-syntax-source-switch" title="View Source Code"></a></div></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-wrapper clearfix bwp-syntax-simple"><table class="text"><thead><tr><td colspan="2"  class="head">Text</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="li1"><td class="ln"><pre class="de1">1
2
3
4
5
</pre></td><td class="de1"><pre class="de1">[root@phantom ~]# tail /var/log/yum.log
...
...
Updated: postfix - 2:2.3.3-2.1.el5_2.i386
...</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-source"><pre class="no-parse">[root@phantom ~]# tail /var/log/yum.log
...
...
Updated: postfix - 2:2.3.3-2.1.el5_2.i386
...</pre></div></div>

<p>Ahhhh&#8230; bugger.:'(</p>
<h2>Path of enlightenment</h2>
<p>OK&#8230; now I&#8217;m thinking that some stupid numpty has released the wrong rpm in the wrong repository, because I know that I set things up originally to exclude the main repositories for postfix updates and only get it from the centosplus repository. Of course I did. I&#8217;m sure. I think. mmmmm&#8230; ok, let me check&#8230;</p>

<div class="bwp-syntax-block clearfix">
<div class="bwp-syntax-toolbar"><div class="bwp-syntax-control"><a href="javascript:;" class="bwp-syntax-source-switch" title="View Source Code"></a></div></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-wrapper clearfix bwp-syntax-simple"><table class="text"><thead><tr><td colspan="2"  class="head">Text</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="li1"><td class="ln"><pre class="de1">1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
21
22
23
</pre></td><td class="de1"><pre class="de1">[root@phantom ~]# vi /etc/yum.repos.d/CentOS-Base.repo
...
...
#released updates
[updates]
name=CentOS-$releasever - Updates
mirrorlist=http://mirrorlist.centos.org/?release=$releasever&amp;amp;arch=$basearch&amp;amp;repo=updates
#baseurl=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/$releasever/updates/$basearch/
gpgcheck=1
gpgkey=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/RPM-GPG-KEY-CentOS-5
priority=1
exclude=kernel* posfix* &nbsp; &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;------looky at what we have here..
...
...
[centosplus]
name=CentOS-$releasever - Plus
mirrorlist=http://mirrorlist.centos.org/?release=$releasever&amp;amp;arch=$basearch&amp;amp;repo=centosplus
#baseurl=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/$releasever/centosplus/$basearch/
gpgcheck=1
enabled=1
gpgkey=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/RPM-GPG-KEY-CentOS-5
priority=2
includepkgs=kernel* postfix*</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-source"><pre class="no-parse">[root@phantom ~]# vi /etc/yum.repos.d/CentOS-Base.repo
...
...
#released updates
[updates]
name=CentOS-$releasever - Updates
mirrorlist=http://mirrorlist.centos.org/?release=$releasever&amp;amp;arch=$basearch&amp;amp;repo=updates
#baseurl=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/$releasever/updates/$basearch/
gpgcheck=1
gpgkey=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/RPM-GPG-KEY-CentOS-5
priority=1
exclude=kernel* posfix*   &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;------looky at what we have here..
...
...
[centosplus]
name=CentOS-$releasever - Plus
mirrorlist=http://mirrorlist.centos.org/?release=$releasever&amp;amp;arch=$basearch&amp;amp;repo=centosplus
#baseurl=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/$releasever/centosplus/$basearch/
gpgcheck=1
enabled=1
gpgkey=http://mirror.centos.org/centos/RPM-GPG-KEY-CentOS-5
priority=2
includepkgs=kernel* postfix*</pre></div></div>

<p>Ooops.  Can you spot it? :yes: Yep, exactly &#8211; every entry apart from the updates was excluding &#8220;postfix&#8221;, whilst the updates were excluding &#8220;posfix&#8221;.. :no: </p>
<h2>Fixing the shame..</h2>
<p>That, my friend, is the scourge of bugs everywhere.. the humble typo. ah well. Lesson learnt.. now just to download the previous centosplus package for postfix with mysql built in and re-install it (and fix that damn typo):</p>

<div class="bwp-syntax-block clearfix">
<div class="bwp-syntax-toolbar"><div class="bwp-syntax-control"><a href="javascript:;" class="bwp-syntax-source-switch" title="View Source Code"></a></div></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-wrapper clearfix bwp-syntax-simple"><table class="text"><thead><tr><td colspan="2"  class="head">Text</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="li1"><td class="ln"><pre class="de1">1
2
3
</pre></td><td class="de1"><pre class="de1">[root@phantom ~]# wget http://www.mirrorservice.org/sites/mirror.centos.org/5.2/centosplus/i386/RPMS/postfix-2.3.3-2.el5.centos.mysql_pgsql.i386.rpm
[root@phantom ~]# rpm -Uvh ----replacepkgs ----force postfix-2.3.3-2.el5.centos.mysql_pgsql.i386.rpm
[root@phantom ~]# sed -i 's/posfix/postfix/g' /etc/yum.repos.d/CentOS-Base.repo</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div>
<div class="bwp-syntax-source"><pre class="no-parse">[root@phantom ~]# wget http://www.mirrorservice.org/sites/mirror.centos.org/5.2/centosplus/i386/RPMS/postfix-2.3.3-2.el5.centos.mysql_pgsql.i386.rpm
[root@phantom ~]# rpm -Uvh ----replacepkgs ----force postfix-2.3.3-2.el5.centos.mysql_pgsql.i386.rpm
[root@phantom ~]# sed -i 's/posfix/postfix/g' /etc/yum.repos.d/CentOS-Base.repo</pre></div></div>

<p>phew&#8230; mail server back up and working again.  I thought for a brief second that it was going to be a major problem, but, thankfully, a download + install to rollback and a correction of a typo later.. and I&#8217;m back up and running <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />  A lesson in scrutiny of important configuration data has been learnt..:lalala: until the next time.. ;D</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/linux/centos-postfix-mysql-and-a-typo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
