<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tahir Khalid &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/author/kermit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Web API 2 &#8211; don&#8217;t get caught with your parameters down</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/web-api-2-dont-get-caught-with-your-parameters-down/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/web-api-2-dont-get-caught-with-your-parameters-down/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tahir Khalid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[ASP.NET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Server Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.net 4.5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web api 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4130</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, A quick post for anyone else who has been literally dying from a lack of sleep trying to workout something that should be fairly simple. Quick background:  I got interested in Web API after I decided to build a friend a simple booking website driven by HTML5, jquery and originally an ASP.NET/c# .NET 4 [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi,</p>
<p>A quick post for anyone else who has been literally dying from a lack of sleep trying to workout something that should be fairly simple.</p>
<p>Quick background:  I got interested in Web API after I decided to build a friend a simple booking website driven by HTML5, jquery and originally an ASP.NET/c# .NET 4 Web Service.  Having tested it out I came across a CORS related issue and being very impatient I just could not be bothered to work around it (and lets face it, if you have to do that with CORS its a hack in my book, it just doesn&#8217;t feel right in the dynamic world of Web API 2.x).</p>
<p>So I thought it was about time I looked at Web API proper and as 2.0 had recently surfaced it was a good a time as any to jump on board.</p>
<p>First things first I created a simple test app remembering my good friend Kevin&#8217;s advice to me: &#8220;keep that **** simple or I will come round and choke you out!&#8221; &#8211; no greater words spoken.  I followed this good tutorial to get me started: <a title="Getting Started with ASP.NET Web API 2 (C#)" href="http://www.asp.net/web-api/overview/getting-started-with-aspnet-web-api/tutorial-your-first-web-api" target="_blank"><span style="color: #000000">Getting Started with ASP.NET Web API 2 </span></a><span style="color: #898989"><a title="Getting Started with ASP.NET Web API 2 (C#)" href="http://www.asp.net/web-api/overview/getting-started-with-aspnet-web-api/tutorial-your-first-web-api" target="_blank">(C#)</a> </span>however what seems to be a common occurrence with me, shit just goes wrong!</p>
<p>So what gives? Well I kept getting the dreaded 404 error when I adapted the tutorial to my simple project which consists of the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>HTML page that has a $.getJSON block which calls the uri (for this simple test I did which was to call a parameter less method, well I tried)</li>
<li>Web API 2 project consisting of:
<ul>
<li>simple entity called TestMessage that has a couple of properties like name, messagetext</li>
<li>simple controller inheriting from ApiController and implementing an IHttpActionResult method called GetMessage()</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>So noting too fancy:</p>
<pre>    public class TestMessage
    {
        public string Name{ get; set; }
        public string MessageText { get; set; }
    }</pre>
<p>The controller class:</p>
<pre>public IHttpActionResult GetMessage()
{
   return Ok("{}");
}</pre>
<p>The little gotcha above btw is that you need a return JSON object or null otherwise you will get a failed response at the client side, not the least of my worries though as I was getting another 404 message:</p>
<p>&#8220;No matching action method found in the selected controller&#8221;</p>
<p>Awesome, just what I was expecting!  I thought okay simple enough just a mismatch somewhere but nope wasn&#8217;t anything I tried and I spent days scouring through Stack Overflow (and occasionally crying) and other online resources (part of the problem being I had no clue what my question was to begin with or rather the correct search terms, this came later after much much pain and vomiting).</p>
<p>Some bright spark suggested decorating the method but that completely breaks the new Web API pattern, just didn&#8217;t seem right and felt like a major hack again so I went back to trying to workout how and why I was getting this 404 issue.  I even tried changing my client side call from $.getJSON to the old school $.Ajax making a GET call but still failed until I eventually came across a great post that set me on the right track (but wasn&#8217;t quite the complete solution).</p>
<p>By the way at any point in your development hell you go through this, make sure you get a handle on how to debug Web API using resources like <a title="Get Firebug" href="http://getfirebug.com/" target="_blank">Firebug </a>(Chrome Debugger is good but the layout is too shitty for me and I hate Google anyway) and <a title="Fiddler" href="http://www.telerik.com/fiddler" target="_blank">Fiddler </a>(an awesome tool for composing JSON requests and tracking requests/responses for stuff like Web API).</p>
<p>First I came across this great article by a cool developer called Dave Ward (author of the Encosia website): &#8220;<a title="Using jQuery to POST [FromBody] parameters to Web API" href="http://encosia.com/using-jquery-to-post-frombody-parameters-to-web-api/" target="_blank">Using jQuery to POST [FromBody] parameters to Web API</a>&#8221; however when I followed the steps mentioned by Dave I was still getting some problems namely I was not able to post any kind of JSON data using the getJSON jquery method so what the hell was going on, again?!  Well the first part was resolved by using the [FromBody] as suggested by Dave but something else was still causing my request to turn to shit.</p>
<p><span style="color: #999999"><em>Disclaimer: Shit is a universal word used by developers and has a neutral meaning neither an offensive or defensive word but cool all the same!</em></span></p>
<p>Turns out the JSON data was being passed in as a string and therefore just being ignored and set to null and the solution lay here in this awesome Stack Overflow post: <a title="http://stackoverflow.com/a/29978090" href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/29978090" target="_blank">http://stackoverflow.com/a/29978090</a></p>
<p>Yep everything is awesome now so the second part of the solution was to set the type of the incoming parameter to that of my entity i.e. the TestMessage class I pasted earlier in this post and then in my getJSON jquery method I did something like this:</p>
<pre>        function SendMessage() {
            $.getJSON("http://localhost/api/message/getmessage, { "name": "kermit", 
                      "messagetext": "hello, LTD!" })

                .done(function (data) {
                    $('#message').text("OK");
                })
                .fail(function (jqXHR, textStatus, err) {
                    $('#message').text('Error: ' + err);
                });
        }</pre>
<p>And hey presto all sorted.   What we did here was to create a complex parameter using a JSON format which is then passed through to the controller action GetMessage.  I expanded on this by making my action more complex using the excellent <a title="Newtonsoft Json.Net" href="http://www.newtonsoft.com/json" target="_blank">Newtonsoft JSON library</a> to assist with deserialising the data, inflating an entity and then building up an email message to send out using the <a title="System.Net.Mail Namespace" href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.net.mail(v=vs.110).aspx" target="_blank">System.Net.Mail</a> namespace.</p>
<p>Well that worked for me and I hope it works for you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/web-api-2-dont-get-caught-with-your-parameters-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Windows 10, how I doth hateth thee mostest</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tahir Khalid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Professionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[System Admins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 8.1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[How&#8217;s it going folks, thought I&#8217;d get another post written up before I switch over to video logs in the future (watch this space). So I don&#8217;t really need to do a big introduction to Windows 10, there was a lot of buzz going about the internet not least due in part to the upgrade [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How&#8217;s it going folks, thought I&#8217;d get another post written up before I switch over to video logs in the future (watch this space).</p>
<p>So I don&#8217;t really need to do a big introduction to Windows 10, there was a lot of buzz going about the internet not least due in part to the upgrade icon that appeared in the notification tray (from Windows 7 to Windows 8.1) and like many people I became curious as to what exactly Windows 10 would mean to me and the rest of the world. I hadn&#8217;t looked at the beta and the RC releases that came out for Windows 10 even through they were available to developers about a year ago but this was mostly because I had made the jump from Windows 7 to Windows 8 (ouch) and then to Windows 8.1 Professional (easily the best version to date but more on this later).</p>
<p>I remember some of the early hype surrounding Windows 10 namely around the technology and what it would offer (the same sort of hype that appeared before Windows 7 was released to the wild) but the biggest one was how it would revolutionise the Windows desktop and make development more exciting with the introduction of dedicated tools for Universal App&#8217;s &#8211; great I thought this could be a step in the right direction. We had seen some of the buzz already with the announcement of ASP.NET 5 and related technologies such as .NET Core as well as releasing chunks of the code to the community via github (<a title="Announcing ASP.NET 5" href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/AnnouncingNET2015NETAsOpenSourceNETOnMacAndLinuxAndVisualStudioCommunity.aspx" target="_blank">ASP.NET 5</a>).  Along with this news we saw Visual Studio Community Edition and Visual Studio Code hinting at a future where we would not be tied down to a Windows desktop and could code on anything from Linux to OS X  &#8211; more cool stuff! So I bought into the hype and I reserved my copy and while I did not have a compelling reason to upgrade from a rock solid Windows 8.1 Professional platform (running on an HP Elitebook 8560w Mobile Workstation) I was hopeful that Windows 10 would build on the great work of Windows 8.1 (wishful thinking I know).</p>
<p>Before I hear &#8220;ah but Windows 8 was crap dude it was the Vista of this generation!&#8221;, yes true but Windows 8.1 for me was the saving grace, they got it right but due to some negligence or poor marketing most of the general public had no clue that Windows 8.1 was an entirely different product, better in a million ways (and most still don&#8217;t know this) so they chose to ignore it and stick to Windows 7 (which still ins&#8217;t a bad move). I have to give it to Microsoft, they generated the right buzz by allowing people to reserve their digital download of Windows 10.  Word-of-mouth is powerful marketing tool and that&#8217;s exactly what happened here (albeit through the power of social media like Twitter, Facebook and Email) and in this case it was enough to get people to want to get their digital copy of Windows 10 and install it including myself where I couldn&#8217;t wait so I went ahead and downloaded <a title="Windows 10 Download Toolkit" href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windows10" target="_blank"><strong>this</strong></a> toolkit from Microsoft to create my own ISO locally.</p>
<p>After following the instructions to create the external media, I selected ISO and waited while the toolkit proceeded to download the necessary files and create an ISO for me (I recommend you go make a cup of tea at this point).  After the ISO was created I extracted the files to a folder on my C:\ drive and then ran the setup and followed the on-screen instructions to upgrade Windows 8.1 to Windows 10 (choosing to retain my Data &amp; Apps).   This was quite a smooth process all but 1 of my applications worked however here is where the fun started&#8230; We are led to believe that the upgrade process is seamless however its was anything but, I had to reinstall all my drivers for them to work again (even though Windows 10 reported everything as being functional) and if you don&#8217;t do this you will start experiencing strange problems from your SSD drive not running at full speed, CPU running in a stepped state to sound being 50% of its actual volume.</p>
<p>About an hour later I was up and running properly and Windows 10 started to behave, initially very impressed, loved the subtle desktop UI design touches and this time almost everything has a WPF interface to it which is great (to a point) but again Microsoft screwed up here as some screens are just not thought out properly where a typical WinForms dialog has not been thoughtfully transformed over to it&#8217;s WPF counterpart or rather it&#8217;s been over engineered and what should be a simple interface becomes a multi-screen click nightmare (more on this later). Then we have the issue with the CPU running hot. On my humble HP Mobile Workstation I have to keep an eye on the CPU temp as it can run hot (as it&#8217;s meant to) but I had it set up a particular way in Windows 8.1 (using a combination of <a title="Core Temp" href="http://alcpu.com/CoreTemp/" target="_blank">Core Temp </a>and the awesome <a title="Notebook FanControl" href="https://github.com/hirschmann/nbfc" target="_blank">Notebook FanControl</a> by <span style="font-weight: bold">Stefan Hirschmann) </span>so that the system ran cool and quiet more often however the same did not transfer over to Windows 10 so easily and I found for whatever reason the CPU was running at least 5% hotter than on Windows 8.1 and more often (and this seems to be a common problem where many notebook users have reverted back to Windows 7 due to this issue). So what would be causing this problem and why?</p>
<p>Try as I might I could not pin point the issue and Windows 10 would not give up any clues suggesting everything was idle when it obviously wasn&#8217;t and the CPU was busy doing something in the background.  Eventually I found the culprit but try to remedy the problems actually broke Windows 10 functionality and let me explain how. The reason the CPU was running hotter is because it was actually busy doing some work for Cortana, the humble Paperclip evolved through AI, sex change acquiring a female voice and making you believe it can do anything (no Cortana&#8217;s last name is not Jenner, I did check). I saw this before, in Windows 7 a long time ago and some people caught on to what Microsoft was up to and these invisible background processes were removed form subsequent service pack releases.</p>
<p>In the case of Windows 10 you are literally lied to, nothing is reported as running, the event viewer screen doesn&#8217;t record any activity yet when you fire up Systools Process Monitor there is a feint trace of activity &#8211; this behavior is the same as what malware and malicious applications have, not good Microsoft! So to follow up on my hunch I disabled the search features of Cortana complete, opted out of the other sub features and while this reduced the CPU activity (and heat) it did not completely remedy the problem as the CPU was still obviously doing something causing it to heat up &#8211; one idea could be drivers but surely Microsoft would have had plenty of time to sort this out especially for something as common as an i7 QuadCore sandybridge CPU.</p>
<p>But that wasn&#8217;t the last of my issues either; At this point I was quite satisfied I had remedied the teething problems (to be expected with a new system) and was willing to give Windows 10 another go (heck I had been praising it on Twitter for days) but then I was horrified to find the system had been crippled because I had disabled Cortana and the other sub features but we are never made aware of this and Microsoft for obvious reasons didn&#8217;t announce this fact either. So what are the symptoms?  Firstly you will notice the new Start panel doesn&#8217;t work properly, some tiles don&#8217;t appear, some apps won&#8217;t show up on the search and fundamental core applications simply disappear unless you enable search features again&#8230;why would Microsoft do this, what a shitty thing to do!</p>
<p>So this obviously had me concerned as did the fact that Cortana wanted to know EVERYTHING about me, intercept everything I did, socially and via messaging to which said &#8220;YOU&#8217;RE HAVING A LAUGH MATE!&#8221; and promptly renamed Cortana to something else beginning with C and ending with Face. I had a moan on Twitter obviously at this point and to be fair Microsoft Support were quick to respond asking me to try using the built-in feedback and support application, cool&#8230;hold on you muppets that won&#8217;t work because I disabled Cortana so that native application doesn&#8217;t appear anymore but wait there is more bullcakes to follow.</p>
<p>I then followed the link in Windows 10 to join some program that lets me get early releases of updates and software which in turn also enables the feedback feature however this is stuck in an infinite loop of death and you never ever get the feedback app or get to actually provide any feedback &#8211; dipshits! To add insult to injury I was then tweeted to use their support website but get this, I have to pay for that support &#8211; really WTF?!  I had a total nerd rage at this point and told Microsoft to do one and promptly wiped windows 10 and went back to Windows 8.1 Professional, peace at least (for a while). <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter.png"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4122" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter-229x300.png" alt="windows-10-twitter" width="229" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter-229x300.png 229w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter.png 683w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /></a></p>
<p>So I was going to mention a bunch of other crap with Windows 10? Well here is a list:</p>
<ul>
<li>DPI sucks big time, wtf were Microsoft thinking, just give us proper DPI control over the screens (why do I have to go search the internet for a registry hack)</li>
<li>Key power features hidden or removed like Group Policy Editor that you as an administrator can&#8217;t administer</li>
<li>Windows Themes: You have to go through a convoluted series of screens to something called slideshow to then go to a Windows 7 personalisation screen that has key controls missing!!!</li>
<li>Can&#8217;t use older applications at all, Windows 10 will block them even though they WILL work fine (only way round is to hack the registry again)</li>
<li>Some registry changes/hacks are overridden by Windows 10 and restored to default settings wiping your FIXES</li>
<li>You CANNOT opt out of Automatic Updates and this is wrong, period</li>
</ul>
<p>The biggest issue for me is that Windows 10 is essentially a full blown anti-privacy tool and there is no way to opt out of this.  Free is most certainly not free here and I would advise people to read the terms and conditions that we all click through without noticing because there is some scary stuff in there like Microsoft being able to access your mic, camera and data on your Windows 10 OS as they see fit whenever they want, no thanks. Here is an interesting video for you guys: <a title="Do not install Windows 10" href="https://youtu.be/tWs6mk-HWLk" target="_blank">https://youtu.be/tWs6mk-HWLk</a> Finally if you do downgrade like I did, you need to be aware that Microsoft will attempt to force Windows 10 on you so you need to remove some things using <a title="Remove GWA" href="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/get-rid-windows-10-upgrade-notification-windows-7-8/" target="_blank"><strong>this guide</strong></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Please sir, can I have some more?&#8221; &#8211; shiny hardware and .NET</title>
		<link>/index.php/uncategorized/please-sir-can-i-have-some-more-shiny-hardware-and-net/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/uncategorized/please-sir-can-i-have-some-more-shiny-hardware-and-net/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 03:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tahir Khalid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3137</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to one of my rare blog posts almost at the end of 2014! I wanted to change the subject a bit from the regular blog posts and talk about something that most developers either take for granted or take seriously (I am the latter) and that is the hardware they choose (or [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello and welcome to one of my rare blog posts almost at the end of 2014!</p>
<p>I wanted to change the subject a bit from the regular blog posts and talk about something that most developers either take for granted or take seriously (I am the latter) and that is the hardware they choose (or are given) to develop on.</p>
<p>I think as I have become more experienced over time as a developer I have started to create a wish list in the back of my mind for the ideal developer platform I need to do my job and more importantly for me to enjoy developing on because too many times I have worked in roles where not enough emphasis or priority was placed on what the developers needed to do their job correctly.</p>
<p>This wasn&#8217;t so much a case of tight purse strings as lack of understanding at the time as to what developers require and as it was usually up to the infrastructure folks to commission the hardware they usually ended up delivering what other users had which wasn&#8217;t always right and equally I think some developers had a vague idea of what they needed but were not hardware addicts or power users like other IT folks so they didn&#8217;t always voice concerns or specific requirements.</p>
<p>I am fortunate in that I have done development roles were the hardware was inadequate and abysmal and in one case it took over a year to obtain more memory into what was an already struggling Dell desktop machine&#8230;with a single screen &#8211; THE HORROR!</p>
<p>Things did improve, alibet slowly and I think that was down more to me as a developer because over time in interviews and/or during 1-2-1 and developer forums I would start to raise concerns and in the case of some recent past interviews one of my primary questions to the employers was: &#8220;What&#8217;s the hardware like, what&#8217;s the software like, how is the Group policy, Servers&#8221; and so on because as a developer I should know what I need to do my job and equally development managers should know what their guys need to work efficiently.</p>
<p>Fortunately the last 5+ years I have always used HP hardware from the might Z600 Xeon Workstation to the rather nifty small form factor EliteDesk series PC&#8217;s and always in all cases HP&#8217;s workstation build quality impressed me as did the consistent performance and reliability.</p>
<p>So this set the ball in motion&#8230;for a long time I have been promising myself a new mobile workstation for the home however at the time (couple of years ago) I was struggling for choice as there wasn&#8217;t much on the market in this category and what was available was either very expensive or came in the guise of one of those behemoth gaming notebooks.</p>
<p>Why a gaming notebook?  It was (and still is to some degree) the only notebook that had the spec to give me confidence it would not become redundant after a years use but also the fact that I could tap into desktop workstation like performance.  So this left little choice:</p>
<ul>
<li>Some ugly but well spec&#8217;d gaming notebook</li>
<li>A Dell Precision notebook (expensive)</li>
<li>The Lenovo Thinkpad series (the good ones like the 520W and 530 series)</li>
<li>HP EliteBook series (again expensive)</li>
</ul>
<p>The problem was trying to find a lot of power, memory and performance in a laptop/notebook package that would not require its own power station, not give off enough radiation to give me heat stroke and be fairly portable in the sense that I could move it around the house as I pleased as I wanted the peace and quiet these notebooks offer over a noisy but powerful desktop workstation.</p>
<p>So about 2 weeks ago I decided I would take another look on eBay, see what new trends were going in terms of laptops/notebooks and workstations &#8211; eBay is good like that, you can get an idea of what is becoming popular and last years business laptop is this years performance bargain.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not about outright speed or cores, its about the reliability and rock solid performance you get with business class notebooks because quite frankly they are better built than the plastic laptops you get in your local retail shop and most business laptops/notebooks have rugged good looks to boot.</p>
<p>One such notebook popped up in my radar, the HP 8560w Mobile Workstation &#8211; up to this point I had known about the older HP EliteDesk notebooks which were very nice to use and had a very high quality metallic finish to them but they always lacked in power or at least that&#8217;s what I thought until I came across the 2011 model advertised as &#8220;Military specification mobile workstation&#8221; which obviously perked my interest.</p>
<p>After obsessively researching the internet about this particular HP 8560w mobile workstation I was very impressed by what I read in reviews and from comments made my former, current and new owners &#8211; these notebooks are serious power houses when spec&#8217;d correctly.  So off I went on my merry way and by pure luck came across one of these:</p>
<div style="width: 522px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img src="http://ic.tweakimg.net/ext/i/1316180342.jpeg" alt="HP EliteBook 8560w Mobile Workstation" width="512" height="435" /><p class="wp-caption-text">HP EliteBook 8560w Mobile Workstation</p></div>
<p>And the specification of this one wasn&#8217;t shy either:</p>
<p>Intel Quad Core i7 mobile processor 2.3Ghz/3.75Ghz</p>
<p>32GB Crucial DDR3 High speed memory</p>
<p>256GB OCZ Vertex SSD Drive</p>
<p>500GB SATA 2 secondary drive</p>
<p>nVidia Quadro 2000M 2GB Graphics card</p>
<p>15.6&#8243; Dreamcolor Panel with a native resolution of 1920&#215;1080 pixels!</p>
<p>High quality metal chassis and outer skin with metallic brushed finish</p>
<p>Backlit keyboard</p>
<p>External BD-Rom drive</p>
<p>eSata port, Display Port, USB 2 &amp; 3 ports, firewire port and 1 x USB powered port</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Safe to say the specification goes above and beyond what most people would need from a notebook but for me it means that I have no issues with the notebook lasting several years at least and being able to perform to a very high level.   After agreeing a deal with the eBay seller I handed over almost £600 pounds (about $930 US dollars) for 1 used HP 8560w notebook &#8211; it&#8217;s bit of a gamble with eBay with regards to item condition and quality as some sellers tend to be creative with their description and using actual photo&#8217;s of what you are purchasing however common sense prevailed and I checked out the sellers eBay history (100% positive) and I could the seller had been doing this for a while so wasn&#8217;t completely clueless.</p>
<p>Some swift email and texts later and we had agreed for me to collect said notebook, a somewhat long drive to the other side of London (almost 200 miles in total) however the trip was worth the effort and the seller turned out to be a nice honest trader who was true to his word and when he revealed the notebook it was in flawless condition, actually I was taken back at how &#8220;mint&#8221; it looked, almost new bar for one very minor defect with the locking mechanism that wasn&#8217;t even noticeable &#8211; overall a very good eBay buying experience.</p>
<p>As a bonus the guy threw in a registered installation of Windows 8.1 Standard (it does the job), a new Belkin notebook bag which is rather hefty but can accommodate the rugged HP 8560w notebook very well including all its peripherals and power supply which is like a brick itself consuming about 150W, not shy then.</p>
<p>What has impressed me the most is the very high level of engineering that has gone into designing and constructing the HP 8560w mobile workstation (to give it it&#8217;s full name), it really is leagues apart from your typical laptops/notebooks, both commercial and business models and dare I say it is better in many ways to the solid lump of metal that is the Macbook Pro.  Yes it doesn&#8217;t have the finish of the Apple products but in many ways it&#8217;s better and more appealing to the eye because it has a rugged metallic finish that shouts &#8220;I am a techies toy not a portable mirror&#8221; &#8211; it would not look out of place in an engineering lab which is one of many scenarios HP must have envisioned this notebook to be used.</p>
<div style="width: 473px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img src="http://www.kuchbhibecho.com/images/product/pro/13934228691392389602_602226778_10-HP-EliteBook-8560w-.jpg" alt="Rugged good looks" width="463" height="348" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Rugged good looks</p></div>
<div style="width: 477px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img src="http://www.ubergizmo.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/hp-elitebook-8560w-03.jpg" alt="Beautifully engineered" width="467" height="312" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Beautifully engineered</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s not sleek and it&#8217;s not trying to compete with the wafer designs however it is very well finished from the flush port recesses to the solid tactile keyboard and very usable touch pad it ticks all the boxes for me as a beautiful lump of well engineered technology.</p>
<p>So how does it perform?</p>
<p>Really really well, what&#8217;s most impressive is the boot time from cold power up to the Windows 8.1 desktop, it takes more than 6 to 8 seconds which is bloody fast and all silently thanks to the very cool bit of kit that is the OCZ Vertex SSD Drive (it&#8217;s blindingly fast).</p>
<p>While Windows 8.1 doesn&#8217;t have the Windows Experience index visible anywhere like Windows 7 had, however th<span style="color: #000000">he underlying benchmark utility, known as the Windows System Assessment Tool (WinSAT), is still there in Windows 8.1 and can be accessed the following way:</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000">Open a command prompt as administrator, then type &#8220;winsat prepop&#8221; and press Enter. This will run the benchmark and store the results on your PC as XML file</span></p>
<div style="width: 630px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img src="http://cnet2.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2014/01/01/3ebcecc0-8533-11e3-bc97-14feb5ca9861/resize/620x/a89d3999dc93211414aa91967400bfb9/winsat_prepop.png" alt="Open command line and type Winsat preprop" width="620" height="320" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Open command line and type Winsat preprop</p></div>
<p>This will execute the Winsat command and create an xml results file that you can then access through Windows Powershell to obtain your results:</p>
<div style="width: 630px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img src="http://cnet2.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2014/01/01/3ebf6e94-8533-11e3-bc97-14feb5ca9861/resize/620x/b90d663ad09fc70695bce75590accb82/get_winsat.png" alt="Windows Powershell Winsat utility" width="620" height="355" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Windows Powershell Winsat utility</p></div>
<p style="color: #000000"><strong>CPUScore</strong> is the score for the processors on the PC.<br />
<strong>D3DScore</strong> is the score for the 3D graphics capabilities of the PC.<br />
<strong>DiskScore</strong> is the score for the sequential read throughput on the system hard disk.<br />
<strong>GraphicsScore</strong> is the score for the graphics capabilities of the PC.<br />
<strong>MemoryScore</strong> is the score for the memory throughput and capacity of the PC.</p>
<p style="color: #000000">That&#8217;s it. If you&#8217;re looking for your base score, look at the number next to <strong>WinSPRLevel</strong>, which is just the lowest score of the five categories.</p>
<p style="color: #000000">The HP 8560w scored an impressive 6.7 base score with high scores of 7.1 and 7.3 for the CPU and memory&#8230;and that memory, it makes such a difference when you use the notebook for development running a local SQL 2012 Development server, several Visual Studio 2013 instances and a few other tools to boot plus Firefox browser &#8211; there is no lag, at all.</p>
<p style="color: #000000">Now this could be due to the OCZ SSD drive or the memory but I suspect it&#8217;s a combination of the both, either ways its blisteringly fast (I have all my main apps running from the SSD drive and all my data etc on 1TB SATA 2 secondary drive).</p>
<p style="color: #000000">The screen is not to everyone&#8217;s taste and I found I was squinting a lot at the native resolution of 1920&#215;180 pixels on the 15.6&#8243; panel, frankly it&#8217;s too high a resolution for a small panel but you cannot deny the quality of the Dreamcolor panel &#8211; one of the most crisp and brilliantly coloured panels I have used in a long time (it&#8217;s actually better than my large HP monitor!).  In hindsight I should have gone for the larger 8570w notebook which has the 17&#8243; display making for easier reading however after a few adjustments of the font size and some tweaking in my favourite apps like Visual Studio I quickly became comfortable.</p>
<p style="color: #000000">So in conclusion&#8230;</p>
<p style="color: #000000">A very impressive piece of engineering that offers true desktop replacement technology in a reasonable notebook size package without sacrificing quality or comfort.  It can play games quite comfortably while not as good as a dedicated gaming notebook or desktop its adequate as can be seen from this demo (on a lower spec Quadro mind you): <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rf6K3S4Gdoc">Crysis 3 Demo</a></p>
<p style="color: #000000">I highly recommend for others to take a serious look at yesterdays business laptops and mobile workstations as they can offer a lot for very little money and give you a product that has a much higher build quality and still enough performance to be usable for a number of years!</p>
<p style="color: #000000">Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year everyone!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/uncategorized/please-sir-can-i-have-some-more-shiny-hardware-and-net/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ASP.NET MVC 4 Razor Starter Guide &#8211; How to avoid punching your Laptop to Death</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/uidevelopment/ajax/asp-net-mvc-4-razor-starter/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/uidevelopment/ajax/asp-net-mvc-4-razor-starter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 01:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tahir Khalid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AJAX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[$ not defined]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asp.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mvc 4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[razor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starter guide]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/12/asp-net-mvc-4-razor-starter/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to my seocond blog post for LessThanDot (I think) and in this post I will discuss how to setup a working ASP.NET MVC 4 (with Razor) project using the Empty Template.
That's right, a blank project, I didn't want the templates doing the&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello and welcome to my blog post for LessThanDot and in this post I will discuss how to setup a working ASP.NET MVC 4 (with Razor) project using the Empty Template.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right, a blank project, I didn&#8217;t want the templates doing the work for me, I wanted to create a lean project that I had control over and I thought this would be easy enough but I was very wrong and tripped over a couple of times so hopefully this post will avoid any confusion and pain for newbies to the world of ASP.NET MVC (and avoid having to punch their laptop to death).</p>
<p>&#8220;Wait you punched your laptop to death?!&#8221;</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/punchedmylaptoptodeath.jpg" alt="Punched My Laptop To Death @ vurso.co.uk" width="350" height="85" /></p>
<p>Yes, metaphorically speaking as per my above tweet&#8230;I came close to actually doing it in real life, that&#8217;s how frustrated I was but alas frustration can often lead to lots of fun learning which I did in between the random expletives and &#8220;WTF!&#8221; shouts throughout this process.</p>
<p>So lets start, the first thing you want to do is <span style="background-color: #ffcc00;">NOT USE THE TEMPLATES!</span> I know I know, sounds crazy but trust me you want to do it right and this is the best way my friends.</p>
<p>Start Visual Studio 2012 and then select the ASP.NET MVC 4 project type:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/aspdotnetmvc4projtype.JPG" alt="ASP.NET MVC 4 Project Type" width="350" height="35" /></p>
<p>Give the project a meaningful name and then left-click the OK button to continue. You will then be presented with the following screen (Project Tempaltes), select the <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Empty</span> Project type and left-click OK to continue.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/projecttemplates.jpg" alt="ASP.NET MVC 4 Project Templates" width="280" height="165" /></p>
<p>If everything goes to plan Visual Studio will start generating your project folders and files and present you with the Empty Solution:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/emptysolution.jpg" alt="ASP.NET MVC 4 Empty Solution" width="185" height="180" /></p>
<p>You will need to do a few things first before the project can actually work (i.e. if you want to use any kind of JavaScript/jquery/ajax and Web Content).  First we need to add some folders so right-click the project name (MvcApplication3 fro example) and select <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Add &gt; </span><span style="background-color: #99ccff;">New Folder</span> and label it <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Scripts</span> (or alternatively if you have created another template based MVC site such as the Internet one just drag the Scripts folder from Windws Explorer into your Visual Studio 2012 IDE and drop it onto the project name which will cause Visual Studio 2012 to take a copy of the folder and create it locally with files below your project).</p>
<p>Expand the Views folder which currently only has the web.config file.  Right-click the Views folder and select <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Add &gt; </span><span style="background-color: #99ccff;">New Folder</span> labelling it <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Home</span>.  Create another one and call it <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Shared</span>, these two folders will contain the default views Index.cshtml and _Layout.cshtml (the shared view is like the MasterPage from the previous ASP.NET Form development days, it is used as a global view providing common page structure and other features across your views).</p>
<p>Now the important bit, you need to download the correct Web.Optimization package as its not included in your project and trying to create, build and compile any kind of web enabled page will cause no end of grief no less messages such as:</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 18px; background-color: #eeeeee;"><span style="font-family: 'courier new', courier;">Compiler Error Message: CS0103: The name &#8216;Scripts&#8217; does not exist in the current context</span></span></p>
<p>You may also see initial errors such as:</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 18px; background-color: #eeeeee;"><span style="font-family: 'courier new', courier;">$ is not defined</span></span></p>
<p>All these can be avoided by running the following command from the nuget package manager command line.  To access the command line you need to display the command window:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/nugetcommandline.jpg" alt="nuget Package Manager Command Line" width="434" height="185" /></p>
<p>Left-clicking the Command Line option will display a new command window at the bottom of your IDE which lets you enter nuget package manager specific commands.  Enter the following command to download the correct package for your project:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/nugetpackageget.jpg" alt="Get nuget package from Visual Studio 2012" width="321" height="100" /></p>
<p>Once the package has been downloaded you will need to configure your <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Web.Config</span> files, <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Global.asax</span> file and add a new class in the <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">App_Start</span> folder so lets do this now.</p>
<p>Open up your root Web.config file and add the following line below the other namespaces (in the pages &gt; namespaces section):</p>
<pre style="font-family: Consolas; font-size: 13; color: #dfdfbf; background: #333333;"><span style="font-size: small;">&lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">add</span> namespace="<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">System.Web.WebPages</span>" /&gt;</span><span style="font-family: Consolas;">
</span></pre>
<p>You will also need to do the same for your other web.config file located in the root of the Views folder.</p>
<p>Next you need to modify your <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Global.asax</span> file located in the root of the project and add the following line below the other statements in the <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Application_Start()</span> method:</p>
<pre style="font-family: Consolas; font-size: 13; color: #dfdfbf; background: #333333;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="color: #8acccf;">BundleConfig</span>.RegisterBundles(<span style="color: #8acccf;">BundleTable</span>.Bundles);</span><span style="font-family: Consolas;">
</span></pre>
<p>Now you need to add a new class called BundleConfig.cs in the App_Start folder.  Modify the using block to look like this:</p>
<pre style="color: #dfdfbf; background-color: #333333; background-position: initial initial; background-repeat: initial initial;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="color: #efc986;">using</span> System.Web;
<span style="color: #efc986;">using</span> System.Web.Optimization;</span></pre>
<p>Modify the contents of the class block to look like this:</p>
<pre style="color: #dfdfbf; background-color: #333333; background-position: initial initial; background-repeat: initial initial;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="color: #7a987a;">// For more information on Bundling, visit http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=254725</span>
<span style="color: #efc986;">public</span> <span style="color: #efc986;">static</span> <span style="color: #efc986;">void</span> RegisterBundles(<span style="color: #8acccf;">BundleCollection</span> bundles)
{
    bundles.Add(<span style="color: #efc986;">new</span> <span style="color: #8acccf;">ScriptBundle</span>(<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/bundles/jquery"</span>).Include(
                <span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/Scripts/jquery-{version}.js"</span>));
 
    bundles.Add(<span style="color: #efc986;">new</span> <span style="color: #8acccf;">ScriptBundle</span>(<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/bundles/jqueryui"</span>).Include(
                <span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/Scripts/jquery-ui-{version}.js"</span>));
 
    bundles.Add(<span style="color: #efc986;">new</span> <span style="color: #8acccf;">ScriptBundle</span>(<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/bundles/jqueryval"</span>).Include(
                <span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/Scripts/jquery.unobtrusive*"</span>,
                <span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/Scripts/jquery.validate*"</span>));
 
    <span style="color: #7a987a;">// Use the development version of Modernizr to develop with and learn from. Then, when you're</span>
    <span style="color: #7a987a;">// ready for production, use the build tool at http://modernizr.com to pick only the tests you need./</span>
    bundles.Add(<span style="color: #efc986;">new</span> <span style="color: #8acccf;">ScriptBundle</span>(<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/bundles/modernizr"</span>).Include(
                <span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/Scripts/modernizr-*"</span>));
}</span></pre>
<p>Now save the file and we need to create a controller file and two view pages.  Right-click the Controllers folder and left-click on <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Add &gt; Controller&#8230;</span> to display the New Controller dialog:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/newcontroller.jpg" alt="New MVC 4 Controller" width="280" height="145" /></p>
<p>Give it the name <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">HomeController</span> and left-click on Add to continue.  Now we need to create the Index view the controller will work with.  Before we do that we need to create a view that will <a title="ASP.NET MVC 3: Layouts with Razor" href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2010/10/22/asp-net-mvc-3-layouts.aspx" target="_blank">&#8220;automagically&#8221; assign the same razor layout</a> to all your views so right-click the <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Views</span> folder and left-click on <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Add &gt; View&#8230;</span> (VS 2012 is clever enough to recognise the context you&#8217;re in, in this case the Views folder).  The Add View dialog box will appear:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.vurso.co.uk/ltd/mvc-4-with-razor-starter-guide/addview.jpg" alt="ASP.NET MVC 4 Add View" width="200" height="252" /></p>
<p>Make sure you un-tick the &#8220;Use a layout or master page:&#8221; checkbox (as all your views will be using this <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">_ViewStart</span> file).</p>
<p>Now modify the file to look like this:</p>
<pre style="color: #dfdfbf; background-color: #333333; background-position: initial initial; background-repeat: initial initial;"><span style="font-size: small;">@{
    Layout = <span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/Views/Shared/_Layout.cshtml"</span>;
}</span></pre>
<p>Next we need to create the Index View so right-click the Home folder (the one you created earlier) and select <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Add &gt; View&#8230;</span> to display the Add View dialog box and label this view page <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Index</span> and finally left-click Add to create it.</p>
<p>Modify the contents of the file to look like this:</p>
<pre style="color: #dfdfbf; background-color: #333333; background-position: initial initial; background-repeat: initial initial;"><span style="font-size: small;">@{
    ViewBag.Title = <span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"My first LTD Mvc 4 Index Page"</span>;
}
@<span style="color: #efc986;">using</span> (Html.BeginForm())
{
     &lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">h1</span>&gt;Hello, World!&lt;/<span style="color: #efc986;">h1</span>&gt;
}</span></pre>
<p>Finally you need to create the shared layout view page, right-click the <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Shared</span> folder and left-click <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Add &gt; View&#8230;</span> to display the Add View dialog box, label the view page as <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">_Layout</span> and ensure as with the previous pages the &#8220;Use a layout or master page&#8221; checkbox is un-ticked.</p>
<p>Modify the <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">_Layout.cshtml</span> view page to look like this:</p>
<pre style="color: #dfdfbf; background-color: #333333; background-position: initial initial; background-repeat: initial initial;"><span style="font-size: small;">&lt;!<span style="color: #efc986;">DOCTYPE</span> html&gt;
&lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">html</span> lang=<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"en"</span>&gt;
&lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">head</span>&gt;
    &lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">meta</span> name=<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"viewport"</span> content=<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"width=device-width"</span> /&gt;
    &lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">title</span>&gt;@ViewBag.Title&lt;/<span style="color: #efc986;">title</span>&gt;
&lt;/<span style="color: #efc986;">head</span>&gt;
&lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">body</span>&gt;
    &lt;<span style="color: #efc986;">div</span>&gt;
        @RenderBody()
    &lt;/<span style="color: #efc986;">div</span>&gt;
    @<span style="color: #8acccf;">Scripts</span>.Render(<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"~/bundles/jquery"</span>)
    @RenderSection(<span style="color: #dfaf8f;">"scripts"</span>, required: <span style="color: #efc986;">false</span>)
&lt;/<span style="color: #efc986;">body</span>&gt;
&lt;/<span style="color: #efc986;">html</span>&gt;</span></pre>
<p>This should be enough for you to compile the project however it will still cause you pain unless you save your project and restart Visual Studio 2012, after which the references and page helpers should kick into life.</p>
<p>Build and Compile your project and then press <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">F5</span> or click on the <span style="background-color: #99ccff;">Debug</span> button to fire up your project, if all has gone well you should see a simple page with the words &#8220;Hello, World!&#8221; across the top left.</p>
<p>Well done, now go make a cup of tea and eat some digestives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/uidevelopment/ajax/asp-net-mvc-4-razor-starter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Developer, can do new tricks, require good home</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/hi-i-m-a-developer/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/hi-i-m-a-developer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tahir Khalid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Operating Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle client]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[system administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual studio]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/02/hi-i-m-a-developer/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The world of development is an interesting one where creativity comes alive through code to produce wonderful programs that do lots of cool stuff.
Okay that's the Wizard of Oz intro over, is it really that rosy?
It seems the world of development has c&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">The world of development is an interesting one where creativity comes alive through code to produce wonderful programs that do lots of cool stuff.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Okay that&#8217;s the Wizard of Oz intro over, is it really that rosy?</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">It seems the world of development has changed a great deal and gone are the days when you could just be a code cutter (though such roles do exist and are required), it seems a developer has to now master a wide array of skills and do battle with various foes like the Windows Operating System (<em>level 72 elite boss for those that are keeping track&#8230;</em>) as well trying to do their day job (<em>which in itself now consists of different minion roles</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">With the advances in .NET development there are a wide range of Frameworks, Tools and Add-Ons that can be worked with, installed and generally cried over (<em>a black hole in which I have been sucked into, the crying bit&#8230;</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/coders.jpg?mtime=1359936989" alt="Coders" width="282" height="202" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Now I can hear you say, that&#8217;s all good but we don&#8217;t have those problems, we have a <strong>Textbook Development Team</strong> with a <strong>Textbook It Support Team</strong> in a <strong>Textbook Office</strong> but that is not quite the real world and you will often have boundaries between teams becoming thinner or more common now, the lack of resources and/or teams (<em>leaving the task of taking on those roles and their responsibilities up to the individuals in the department and organisation</em>).</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">But then the question has to be asked, just how efficient and proficient can you be as an individual, a team and a department if you are spending a percentage of your available resource and effort performing other duties, often to prepare something prior to performing your actual task or after the event where you still need to perform a multitude of other tasks (<em>covering various roles like administration etc.</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">And this is where my hell begins&#8230;</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;">Now don&#8217;t get me wrong, I enjoy the techie element of my role, I feel I fulfil the developer title more fully by being able to flex my many different skills (<em>making me adaptable for almost any occasion</em>), a result of accumulating experience in a wide range of sectors starting from my humble beginnings as an IT Support guy, moving into a System Administration role, sideways across into Application Support, Technical Project Lead, Solution Architecture and back into Software Development in my current role as an Senior .NET Enterprise Developer (</span><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><em>not Star Trek&#8230;I wish it was, but it&#8217;s not and I have to live with that disappointment for the rest of my career life&#8230;I tried do the Spock hand thing, got strange looks from the others in the developer forum&#8230;</em></span><span style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 14.25pt;">).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">In the company where I work now, my team is fairly self-sufficient and that often means we do a lot of the stuff ourselves (<em>whilst still going through proper channels as required</em>) which is great as it means we can quickly prototype solutions through a Virtual Machine on our PC or install a particular tool we need to perform some task &#8211; all of this means that we generally have control over our own PC&#8217;s (<em>as all developers should&#8230;but they don&#8217;t unfortunately</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">But it&#8217;s a double edged sword as I found out the past few days and while being able to administer your own PC&#8217;s and Server&#8217;s is great it can quickly become a bottomless pit that you simply can&#8217;t escape no matter how many Bear Ghryll&#8217;s episodes you have watched (<em>some English guy on the TV that does cool stuff to survive, like James Bond for the wild</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">So begins my particular episode&#8230;</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I have a pretty snazzy developer PC inherited from my predecessor, a rather cool Hewlet Packard Z600 Workstation specced up to the hilt with serious &#8216;Uber&#8217; hardware (<em>dual quad Xeon&#8217;s, stupid amount of memory, SSD&#8217;s, drool&#8230;</em>) and thankfully I have complete control over it (<em>mostly</em>) so I had the chance to configure my PC the way I wanted it to do the development I needed to do.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I have the usual culprits on there, Visual Studio 2010 Premium SP1, MSSQL Server 2008 R2, VMware, lots of useful tools (<em>Notepad++, Red Gate, Solitaire</em>) all running on a Windows 7 Professional 64 bit&#8230;nothing out of the ordinary there I hear you say, ah I haven’t told you about that little evil gremlin called Oracle, more specifically Oracle 64 bit and 32 bit clients on a 64 bit operating system (<em>yes, that combination should cause you to feel nauseous</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">The goal was simple, get the latest version of a large .NET Enterprise project, build it, tweak it, break it and glue it back together.  However there was one caveat, I needed to then install the following in some order (<em>mostly like this one</em>):</span></span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;"> </span></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Install the Oracle 64 bit Client for Windows</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;"> </span></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Install the 64 bit ODAC stuff (<em>for some nice ODACness</em>), the Xcopy version btw</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;"> </span></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Install the 32 bit Client (ODT with ODAC)</span></span></li>
</ul>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Simple enough I thought, having virtual zero Oracle skills I was up for the challenge and felt confident I had the knowhow and experience (<em>plus large balls</em>) to deal with any issues that might crop up and like a true techie I refused to read the manual (<em>text file in the case of Oracle products</em>)…I was in for a bumpy ride it seems.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">* It should be noted here, if you do happen to install the 32 bit client first and/or the Oracle Developer Tools and ODAC (32 bit), you will have seriously random Installation problems trying to install Oracle 64 bit Client (<em>the solution is to follow the instructions further down in this post to remove and clean up your PC</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I went ahead and installed the 64 bit Client, in this case I used the client installation that came provided with the Oracle 11g database installation CD (<em>supplied by the tech support guys</em>), selected <strong>Administrator</strong> as the installation type, pointed the installer to where I wanted the files to go, set the Oracle Home directory and went ahead with the installation (<em>no problems here</em>).</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/oracle-installer.jpg?mtime=1359936990" alt="Oracle Installer" width="399" height="274" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">All good so far, put my <strong>TNSNAMES.ORA</strong> file into the  <strong>{Oracle_Home}Product11.2.0Client_X64NetworkAdmin</strong> folder, fired up a Command console and used Sqlplus to connect to an Oracle 11g database server that was supplied by the tech support team, worked like a charm.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">After doing this I installed the Xcopy version of the 64 bit ODAC libraries and tools which can only be installed by the command prompt so you need to run a command similar to this in the installation directory:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="background-color: #000000;"><span style="color: #ffffff;"><span style="font-family: 'courier new', courier;">install.bat all c:oracle OracleHome_Client1 </span></span></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Or something similar to the above command which should go ahead and install the required ODAC bits into the proper place (<em>you need to ensure you specify the Oracle Home directory</em>).  Again this went fairly smoothly as well with no hick-ups so up next was the 32 bit client and here you need to make sure you install the Oracle Developer Tools with ODAC which includes the 32 bit client otherwise you will experience much pain as I did (<em>where I installed the 32 bit client, then ODAC and other bits which caused no end of pain due to path problems, mismatched versions of dll’s etc</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">The above allows you to correctly use PL/SQL Developer (<em>if you have this cool application installed</em>) as long as you remember to go into the <strong>Tools &gt; Preferences &gt; Connection</strong> section and set the OCI Library to the correct location (<em>e.g. {oracle_home}product11.2.0client_1oci.dll or client_1binoci.dll depending on your version</em>) and any other application that requires the 32 bit Oracle Client.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Now the above hard work should be adequate to get a working Developer Workstation with both 64 bit and 32 bit Oracle Clients and Developer Tools however there is always a but…what I didn’t tell you was the amount of pain I went through to get the above installation list right, and believe me it was extremely painful and as I have found out after posting this blog page, there a few other client combinations that can work e.g. having a primary 32 bit Oracle Client installation with the developer tools and a 64 bit Instant Client installation (<em>will save this for a future post</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I spent an awfully long time getting my workstation working and when things did go wrong (<em>which they did a lot, just Google the various issues people have had trying to install and use Oracle clients with their Visual Studio developer machines</em>) I barely got any work done which prompted my colleague to say:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="background-color: #ffff99;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><strong>“We have to do so much administration work, just to get to a solution developed and delivered”</strong></span></span></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Which got me thinking, this is very true and probably becoming the norm now with modern development, more so in my case due to the nature of the team I am in i.e. we develop lots of bespoke solutions, integration various systems together, sometimes involving small pieces of development to large scale projects.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">What I haven’t shared is the nightmare scenario I ended up in with a totally messed up pair of gac’s (<em>32 bit and 64 bit</em>) and problems compiling any of our projects because they all used one combination or another of the Oracle client (<em>mostly 64 bit now</em>).  So if anyone has had this problem here is the proper way to deal with it…</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Open Command Prompt and change to the directory containing your Oracle client installation and run the deinstall.bat batch script:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="background-color: #000000;"><span style="color: #ffffff;"><span style="font-family: 'courier new', courier;">{oracle_home}product11.2.0Client_X64Deinstalldeinstall.bat</span></span></span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Once the de-installation (<em>uninstall to you and me…Oracle people…</em>) is complete you need to run the Oracle Universal Installer (<em>semi-cool Java tool…Java is not cool, the app is however</em>).  When this app fires up you have the option to Deinstall any installations on your system:</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/oracle-installer-deinstall.jpg?mtime=1359936990" alt="Oracle Deinstall" width="372" height="270" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Select all the products and then click on Remove to uninstall (<em>deinstall</em>) the products:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/oracle-installer-deinstall-inventory.jpg?mtime=1359936991" alt="Inventory" width="150" height="245" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">If you have no issues with the uninstallation of the Oracle Client stuff you will need to go into the Windows Registry to make sure you remove any references to an Oracle installation otherwise your future Oracle Client installation exercises will result in broken installations and more headaches.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Edit the registry (click START &gt; type regedit32) and start with the following registry location:</span></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt; line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINESOFTWARE</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Find the Oracle Key and delete it, do the same for the HKEY_CURRENT_USER and HKEY_USERS (<em>you will need to go through the various sub parent keys and find any Oracle sub Keys and delete them</em>). </span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Don&#8217;t forget to clear the gac&#8217;s (both 32 bit and 64 bit), I found this the simplest way of doing it:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Start Command Prompt for Visual Studio 32 bit</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Type gacutil /l &gt; c:gac32list.txt</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Open the gac32list.txt file and find the word Oracle</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">In the Command Prompt window type the following commands: </span>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">gacutil /u Oracle.DataAccess</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">gacutil /u Oracle.Database.Extensions</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">gacutil /u Oracle.Web</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Close the Command Prompt window</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Start Command Prompt for Visual Studio 64 bit</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Repeat the above commands</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Close the Command Prompt window</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">This should give you a clean installation and hopefully allow you to get a working installation of the Oracle clients on your .NET Developer Workstation.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">So back to the question at hand, just what kind of developer does a developer need to be?  Someone who is comfortable at administering their local, virtual and remote computers?  And just how much effort should be made before you require assistance (<em>and will that not take more effort</em>) but what if you work in an environment where the resources are not available and you have to <strong>“man up”</strong> (<em>so to speak</em>) and take the reins, do you factor that into any and every piece of work and project you do?</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Well in an ideal world you would minimize the effort required for each subsequent piece of work and/or project however you cannot avoid the moments when you will simply have to dig into the trenches and get your hands dirty so be prepared to lose half your estimated time (<em>if not more</em>) battling system incompatibilities, software bugs, assembly hell and those gremlins that keep causing you to see spots on your screen (<em>honest</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Set aside time to climb a difficult mountain and get your hands cut, you will need to work out the many holes in your nice setup and as more and more technical requirements popup don’t expect everything to work well together the first time (<em>you have to integrate your own development environment first</em>). </span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">So key here is to develop the expertise if you don’t have it at hand, become adaptable but remain honest to yourself (<em>you will have to go through some pain to get to the fruits of your labour</em>).  Use knowledge base tools (<em>Wiki</em>) to record your efforts, communicate your findings with your colleagues and attempt to automate and make reusable as much of what you use as possible.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">This will help you better deal with those moments when you have to spend most of your effort on the administration of your development work as appose to the actual developing and as a bonus increase your skills repertoire which every modern developer shouldn’t shy away from (<em>becoming more agile in nature by having a can-do attitude</em>).</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kermit/mememe.jpg?mtime=1359936991" alt="mememe" width="98" height="156" /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">I dedicate my first LTD blog post to Chrissie1.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"><br /></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><span style="line-height: 14.25pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">References:</span></strong></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/enterprise-edition/downloads/index.html"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Oracle 11g Database Download (includes the clients)</span></a></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/windows/downloads/index-090165.html"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">ODAC Xcopy 64 bit Download</span></a></p>
<p style="line-height: 14.25pt; tab-stops: 522.0pt;"><a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/topics/dotnet/utilsoft-086879.html"><span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;">Oracle Developer Tools with ODAC 32 bit</span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/hi-i-m-a-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
