<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>idera &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/idera/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Diagnostic Manager &#8211; Alert Statuses</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/diagnostic-manager-alert-statuses/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/diagnostic-manager-alert-statuses/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Conan]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diagnostic manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/06/diagnostic-manager-alert-statuses/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As you might imagine, I rely on Idera's Diagnostic Manager quite a bit.  Diagnostic Manager monitors many different things within each SQL Instance will alert to them when they met the thresholds you configure.  Now if you only a few SQL Instances monit&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As you might imagine, I rely on Idera&#8217;s Diagnostic Manager quite a bit.  Diagnostic Manager monitors many different things within each SQL Instance will alert to them when they met the thresholds you configure.  Now if you only a few SQL Instances monitored, you may not have many alerts, but if you have dozens of SQL Instances monitored, you could have several dozen alerts all the time.  </p>
<p>Maybe some of those alerts are not going to cause your system to crash right away, but you want to keep them in mind to show your boss that you need more memory or disk space.</p>
<p>So how do you know if something critical just happened that you really should look at and isn&#8217;t part of the other 50 alerts that just noise for right now?</p>
<p>This is where I use the different alert statuses and have defined what each status means.</p>
<p>Critical (Red) status means I want our support center who is watching the alerts page 24&#215;7 to call me anytime of the day or night about it.  I keep things like job failures, disk space that is really low and custom alerts about backups being really behind for example in this spot.  When a alert goes to critical and it is not something that I need to know about immediately, I will re-adjust to only go as far as a warning level.</p>
<p>Warning (Yellow) status means that this is something that I want to know about and could be become a serious issue, but I don&#8217;t need a 3AM wake up call about it.  For me it&#8217;s almost as important as a critical alert and is something that I will look at, but I won&#8217;t drop everything right now for it.</p>
<p>OK (Blue) status means it&#8217;s something I need to be aware of, but could go for days or weeks before I do something about it.  For example, our dev system is using 90% of the available memory.  That&#8217;s fine because it won&#8217;t be growing larger than that and we are actually migrating SQL Instances over to a new 2012 Environment.</p>
<p>This allows me to quickly sort through the alerts to see which ones I should be working on and concerned about (aka, prioritizing my time!)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/diagnostic-manager-alert-statuses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diagnostic Manager Quick Tip &#8211; New Server Tag</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip-new/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip-new/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Conan]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Modelling and Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diagnostic manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/06/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip-new/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Where I work, we like to buy Diagnostic Manager Licenses in batches.  So every quarter or so I add in a bunch of new instances.  When you start getting over 25 instances being monitored, it gets tricky to remember which 5 instances you just added into t&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Where I work, we like to buy Diagnostic Manager Licenses in batches.  So every quarter or so I add in a bunch of new instances.  When you start getting over 25 instances being monitored, it gets tricky to remember which 5 instances you just added into the mix.</p>
<p>One solution that I like to use, is to create a &#8220;New Server&#8221; tag and slap it on each server as it add it.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s just right in and create the &#8220;New Server&#8221; tag.  From the File Menu choose Manage Tags.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/tag1.jpg?mtime=1338861169"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/tag1.jpg?mtime=1338861169" width="231" height="150" /></a></div>
<p>Near the bottom of the Manage Tags screen, choose Add.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/tag2.jpg?mtime=1338861170"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/tag2.jpg?mtime=1338861170" width="578" height="544" /></a></div>
<p>Enter &#8220;New Server&#8221; into the Name field and click on ok.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/tag3.JPG?mtime=1338861170"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/tag3.JPG?mtime=1338861170" width="359" height="121" /></a></div>
<p>Now as you add servers, assign them to the &#8220;New Server&#8221; tag and then you can filter on them!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip-new/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diagnostic Manager Quick Tip &#8211; Job Messages</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Conan]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Database Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diagnostic manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/05/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A great use of Idera's Diagnostic Manager is to manage your SQL Job's and knowing which jobs have failed, which ones are running long and which ones have been running for the last 10 hours.  You even get to adjust the thresholds for each all of those me&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A great use of Idera&#8217;s Diagnostic Manager is to manage your SQL Job&#8217;s and knowing which jobs have failed, which ones are running long and which ones have been running for the last 10 hours.  You even get to adjust the thresholds for each all of those metrics.</p>
<p>If a job fails, you can don’t have check the history of the job in SSMS to see why it failed.  Instead you can do it right from Diagnostic Manager.  From SQL Agent Jobs in the Services section, find a click on the job you want to know the history of in the top section.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DMJobMessage1.jpg?mtime=1337826030"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DMJobMessage1.jpg?mtime=1337826030" width="1128" height="385" /></a></div>
<p>The history will be displayed on the lower section and you can expand each run of the job.  Find the failed execute of the job that you want more information about and expand it.  If you hover over the message it will pop up displaying the whole message.  The problem is that it disappears really fast and can be annoying or hard to read if it is long.</p>
<p>So here is today’s tip!  Right click on the message and choose “View Message”.  Now the message opens in a pop up window that you can change the size of, highlight and copy and paste the details.  When you are finished reading it, you can close it.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DMJobMessage2.jpg?mtime=1337826030"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DMJobMessage2.jpg?mtime=1337826030" width="905" height="441" /></a></div>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DMJobMessage3.jpg?mtime=1337826031"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DMJobMessage3.jpg?mtime=1337826031" width="758" height="363" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/diagnostic-manager-quick-tip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diagnostic Manager &#8211; Custom Alerts</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/diagnostic-manager-custom-alerts/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/diagnostic-manager-custom-alerts/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 09:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Conan]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diagnostic manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/04/diagnostic-manager-custom-alerts/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the great things about Diagnostic Manager is the ability to create custom alerts.  This is something I believe needs a bit more work, but even in its current state, it is really useful.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the great things about Diagnostic Manager is the ability to create custom alerts.  This is something I believe needs a bit more work, but even in its current state, it is really useful.</p>
<p>The example that we&#8217;ll walk through is something that would actually make a great built in alert.  We will create an alert based on the time of our oldest current database backup.</p>
<p>To start off, click on &#8220;Administration&#8221; in the bottom right hand corner:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Administration Menu.JPG?mtime=1332527611"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Administration Menu.JPG?mtime=1332527611" alt="" width="302" height="203" /></a></p>
<p>Next Click on Custom Counters (there are two spots that you can click on for it):</p>
<div class="image_block">
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Administration Menu2.JPG?mtime=1332527857"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Administration Menu2.JPG?mtime=1332527857" alt="" width="603" height="310" /></a></div>
</div>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;">Now in the menu ribbon, click on Add.</div>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Add.jpg?mtime=1332528329"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Add.jpg?mtime=1332528329" alt="" width="364" height="161" /></a></div>
<p>On the first screen of the wizard, click on Next at the bottom.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 1.JPG?mtime=1332528009"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 1.JPG?mtime=1332528009" alt="" width="633" height="564" /></a></div>
<p>We are going to base our Custom Counter/Alert on a SQL Query, so choose the 3rd option: Custom SQL Script.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 2.JPG?mtime=1332528329"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 2.JPG?mtime=1332528329" alt="" width="630" height="558" /></a></div>
<p>On the next screen we add the SQL Query.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 3.JPG?mtime=1332529354"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 3.JPG?mtime=1332529354" alt="" width="639" height="564" /></a></div>
<p><!-- codeblock="tsql" -->
<pre>&lt;code&gt;
SELECT ROUND(MAX(DATEDIFF(MINUTE,LastBackUpTaken,GETDATE()))/60.0,2)  
FROM  
( 
SELECT sdb.Name AS DatabaseName
,COALESCE(MAX(bus.backup_finish_date),GETDATE()-100) AS LastBackUpTaken    
FROM master..sysdatabases sdb    
LEFT OUTER JOIN msdb.dbo.backupset bus    
ON bus.database_name = sdb.name    
WHERE sdb.Name NOT IN ('tempdb','model')   
AND bus.type = 'L'   
GROUP BY sdb.Name  
) 
DBList;</pre>
<p>*Note the code provided above is different from the screenshot. While proof reading this article, I realized that I forgot include the backup type in the query.</p>
<p>On the next screen we want to leave the Customize Calculation Type set to "Use collected value".  We are doing this because we want to base the alert off the most recent value.  If we had chosen to set it to "Use per second value since last collection" then it would base the alert on the difference between the most recent two results of our query.</p>
<p>On the same screen we also want to leave the Customize Scale Factor at 1.  We are doing this because we've already set our query to return the number of hours since the latest current backup was completed.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 4.JPG?mtime=1332529893"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 4.JPG?mtime=1332529893" alt="" width="633" height="563" /></a></div>
<p>If we click on the test button we can run the query on all or some of our monitored instances to ensure it works.  When you are finished testing, click on Done and then Next.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Test.jpg?mtime=1332529893"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Test.jpg?mtime=1332529893" alt="" width="644" height="549" /></a></div>
<p>You want to be sure to put a meaningful and descriptive name on the next screen.  This is the name that will appear in the alerts screen.</p>
<p>For my case, I don't have many custom alerts so I keep keep the category set to Custom for all of them.</p>
<p>I setthe description that you see in the screenshot below so that I include the code to find which databases need to be backed up is at my fingertips.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 5.JPG?mtime=1332531299"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 5.JPG?mtime=1332531299" alt="" width="635" height="563" /></a></div>
<p>On the next screen, we want to choose the option of "Higher values are worse than lower values" because a higher number means it's been longer since the last backup.</p>
<p>I like to set the informational warning at 24 hours.  At that point it is not a problem, but something I want to be aware of.  The warning is set at 26 hours because it could just be that a backup is running long for some reason.  When we hit 28 hours that means that something is definately not right.</p>
<p>This is the type of counter that I want on every instance no matter it is used for, so I check the bottom check box.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 6.JPG?mtime=1332531299"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 6.JPG?mtime=1332531299" alt="" width="634" height="563" /></a></div>
<p>The next screen just tells you that you have completed the wizard and warns you that you still need to link the custom counter to your monitored SQL Instances.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 7.JPG?mtime=1332531299"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 7.JPG?mtime=1332531299" alt="" width="633" height="555" /></a></div>
<p>On the next screen you can select whether or not you want to link this new customer counter your monitored SQL Instances right away.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 8.JPG?mtime=1332531784"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter Wizard 8.JPG?mtime=1332531784" alt="" width="624" height="141" /></a></div>
<p>The other way to link the custom counter is to select the counter and choose link from the menu above it.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter List.jpg?mtime=1332531784"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - Custom Counter List.jpg?mtime=1332531784" alt="" width="595" height="172" /></a></div>
<p>I won't do any screenshots of the screen where you choose which servers to link because it is a very straight forward screen where you select the SQL Instance from the left side and click on the add button.</p>
<p>At the start of this blog post, I mentioned that there are some change that would be really helpful.  What I meant by that is adding the option to include a second query that would be executed and the results displayed as a "drill in" option for the counter.</p>
<p>You can also easily turn this counter into one for log backups</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/diagnostic-manager-custom-alerts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diagnostic Manager &#8211; Viewing History outside of 8AM to 5PM</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/diagnostic-manager/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/diagnostic-manager/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Conan]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diagnostic manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/03/diagnostic-manager/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Prior to being a full-fledged DBA, I was a SQL Developer for a Warehouse Management System called HighJump.  HighJump is a very fast paced system with system owners who partner very closely with IT.  This also means, that I was working closely with peop&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to being a full-fledged DBA, I was a SQL Developer for a Warehouse Management System called HighJump.  HighJump is a very fast paced system with system owners who partner very closely with IT.  This also means, that I was working closely with people who were very sensitive any system issues and wanted answers fast.</p>
<p>I was just making the move from SQL Developer to DBA when I first learned of Idera&#8217;s Diagnostic Manager.  My first task to was to learn more about this product that the DBA who I was replacing convinced my new boss to buy 10 licenses of.</p>
<p>So when I learned that Diagnostic Manager would record the state of the SQL Instance every &#8220;x&#8221; minutes (user defined), I was very excited.  This meant that I could go back in time to see what was happening during the &#8220;the system was slow between 5:00 and 5:30 yesterday morning&#8221;.</p>
<p>The next time I saw an e-mail asking what happened that morning around 4:00AM, I jumped into action.  I opened Diagnostic Manager and clicked on the SQL Instance in question and hit the History Browser window:</p>
<p><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - History Browser Button.jpg?mtime=1331600719"><img style="border-style: initial; border-color: initial;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - History Browser Button.jpg?mtime=1331600719" alt="" width="476" height="130" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">On the right side of the screen, we can now navigate the Calendar to quickly go back to a specific day.  Because the issue I was looking at was from that day, I figured I just needed to scroll down to 4:00 AM and start looking at the different metrics.  Well imagine my surprise when I couldn&#8217;t find anything from before 8:00 AM!  I looked at previous days and they only had data from 8:00 AM to 5:00 PM&#8230;</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: left;">
<p><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - History Browser.jpg?mtime=1331600733"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - History Browser.jpg?mtime=1331600733" alt="" width="234" height="452" /></a></p>
</div>
<p style="text-align: left;">I starting thinking that I missed a setting when I added this Instance.  Maybe Diagnostic Manager is only captures data between 8:00 AM and 5:00 PM?</p>
<p>After looking around for what felt like hours, I sent Idera&#8217;s Support an e-mail.  Idera&#8217;s Support is top notch.  I got a reply within an hour with the exact details that I needed.</p>
<p>If you notice, in the above screenshot there is a blue link right below the Calendar that says &#8220;Between 8:00 AM and 5:00 PM&#8221;.  If you click on that link you will get this screen:</p>
<p><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM - History Browser Options.jpg?mtime=1331600726"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM - History Browser Options.jpg?mtime=1331600726" alt="" width="308" height="218" /></a></p>
<p>Like most people, we are a 24/7/365 shop and I need to be able to look at snapshots from any point of time.  So I chose the top option &#8220;Show all snapshots&#8221;.  Now I can see all of my snapshots!</p>
<p>I encourage you to learn more about Idera and to start a free trial of Diagnostic Manager.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx">https://twitter.com/#!/Idera_Software</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx">http://www.idera.com/Content/Home.aspx</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/diagnostic-manager/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Idera Diagnostic Manager for End Users</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/start-of-a-series-on/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/start-of-a-series-on/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 11:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Conan]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diagnostic manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/03/start-of-a-series-on/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Do you have a group of developers who as soon as their application has any issues they call you because it must be the database server?  Do you have managers who really want to know if all the jobs are running successfully?  Yeah, me too.
That's one of&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you have a group of developers who as soon as their application has any issues they call you because it must be the database server?  Do you have managers who really want to know if all the jobs are running successfully?  Yeah, me too.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s one of the really cool things with Diagnostic Manager.  You can setup security for Active Directory Groups, Active Directory Logins and SQL Logins for read only access in the Console.</p>
<p> </p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/media/users/kconan/DM Security.jpg?mtime=1331558267"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/kconan/DM Security.jpg?mtime=1331558267" alt="" width="1206" height="627" /></a></div>
<p> </p>
<p>(Click Administration in the bottom left corner, then Application Security on the left side)</p>
<p>Now End Users can install the Idera Diagnostic Manager Console to find out the health of the monitored SQL Instances, Job History, blocking, etc. on their own.</p>
<p><span style="font-family: Georgia, serif; font-size: 10pt; background-color: white; line-height: 14.25pt;">At my company, we have dozens of End Users with Diagnostic Manager installed and it does not appear to be having a noticeable impact on the monitored SQL Instances.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/start-of-a-series-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
