<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	>
	<title type="text">Comments on Introducing SQL Server to Oracle</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A Technical Community for IT Professionals</subtitle>

	<updated>2019-02-26T12:40:14Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comments" />
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/feed/atom/" />
	<id>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/feed/atom/</id>
<generator uri="https://wordpress.org/" version="4.6.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Diego</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2255" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Diego</name>
			<uri>http://pinoy-pride.com/gamezone.php?page=playgame&#038;game=4421</uri>
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2255</id>
		<updated>2010-01-20T21:40:04Z</updated>
		<published>2010-01-20T21:40:04Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2255"><![CDATA[<p>I definitely enjoyed reading your insight and learning from your blogsite.  Thank you for the interesting and informative article.  &#8211; Diego</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Erik</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2254" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Erik</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2254</id>
		<updated>2009-12-11T17:46:07Z</updated>
		<published>2009-12-11T17:46:07Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2254"><![CDATA[<p>Oh man, every time I&#8217;ve set up the Oracle client it&#8217;s been hell. It takes me hours every time and I always end up with strange issues. The last time I wanted to install an Oracle instance and the latest version of SQL Developer. The SQL Developer version from the Oracle full install was apparently not the same as the latest version, and I had all sorts of problems trying to decide things like, do I put the two installs in the same home? Wait, which home? Evidently there are two kinds of homes (I can&#8217;t even remember them now). I had to research for many minutes at each step in the install process just to understand what the heck I was being asked.</p>
<p>I also totally dislike how the Oracle software has to do everything all its own way. They can&#8217;t use standard Windows controls like the rest of the planet, no, they have to roll their own controls that don&#8217;t work the same and so add yet more confusion and stumbling around (things like combo boxes and scroll bars and other controls that didn&#8217;t accept my normal keyboard shortcuts I like to use).</p>
<p>Connecting to SQL Server is as easy as knowing its network name and instance name (though usually there isn&#8217;t one) and having some credentials. Oracle&#8217;s text setup file tnsnames requires arcane crazy syntax, and this seems like something that should go the way of ini files: right into the void as an outdated technology from 15 years ago.</p>
<p>Comparing how easy it is to set up a SQL Server instance with or without client tools, and the ease of connecting to a new server, earns a huge black eye for Oracle in my opinion. I&#8217;m not an Oracle DBA and don&#8217;t plan to ever be one; but I do need to work with Oracle databases sometimes, and I think it shouldn&#8217;t be that hard.</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Jamie Thomson</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2253" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Jamie Thomson</name>
			<uri>http://sqlblog.com/blogs/jamie_thomson/</uri>
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2253</id>
		<updated>2009-12-11T15:55:29Z</updated>
		<published>2009-12-11T15:55:29Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2253"><![CDATA[<p>I feel your pain with the Oracle client. It *is* difficult to install. Maybe/Probably that&#8217;s because of my familiarity with SQL Server and its tools but regardless&#8230;I found it hard!!</p>
<p>-Jamie</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Ted Krueger (onpnt)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2252" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Ted Krueger (onpnt)</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2252</id>
		<updated>2009-12-11T15:22:50Z</updated>
		<published>2009-12-11T15:22:50Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2252"><![CDATA[<p>Unfortunately there was nothing standard about the Oracle database that I had to deal with (but is there ever?!).  I was forced to handle constraints with key tables in my SQL Server DB in order to retain my integrity of the data.  On import I have to custom join based on look ups what data is required to come in and bring the relating data along with it.  I made several passes with about 4 different methods in SSIS to handle this and it came down to a very basic way of using the SQL Server side joined to the Oracle side on keys to run down to several data flow tasks with a few needs of script transforms and then simple data conversions.  All in all I have an almost replica of Oracle in SQL Server with about 20 added tables to handle the poor design issues.  The Direct import of all the tables from Oracle to SQL Server is really just that.  Every table is brought over as a snapshot in time of the Oracle database.  During the extract I take the data that is required to perform on the SQL Server side as it needs to and make it relational in my own design.  The one thing this did to my development time was lengthen the validation and UAT process of the finish process and objects the user accepts.  </p>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to point the finger of bad database design but this one was horrid.  Keys were hidden in long char columns that forced my substring abilities to the end while keeping the import quick.  The only thing I had on my side was the fact I could limit the import to a point in time and the hours on which the data was changing is a set shift.  If the process changes and the operation of this one database goes 24/7, the entire ETL side will have to be revisited and I will look to replication I think or go with query tuning over ETL tuning.  On a side note, the only major hassle was date conversions when it came to data type issues.  I think anyone that has done this feels that though.  </p>
<p>I actually set a linked server up for the only purpose of validations while doing all this work and I know what you&#8217;re saying.  Very painful!  </p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s enjoyable putting this kind of new object into the daily mix that you feel comfortable with.  New challenges are alway exciting but yes, that is weird 😉</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: sensware</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2251" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>sensware</name>
			<uri>http://blog.sqlpositive.com/</uri>
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2251</id>
		<updated>2009-12-11T14:38:13Z</updated>
		<published>2009-12-11T14:38:13Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2251"><![CDATA[<p>One thing I&#8217;m curious is:<br />
How did you transformed the rest of Oracle objects?  (e.g. Sequences, Triggers, Constraints etc)<br />
Was this the manual that your team will be working on?</p>
<p>
BTW: I know your pain about tnsnames.ora and setting the listeners on networks but once you work with Oracle for a while you get the hang of it.<br />
I for one would like to work in an environment w/ Oracle and SQL server &#8230; haven&#8217;t found it yet. (and yes I am a little weird) 🙂</p>
<p>One thing that is more painful is setting up Oracle Linked servers and assigning security over those&#8230; that one is pretty messed up!</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: Ted Krueger (onpnt)</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2250" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>Ted Krueger (onpnt)</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2250</id>
		<updated>2009-12-11T14:05:41Z</updated>
		<published>2009-12-11T14:05:41Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2250"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I set much higher but I also have a line designated for data so I was able to do that without killing the network IO for others</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: SQLDenis</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2249" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2249</id>
		<updated>2009-12-11T13:59:11Z</updated>
		<published>2009-12-11T13:59:11Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2249"><![CDATA[<p>Out of curiosity&#8230;did you increase packet size when copying large amount of data?</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>By: SQLDenis</title>
		<link rel="alternate" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2248" type="text/html" />

		<author>
			<name>SQLDenis</name>
			
		</author>

		<id>/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2248</id>
		<updated>2009-12-11T13:58:11Z</updated>
		<published>2009-12-11T13:58:11Z</published>
		<content type="html" xml:base="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/#comment-2248"><![CDATA[<p>At least you don&#8217;t have to deal with FoxPro or Access&#8230;&#8230;Excel is another painpoint..but I heard that you are the Excel master and that you actually like XNF (Excel Normal Form) data sets  🙂</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t even get me started about SalesForce or PeopleSoft</p>
<p>Seriously&#8230;. heterogeneous, disparate database systems are always a pain in the neck&#8230; luckily we have tools these days like SSIS and JitterBit</p>
]]></content>
		<thr:in-reply-to ref="/index.php/2009/12/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/introducing-sql-server-to-oracle/" type="text/html" />
	</entry>
</feed>
