<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>biml &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/biml/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dealing with the mysterious “True” column in BIML</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/dealing-with-the-mysterious-true-column-in-biml/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/dealing-with-the-mysterious-true-column-in-biml/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 14:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bids helper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biml]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[issue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2423</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently I ran into the following error when compiling BIML into SSIS packages: The message itself is not very revealing: The data type for input buffer column ‘True’ on the ScriptComponent input buffer ‘Input0’ does not match the mapped output column from the previous transformation. You might have guessed it already; there is no column [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">Recently I ran into the following error when compiling BIML into SSIS packages:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/BIMLissue.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2425" alt="BIMLissue" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/BIMLissue.png" width="1200" height="92" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/BIMLissue.png 1200w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/02/BIMLissue-300x23.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/02/BIMLissue-1024x78.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The message itself is not very revealing:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><i>The data type for input buffer column ‘True’ on the ScriptComponent input buffer ‘Input0’ does not match the mapped output column from the previous transformation.</i></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">You might have guessed it already; there is no column called <b>True</b> in the data flow. A quick Google search brought back this topic on the Varigence forums: <a href="http://www.varigence.com/Forums?threadID=289">Error: Script Transformation</a>. However, uninstalling BIDS Helper and installing an older version (and possible lose other functionality) is not an option. Besides, the BIML code worked when I generated the package for another table, so BIDS Helper was not to blame.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">After a quick debug using Messageboxes – so old school and <a href="http://www.bimlgeek.com/1/post/2013/08/using-windows-forms-messageboxshow-to-debug-bimlscript.html">it is possible in BIMLScript by the way</a> – I confirmed it had nothing to do with the C# code generating the BIML.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">So let’s take another good look at the error message. It mentions something about data types not being correct. All the data types were simple varchars, numerics and datetimes and I was sure I mapped them to the corresponding <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.data.dbtype(v=vs.110).aspx">DBType</a>. After all, the code works for other tables.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">And then it hit me: the destination table had some columns with a greater length than the source column. For example varchar(250) instead of varchar(213). I enlarged them to deal with the risk of other sources being added with larger columns. In the SSIS data flow, the metadata of the columns is derived from the columns returned by the source query. However, in the script component I specified the metadata of the destination columns, all having another length. I changed the lengths of the destination columns, lo and behold, the BIML script compiled successfully. Apparently SSIS (or BIML) has some serious issues of the metadata of an input column doesn&#8217;t match 100% the metadata of the output column of the previous component.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">If now only one of the kind BIML developers would substitute <i>true</i> with the actual column name, life would be much easier.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/ssis/dealing-with-the-mysterious-true-column-in-biml/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>T-SQL Tuesday #50: Automation, how much of it is the same?</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/t-sql-tuesday-50-automation/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/t-sql-tuesday-50-automation/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 09:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biml]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsql2sday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2240</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s the second Tuesday of the New Year, so here comes the first T-SQL Tuesday of 2014! SQLChow (blog &#124; twitter) has the honour to host this jubilee edition of the world famous blog party. The theme of this month is the utterly DBA-related topic of Automation. However, it is pretty easy to give it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="http://sqlchow.wordpress.com/2014/01/07/t-sql-tuesday-050-automation-how-much-of-it-is-the-same/"><img class="alignleft" alt="TSQL2sday" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/TSQL2sday.png" width="120" height="121" /></a>It’s the second Tuesday of the New Year, so here comes the first T-SQL Tuesday of 2014! SQLChow (<a href="http://sqlchow.wordpress.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/SqlChow">twitter</a>) has the honour to host this jubilee edition of the world famous blog party. The theme of this month is the utterly DBA-related topic of <i>Automation</i>. However, it is pretty easy to give it a BI spin.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Even we measly BI developers can automate some parts of the development. I’m talking about BIML, a metadata driven markup language (XML for the people that like acronyms) that can generate SSIS packages like you’ve never seen before. BIML is developed by the nice people at <a href="http://www.varigence.com/">Varigence</a> and an open-source implementation is available in the widely popular Visual Studio add-in <a href="http://bidshelper.codeplex.com/">BIDS Helper</a>, which you can download for free at Codeplex. This post will not explain what BIDS exactly is and how it works; I already did that in an article series at MSSQLTips.com. You can find those <a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3094/introduction-to-business-intelligence-markup-language-biml-for-ssis/">here</a>, <a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3115/using-biml-to-generate-an-ssis-import-package/">here</a> and <a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3124/generate-multiple-ssis-packages-using-biml-and-metadata/">here</a>. Make sure you also check the very excellent resources I link to at the bottom of the articles. The key point you need to remember is that you can use metadata (data about how and where your data is stored) and some scripting with .NET and XML to generate SSIS packages on the fly.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The only way a solution with BIDS can work is that you have a lot of the same (see how I referred to the title? Extra bonus points.) Developing a BIML script to generate a single package is just plain crazy. It is much easier to do this directly in BIDS (SSDT/SSDTBI) instead of meddling with those XML tags. However, if you can generate a whole bunch of packages in one single click – for example 20 packages importing flat files or 15 packages doing incremental loads for dimensions – you just saved yourself a whole bunch of time. And that’s where the strength of BIML lies. Take a look at your projects and your SSIS packages and see if you can recognize patterns between them. I bet you can find some. These are opportunities to save a bunch of tedious development effort.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">To give an example: in my current project, I created a few packages that all do the same thing: read from the source, calculate a hash value, do a lookup on the destination table and determine if a row is an insert or an update (using the hash value). Inserts are directly sent to the destination table, updates are sent to a staging table. Using this staging table a set-based update is issued against the destination table. Finally a SQL statement checks if rows from the destination table are missing in the source (deletes) and a delete flag is marked for those rows. This pattern was exactly the same for each package. Due to time constraints I couldn’t develop a BIML script because it would take me the same amount of time to develop those packages by hand (about 2 days) and there was a hard deadline. However, I will see if I can find time in the following weeks to develop a BIML script anyway, because I know sources will be added in the future. And when they do, I just need to fill in some metadata in a table and the package will be generated with a simple click. This will potentially saves days of work, and I can always take the script to other projects where similar patterns are needed.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">So BI developers, what are you waiting for? Automate!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/t-sql-tuesday-50-automation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Create ETL solutions faster with metadata driven development – Session Materials</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/create-etl-solutions-faster-with/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/create-etl-solutions-faster-with/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 12:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biml]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlserverdays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/11/create-etl-solutions-faster-with/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week was the 2013 edition of the SQL Server Days. It was an amazing event: there was a great audience, fantastic speakers and nice booths by the sponsors (especially the bar with Belgian beer was pretty awesome). It was great meeting up with the #s&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Last week was the 2013 edition of the SQL Server Days. It was an amazing event: there was a great audience, fantastic speakers and nice booths by the sponsors (especially the bar with Belgian beer was pretty awesome). It was great meeting up with the #sqlfamily again.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Anyway, I gave a session about using <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/ssis/speaking-about-biml">BIML</a> to generate SSIS packages based on metadata. The session went pretty well: demos didn’t crash and the audience had some good questions (which I was luckily able to answer).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For those of you interested, you can download the slide deck of the session – which contains a lot of links to very useful resources – at <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/KoenVerbeeck/sql-server-days-2013-create-etl-solutions-faster-with-metadata-driven-development">slideshare</a>. I used a small application I wrote to upload flat file metadata to a database. You can find the code <a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SSD2013/MetadataLoader.zip?mtime=1384287593">here</a>. I do not provide any support however and using it is at your own risk. A zip file with sample flat files, the .sql scripts and the BIML script used in the demos can be downloaded <a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SSD2013/GenerateSSISWithBIML.zip">here</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you attended the session, I hope you enjoyed it and that you consider using BIML in your next projects.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">See you at the SQL Server Days next year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/mssqlserver/create-etl-solutions-faster-with/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speaking about BIML at the SQL Server Days 2013</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/speaking-about-biml/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/speaking-about-biml/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 11:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server Admin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biml]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlserverdays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqlug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/10/speaking-about-biml/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’m very thrilled to be selected again as a speaker for the sixth edition of the SQL Server Days! The biggest SQL Server event of the year in Belgium, with lots of learning opportunities for developers, BI folks and DBAs. This event is organized by SQLU&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">I’m very thrilled to be selected again as a speaker for the sixth edition of the SQL Server Days! The biggest SQL Server event of the year in Belgium, with lots of learning opportunities for developers, BI folks and DBAs. This event is organized by SQLUG, the Belgian SQL Server user group.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://sqlug.be/"><img style="float: left;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SSD2013/sql_ug_logo.jpg?mtime=1381828300" alt="" width="133" height="75" /></a></p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">My session is titled </span><em>Create ETL solutions faster with metadata driven development</em><span style="text-align: justify;"> and shows you how you can use </span><a style="text-align: justify;" href="http://www.varigence.com/Products/Biml/Capabilities">BIML</a><span style="text-align: justify;"> and metadata to create SSIS solutions dynamically. The abstract is as follows:</span></p>
<p><em>Working on your 20th staging package? Do you need to import 30 different flat files? Don’t have the time to create all those packages?</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>By using Biml – Business Intelligence Markup Language – you can describe your BI solution in a declarative fashion. You can turn tedious, repetitive work into reusable scripts which generate SSIS packages for you, cutting back drastically on development time.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>This session will introduce you to Biml and get you started on building reusable patterns for common BI tasks.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Of course, my session is not the only good one. There are tons of great speakers that will bring awesome amounts of knowledge and learning to this great event: <a href="http://kevinekline.com/">Kevin Kline</a>, <a href="http://weblogs.sqlteam.com/mladenp/default.aspx">Mladen Prajdic</a>, <a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/stacia_misner/">Stacia Misner</a>, <a href="http://thomaslarock.com/">Thomas “bacon” Larock</a>, <a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/ilikesql_by_dandyman/">Dandy Weyn</a>, <a href="http://markgstacey.net/">Mark G Stacey</a>, <a href="http://sqlblog.com/blogs/marco_russo/default.aspx">Marco Russo</a>, <a href="http://www.purplefrogsystems.com/blog/">Alex Whittles</a>, <a href="http://www.scottlklein.com/">Scott Klein</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sqlwaldorf">Nico Jacobs</a>, <a href="http://blog.hoegaerden.be/">Valentino Vranken</a> and many more! There are 5 precon tracks at November 7<sup>th</sup> and 5 regular tracks at November 8<sup>th</sup> with <a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/2013/agenda">25 sessions</a>!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For more practical details I gladly refer you to the <a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/2013/">SQL Server Days website</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For the moment there is a great price deal: every registered attendee can bring a colleague for free! What are you waiting for?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/2013/bring-a-colleague-for-free"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/SSD2013/byoc.jpg?mtime=1381828293" alt="" width="472" height="196" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbadmin/mssqlserveradmin/speaking-about-biml/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
