<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Windows 8 &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/sysadmins/windows-8/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Windows 10, how I doth hateth thee mostest</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tahir Khalid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Professionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[System Admins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 8.1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[How&#8217;s it going folks, thought I&#8217;d get another post written up before I switch over to video logs in the future (watch this space). So I don&#8217;t really need to do a big introduction to Windows 10, there was a lot of buzz going about the internet not least due in part to the upgrade [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How&#8217;s it going folks, thought I&#8217;d get another post written up before I switch over to video logs in the future (watch this space).</p>
<p>So I don&#8217;t really need to do a big introduction to Windows 10, there was a lot of buzz going about the internet not least due in part to the upgrade icon that appeared in the notification tray (from Windows 7 to Windows 8.1) and like many people I became curious as to what exactly Windows 10 would mean to me and the rest of the world. I hadn&#8217;t looked at the beta and the RC releases that came out for Windows 10 even through they were available to developers about a year ago but this was mostly because I had made the jump from Windows 7 to Windows 8 (ouch) and then to Windows 8.1 Professional (easily the best version to date but more on this later).</p>
<p>I remember some of the early hype surrounding Windows 10 namely around the technology and what it would offer (the same sort of hype that appeared before Windows 7 was released to the wild) but the biggest one was how it would revolutionise the Windows desktop and make development more exciting with the introduction of dedicated tools for Universal App&#8217;s &#8211; great I thought this could be a step in the right direction. We had seen some of the buzz already with the announcement of ASP.NET 5 and related technologies such as .NET Core as well as releasing chunks of the code to the community via github (<a title="Announcing ASP.NET 5" href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/AnnouncingNET2015NETAsOpenSourceNETOnMacAndLinuxAndVisualStudioCommunity.aspx" target="_blank">ASP.NET 5</a>).  Along with this news we saw Visual Studio Community Edition and Visual Studio Code hinting at a future where we would not be tied down to a Windows desktop and could code on anything from Linux to OS X  &#8211; more cool stuff! So I bought into the hype and I reserved my copy and while I did not have a compelling reason to upgrade from a rock solid Windows 8.1 Professional platform (running on an HP Elitebook 8560w Mobile Workstation) I was hopeful that Windows 10 would build on the great work of Windows 8.1 (wishful thinking I know).</p>
<p>Before I hear &#8220;ah but Windows 8 was crap dude it was the Vista of this generation!&#8221;, yes true but Windows 8.1 for me was the saving grace, they got it right but due to some negligence or poor marketing most of the general public had no clue that Windows 8.1 was an entirely different product, better in a million ways (and most still don&#8217;t know this) so they chose to ignore it and stick to Windows 7 (which still ins&#8217;t a bad move). I have to give it to Microsoft, they generated the right buzz by allowing people to reserve their digital download of Windows 10.  Word-of-mouth is powerful marketing tool and that&#8217;s exactly what happened here (albeit through the power of social media like Twitter, Facebook and Email) and in this case it was enough to get people to want to get their digital copy of Windows 10 and install it including myself where I couldn&#8217;t wait so I went ahead and downloaded <a title="Windows 10 Download Toolkit" href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windows10" target="_blank"><strong>this</strong></a> toolkit from Microsoft to create my own ISO locally.</p>
<p>After following the instructions to create the external media, I selected ISO and waited while the toolkit proceeded to download the necessary files and create an ISO for me (I recommend you go make a cup of tea at this point).  After the ISO was created I extracted the files to a folder on my C:\ drive and then ran the setup and followed the on-screen instructions to upgrade Windows 8.1 to Windows 10 (choosing to retain my Data &amp; Apps).   This was quite a smooth process all but 1 of my applications worked however here is where the fun started&#8230; We are led to believe that the upgrade process is seamless however its was anything but, I had to reinstall all my drivers for them to work again (even though Windows 10 reported everything as being functional) and if you don&#8217;t do this you will start experiencing strange problems from your SSD drive not running at full speed, CPU running in a stepped state to sound being 50% of its actual volume.</p>
<p>About an hour later I was up and running properly and Windows 10 started to behave, initially very impressed, loved the subtle desktop UI design touches and this time almost everything has a WPF interface to it which is great (to a point) but again Microsoft screwed up here as some screens are just not thought out properly where a typical WinForms dialog has not been thoughtfully transformed over to it&#8217;s WPF counterpart or rather it&#8217;s been over engineered and what should be a simple interface becomes a multi-screen click nightmare (more on this later). Then we have the issue with the CPU running hot. On my humble HP Mobile Workstation I have to keep an eye on the CPU temp as it can run hot (as it&#8217;s meant to) but I had it set up a particular way in Windows 8.1 (using a combination of <a title="Core Temp" href="http://alcpu.com/CoreTemp/" target="_blank">Core Temp </a>and the awesome <a title="Notebook FanControl" href="https://github.com/hirschmann/nbfc" target="_blank">Notebook FanControl</a> by <span style="font-weight: bold">Stefan Hirschmann) </span>so that the system ran cool and quiet more often however the same did not transfer over to Windows 10 so easily and I found for whatever reason the CPU was running at least 5% hotter than on Windows 8.1 and more often (and this seems to be a common problem where many notebook users have reverted back to Windows 7 due to this issue). So what would be causing this problem and why?</p>
<p>Try as I might I could not pin point the issue and Windows 10 would not give up any clues suggesting everything was idle when it obviously wasn&#8217;t and the CPU was busy doing something in the background.  Eventually I found the culprit but try to remedy the problems actually broke Windows 10 functionality and let me explain how. The reason the CPU was running hotter is because it was actually busy doing some work for Cortana, the humble Paperclip evolved through AI, sex change acquiring a female voice and making you believe it can do anything (no Cortana&#8217;s last name is not Jenner, I did check). I saw this before, in Windows 7 a long time ago and some people caught on to what Microsoft was up to and these invisible background processes were removed form subsequent service pack releases.</p>
<p>In the case of Windows 10 you are literally lied to, nothing is reported as running, the event viewer screen doesn&#8217;t record any activity yet when you fire up Systools Process Monitor there is a feint trace of activity &#8211; this behavior is the same as what malware and malicious applications have, not good Microsoft! So to follow up on my hunch I disabled the search features of Cortana complete, opted out of the other sub features and while this reduced the CPU activity (and heat) it did not completely remedy the problem as the CPU was still obviously doing something causing it to heat up &#8211; one idea could be drivers but surely Microsoft would have had plenty of time to sort this out especially for something as common as an i7 QuadCore sandybridge CPU.</p>
<p>But that wasn&#8217;t the last of my issues either; At this point I was quite satisfied I had remedied the teething problems (to be expected with a new system) and was willing to give Windows 10 another go (heck I had been praising it on Twitter for days) but then I was horrified to find the system had been crippled because I had disabled Cortana and the other sub features but we are never made aware of this and Microsoft for obvious reasons didn&#8217;t announce this fact either. So what are the symptoms?  Firstly you will notice the new Start panel doesn&#8217;t work properly, some tiles don&#8217;t appear, some apps won&#8217;t show up on the search and fundamental core applications simply disappear unless you enable search features again&#8230;why would Microsoft do this, what a shitty thing to do!</p>
<p>So this obviously had me concerned as did the fact that Cortana wanted to know EVERYTHING about me, intercept everything I did, socially and via messaging to which said &#8220;YOU&#8217;RE HAVING A LAUGH MATE!&#8221; and promptly renamed Cortana to something else beginning with C and ending with Face. I had a moan on Twitter obviously at this point and to be fair Microsoft Support were quick to respond asking me to try using the built-in feedback and support application, cool&#8230;hold on you muppets that won&#8217;t work because I disabled Cortana so that native application doesn&#8217;t appear anymore but wait there is more bullcakes to follow.</p>
<p>I then followed the link in Windows 10 to join some program that lets me get early releases of updates and software which in turn also enables the feedback feature however this is stuck in an infinite loop of death and you never ever get the feedback app or get to actually provide any feedback &#8211; dipshits! To add insult to injury I was then tweeted to use their support website but get this, I have to pay for that support &#8211; really WTF?!  I had a total nerd rage at this point and told Microsoft to do one and promptly wiped windows 10 and went back to Windows 8.1 Professional, peace at least (for a while). <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter.png"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4122" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter-229x300.png" alt="windows-10-twitter" width="229" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter-229x300.png 229w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/windows-10-twitter.png 683w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /></a></p>
<p>So I was going to mention a bunch of other crap with Windows 10? Well here is a list:</p>
<ul>
<li>DPI sucks big time, wtf were Microsoft thinking, just give us proper DPI control over the screens (why do I have to go search the internet for a registry hack)</li>
<li>Key power features hidden or removed like Group Policy Editor that you as an administrator can&#8217;t administer</li>
<li>Windows Themes: You have to go through a convoluted series of screens to something called slideshow to then go to a Windows 7 personalisation screen that has key controls missing!!!</li>
<li>Can&#8217;t use older applications at all, Windows 10 will block them even though they WILL work fine (only way round is to hack the registry again)</li>
<li>Some registry changes/hacks are overridden by Windows 10 and restored to default settings wiping your FIXES</li>
<li>You CANNOT opt out of Automatic Updates and this is wrong, period</li>
</ul>
<p>The biggest issue for me is that Windows 10 is essentially a full blown anti-privacy tool and there is no way to opt out of this.  Free is most certainly not free here and I would advise people to read the terms and conditions that we all click through without noticing because there is some scary stuff in there like Microsoft being able to access your mic, camera and data on your Windows 10 OS as they see fit whenever they want, no thanks. Here is an interesting video for you guys: <a title="Do not install Windows 10" href="https://youtu.be/tWs6mk-HWLk" target="_blank">https://youtu.be/tWs6mk-HWLk</a> Finally if you do downgrade like I did, you need to be aware that Microsoft will attempt to force Windows 10 on you so you need to remove some things using <a title="Remove GWA" href="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/get-rid-windows-10-upgrade-notification-windows-7-8/" target="_blank"><strong>this guide</strong></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-10-how-i-doth-hateth-thee-mostest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enabling Hyper-V Platform in a Windows 8.1 VM</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 03:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Davis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/12/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This weekend I decided to take advantage of the Windows Phone Preview Program for Developers and update my Lumia 920 to Update 3 for WP8.  While Update 3 was downloading and installing on my phone, I decided to install the Windows Phone SDK 8.0 which;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend I decided to take advantage of the <a href="http://dev.windowsphone.com/en-us/featured/update3">Windows Phone Preview Program for Developers</a> and update my Lumia 920 to Update 3 for WP8.  While Update 3 was downloading and installing on my phone, I decided to install the Windows Phone SDK 8.0 which includes Visual Studio Express for Windows Phone on a Win 8.1 VM that I use for development purposes.</p>
<p>Installation was quick and painless until the very end when I received a message stating that the installation was unable to enable Hyper-V.  When I tried to enable it manually by going into Control Panel -&gt; Programs &amp; Features -&gt; Turn Windows Features On or Off, the Hyper-V Platform checkbox was grayed out.  Upon hovering over the check box I received a tool tip stating &#8220;Hyper-V cannot be installed: A Hypervisor is Already Running&#8221;.</p>
<p>At this point I was confused as I had previously installed VS Express for Windows Phone on another VM and had successfully run it along with the emulator (the emulator runs in Hyper-V).  Because of this I knew the VM host machine was correctly setup to allow VM Workstation to run virtualized environments within VM&#8217;s.  I then compared the two VM&#8217;s and found there were a few differences:</p>
<ul>
<li>Original install was an older version of VS Express for Windows Phone</li>
<li> Original install was on a Windows 8 VM </li>
<li>New install was the latest version of VS Express for Windows Phone </li>
<li>New install was on a Windows 8.1 VM </li>
<li>Both VM&#8217;s are running on VM Workstation 9.0.1 </li>
</ul>
<p>After reviewing the two VM&#8217;s I realized there must be something different with either the latest version of VS Express for Windows Phone, Windows 8.1, or both. Doing a little more research I found there were two things I needed to do:</p>
<ol>
<li>Enable &#8220;Virtualize Intel VT-x/EPT or AMD-V/RVI&#8221; in the settings of the VM
<div class="image_block"><a href="/media/users/brian78/HyperV/VMSettings.png?mtime=1387680976"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/brian78/HyperV/VMSettings.png?mtime=1387680976" alt="" width="362" height="140" /></a></div>
</li>
<li>Open the .vmx file for the virtual machine in a text editor and add the following lines to the end of it
<ol>
<li>hypervisor.cpuid.v0 = &#8220;FALSE&#8221;</li>
<li>mce.enable = &#8220;TRUE&#8221;</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>After doing both of these I started the VM and intended to go back in and turn on Hyper-V, however, when I got back to the settings I was happy to see that &#8220;Hyper-V Platform&#8221; was already enabled.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/media/users/brian78/HyperV/WinFeatures.png?mtime=1387680966"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/users/brian78/HyperV/WinFeatures.png?mtime=1387680966" alt="" width="415" height="364" /></a></div>
<p>ï¿½</p>
<p>With Hyper-V successfully enabled and running I was then able to run VS Express for Windows Phone along with the Windows Phone Emulator.</p>
<p>By the time I was finished with this, Update 3 had successfully installed on my phone and I was ready to go.  Now, not only do I not have to wait for AT&amp;T to release updates, but I can start developing apps for my phone as well.  Now I just need to find the spare time and start developing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/windows/enabling-hyper-v-platform-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Download Windows 8.1 preview right now</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/download-windows-8-1-preview/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/download-windows-8-1-preview/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 18:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 8.1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/06/download-windows-8-1-preview/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you want to try out Windows 8.1 preview right now, you can. Be aware that when you install Windows 8.1 preview that you will have to reinstall all your apps. If you then upgrade to the final RTM version you will have to do this again. 

Going from&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you want to try out Windows 8.1 preview right now, you can. Be aware that when you install Windows 8.1 preview that you will have to reinstall all your apps. If you then upgrade to the final RTM version you will have to do this again. </p>
<p>Going from Windows 8 to Windows 8.1 RTM does not have this reinstall requirement nonsense</p>
<p>You can download Windows 8.1 preview here http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-8/download-preview</p>
<p>To see what is new in Windows 8.1, check out the <a href="http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=302189">Windows 8.1 Preview Product Guide.</a></p>
<p>Here is also a video showing Windows 8.1</p>
[video:youtube:VQb5caeSo00]
<p>Here is another video released today, this is is an ad really<br />
[video:youtube:7BN0W7CONpw]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/download-windows-8-1-preview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 5 minute guide to get started with Windows 8</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/the-5-minute-guide-to/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/the-5-minute-guide-to/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 06:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLArcher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Operating Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/09/the-5-minute-guide-to/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Windows 8 has been a hot topic of late - especially getting started with it. We already had a post from our very own Denis Gobo (@denisgobo) in how to shut down Windows 8. This led me to write a quick post on some features you may or may not know of.

Wi&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Windows 8 has been a hot topic of late &#8211; especially getting started with it. We already had a post from our very own Denis Gobo (<a href="http://www.twitter.com/denisgobo">@denisgobo</a>) in <a href="/index.php/SysAdmins/windows-8/how-to-shutdown-windows-8">how to shut down Windows 8</a>. This led me to write a quick post on some features you may or may not know of.</p>
<p>Windows 8 has a great design for touch screens, and some great shortcuts for the PC User as well. I&#8217;ve been using it since Consumer Preview and to be honest &#8211; it did take a week or so to get used to the new interface. There are one or two tricks, that when you know them, make it a lot easier to work with as a PC User.</p>
<p>To start of with, I am going to talk a bit about charms. Charms is the new &#8220;navigation&#8221; for Windows 8 &#8211; it appears on the right hand side whenever you move your mouse to either the top right, or bottom right corners of the screen.</p>
<p>This will bring up the following:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/Charms_Menu.jpg?mtime=1347266235"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/Charms_Menu.jpg?mtime=1347266235" width="270" height="1079" /></a></div>
<p>In order they are:</p>
<p>1. Search<br />
2. Share<br />
3. Windows 8 UI<br />
4. Devices<br />
5. Settings</p>
<p>There is one thing about charms which is a very subtle yet powerful feature&#8230; it is context sensitive! Depending which application is active, will depend what charms enables you to do. Some of you might have downloaded the Wikipedia app (for example) from the store; good looking, side scrolling; so how do you search? With the charms menu, just open it up and search whatever you&#8217;re looking for. For those of you which lives in a suffocated broadband area like me &#8211; this is also where you go to limit the amount of data which live tiles uses in the Win8UI (this however is only from RTM onwards).</p>
<p>Another handy feature is Flip-2D &#8211; better known as the 3D Aero flip in Windows Vista/7. This is done by moving your mouse to the top left corner of the screen, or pressing WIN + Tab.</p>
<p>It looks similar to this:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView.jpg?mtime=1347266256"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView.jpg?mtime=1347266256" width="441" height="524" /></a></div>
<p>When it is fully expanded it will look like this (this one is cropped, at the bottom you will have the link to the Win8UI):</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView_2.jpg?mtime=1347267039"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/QuickView_2.jpg?mtime=1347267039" width="187" height="374" /></a></div>
<p>A big question would be why to use this one instead of ALT + Tab? While ALT + Tab cycles through both the desktop apps and your Win8 apps, the WIN + Tab allows you to select an individual application and pin it either side of your screen directly if you do not want to close your active application. Apart from this, the only other difference is that it does not cycle through desktop applications.</p>
<p>The last quick feature is the poweruser menu, which is accessible by right clicking on the Win8UI shortcut on the bottom left of the screen:</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/PowerUser.jpg?mtime=1347266245"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/sqlarcher/Windows8Guide/PowerUser.jpg?mtime=1347266245" width="351" height="395" /></a></div>
<p>This gives you quick access to control panel, command line, etc. which is very useful.</p>
<p>The last most notable feature is Hyper-V which is available in Windows 8 Pro and Enterprise editions, with the limit being an x64 edition with a SLAT capable CPU. This is very handy especially when you build and destroy multiple virtual machines and do not want to install a Server edition on your Computer/Laptop or if you do not have access to a separate virtual environment. This is enabled via the add/program features.</p>
<p>One last shortcut that I find extremely useful when working with SQL Server Data Tools, Management Studio, etc. is CTRL + Shift. When holding these two keys and launching an application from Win8UI, this immediately launches the application in Administrator Mode.</p>
<p>If there is any features you find handy, feel free to leave a comment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/the-5-minute-guide-to/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to name groups of tiles in Windows 8</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/how-to-name-groups-of/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/how-to-name-groups-of/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/08/how-to-name-groups-of/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Take a look at my Windows 8 start screen



As you can see, I have a main and an apps tile group

Below is an image of all my grouped tiles


So how do you do accomplish this?]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is a view of my Windows 8 start screen</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/7801193080/" title="Windows 8 start screen visible part"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8299/7801193080_06ab747d2a.jpg" width="500" height="313" alt="Windows 8 start screen visible part" /></a></p>
<p>As you can see, I have given my group of tiles a name, there is a main and an apps tile group, there are more which are not visible unless you scroll.</p>
<p>So how do you do name a group of tiles?</p>
<p>What you have to do first is click on the minimize sign in the right bottom corner of your screen</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling2.png?mtime=1345253387"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling2.png?mtime=1345253387" width="168" height="151" /></a></p>
<p>Once you click the minimize sign, you will see that all your tiles are now visible</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/7801049122/" title="Windows 8 Layout"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7801049122_23ed09a373.jpg" width="500" height="313" alt="Windows 8 Layout" /></a></p>
<p>Now right click on one group of the tiles<br />
<a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling3.png?mtime=1345253395"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling3.png?mtime=1345253395" width="291" height="191" /></a><br />
<br />You should see a check mark now</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling4.png?mtime=1345253403"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling4.png?mtime=1345253403" width="370" height="447" /></a></p>
<p>Besides the  check mark, you will also see a name group icon, click on this icon, you will now see a box where you can type the name for the group</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling5.png?mtime=1345253410"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Labeling5.png?mtime=1345253410" width="332" height="214" /></a><br />
Give the group a name that you like and you will see that name appear above the group of icons</p>
<p>Back to the image where you can see how I named my groups of tiles</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/denisgobo/7801049122/" title="Windows 8 Layout"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7801049122_23ed09a373.jpg" width="500" height="313" alt="Windows 8 Layout" /></a></p>
<p>You can move groups around once you are in the minimized view mode, just click on a group and drag it where you want to place it</p>
<p>I installed the RTM version of Windows 8 less than 48 hours ago and I can tell you that I will never want to go back to Windows 7, Windows 8 is noticeable faster than Windows 7 and I think the changes are for the better. There is no real need for a start menu, whenever you need something just start typing. If I want to run Excel, all I have to do is type <em>exc</em> and hit enter. If you don&#8217;t hit enter, you will see something like the following</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/StartExcel.png?mtime=1345254983"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/StartExcel.png?mtime=1345254983" width="425" height="191" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/how-to-name-groups-of/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to shutdown windows 8</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/how-to-shutdown-windows-8/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/how-to-shutdown-windows-8/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 20:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/08/how-to-shutdown-windows-8/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you installed Windows 8, you might be wondering how to shut down or restart this operating system. There is no more start button so where do you start?

There are a couple of ways to shut down the operating system

1) Hit CTRL + ALT + DELETE and&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you installed Windows 8, you might be wondering how to shut down or restart this operating system. There is no start button anymore so where do you shut it down?</p>
<p>There are a couple of ways to shut down the operating system</p>
<p>1) Hit CTRL + ALT + DELETE and then click on the power button in the lower right corner</p>
<p>2) Move the mouse to the upper right corner of you screen and wait for the charms bar to appear, click on settings, now click on power</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Win8pic2.png?mtime=1345241321"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Win8pic2.png?mtime=1345241321" width="302" height="277" /></a></div>
<p>Now you will get a couple of choices, pick the one you want</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Win8pic3.png?mtime=1345241327"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/SysAdmins/Win8pic3.png?mtime=1345241327" width="285" height="310" /></a></div>
<p>3) Hit Windows Key + C, this short cut will show the charms bar, this is the same as in the step above</p>
<p>4) Hit Windows Key + I, this is probably the easiest since you see the power button immediately</p>
<p>5) ALT + F4, just keep hitting ALT + F4 until you get the shutdown dialog</p>
<p>6) Unplug desktop or remove battery from laptop  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />
Of course nobody would pick option 6 right?  Right?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/windows-8/how-to-shutdown-windows-8/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
