<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>silverlight &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/silverlight/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Silverlight 5 available for download, will it be the last version?</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/application-lifecycle-management/silverlight-5-available-for-download/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/application-lifecycle-management/silverlight-5-available-for-download/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Application Lifecycle Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/12/silverlight-5-available-for-download/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has made Silverlight 5 available for download.


Here are some of the developer related enhancements:

XAML Debugging with breakpoints for binding debugging
Implicit data templates for easy UI reuse
Double (and multi) click support
GPU&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has made Silverlight 5 available for download.</p>
<p>Here are some of the developer related enhancements:</p>
<p>XAML Debugging with breakpoints for binding debugging<br />
Implicit data templates for easy UI reuse<br />
Double (and multi) click support<br />
GPU-accelerated XNA-compatible 3D and immediate-mode 2D API<br />
Low-latency sound effects and WAV support<br />
Real operating system windows and multi-display support<br />
Significant performance improvements, fixes and much more</p>
<p>The question on my mind is if anyone should invest in Silverlight 5, will there be a version 6 or is this the last version that will be delivered? You can still use your Silverlight skillset to build WinPhone apps but the future is HTML 5 + JavaScript.<br />
Take a look at the Windows 8 Win RT image&#8230;see SilverLight anywhere? </p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/EnterpriseDev/.evocache/WinRT.PNG/fit-400x320.PNG?mtime=1323526718" alt="" title="" /></p>
<p>Silverlight also doesn&#8217;t run in the browser on mobile platforms, Adobe announced a couple of weeks ago that they are stopping developing Flash for mobile platforms as well&#8230;yes Steve Jobs is laughing from his grave. IE 10 on the Metro version of Windows 8  does not support plugins, this means no Flash or Silverlight</p>
<p>Either way, you can download Silverlight 5 here: http://www.microsoft.com/silverlight/  it might be the last version that you will download</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/application-lifecycle-management/silverlight-5-available-for-download/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Silverlight 5 Beta Is Available For Download</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/serverprogramming/silverlight-5-beta-is-available/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/serverprogramming/silverlight-5-beta-is-available/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AJAX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft IIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Server Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XHTML and CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2011/04/silverlight-5-beta-is-available/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Silverlight 5 Beta is available for download


These are the top beta features



  XAML Debugging with breakpoints for binding debugging

  Implicit data templates for easy UI reuse

  Double (and multi) click support

  GPU-accelerated XN&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Silverlight 5 Beta is available for download</p>
<p>These are the top beta features</p>
<ul>
<li>XAML Debugging with breakpoints for binding debugging</li>
<li>Implicit data templates for easy UI reuse</li>
<li>Double (and multi) click support</li>
<li>GPU-accelerated XNA-compatible 3D and immediate-mode 2D API</li>
<li>Low-latency sound effects and WAV support</li>
<li>Real operating system windows and multi-display support</li>
<li>Significant performance improvements, fixes and much more</li>
</ul>
<p>More info about new features here: http://www.microsoft.com/silverlight/future/</p>
<p>There are also these items for download </p>
<ul>
<li>Silverlight 5 Beta Tools for Visual Studio SP1 (required)</li>
<li>Expression Blend Preview for Silverlight 5 (optional)</li>
<li>Silverlight 5 Features Document (optional)</li>
</ul>
<p>Download Silverlight 5 Beta and the optional downloads here: http://www.silverlight.net/getstarted/silverlight-5-beta/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/serverprogramming/silverlight-5-beta-is-available/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Silverlight, RIA, Datagrids, and Joins</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/silverlight-ria-datagrids-and-joins/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/silverlight-ria-datagrids-and-joins/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 13:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ThatRickGuy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entity framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/08/silverlight-ria-datagrids-and-joins/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately we&#8217;ve been playing around with RIA services for Silverlight. Using them we lose the use of our stack, but the speed of development with them is quite impressive. Watch and Learn If you are unfamiliar with RIA in Silverlight, I would recommend this video: http://www.silverlight.net/learn/videos/all/net-ria-services-intro/. It is a complete walk through of creating a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately we&#8217;ve been playing around with RIA services for Silverlight. Using them we lose the use of our stack, but the speed of development with them is quite impressive. </p>
<h2>Watch and Learn</h2>
<p>If you are unfamiliar with RIA in Silverlight, I would recommend this video: <a href="http://www.silverlight.net/learn/videos/all/net-ria-services-intro/">http://www.silverlight.net/learn/videos/all/net-ria-services-intro/</a>. It is a complete walk through of creating a demo from the &#8216;Business Application&#8217; template in Visual Studio for SL 3. If you are working in SL4, be sure to check the comments in the video for the breaking changes.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s the Skinny?</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s pretty fancy stuff. You make an Entity Framework model, based on your database. Then when you compile, the template generates a whole bunch of code for you. First, on the server it generates a Service and a Metadata class to expose your data entities and basic CRUD functionality to the client. Then in the client, another class is generated that handles the serialization and exposing of those server classes client side. One of the most impressive things about this interaction though, is that the return objects from the server are IQueriable, not arrays. Which gives you the ability to perform LINQ and deferred execution from the client!</p>
<h2>So Why the Fuss?</h2>
<p>Watch the video, play around with it. I&#8217;m not going to go through the whole thing here, but I will show you something I ran into.</p>
<p>I have a relational database, in this case I am looking at the <em>League</em> and <em>Player</em> tables. <em>League</em> has an OwnerPlayer_ID field that links to the <em>Player</em> table. The problem though, by using the RIA services and bindings out of the box, is that while the League class has a .Player property, it will never be populated. And showing people that a League is owned by Player #5237 isn&#8217;t nearly as helpful as showing them the Player&#8217;s name. We have to make 2 changes to get this to work correctly.</p>
<h2>Reprimanding that Lazy EF</h2>
<p>On the server side, find your service class. It should be called something like &#8216;MyApplicationDomainService1&#8217; and be in the &#8216;Services&#8217; folder by default. In that class look for a method called &#8216;GetMyObjects&#8217; where MyObjects is the collection you are binding to on the client side. It should contain something like &#8216;Return (Me.ObjectContext.MyObjects)&#8217;. Change it to:<br />
<code =VB>Return (Me.ObjectContext.MyObjects.Include("MyChildObject")</code><br />
In my case this was the &#8216;GetLeagues&#8217; method and it contains: &#8216;Return (Me.ObjectContext.Leagues.Include(&#8220;Player&#8221;))&#8217;</p>
<p>This will tell the Entity Framework model that it should Eager Load the .Player property. But before we rejoice and rebuild, wait, there&#8217;s more!</p>
<h2>Getting RIA up off the Couch</h2>
<p>Next up, right next to the DomainService1 file should be a file called MyApplicationDomainService1.metadata. In this file we need to find the class that represents what we are querying (The &#8220;MyObject&#8221; from the previous step). In that class you should see the property you want to load (The &#8220;MyChildObject&#8221; from above). On this property, you want to prepend the &lt;Include()&gt; attribute. This will tell the RIA services that it should include this property in the serialization and transmission of the query results. </p>
<p>In my case of League and Owner Player, it looks like this:</p>
<pre>    Friend NotInheritable Class LeagueMetadata
             
        '...

        &lt;Include()&gt;
        &lt;Display(AutoGenerateField:=False)&gt;
        Public Property Player As Player
        '...
    End Class</pre>
<h2>And the Grid?</h2>
<p>Now that the EF is loading the data we want, and the RIA services are returning the data we want, all we have to do is bind it! And this is the easiest part. It is just like they show in the video, with one minor change. Instead of just binding on the primary object&#8217;s property, we use dot notation to get at the child object&#8217;s property. Shown here as the &#8220;Player.Name&#8221; binding</p>
<pre>&lt;sdk:DataGrid x:Name="grdLeagues" Margin="4,20,4,4" Grid.Row="1" ItemsSource="{Binding ElementName=LeagueDomainDataSource, Path=Data}" AutoGenerateColumns="False"&gt;
    &lt;sdk:DataGrid.Columns&gt;
        &lt;sdk:DataGridTextColumn Binding="{Binding Path=Name}" Header="Name" /&gt;
        &lt;sdk:DataGridTextColumn Binding="{Binding Path=Player.Name, Mode=OneWay}" Header="Organizer" /&gt;
        &lt;sdk:DataGridTextColumn Binding="{Binding Path=Province}" Header="State" /&gt;
        &lt;sdk:DataGridTextColumn Binding="{Binding Path=City}" Header="City" /&gt;
        &lt;sdk:DataGridTextColumn Binding="{Binding Path=LGS}" Header="Game Store" /&gt;
    &lt;/sdk:DataGrid.Columns&gt;
&lt;/sdk:DataGrid&gt;</pre>
<p>-Rick</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/silverlight-ria-datagrids-and-joins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual Studio 2010 and Microsoft .NET Framework 4 Available for download today</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-and-microsoft-net-fra/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-and-microsoft-net-fra/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 11:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[C#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VB.NET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight 4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual studio 2010]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/04/visual-studio-2010-and-microsoft-net-fra/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2010 and Microsoft .NET Framework 4 will be available for download later today on MSDN. Right now it looks like the time that it will be available is 10 AM PDT. Now when it is available on MSDN don&#8217;t just download it from the first place you see it, check Top Downloads first [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev//logo_vstudio.png" alt="" title="" width="155" height="23" /></div>
<p>Visual Studio 2010 and Microsoft .NET Framework 4 will be available for download later today on MSDN. Right now it looks like the time that it will be available is 10 AM PDT.</p>
<p>Now when it is available on MSDN don&#8217;t just download it from the first place you see it, check Top Downloads first ( http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/subscriptions/bb608344.aspx ) The top downloads page uses Akamai and the downloads are much faster than the regular MSDN downloads.</p>
<p>Microsoft also announced that SilverLight 4 will be released to the web later this week.</p>
<p>You can get more infor from the Visual Studio page here: http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/en-us</p>
<p>The press release can be found here: http://www.microsoft.com/Presspass/press/2010/apr10/04-11VS10PR.mspx</p>
<p>Visual Studio 2010 Express is publicly available now. Get it here: http://www.microsoft.com/express/Windows/</p>
<p>Installing it now, here is what I generally install<br />
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DesktopDev//Ultimate.PNG" alt="" title="" width="756" height="581" /></p>
<p>When you cut out C++ and SQL Server Express/Sharepoint you save 3GB</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-and-microsoft-net-fra/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Detecting Property Changes in an Observable Collection</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/detecting-property-changes-in-an-observa/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/detecting-property-changes-in-an-observa/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 19:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ThatRickGuy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/04/detecting-property-changes-in-an-observa/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A quick and simple demo on how to set up a custom ObservableCollection to raise PropertyChanged events from the items it contains.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Work, Work, Work</h3>
<p>I was working on a new interface this week for a rather complex item selection system. It deals with hierarchies and mandatory selections, multi-selects and single-selects. In order to make it easier for users to see what items were already selected, there was also a list of just the selected items.</p>
<h3>Oh ObservableCollection, I See You!</h3>
<p>I toyed around with a few different options, and debated some of them out with Adam, and finally decided to run with binding and an Observable Collection.</p>
<h3>Everything is better with LINQ</h3>
<p>One of the great things about observable collections is that you can pass them around like candy, make a change to it from any number of locations, and it will update all of the controls bound to it. Mix in a little LINQ and you&#8217;ve got some awesome functionality with very little code.</p>
<h3>What Do You Mean CollectionChanged Doesn&#8217;t Fire?</h3>
<p>One of the things I needed to do though, was to detect when the user selected an item from the collection. When the IsChecked flag was flipped, I needed to go to the server to get any child items. But the Observable Collection does not expose property changed events, which started me down this path. </p>
<h3>The User Interface</h3>
<p>For this demo app, the UI is pretty simple. I just have two list boxes. Each list box has a DataTemplate with a CheckBox in it. The CheckBox has its Content bound to the &#8220;Text&#8221; member and IsChecked is bound to a like named member. The IsChecked property is also set to TwoWay mode. This means that when the user changes its checked state, it will update the underlying collection.</p>
<pre>        &lt;ListBox x:Name="lst1" Grid.Column="0" &gt;
            &lt;ListBox.ItemTemplate &gt;
                &lt;DataTemplate&gt;
                    &lt;CheckBox Content="{Binding Text}" IsChecked="{Binding IsChecked, Mode=TwoWay}" /&gt;
                &lt;/DataTemplate&gt;
            &lt;/ListBox.ItemTemplate&gt;
        &lt;/ListBox&gt;</pre>
<h3>On to the Items</h3>
<p>For the most part the Item class just contains our properties, but we have to beef it up just a bit. First, it needs <code class="codespan">Implements System.ComponentModel.INotifyPropertyChanged</code>. INotifyPropertyChanged will create a public event called &#8220;PropertyChanged&#8221;. In order to save ourselves a bit of repeating code, we can make a method called <em>onPropertyChanged</em> that raises that event for us:</p>
<pre>        Private Sub onPropertyChanged(ByVal PropertyName As String)
            RaiseEvent PropertyChanged(Me, New System.ComponentModel.PropertyChangedEventArgs(PropertyName))
        End Sub</pre>
<p> Also in the item class we need to tweak the properties a bit. For instance:</p>
<pre>        Private _IsChecked As Boolean
        Public Property IsChecked() As Boolean
            Get
                Return _IsChecked
            End Get
            Set(ByVal value As Boolean)
                If value &lt;&gt; _IsChecked Then
                    _IsChecked = value
                    onPropertyChanged("IsChecked")
                End If
            End Set
        End Property</pre>
<p>Note that we are only calling the onPropertyChanged event when the value has indeed changed. Also, ensure that the underlying value has changed BEFORE you call the onPropertyChanged, otherwise you&#8217;ll wind up with some really interesting behavior.</p>
<h3>The Collection</h3>
<p>The Observable collection doesn&#8217;t expose the PropertyChanged event by default, so we have to bubble it up ourselves. That means we need to make a new class that inherits from ObservableCollection. In order to get a handler on the Items PropertyChanged events, we need to override the InsertItem and RemoveItem methods. Inside them we Add and Remove an event handler for the Property Changed event. And in the procedure that handles that event, all we need to do is to raise our new public event.</p>
<h3>Back to the MainPage</h3>
<p>In the code of the main page, we need an instance of the collection, using the WithEvents keyword will make it exceptionally easy to attach to our events. In the constructor, we can set the ItemSource of both of our list boxes to that collection. And if you check the objects/events drop downs, you should see that our collection now exposes both a CollectionChanged and ItemPropertyChanged event. Put a message box or break point in each and fire up the app.</p>
<h3>Running</h3>
<p>When you run it, you should see a number of identical items in each list box. When you click on the check boxes of either list, you should see the ItemPropertyChanged event fire, after which both list boxes should reflect the new value in the collection.</p>
<h3>Show me the Demo</h3>
<p>
        <object data="data:application/x-silverlight-2," type="application/x-silverlight-2" width="100%" height="150px"><param name="source" value="http://ringdev.com.web10.reliabledomainspace.com/code/bindingdemo/trainingdemo2.xap" /><param name="onError" value="onSilverlightError" /><param name="background" value="white" /><param name="minRuntimeVersion" value="3.0.40624.0" /><param name="autoUpgrade" value="true" /><a href="http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=149156&amp;v=3.0.40624.0" style="text-decoration:none"><br />
 			  <img src="http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=108181" alt="Get Microsoft Silverlight" style="border-style:none" /><br />
		  </a></object></p>
<h3>Show Me the Code</h3>
<p>Working VS 2008 solution can be downloaded from <a href="http://ringdev.com.web10.reliabledomainspace.com/code/bindingdemo/trainingdemo2.zip">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/detecting-property-changes-in-an-observa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A quick look at Windows Phone 7 development</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/a-quick-look-at-windows-phone-7-developm/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/a-quick-look-at-windows-phone-7-developm/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 17:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xna studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zune hd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/03/a-quick-look-at-windows-phone-7-developm/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today I decided to take a look at Windows Phone 7 development. The first thing I did was download the Windows Phone Developer Tools, you can download it here: http://www.microsoft.com/express/phone/ Windows Phone Developer Tools includes: Visual Studio 2010 Express for Windows Phone Windows Phone Emulator Silverlight for Windows Phone XNA Game Studio 4.0 CTP The [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I decided to take a look at Windows Phone 7 development. The first thing I did was download the Windows Phone Developer Tools, you can download it here: http://www.microsoft.com/express/phone/</p>
<p>Windows Phone Developer Tools includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Visual Studio 2010 Express for Windows Phone</li>
<li>Windows Phone Emulator</li>
<li>Silverlight for Windows Phone</li>
<li>XNA Game Studio 4.0 CTP</li>
</ul>
<p>The download was 228 MB for me, I already had Visual Studio 2008 and Visual Studio 2010 RC on my machine, if you don&#8217;t have those, the download might be bigger.</p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//IPhoneSetup.png" alt="" title="" width="516" height="464" /></p>
<p>Here are the 10 things that will be downloaded and installed.</p>
<p><em>Visual Studio 2010 Express<br />
Silverlight 4<br />
Silverlight 4 SDK<br />
Microsoft Windows Phone Emulator x64<br />
Microsoft Windows Phone Developer Resources<br />
Windows Phone 7 Add-in for Visual Studio 2010<br />
Microsoft Windows Phone Developers Tools CTP<br />
Microsoft XNA Game Studio 4.0<br />
Microsoft XNA Game Studio 4.0 Windows&#8230;..<br />
Silverlight 4 Tools for Visual Studio 2010 RC</em></p>
<p>After everything is downloaded and installed, you will see the following window<br />
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//Phone7Done.png" alt="" title="" width="516" height="464" /><br />
</p>
<h2>Visual Studio 2010 and Windows Phone 7 development</h2>
<p>Now that we are done, we can start playing around with the tools.<br />
The way you develop apps/games for Windows Phone 7 is that you either use Silverlight 4 or XNA Studio 4<br />
If you pick Silverlight for Windows Phone  then the following templates are available<br />
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//PhoneSilverLight.png" alt="" title="Windows Phone 7 Silverlight" width="845" height="560" /><br />
<br />
If you pick XNA Game Studio 4.0 then the following templates are available<br />
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//PhoneXNA.png" alt="" title="Windows Phone 7 XNA Studio" width="845" height="560" /></p>
<p>I decided to pick the Silverlight Windows Phone List Application.<br />
After messing around with it for 15 minutes or so I managed to create the following &#8220;app&#8221;. I put app in quotes because it really doesn&#8217;t do anything yet, it is all static. Hopefully I will be able to grab all the XML feeds we have on this site and plug it into the app. I myself have a Zune HD and I have heard that these apps should also work on the Zune HD.</p>
<p>Below is an image of the &#8220;app&#8221; in action</p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals//PhoneApp.png" alt="" title="" width="292" height="570" /><br />
</p>
<p>I also shot a 2 minute and 11 second video where I play around with the &#8220;app&#8221; and also click around in Visual Studio to show you some of the stuff.</p>
<p>Below is a video of the &#8220;app&#8221; in action</p>
[video:youtube:e7SHq4w17D0]
<h2>Learning about Windows Phone 7 development</h2>
<p>I did all the stuff in this post without having looked at any documentation at all, I have never done any Silverlight development. To me it seems that developing for  Windows Phone is not that difficult. Here are some resources for you if you want to learn more about Windows Phone 7 development. I will take a look at these also over the next couple of weeks and hopefully that &#8220;app&#8221; I created will be able to pull in real live data.<br />
Charles Petzold is writing a book titled Programming Windows Phone 7 Series, right now you can download the draft preview of that book.</p>
<p>This preview ebook contains six chapters in three parts (153 pages total):</p>
<p>Part I Getting Started<br />
Chapter 1 Phone Hardware + Your Software<br />
Chapter 2 Hello, Windows Phone</p>
<p>Part II Silverlight<br />
Chapter 3 Code and XAML<br />
Chapter 4 Presentation and Layout</p>
<p>Part III XNA<br />
Chapter 5 Principles of Movement<br />
Chapter 6 Textures and Sprites</p>
<p>Download this book here: <a href="http://ow.ly/1lhdc">Programming Windows Phone 7 Series(DRAFT Preview)</a></p>
<p>Here are some more resources to learn about Windows Phone development<br />
<a href="http://developer.windowsphone.com/">Windows Phone Developer Portal</a><br />
<a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff402529(VS.92).aspx">Getting Started Guide for Developing for Windows Phone</a><br />
<a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff431744(VS.92).aspx">Code Samples for Windows Phone </a><br />
<a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/learn/courses/WP7TrainingKit/">Windows Phone 7 Series Developer Training Kit</a></p>
<p>That is all for this post, as mentioned before I will take a look at those resources myself and will see if I can make that app have more functionality soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/a-quick-look-at-windows-phone-7-developm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Developing KBay: It&#8217;s All About the Team</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/developing-kbay-what-went-right/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/developing-kbay-what-went-right/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 13:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ThatRickGuy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[team]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/11/developing-kbay-what-went-right/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello Everyone, Rick here again with another little blurb on my most recent Silverlight project, KBay. Today, I&#8217;d like to write a little bit about what went right. Separation of Power One of the biggest attributes of KBay&#8217;s success, IMO, was the segregation of development. My coworker Adam (Hi Adam!) and I handled the majority [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone,</p>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Rick here again with another little blurb on my most recent Silverlight project, KBay. Today, I&#8217;d like to write a little bit about what went right.</p>
<p><img src="http://ringdev.com/code/KBayHome.PNG" alt="KBay Home Page" title="KBay Home Page " style="margin-left:50px;" /></p>
<h3>Separation of Power</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">One of the biggest attributes of KBay&#8217;s success, IMO, was the segregation of development. My coworker Adam (Hi Adam!) and I handled the majority of the work for this project. The initial goal was to try to involve everyone on the App Dev team, to give them more exposure to Silverlight. But with the tight time-line and other priorities, we couldn&#8217;t keep the whole team on page. So after some initial design meetings and DB layout, it largely fell to Adam and me to get it to work. </p>
<h3>Balance Your Strengths</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Adam and I approached the problem from our own strengths. Both of us are more than capable of writing the entire solution, but we both have our strengths and weaknesses. In my case, my experience with Blend and XAML, along with some rudimentary graphics arts knowledge, really allowed me to speed through the front end, while Adam&#8217;s envelope pushing experience with LINQ and Generics allowed him to come up with some really awesome solutions to communication and technical issues.</p>
<h3>Two Heads are Better Than One</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">This separation really allowed us to greatly improve not just our development speed, but it also worked as a sort of code review, where we were both interacting with each other&#8217;s interfaces. Since we had virtually no requirements for the project, it allowed us to brainstorm freely and to consider many options that neither of us would have thought of on our own. </p>
<h3>Lather, Rinse, Repeat</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Both of us were so struck by how excellently this approach worked in our environment, that we have recommended to our management that we reuse it in more projects . And so far, it has continued to work exceptionally well.</p>
<h3>One of These Things is Not Like the Others</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Working in Silverlight, unlike any other mainstream MS platform, means that your only option for interacting with the server is via Webservice or WCF calls. Not only are these the only options (aside from some socket options) but they are also entirely Async in their behavior. </p>
<h3>Limits Are Good?</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">This limitation opens up a number of options and challenges. First, there is a crystal clear separation between the presentation layer and the business/data layer. It allows for developers to be very pure on either side. A web service does nothing for layout and the UI does nothing for data manipulation (save for maybe some caching). </p>
<h3>Green Light Go! Red Light Stop!</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Second, the UI developer can track explicitly when any IO begins and ends, and with a bit of wrapping, control the UI accordingly.</p>
<h3>Unit Testing Made Easy!</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Third, and probably best of all, since almost all of the functionality is being controlled by web services, it is really easy to isolate functionality for integrated unit testing. This has been a huge boon for us in terms of stability of deployments, even in the dev environment with multiple developers. It takes 20 seconds to run every single method through all of our known use cases, and those unit tests are run before every deployment. These unit tests are a critical to reducing risks for off-schedule deployments.</p>
<h3>Are Limits Bad?</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Maybe &#8216;limits&#8217; isn&#8217;t the right word for this. You can still do almost everything you can do through other platforms, you just have to go about it through entirely different means. The limits that exist force developers to go through the new means, using async communication and webservices/WCF instead of continuing to depend on integrated IO and synchronous processing. So while there is a learning curve in changing the way we approach problems in Silverlight, I think that overcoming that curve will enable more developers to think in a parallel style. Removing the interface from the process, and making the processes async forces developers to partake in good development practices. Because every time I see a Windows app go to a white screen because some developer tried running I/O operations on the GUI thread, I cry a little on the inside.</p>
<h3>I Love Log</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">That&#8217;s it for the more abstract summary of the KBay project. I promise my next segment will deal with more of the technical nuts and bolts of the project. Including the communication layer and my personal favorite, LOGGING!!!</p>
<p>-Rick</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/developing-kbay-what-went-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pushing Silverlight for my Company</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/pushing-silverlight-for-my-company/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/pushing-silverlight-for-my-company/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 20:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ThatRickGuy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/11/pushing-silverlight-for-my-company/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It's me again, Rick the Silverlight nut. I've been buried under a pile of work this last month and haven't had a chance to post much of the fun stuff I've been working on. But I've got a few minutes to write about my last big project. So I give you, the story of KBay]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">It&#8217;s me again, Rick the Silverlight nut. I&#8217;ve been buried under a pile of work this last month and haven&#8217;t had a chance to post much of the fun stuff I&#8217;ve been working on. But I&#8217;ve got a few minutes to write about my last big project. So I give you, the story of KBay:</p>
<p><img src="http://ringdev.com/code/KBay.PNG" alt="KBay sample screen" title="KBay Sample Screen" style="margin-left:50px;" /></p>
<h3>The Story So Far&#8230;</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">I work for Kerry Americas, a food product company with a corporate office in Beloit, Wisconsin. Over the last year we have relocated much of our sales, service, R and D, and other folks to a brand new, state of the art office building and production facility. This place rocks. This did however, leave us with a whole lot of cruddy old furniture, that had been well-used in many of our older office spaces. So the building managers, remembering that almost a decade ago the IT shop had given them an EBay-like app used to auction off goods for charity, gave us a call. They wanted us to fire up this archaic app so they could try to move the furniture to employees for charity. My boss, seeing an opportunity for something better, got us 2 weeks to get something running. We could either get the classic site up and running again, or make one from scratch in Silverlight, but it had to be entirely off the books.</p>
<h3>Racing the Clock&#8230;</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">So we worked our fingers to the bone pulling it off after hours, over lunch, etc, but after 9 days we had a working prototype. On day 10 we demo&#8217;d it to the users and they were ecstatic. We had 3 weeks to the auction and we used some of that time to refine and improve the system (I hope to be posting about our communication frame work shortly!)</p>
<h3>Going Live&#8230;</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Last week, Monday morning we went live with over 200 auctions and almost 600 available users. We had a huge load on the server that morning, but everything stayed up and stable. No crashes, no complaints. We had a few minor bugs, and since it was a non-critical app the boss-man gave us the go-ahead to push to production off-schedule.</p>
<h3>Down to the Wire&#8230;</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">Friday evening was the big test though. All of the auctions ended at the exact same time. The managers were joking that they had never seen the parking lot so full on a Friday night. And the web server was showing some severe strain. With 300+ users sitting on their favored auction&#8217;s page, hitting refresh over and over again, the server was having issues keeping up. But it never crashed, it just got slow to access the site.</p>
<h3>In the End&#8230;</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">It was a huge success! The company off loaded almost all of the auctions. The employees got some great deals on some impressive furniture. A local charity food bank picked up a few thousand dollars. And we got Silverlight installed on almost every PC in the building AND got some major good-credit with the users. </p>
<h3>The Post Mortem&#8230;</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">And post-hoc analysis is pointing to an obvious short coming in our interactions. Since we had developed the application so quickly, we had cut some corners. One of those corners was image caching. Each time users were browsing auctions they were downloading every thumbnail, and every time they looked at a single auction, they would download the full sized image. We had mentioned caching briefly during design, but with a 9 day window, we scrapped it and it was forgotten about while we polished. But looking back now, we could have just hosted the images via an ASP.Net page. Not only would that have solved the hosting issue, but it would have also allowed Silverlight to use the built in browser cache for all of the images. A full caching system without writing a single line of code. We&#8217;re kicking ourselves now for not seeing it before, but we&#8217;ll have it in for the next auction!</p>
<h3>More to Come&#8230;</h3>
<p style="text-indent: 30pt;">I hope to have time to post some more of what we learned on this project soon, but I&#8217;ve got another hot deadline approaching for a Silverlight application that mocks Share Point inside of Sales Force.</p>
<p>-Rick</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/pushing-silverlight-for-my-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Catching a Visual State Completion in Silverlight</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/catching-a-visual-state-completion-in-si/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/catching-a-visual-state-completion-in-si/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 11:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ThatRickGuy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storyboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual state]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/09/catching-a-visual-state-completion-in-si/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Catching the completion of a visual state change in Silverlight 3]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just a quickie from the Silverlight front today. </p>
<p>Visual States and the VSM are awesome tools to handling most of your application&#8217;s animations. One annoyance though, Visual States do not have a .Completed event!</p>
<p>Luckily for us, Visual States are composed of Story Boards. Story Boards DO have .Completed events <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>To get it to work, it&#8217;s really simple. First, create your event handling method:</p>
<pre>Private Sub SomeStoryBoard_Completed(ByVal sender As Object, ByVal e As System.EventArgs) 
     MessageBox.Show("StoryBoard Completed!")
End Sub</pre>
<p>Next, in your LayoutRoot_Loaded method, add a handler:</p>
<pre>AddHandler Me.MyVisualState.Storyboard.Completed, AddressOf SomeStoryBoard_Completed</pre>
<p>Where &#8220;MyVisualState&#8221; is the name of the visual state you are trying to work with.</p>
<p>Nothing too fancy there. You just have to know that a VisualState contains a story board and that you can wire up that story board&#8217;s completed event. </p>
<p>There is another way, that is even more simple, but it appears to not be working as intended. If you have any idea&#8217;s why the following doesn&#8217;t work, I&#8217;d love to hear about it.</p>
<p>Start by going into the XAML and finding the Storyboard in the Visual State you are trying to work with. Once you&#8217;ve found it, give the Storyboard a name (x:Name=&#8221;sbSearchOpen&#8221; on line 11 in the following example)</p>
<pre>&amp;lt;VisualStateManager.VisualStateGroups&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;VisualStateGroup x:Name="SearchBox"&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;VisualStateGroup.Transitions&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;VisualTransition GeneratedDuration="00:00:00.6000000"&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;VisualTransition.GeneratedEasingFunction&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;CubicEase EasingMode="EaseOut"/&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;/VisualTransition.GeneratedEasingFunction&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/VisualTransition&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/VisualStateGroup.Transitions&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;VisualState x:Name="SearchOpen"&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;Storyboard x:Name="sbSearchOpen"&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;DoubleAnimationUsingKeyFrames BeginTime="00:00:00" Duration="00:00:00.0010000" Storyboard.TargetName="grdSearch" Storyboard.TargetProperty="(FrameworkElement.Height)"&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;EasingDoubleKeyFrame KeyTime="00:00:00" Value="85"/&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;/DoubleAnimationUsingKeyFrames&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;ObjectAnimationUsingKeyFrames BeginTime="00:00:00" Duration="00:00:00.0010000" Storyboard.TargetName="grdNavSearch" Storyboard.TargetProperty="(FrameworkElement.Margin)"&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;DiscreteObjectKeyFrame KeyTime="00:00:00"&amp;gt;
						&amp;lt;DiscreteObjectKeyFrame.Value&amp;gt;
							&amp;lt;Thickness&amp;gt;0,0,0,85&amp;lt;/Thickness&amp;gt;
						&amp;lt;/DiscreteObjectKeyFrame.Value&amp;gt;
					&amp;lt;/DiscreteObjectKeyFrame&amp;gt;
				&amp;lt;/ObjectAnimationUsingKeyFrames&amp;gt;
			&amp;lt;/Storyboard&amp;gt;
		&amp;lt;/VisualState&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;/VisualStateGroup&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/VisualStateManager.VisualStateGroups&amp;gt;</pre>
<p> Then we can switch to the code behind and in the object list select the sbSearchOpen story board, and in the event list select Completed. This will generate the sbSearchOpen_Completed event:</p>
<pre>Private Sub sbSearchOpen_Completed(ByVal sender As Object, ByVal e As System.EventArgs) Handles sbSearchOpen.Completed
        MessageBox.Show("Search Opened!")
    End Sub</pre>
<p>Totally an easy and intuitive way of catching the end of a story board. Unfortunately, it doesn&#8217;t work. The IDE acts like it expects it to work, but for some reason, at run time, the sbSearchOpen_Completed method will never fire.</p>
<p>-Rick</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/catching-a-visual-state-completion-in-si/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft releases Silverlight 2 announces  development capabilities with Eclipse</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/microsoft-releases-silverlight-2-announc/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/microsoft-releases-silverlight-2-announc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 14:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eclipse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silverlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xaml]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/10/microsoft-releases-silverlight-2-announc/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp. today announced the availability of Silverlight 2, one of the industry&#8217;s most comprehensive and powerful solutions for the creation and delivery of applications and media experiences through a Web browser. Silverlight 2 delivers a wide range of new features and tools that enable designers and developers to better collaborate while creating more accessible, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Corp. today announced the availability of Silverlight 2, one of the industry&#8217;s most comprehensive and powerful solutions for the creation and delivery of applications and media experiences through a Web browser. Silverlight 2 delivers a wide range of new features and tools that enable designers and developers to better collaborate while creating more accessible, more discoverable and more secure user experiences.<br />
Microsoft also announced further support of open source communities by funding advanced Silverlight development capabilities with the Eclipse Foundation’s integrated development environment (IDE) and by providing new controls to developers with the Silverlight Control Pack (SCP) under the Microsoft Permissive License.</p>
<blockquote><p>“We launched Silverlight just over a year ago, and already one in four consumers worldwide has access to a computer with Silverlight already installed,” said Scott Guthrie, corporate vice president of the .NET Developer Division at Microsoft. “Silverlight represents a radical improvement in the way developers and designers build applications on the Web. This release will further accelerate our efforts to make Silverlight, Visual Studio and Microsoft Expression Studio the preeminent solutions for the creation and delivery of media and rich Internet application experiences.”<br />
Silverlight adoption continues to grow rapidly, with penetration in some countries approaching 50 percent and a growing ecosystem that includes more than 150 partners and tens of thousands of applications. During the 17 days of the 2008 Olympics Games in Beijing, NBCOlympics.com, powered by Silverlight, had more than 50 million unique visitors, resulting in 1.3 billion page views, 70 million video streams and 600 million minutes of video watched, increasing the average time on the site (from 3 minutes to 27 minutes) and Silverlight market penetration in the U.S. by more than 30 percent. Broadcasters in France (France Televisions SA), the Netherlands (NOS), Russia (Sportbox.ru) and Italy (RAI) also chose Silverlight to deliver Olympics coverage online. In addition, leading companies such as CBS College Sports, Blockbuster Inc., Hard Rock Cafe International Inc., Yahoo! Japan, AOL LLC, Toyota Motor Corp., HSN Inc. and Tencent Inc. are building their next-generation experiences using Silverlight.<br />
“CBS College Sports Network streams more than 20,000 hours of live content annually for our 150-plus college and university official athletic partners, so we demand that our video player environment be both consumer friendly and robust,” said Tom Buffolano, general manager and vice president, Digital Programming and Subscription, CBS Interactive-Sports. “Silverlight was the perfect choice to help develop and power our new, exclusive online collegiate sports experience, as it features the best price and performance of any streaming media solution on the market today. Silverlight also gives us the most flexibility in expanding the product in the future as we develop embeddable players and mobile platforms and explore new advertising integration opportunities.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Microsoft announced plans to support additional tools for developing Silverlight applications by providing funding to Soyatec, a France-based IT solutions provider and Eclipse Foundation member, to lead a project to integrate advanced Silverlight development capabilities into the Eclipse IDE. Soyatec plans to release the project under the Eclipse Public License Version 1.0 on SourceForge and submit it to the Eclipse Foundation as an open Eclipse project.</p>
<p>Microsoft also will release the Silverlight Control Pack and publish on MSDN the technical specification for the Silverlight Extensible Application Markup Language (XAML) vocabulary. The SCP, which will augment the powerful built-in control set in Silverlight, will be released under the Microsoft Permissive License, an Open Source Initiative-approved license, and includes controls such as DockPanel, ViewBox, TreeView, Accordion and AutoComplete. The Silverlight XAML vocabulary specification, released under the Open Specification Promise (OSP), will better enable third-party ISVs to create products that can read and write XAML for Silverlight.</p>
<p><strong>Highlights of new Silverlight 2 features include the following:</strong></p>
<p>.NET Framework support with a rich base class library. This is a compatible subset of the full .NET Framework.</p>
<p>Powerful built-in controls. These include DataGrid, ListBox, Slider, ScrollViewer, Calendar controls and more.</p>
<p>Advanced skinning and templating support. This makes it easy to customize the look and feel of an application.</p>
<p>Deep zoom. This enables unparalleled interactivity and navigation of ultrahigh resolution imagery.</p>
<p>Comprehensive networking support. Out-of-the-box support allows calling REST, WS*/SOAP, POX, RSS and standard HTTP services, enabling users to create applications that easily integrate with existing back-end systems.</p>
<p>Expanded .NET Framework language support. Unlike other runtimes, Silverlight 2 supports a variety of programming languages, including Visual Basic, C#, JavaScript, IronPython and IronRuby, making it easier for developers already familiar with one of these languages to repurpose their existing skill sets.</p>
<p>Advanced content protection. This now includes Silverlight DRM, powered by PlayReady, offering robust content protection for connected Silverlight experiences.</p>
<p>Improved server scalability and expanded advertiser support. This includes new streaming and progressive download capabilities, superior search engine optimization techniques, and next-generation in-stream advertising support.</p>
<p>Vibrant partner ecosystem. Visual Studio Industry Partners such as ComponentOne LLC, Infragistics Inc. and Telerik Inc. are providing products that further enhance developer capabilities when creating Silverlight applications using Visual Studio.</p>
<p>Cross-platform and cross-browser support. This includes support for Mac, Windows and Linux in Firefox, Safari and Windows Internet Explorer.</p>
<p>More information and details about Silverlight 2 are available by reading the Silverlight 2 fact sheet at http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/presskits/silverlight/default.mspx.</p>
<p>Silverlight 2 will be available for download on Tuesday, Oct. 14, at http://www.microsoft.com/silverlight. Customers already using a previous version of Silverlight will be automatically upgraded to Silverlight 2.</p>
<p>A technology preview of the Soyatec project is available today at http://www.eclipse4sl.org,/ with a complete version available in second half of 2009.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/microsoft-releases-silverlight-2-announc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
