<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Difference between a cross join and a full outer join</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/difference-between-a-cross-join/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/difference-between-a-cross-join/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 12:40:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: SQLDenis</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/difference-between-a-cross-join/#comment-5145</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 17:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/02/difference-between-a-cross-join/#comment-5145</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Adam,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You are right about the old style join syntax, I have seen that happen far too often where a cross join would be executed because someone forgot to add the WHERE condition]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adam,</p>
<p>You are right about the old style join syntax, I have seen that happen far too often where a cross join would be executed because someone forgot to add the WHERE condition</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Adam</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/difference-between-a-cross-join/#comment-5144</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 17:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/02/difference-between-a-cross-join/#comment-5144</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I got all kind of creative answer in responds to this question, some people were describing the cross join as an inner join&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those people weren&#039;t so far from the truth.  Conceptually, a cross join &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the same thing as an inner join -- one without a join condition.   In other words, an inner join is equivalent to doing a cross join and then applying the join condition (ON clause, or WHERE clause in the old syntax).  In fact, at least for some DBMSs, and I believe in the ANSI standard, the CROSS keyword is entirely optional, effectively synonymous with INNER (which is also optional) - that is, FOO INNER JOIN BAR or FOO JOIN BAR is exactly the same thing as FOO CROSS JOIN BAR.   It&#039;s just that stylistically you&#039;d use the latter to emphasize the lack of a join condition when you actually want a total cartesian product.  With the old-style syntax it was all to easy to accidentally do an unqualified cross join by just doing SELECT .. FROM FOO,BAR and forgetting to put the appropriate condition in the WHERE clause; at least the newer syntax helps you remember to make your intention explicit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An outer join is a funny kind of animal - you could think of it as starting with an inner join, then adding the rows from one (left OJ) or the other (right OJ) or both (full OJ) tables that &lt;i&gt;didn&#039;t&lt;/i&gt; match condition X in the original join, padded out appropriately with nulls.  In any case it&#039;s sort of an augmentation of an inner join, not an entirely different concept.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having interviewed a lot of self-described SQL experts myself, I can attest to the reigning confusion in this area.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>
I got all kind of creative answer in responds to this question, some people were describing the cross join as an inner join
</p></blockquote>
<p>Those people weren&#8217;t so far from the truth.  Conceptually, a cross join <i>is</i> the same thing as an inner join &#8212; one without a join condition.   In other words, an inner join is equivalent to doing a cross join and then applying the join condition (ON clause, or WHERE clause in the old syntax).  In fact, at least for some DBMSs, and I believe in the ANSI standard, the CROSS keyword is entirely optional, effectively synonymous with INNER (which is also optional) &#8211; that is, FOO INNER JOIN BAR or FOO JOIN BAR is exactly the same thing as FOO CROSS JOIN BAR.   It&#8217;s just that stylistically you&#8217;d use the latter to emphasize the lack of a join condition when you actually want a total cartesian product.  With the old-style syntax it was all to easy to accidentally do an unqualified cross join by just doing SELECT .. FROM FOO,BAR and forgetting to put the appropriate condition in the WHERE clause; at least the newer syntax helps you remember to make your intention explicit.</p>
<p>An outer join is a funny kind of animal &#8211; you could think of it as starting with an inner join, then adding the rows from one (left OJ) or the other (right OJ) or both (full OJ) tables that <i>didn&#8217;t</i> match condition X in the original join, padded out appropriately with nulls.  In any case it&#8217;s sort of an augmentation of an inner join, not an entirely different concept.</p>
<p>Having interviewed a lot of self-described SQL experts myself, I can attest to the reigning confusion in this area.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: james</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/datadesign/difference-between-a-cross-join/#comment-5143</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[james]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 13:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/02/difference-between-a-cross-join/#comment-5143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Id have got this right!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
...and an excellent question to add to the list for future recruitments]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Id have got this right!</p>
<p>&#8230;and an excellent question to add to the list for future recruitments</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
