<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>forums &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/forums/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>SQL Advent 2012 Day 24: Getting help</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/getting-help/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/getting-help/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Database Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft SQL Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql advent 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008 r2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/12/getting-help/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is day twenty-four of the SQL Advent 2012 series of blog posts. Today we are going to look at how to get help]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is day twenty-four of the <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBProgramming/sql-advent-2012-here-is">SQL Advent 2012 series</a> of blog posts. Today we are going to look at how to get help.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/vicky-/7089908693/" title="Help! by Vicky! &lt;3, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7068/7089908693_f5cb6d839a_m.jpg" width="240" height="125" alt="Help!" style="float:left;margin:0 5px 0 0;" /></a>Imagine if you were stuck with some problem in 1995, you didn&#8217;t have that many choices, you could ask the resident <em>know it all</em> at your job, you could lookup stuff in a book or you could go on the newsgroups and try to get help that way. These days there are many more ways to get help. There are many more books than in 1995, there are also a lot more whitepapers available these days. Twitter is a great way to get help as well if you use a special hashtag. Attend one of the many <a href="http://www.sqlsaturday.com/">SQL Saturday</a> events, there are always experts available who are willing to help you out with your problems. These events are held all over the world and there is a good chance one will be held near your town as well.</p>
<p><strong>Forums/QA sites</strong><br />
Join a QA site like <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions">stackoverflow</a>, head on to a specialized site on stackexchange, here is a list of all of them http://stackexchange.com/sites You can hit some of the <a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/">forums</a> on this site. For SQL server, you can also try <a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/Forums/">SQLServerCentral</a></p>
<p><strong>Twitter</strong><br />
Don&#8217;t be scared to ask for help on twitter, if you don&#8217;t know any of the SQL Server tweeple, use the #sqlhelp hash tag and ask for help, here is an example of what it looks like <a href="https://twitter.com/search/realtime?q=%23sqlhelp&amp;src=typd">#sqlhelp</a><br />
Here is an image of the replies on twitter after I asked a question with the #sqlhelp tag</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Denis/ADvent/sqlhelp.PNG?mtime=1355070897"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/DataMgmt/Denis/ADvent/sqlhelp.PNG?mtime=1355070897" width="516" height="438" /></a></div>
<p>Here is a small list of people with their speciality on twitter</p>
<p><strong>Replication</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hilarycotter">Hilary Cotter</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/onpnt">Ted Krueger</a></p>
<p><strong>Mirroring</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/SQLSoldier">Robert Davis</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/onpnt">Ted Krueger</a></p>
<p><strong>Extended Events</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/SQLPoolBoy">Jonathan Kehayias</a></p>
<p><strong>SQL Internals, checkdb</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/PaulRandal">Paul Randal</a></p>
<p><strong>Indexing</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/KimberlyLTripp">Kimberly Tripp</a></p>
<p><strong>Storage</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/mrdenny">Denny Cherry</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/BrentO">Brent Ozar</a></p>
<p><strong>Optimizer</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/SQL_Kiwiv">Paul White</a></p>
<p><strong>Powershell</strong><br />
<a href="http://twitter.com/SQLvariant">Aaron Nelson</a></p>
<p><strong>SSIS</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/andyleonard">Andy Leonard</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/jamiet">Jamie Thompson</a></p>
<p><strong>Hardware </strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/GlennAlanBerry">Glenn Berry</a></p>
<p><strong>SSRS</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/grrl_geek">Jes Schultz Borland</a></p>
<p><strong>SSAS</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/AJbigdata">Adam Jorgensen</a></p>
<p><strong>T-SQL</strong><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/AaronBertrand">Aaron Bertrand</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/Hugo_Kornelis">Hugo Kornelis</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/ItzikBenGan">Itzik Ben-Gan</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/rob_farley">Rob Farley</a></p>
<p>Start following these people and if you have questions don&#8217;t hesitate to ask them.</p>
<p>That is all for day twenty-four of the <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBProgramming/sql-advent-2012-here-is">SQL Advent 2012 series</a>, come back tomorrow for the next one, you can also check out all the posts from last year here: <a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DataDesign/sql-advent-2011-recap">SQL Advent 2011 Recap</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/dbprogramming/getting-help/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Community Services &#8211; Resources everywhere!</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-help-and-resources/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-help-and-resources/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 16:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/sql-help-and-resources/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the last day of Community Service week for SQL University.  Before we get started, I’d like to say it has been nothing short of a pleasure writing the last two weeks for SQL University.  All of the discussions and topics we a lot of fun to go over and I’m looking forward to hearing from everyone how they were able to use them.  Don’t forget to pass SQL University and the community itself on to the person to your side that may not be aware of them.  Let’s keep building this community together!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the last day of Community Service week for <a href="http://sqlchicken.com/sql-university">SQL University</a>.  Before we get started, I’d like to say it has been nothing short of a pleasure writing the last two weeks for SQL University.  All of the discussions and topics were a lot of fun to go over and I’m looking forward to hearing from everyone how they were able to use them.  Don’t forget to pass SQL University and the community itself on to the person to your side that may not be aware of them.  Let’s keep building this community together!</p>
<p><strong>The last one means, TEST!</strong></p>
<p>Today being our last day of community service week, we’re going to take a quiz.  </p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/quiz.gif" alt="" title="" width="160" height="201" /></div>
<p>Kidding!!!  (I think an apple just whizzed by my head)</p>
<p><strong>Resources</strong> are up to bat and we have a plethora of them available to us in the community.   Between Jes, Coach LaRock and I authoring community service week, we have covered a ton of community information.  </p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/2010/06/14/meet-the-sql-server-community/">Meet the SQL Server Community! </a>– (6/14) by Jes Borland</li>
<li><a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/sql-community-tech-forums">SQL Server Forums-Helping to Build a Knowledge Base </a>(6/15) by Ted Krueger </li>
<li><a href="http://thomaslarock.com/2010/06/sql-university-community-service-week/">DBA Coach LaRock: Community Service Week </a>(6/16)</li>
<li><a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/2010/06/17/sql-community-professional-association-of-sql-server/">SQL Community: Professional Association of SQL Server</a> – (6/17) by Jes Borland</li>
<li><a href="/index.php/ITProfessionals/EthicsIT/sql-community-blogging">Let’s Blog!</a> &#8211; (6/17) by Ted Krueger</li>
</ul>
<p>You could almost take what we’ve gone over and spend the next 2 years diving into just those topics.  There is one other corner of the community that I find to be exceptional that cannot go without discussion.  That is, the companies that stand behind us. </p>
<p>If you are reading this and have been part of a SQL Saturday, SQL Server User Group, Pod cast or any type of resource that requires funds, you already know exactly how devoted SQL related companies are to supporting the SQL Community.  Quest, Red-Gate, Pragmatic Works, Confio, Idera…the list goes on and on.  These companies all sell products that help us make life easier for a DBA or DB Developer.   As many say, they help us be lazy database administrators.</p>
<p>These companies take the vast amount of resources and pour them into building the community.  </p>
<p>Quest Software is a great example.  Quest has not only been a major sponsor for dozens of SQL events but also spends a great deal of resources on providing things like, &#8220;<a href="http://sqlserver.quest.com/kbcategory.jspa?categoryID=291">The pain of the week</a>&#8221; to the community.   <a href="http://sqlserverpedia.com/">SQLServerPedia</a> is a huge resource powered by Quest with Mr. Ozar leading the way.  You could without a doubt spend a month reading, watching and learning from <a href="http://sqlserverpedia.com/">SQLServerPedia</a>. </p>
<p>Red-Gate is another great company supporting the community in a number of ways,  from the <a href="http://www.exceptionaldba.com/">Exceptional DBA of the Year</a> recognition that is going on right now, to the work that Steve Jones (<a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/steve_jones/default.aspx">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/way0utwest">Twitter</a>)and Brad McGehee (<a href="http://www.bradmcgehee.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/bradmcgehee">Twitter</a>) do for the community backed by Red-Gate.  Red-Gate stands behind the community and does a great deal for us all.  And did I mention the SQL Tools rock?</p>
<p>Pragmatic Works is one of my favorite online free resources in the community.  There are so many <a href="http://www.pragmaticworks.com/Resources/webinars/Default.aspx">webinars</a> provided to the community to build on, you could spend another month just watching them to catch up.  Pragmatic Works has an entire <a href="http://www.pragmaticworks.com/Resources/Default.aspx">resource page</a> devoted to the webinars, whitepapers, articles and my personal favorite, the SSIS Cheat Sheet.  Pragmatic Works is a resource that is valued and highly recommended to everyone that touches anything SQL Server related.</p>
<p>I hardly even scratched the surface of these companies&#8217; devotion and support of the SQL Community.   There are dozens of others that I could sit down and praise for everything they do daily.  I&#8217;ve been fortunate to have worked with some of them during SQL Saturdays and User Groups and sat down to talk with them.  If you have a chance to find them at one of these events or meetings, stop by and get to know them.  You will be amazed at just how much they are involved in the community and the passion that comes out for it.  </p>
<p><strong>Don’t forget these resources</strong></p>
<p>Having lunch at your desk today while we talk about all these cool resources we have?  Good!  We can talk about <a href="http://www.sqllunch.com/">SQL Lunch</a>.  SQL Lunch is another resource that is absolutely free and invaluable.   SQL Lunch is composed of the entire world as a location.  There are speakers from all over that take their time out to hold sessions during the lunch hour (in some time zones).  I know I can’t think of a better way to spend my lunch.  And I know if you are a DBA or DB Developer, you are eating at your desk just as often as I do.</p>
<p>SQL Share is another virtual training resource.  SQL Community leaders such as <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/13986/JessicaMoss.aspx">Jessica Moss</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/1379/Jonathan-Kehayias.aspx">Jonathan Kehayias</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/7/Brian-Knight.aspx">Brian Knight</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/18/Andy-Warren.aspx">Andy Warren</a>, <a href="http://www.sqlshare.com/profiles/2626/Grant-Fritchey.aspx">Grant Fritchey</a> and many more are all part of providing this free resource.  These are web casts that focus on SQL Server topics and get right down to it.  They have an amazing talent for making the difficult topics very easy so you pick them up fast and do them the right way.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.simple-talk.com/sql/">Simple-Talk</a>: Do I need to say more?  I spend a lot of time on Simple-Talk.  The amount of knowledge that is held in this resource is almost frightening.  If you sat back and thought of trying to build a knowledge base and author listing like the one on this site, you would think it is impossible.  But it is there and if you don’t use it, you need to start.</p>
<p><strong>Scratched it</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/scratch.gif" alt="" title="" width="250" height="245" align="left" /></div>
<p>Yes, I scratched again.  I’ve only named a handful of places you can find resources to build your knowledge and networking in the SQL Community.  <strong>There is an enormous amount the SQL Community has to offer</strong>.  The homework for everyone is to go out and find people that do not know about the SQL Community and make them aware.  Nothing is ever perfect and everything can build higher and out farther.  The SQL Community has a lot of space to grow and growing with it is the reward we all shall share.</p>
<p>I’ve had a great time doing SQL University the last two weeks.  I hope everyone enjoyed it as much as I have.  As with all of the sessions, I welcome your suggestions on making things better for all of us.  If you would, please take the time to fill out the <a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/a/sqlchicken.com/viewform?hl=en&amp;formkey=dDBoSW02QldrTTc2dER3WVZheUlEX3c6MQ#gid=0">SQL University Course Evaluation</a>.</p>
<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-help-and-resources/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL University &#8211; Let&#8217;s blog</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-blogging/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-blogging/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 16:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/sql-community-blogging/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SQL University is one of the greatest concepts I've seen in the SQL Community.  Thanks to Jorge for coming up with it and organizing it.  Today we are going to talk about something dear and close to the concept of SQL University.  Blogging!  Blogs are an important part of the concept of SQL University.  With them we can easily bring this wealth of knowledge in the course syllabus format with writers from the SQL Community in a vast geographical range and range of expertise.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://sqlchicken.com/sql-university/">SQL University</a> is one of the greatest concepts I&#8217;ve seen in the SQL Community.  Thanks to Jorge Segarra (<a href="http://sqlchicken.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/SQLChicken">Twitter</a>)for coming up with it and organizing it.  Today we are going to talk about something dear and close to the concept of SQL University.  Blogging!  Blogs are an important part of the concept of SQL University.  With them we can easily bring this wealth of knowledge in the course syllabus format with writers from the SQL Community in a vast geographical range and range of expertise.  </p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/blog.gif" alt="" title="" width="296" height="280" /></div>
<p>Getting your day-to-day experiences and knowledge out to the community can be tough sometimes.  We can share what we know and what we learn with the teams we work in, but the walls of our building keep that from going far.  Blogging removes the wall and much does much more for our personal growth.  </p>
<p>Promoting and sharing blogs doesn’t only bring with it satisfaction of sharing what you’ve learned but also allows you to help everyone in the community so we can all build our knowledge base.</p>
<p><strong>My own personal story of blogging</strong></p>
<p>
I wrote my first blog in November of 2008.  The title was, &#8220;<a href="/index.php/DataMgmt/DBAdmin/MSSQLServerAdmin/user-to-schema-to-roles-for-controlling-">User to Schema to Roles for controlling security</a>&#8220;.  I won’t lie; I have learned an enormous amount about how to blog since then.  I’ve learned more about writing period!  Writing is an art form and catching the audience’s attention is important when you write your blogs.  The best part of blogging and writing in general is that everyone has their own way of getting the audience’s attention with humor, technical skills and just downright talent.  You hold that talent inside you, but you need to try it to find it and build on it. </p>
<p>In the SQL Community, we have hundreds (if not thousands) of bloggers out there writing daily and providing step-by-step articles that help us learn new things, fix old things and become better DBA’s all around.   So why write your own if the wealth of knowledge exists and is still pouring out of all of these SQL Community members?</p>
<p><i>If it is written already, I don’t need to write it.</i>  <-- Horrible statement! 


<p>The one reason I can give you to not hold back on starting up your own blog and sharing your SQL Server trials is: everyone sees a situation differently and replays that situation to an audience in many different ways.  Your way (yes, yours) can be the way that a hundred people grasp while other perspectives leave them with questions.  That reason alone takes, &#8220;it&#8217;s already done&#8221; and throws it down the truncate statement.  (Haha! SQL nerd humor is awesome!)  </p>
<p><strong>Let people review them</strong></p>
<p>Letting your guard down and sending your drafted blogs to friends and peers in the SQL Community can be hard.  No one likes to be marked by a red pen or be told that the entire blog may need a new direction.  In some cases, technical reviews find errors and mistakes all over the entire process and even directions describing why what you are telling everyone might not be the best way to do it.</p>
<p>A perfect example is a blog on using TRUNCATE_ONLY.   SHRINK and TRUNCATE_ONLY are just bad.  (Paul Randal (<a href="http://sqlskills.com/blogs/paul">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/paulrandal">Twitter</a>) <a href="http://www.sqlskills.com/blogs/paul/post/backup-log-with-no_log-use-abuse-and-undocumented-trace-flags-to-stop-it.aspx">says so</a>.) Very bad!  Google TRUNCATE_ONLY log and you will find plenty of bad advice, unfortunately.  The use of this option and action is really not a good thing to do on your SQL Servers.  We do see a lot of blogs going out on the topic though, and complete step-by-step instructions on how to do it.  If these blogs were placed under a technical review, the author may have gotten this reply:</p>
<blockquote><p><i>&#8220;Ted, I hate to say it but the blogs needs a lot of help in the technical realm.   Your steps are perfect and solid for anyone to take and get a shrinkfile working.  No doubt about that!  The problem is, you don’t say anything about why shrinkfile is not good and when to use it.  Just says: do it!  I could see how that might lead to a DBA putting a shrinkfile (or database) into a job and running it endlessly.  I would definitely add a description of the action and emergencies where it really is only called on.&#8221;</i></p></blockquote>
<p>I can also honestly say that most of the SQL Community and bloggers we have would be polite and respectful in while doing a review like this.  </p>
<p>While on this topic; thanks to Jes Borland (<a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/grrl_geek">Twitter</a>) for reviewing this blog and adding to it.  </p>
<p><strong>Practice if you are unsure</strong></p>
<p>Are you still unsure about blogging?  Practice a few blogs.  Write them and save them in a lost sea of folders in your Documents.  When you do that, keep your eyes and ears open in the community.  I can pretty much guarantee you that at some point, someone is going to mention the situation you wrote about either happened to them or they need help on it.  Then scramble to get your blog up and give it to them! </p>
<p><strong>Which blogs should I read?</strong></p>
<p>There are leaders in the SQL Community and those leaders all actively blog (and blog a lot).   The list could go on forever if we put them into this lesson, but luckily enough we have PASS to the rescue as always.  PASS collected a list of community bloggers and <a href="http://www.sqlpass.org/Community/BlogDirectory.aspx">posted it</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Still not convinced?</strong></p>
<p>Mike Walsh contributes a lot to the SQL Community.  A little while ago Mike spent the time writing a series on blogging.  The blog series starts with a <a href="http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2009/12/interview-with-mike-walsh-about-blogging/">video chat session with Brent Ozar</a> on experiences with blogging.  Then the series goes into, &#8220;<a href="http://www.straightpathsql.com/archives/2009/12/why-should-i-blog/">Why I should blog</a>&#8220;, &#8220;<a href="http://www.straightpathsql.com/archives/2009/12/how-should-i-blog/">How should I blog</a>&#8221; and the second part of the <a href="http://www.straightpathsql.com/archives/2009/12/blogging-tips-brent-ozar-mike-walsh-interview/">interview with Brent</a>.  The series is excellent and answers a lot of questions and pumps you up to get into blogging SQL Server and about the community.  If I haven’t convinced you how blogging can be extremely gratifying, Mike will.  </p>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to attend another SQL University course! Please take the time to fill out the <a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/a/sqlchicken.com/viewform?hl=en&amp;formkey=dDBoSW02QldrTTc2dER3WVZheUlEX3c6MQ#gid=0">SQL University Course Evaluation</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-blogging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SQL Server Forums – Helping to build a knowledge base</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-tech-forums/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-tech-forums/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 16:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Processes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server 2008]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/sql-community-tech-forums/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We're devoting an entire class to technical forums this week.  Forums have been around as long as most of the online community services have been.  They offer (mostly) unsolicited help at (mostly) no charge to the person requesting the help.  The word mostly worked its way into that last statement quite a bit.  There are resources out there that will allow the solicitation of the members and will charge for help.  This class is not going to discuss any of those services.  Why?  Because we are discussing the SQL community and this community truly puts itself out in front of everyone in need without asking for much of anything in return.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/sqlu_tiny.gif" alt="" title="" width="54" height="60" align="left" /></div>
<p>Welcome to another day of the Community Service week for <a href="http://sqlchicken.com/sql-university">SQL University</a>.  Jes Borland (<a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/">Blog</a> | <a href="http://twitter.com/grrl_geek">Twitter</a>) wrote an <a href="http://jesborland.wordpress.com/2010/06/14/meet-the-sql-server-community/">excellent class</a> yesterday on the SQL Community and areas that help connect us all.  Today we&#8217;re going to move on into the service parts of the SQL community and show how we can keep building the community.  I’d like to thank Jes again for helping author todays topic on technical forums.  </p>
<p>As with all SQL University weeks, please take a moment to rate us by filling out the <a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/a/sqlchicken.com/viewform?hl=en&amp;formkey=dDBoSW02QldrTTc2dER3WVZheUlEX3c6MQ#gid=0">SQL University Course Evaluation</a>.  We greatly appreciate your feedback so we can all become better.  </p>
<p>We&#8217;re devoting an entire class to technical forums this week.  Forums have been around as long as most of the online community services have been.  They offer (mostly) unsolicited help at (mostly) no charge to the person requesting the help.  The word mostly worked its way into that last statement quite a bit.  There are resources out there that will allow the solicitation of the members and will charge for help.  This class is not going to discuss any of those services.  Why?  Because we are discussing the SQL community and this community truly puts itself out in front of everyone in need without asking for much of anything in return.  The community devotes countless hours to supporting the strong foundation that it has constructed over the years.  Rarely will you find a part of it in which a request for money, goods or payback will be requested or expected.  In most cases, the gratitude of the solution being worked out amongst ourselves is the reward and payback.   The community takes that to heart and it is why you may not find another group like the SQL community.</p>
<p><strong>All bases covered</strong></p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/big _circle.gif" alt="" title="" width="645" height="504" /></div>
<p>SQL Server has grown to cover a wide flavor of specialized fields over the last decade.  Business Intelligence, CLR specialists, Tuning Experts, Mud Wrestling administrators, SAN Experts, Broker Experts, Full Text Search Experts, T-SQL Experts…the list goes on and on.  A lot of these experts fit into groups such as the BI group, the SQL Programming group and the DBA group.  In each of these groups you will find leaders that jump at the opportunity to throw what they know out into the public to help with any problems, new development or implementations.  These members of the community often are referred to as answerers.  And even the answerers turn to the others for help in the time of need, so we all become answerers in the community. </p>
<p><strong>The list</strong></p>
<p>How do you find these leaders and others that devote even minutes of their day to helping?</p>
<p>Below is a list of some sites that I, and other authors this semester, visit daily or hourly,  or sometimes lurk at with their finger on the refresh button:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/en/category/sqlserver/">MSDN SQL Forums</a></li>
<li><a href="http://serverfault.com/">Serverfault</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/Forums/">SQLServerCentral Forums</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sqlteam.com/forums/">SQL Team Forums</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forum.lessthandot.com/viewforum.php?f=14&amp;sid=95273364bfa1d4cbee1b6a2bf998431b">LessThanDot.com SQL Forums</a></li>
</ul>
<p>These forums are available for free and are a resource that should not be set to the side lightly.  The members of these forums all have a great deal of unique, real-life experiences to share, and will help in building your own knowledge.   If everyone in the community helps build the forums, the knowledge base that can be composed is truly infinite in nature. </p>
<p><strong>Reward yourself by giving back</strong></p>
<p>When asking questions in forums around the SQL community, there is one way that you will find even more value in the resource.  Start answering the questions and helping others!  No one knows the answer to everything!  What will often happen is that you can assist in searching other resources, testing on your resources that may not be available to the other people asking for help or simply work through the problem and troubleshoot in your unique way.  This builds both sides in learning more about SQL Server and everyone benefits. </p>
<p>Never feel uncomfortable helping others.  Helping is one of the foundations of increasing your knowledge of SQL Server.  Everyone won’t run into the same problem in our careers working on SQL Server, so we may never be exposed to specific situations.  By giving back on these forums and working through issues that you may not have come across, you benefit by learning the situation, path to recovery and complete solution.  Imagine the power behind that knowledge if the same problem comes up in your own environment someday!  So when you ask a question on one of these SQL Server forum resources, think about looking around to see if you might be able to help out and give a little back.  You may just become addicted like many of us have over the years.</p>
<p><strong>Obligation</strong></p>
<p>It is absolutely critical to understand that the members in these forums do not have a binding agreement to help nor are they obligated in any way to stick through it.  Usually, the members helping will go to great lengths to solve the problems.  If a person does not stick through it though, becoming frustrated with them is usually not the best reaction.  The member helping may have had a problem of their own come up, or had to leave their computer for a time.  Every reply is given for free and as-is.  Reacting negatively when a member that is helping you leaves abruptly may cause repercussions in the future, when you have another question. </p>
<p>When every resource fails you: Books Online, real books, your secret cube buddy that knows how to write SELECT *, the help desk solution of reboot doesn’t work &#8211; give the technical forums a try.  When you get an answer and are sitting back relaxing, push the chair back to the keyboard and see if you can return the favor by helping on the next thread under yours.</p>
<p>
<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/crazy_hair_puller.gif" alt="" title="" width="101" height="160" align="left" /></div>
<p>There is no need to pull your hair out at the roots; no need to call the CTO and tell them you quit before they fire you for not being able to fix it; no need to literally break down.  Give it a try and post your situation on a SQL Server forum.  I think you will be pleasantly surprised at the results you receive.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/sql-community-tech-forums/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
