<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ie &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/ie/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Has FireFox lost its Mojo, are FireFox user jumping ship to Chrome?</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 11:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/05/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have been using Chrome for over a year now and have been very happy with it. Yesterday version 5 was released, you can get it here: http://www.google.com/chrome I decided to look at some stats for this site and compared April of this year to April of last year. The image below has this information. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have been using Chrome for over a year now and have been very happy with it. Yesterday version 5 was released, you can get it here: http://www.google.com/chrome</p>
<p>I decided to look at some stats for this site and compared April of this year to April of last year. The image below has this information.</p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/WebDev//BrowserPercentage.PNG" alt="" title="" width="592" height="756" /></p>
<p>As you can see FireFox lost about 10% while Chrome gained 9% and Safari gained almost 1%. So what is going on, are the early adapters switching to Chrome from FireFox? Take a look at the <a href="http://marketshare.hitslink.com/browser-market-share.aspx?qprid=1">NetMarket stats</a></p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/WebDev//stats.PNG" alt="" title="" width="750" height="242" /></p>
<p>FireFox had 24.72% of all bowser traffic in November, in April it had 24.59%, FireFox didn&#8217;t gain anything in the last 6 months.</p>
<p>So what is going on? When Internet Explorer 6 was the dominant browser it was very easy for FireFox to grab market share. Internet Explorer 6 was a mess, Internet Explorer 8 is better but still not as good as either FireFox or Chrome in my opinion.</p>
<p>So what will happen to FireFox will they ever pass 25% or is this a downward spiral and within a year Chrome will have that 25% and FireFox will be at 15% or so? With all the new stuff like the Google&#8217;s App Store that Google is adding to Chrome its usage will have to grow fast.</p>
<p>What browser do you use and did you try Chrome and if so did you like it?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/has-firefox-lost-its-mojo-are-firefox-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Banish IE6? Not As Easy As You Think</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 12:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 7]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/05/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You have all seen sites that popup messages telling you that your IE6 browser is insecure and that you should upgrade to IE7/8, FireFox or Chrome. The reason for this is of course that IE6 is a terrible browser to develop against; nobody wants to spend half their time putting in CSS hacks so that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You have all seen sites that popup messages telling you that your IE6 browser is insecure and that you should upgrade to IE7/8, FireFox or Chrome. The reason for this is of course that IE6 is a terrible browser to develop against; nobody wants to spend half their time putting in CSS hacks so that their webpage looks halfway decent. Some sites like <a href="http://37signals.blogs.com/products/2008/07/basecamp-phasin.html">37signals decided to dump IE6</a> completely </p>
<p>So here is the problem with this, most companies I interact with won’t let you run as an administrator and you cannot install a single thing. Yeah you can download another browser but you can’t install it. Most of these companies also have windows update disabled on the machines, updates are pushed through LANDesk. A new browser is not part of these update pushes. Just imagine that you call help desk to ask them to install a new browser on your machine. Most probably you will get an answer that IE6 is the corporate standard and that it is the browser you have to use.</p>
<p>Of course some companies developed internal apps that use ActiveX and will only work on IE6, this is another reason that IE6 will not go away any time soon.</p>
<p>On our site IE6 still commands about 30% usage of total IE usage. Here is the breakdown for the last 10 months</p>
<pre>Aug 2008 30.06%
Sep 2008 31.14%
Oct 2008 30.10%
Nov 2008 28.62%
Dec 2008 28.95%
Jan 2009 29.74%
Feb 2009 30.38%
Mar 2009 29.73%
Apr 2009 25.90%
May 2009 24.76%</pre>
<p>As you can see it was around 30% until April and then it dropped. This drop is probably because of the introduction of IE8 in April at Mix09</p>
<p>Here is all IE for May</p>
<pre>IE7 57.73%	
IE6 24.76%	
IE8 17.51%</pre>
<p>As you can see IE8 is closing in on IE6 fast, it is however also taking market share away from IE7</p>
<p>It will be interesting to see how many people will upgrade to Windows 7 this year, so far XP is still king For the month of May 2009 XP traffic was 68.24% of all windows machines on our site</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/banish-ie6-not-as-easy-as-you-think/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
