<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>vista &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/vista-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to mount ISO images on Vista or Windows 7</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/how-to-mount-iso-images-on-vista-or-wind-7/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/how-to-mount-iso-images-on-vista-or-wind-7/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 11:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Operating Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iso files]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mounting files]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vista]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 7]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/06/how-to-mount-iso-images-on-vista-or-wind-7/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every time you buy a new computer you of course need to install a bunch of software. In my case this would be stuff mostly from MSDN Visual Studio 2008 + Service pack 1 SQL Server 2008 + Service pack 1 Expression Studio 2 Win XP SP 3 (to run on a virtual machine) Windows [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every time you buy a new computer you of course need to install a bunch of software. In my case this would be stuff mostly from MSDN </p>
<p><em>Visual Studio 2008 + Service pack 1<br />
SQL Server 2008 + Service pack 1<br />
Expression Studio 2<br />
Win XP SP 3 (to run on a virtual machine)<br />
Windows 7 RC (to run on a virtual machine)<br />
Visual Studio 2010 (to run inside the Win 7 virtual machine)<br />
Office 2007 Ultimate</em></p>
<p>The nice thing about Virtual machines is that you can mount an ISO right inside the machine, this way you don&#8217;t have to burn a CD or install a ISO mounter inside the virtual machine itself</p>
<p>If you upgraded from Windows XP to Vista you probably wonder how to mount images. On XP you might have used alcohol or the VCdControlTool provided (but unsupported) by Microsoft. On Vista (and I am running the 64 bit version) you can use <a href="http://www.magiciso.com/">MagicISO</a>. If you end up using this tool on a regular basis the I would suggest paying the $29 for it otherwise companies will stop making tools like this.<br />
MagicISO is very easy to use. After you install the program you will see a new icon in the  taskbar.</p>
<p>To mount an ISO do the following<br />
In the taskbar right click on the MagicISO button<br />
<img src="http://imgur.com/xVFHL.jpg" alt="In the taskbar right click on the MagicISO button" /></p>
<p>Select the topmost entry labeled Virtual CD/DVD-ROM, click on K: No Media<br />
<img src="http://imgur.com/tnvGo.jpg" alt="Select the topmost entry labeled Virtual CD/DVD-ROM, click on K: No Media" /></p>
<p>After that select Mount<br />
<img src="http://imgur.com/i47jQ.jpg" alt="After that select Mount" /></p>
<p>Now navigate to the folder that you have the ISO in<br />
<img src="http://imgur.com/4ae1m.jpg" alt="navigate to the folder that you have the ISO in" /></p>
<p>After you select the ISO you will see the following dialog box<br />
<img src="http://imgur.com/uHGpj.jpg" alt="dialog box" /></p>
<p>Now you can either run the program immediately or click on the K drive. It is as simple as that. MagicISO has versions optimized for Win 7 and Server 2008 and versions optimized for Vista</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/how-to-mount-iso-images-on-vista-or-wind-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enabling ReadyBoost In Vista</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/enabling-readyboost-in-vista/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/enabling-readyboost-in-vista/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 16:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Operating Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[readyboost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vista]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/06/enabling-readyboost-in-vista/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I just got a brand new shiny QuadCore PC with 6GB of RAM and Vista on it. I decided to setup ReadyBoost since I have a couple of USB dongles laying around. How does ReadyBoost work? Here is what Wikipedia has to say Using ReadyBoost-capable flash memory (NAND memory devices) for caching allows Windows [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I just got a brand new shiny QuadCore PC with 6GB of RAM and Vista on it. I decided to setup ReadyBoost since I have a couple of USB dongles laying around. </p>
<p>How does ReadyBoost work? Here is what <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readyboost">Wikipedia</a> has to say</p>
<blockquote><p>Using ReadyBoost-capable flash memory (NAND memory devices) for caching allows Windows Vista to service random disk reads with performance that is typically 80-100 times faster than random reads from traditional hard drives. This caching applies to all disk content, not just the page file or system DLLs. Flash devices typically are slower than a hard disk for sequential I/O so, to maximize performance, ReadyBoost includes logic that recognizes large, sequential read requests and has the hard disk service these requests</p></blockquote>
<p>Here are the requirements for the USB Device</p>
<p>For a device to be compatible and useful it must conform to these requirements:</p>
<ul>
<li>The removable media&#8217;s capacity must be at least 256 MB—250 MB after formatting. Windows Vista x86 is limited to using 3.5GB (Vista x64 can support up to 16GB); this restriction has been removed in Windows 7.</li>
<li>The device must have an access time of 1 ms or less.</li>
<li>The device must be capable of 2.5 MB/s read speeds for 4 KB random reads spread uniformly across the entire device, and 1.75 MB/s write speeds for 512 KB random writes spread uniformly across the device</li>
</ul>
<p>If you device meets that then follow these steps to enable ReadyBoost.</p>
<p>First find your USB device. Go to my computer, right click on the device and select properties.</p>
<p><img src="http://imgur.com/yGaRb.png" alt="right click on the device and select properties" /></p>
<p>If your device is ReadyBoost  enabled a tab named ReadyBoost will be visible</p>
<p>
<img src="http://imgur.com/4dPgq.png" alt="a tab named ReadyBoost will be visible" /></p>
<p>Finally check use this device, give it at least 640MB and you are ready to go</p>
<p>
<img src="http://imgur.com/GEW84.png" alt="ive it at least 640MB" /></p>
<p>Some additonal info about ReadyBoost can be found here: http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windows-vista/features/readyboost.aspx</p>
<p>ReadyBoost will also be available in Windows 7</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/enabling-readyboost-in-vista/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cool Way To Launch The Malicious Software Removal Tool</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/cool-way-to-launch-the-malicious-softwar/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/cool-way-to-launch-the-malicious-softwar/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 14:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics and IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malicious software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vista]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xp]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/01/cool-way-to-launch-the-malicious-softwar/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a cool way to launch the Malicious Software Removal Tool by Microsoft. I was listening to the Security Now 180: Listener Feedback 58 podcast and Leo Laporte and Steve Gibson described a cool way to launch the Malicious Software Removal Tool Here are both ways 1) Click on Start&#8211;>Run enter MRT and hit [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is a cool way to launch the Malicious Software Removal Tool by Microsoft. I was listening to the <a href="http://twit.tv/sn180">Security Now 180: Listener Feedback 58</a> podcast and Leo Laporte and Steve Gibson described a cool way to launch the Malicious Software Removal Tool</p>
<p>Here are both ways<br />
1) Click on Start&#8211;>Run enter MRT and hit enter</p>
<p>2) Right click anywhere on the desktop, then select New&#8211;>Shortcut, type MRT into the edit field, and hit Next and then Finish.  This will create a shortcut to MRT.exe, in this case the shortcut points to %windir%system32MRT.exe. Now you can just click on the shortcut to launch the Malicious Software Removal Tool</p>
<p>This will work on Vista and XP. Pretty cool right? I think everyone should listen to Security Now, If you are not subscribed to it then you should do it right now.</p>
<p>I will create a blogpost next week about all the podcast that I listen to</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/ethicsit/cool-way-to-launch-the-malicious-softwar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
