<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>communication &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/communication/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Communications Hack for Helpful Ideas</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/helpful-developers-and-angry-coworkers/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/helpful-developers-and-angry-coworkers/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 17:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Professionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4711</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;re taking a break from the two week project and bump into Joe at the coffee machine. He&#8217;s a little frazzled and starts telling you about this little task he took on Monday that is kicking his butt. While he&#8217;s explaining you realize he might have missed a simpler answer, so you ask him if [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;re taking a break from the two week project and bump into Joe at the coffee machine. He&#8217;s a little frazzled and starts telling you about this little task he took on Monday that is kicking his butt. While he&#8217;s explaining you realize he might have missed a simpler answer, so you ask him if he tried it. He immediately gets angry, of course he tried it, what are you trying to say? And here&#8217;s all the ways that wouldn&#8217;t work, and so on, then disappears back into his office. </p>
<p>Why is Joe always so annoyed? He needs to work on his communication skills.</p>
<h3>Joe&#8217;s Perspective</h3>
<p>You&#8217;re three days into a one hour problem, having chased down and exhausted 4 different approaches before finally finding an approach that is going to work. It&#8217;s a little ugly and you&#8217;re a little frustrated that it&#8217;s Wednesday afternoon on a task you though would be done by lunch on Monday. While you&#8217;re waiting for the coffee machine to do it&#8217;s thing, Mary joins you and asks how it&#8217;s going. Being top of mind, you start talking about the frustrating problem you&#8217;re working on and the (annoyingly) complex solution you&#8217;ve come up with. </p>
<p>Two sentences in, Mary jumps in, <i>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you do X?&#8221;</i></p>
<p><i>&#8220;What, you think I didn&#8217;t try that already?&#8221;</i> your inner voice wants to respond. </p>
<p>It puts you on the defensive, so you quickly explain why that wouldn&#8217;t work, maybe putting a little too much annoyance in your voice (but then again, she did assume you missed the solution she came up with in 5 seconds for a problem you&#8217;ve spent 2 days and 4 solutions on…). </p>
<p>Why does Mary always think so little of others?</p>
<h2><i>&#8220;Why did you…&#8221;</i> sounds different on the receiving end</h2>
<p>We&#8217;re problem solvers and want to solve challenges. It might be to help someone, it might be to help reinforce an image of ourselves as the smartest person on the team, or it might just be because problem solving is fun. When we offer a better solution and someone bites our hand off for it, we walk away thinking a little bit worse of them.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s easy to blame &#8220;Joe&#8221; and call him quick to anger, but sometimes we&#8217;re the &#8220;Joe&#8221; in the story and don&#8217;t know why we have to prove everything we say.</p>
<p><i>&#8220;Why did&#8230;&#8221;</i> can sound like a demand for an explanation or a challenge to our ability when we&#8217;re stressed and on the receiving end. However from the asking side it&#8217;s just words, most of the time we&#8217;re saying <i>&#8220;Why did you&#8230;?&#8221;</i> but thinking <i>&#8220;I wonder if they tried&#8230;?&#8221;</i>.</p>
<p>Communication takes two people, so weis the listener as well as the speaker. In the story above, Joe and Mary failed to communicate and it escalated. if it occurs frequently enough, it will leave them predisposed to one another and they&#8217;ll start purposefully treating one another antagonistically.</p>
<h2><i>&#8220;Have you considered…?&#8221;</i></h2>
<p>A few years back I was frequently butting heads (and vice versa) with a developer I respect a lot and consider a friend. It was a small team and I was spending more time developing then managing, so besides having naturally strong opinions as a developer, I had the manager title adding greater emphasis to everything I said.</p>
<p>Our conversations frequently devolved into defensive debates, and one day during a one-on-one we realized that the word choice we started conversations was the thing that tended to start off us of on the wrong foot. We decided to start using the phrase <i>&#8220;Have you considered&#8230;?&#8221;</i> in all of those cases where we would normally use <i>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you&#8230;?&#8221;</i></p>
<p>The change was instant and our conversations and whiteboarding sessions were immediately an order of magnitude better.</p>
<h2>Here&#8217;s why we think it worked</h2>
<p><i>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t [you]&#8230;?&#8221;</i> is really asking you to explain your actions (or lack of). It sounds like a challenge and it&#8217;s not hard to wonder if they also meant <i>&#8220;&#8230;and I assume you didn&#8217;t think of that&#8221;</i>. Add in some stress to exaggerate the possibility of a challenge into hearing one that most of the time isn&#8217;t there, and we&#8217;re instantly on the defensive.</p>
<p><i>&#8220;Have you considered&#8230;?</i>&#8221; is a more collaborative question. It forces you to acknowledge that they might have already considered what you&#8217;re about to say and, if you continue to say it, invites a conversation instead of an explanation. You have to actually want to hear about it if they tried the suggestion and it didn&#8217;t work. And the times where you did just want to drop in the answer and walk on, it forces you to rethink whether you want to be the person that assumes the folks around you can miss something for days that you noticed in 30 seconds (even if it&#8217;s true 90% of the time, you&#8217;re going to be wrong 10% of the time and annoying 110% of the time).</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t believe me? Try out these phrases:</p>
<p><i><br />
&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you use the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Have you considered using the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Why aren&#8217;t you using Angular for that project?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Have you considered Angular for that project?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you break that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Have you considered breaking that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
</i></p>
<p>Now try reading them in the other order:</p>
<p><i><br />
&#8220;Have you considered using the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you use the repository pattern for that problem?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Have you considered Angular for that project?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Why aren&#8217;t you using Angular for that project?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Have you considered breaking that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you break that 1000-line class into submodules?&#8221;<br />
</i></p>
<p>Can both versions of these questions be interpreted the same? Absolutely. But as you add stress, distraction, any history of interrupting folks to tell them at length how they should be solving their problems, &#8220;Why didn&#8217;t you&#8230;&#8221; does start to sound more like a challenge.</p>
<h2>The results as we spread it further</h2>
<p>It absolutely worked in our situation, to the degree that we shared the phrase and results with the rest of the team a few weeks later and, several years later, we continue to use it and introduce it to new folks. It may not be exactly the phrase you need in your environment, but find a phrase that everyone interprets as &#8220;I respect you, would like to know more about the problem, and wonder what you found when trying X&#8221; and use it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/helpful-developers-and-angry-coworkers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hiding Outages is a Short Term Game</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/hiding-outages-is-a-short/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/hiding-outages-is-a-short/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eli Weinstock-Herman (tarwn)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IT Service Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running My Own IT Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outages]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/10/hiding-outages-is-a-short/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[5:20 PM on Saturday night, looking for the correct size air filter at the local superstore. My phone dings and chirps, as I receive almost simultaneous email and twitter alerts; our production application can't talk to it's database. As a SaaS company, it rolls downhill. An unexpected outage with our application means an unexpected service outage for our customers. Time to head home and start troubleshooting.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>5:20 PM</strong> on Saturday night, looking for the correct size air filter at the local superstore. My phone dings and chirps, as I receive almost simultaneous email and twitter alerts; our production application can&#8217;t talk to it&#8217;s database. As a SaaS company, it rolls downhill. An unexpected outage with our application means an unexpected service outage for our customers. Time to head home and start troubleshooting.</p>
<p><strong>5:45 PM</strong>. After logging into the service provider dashboard, I find that the database services tab is completely non-functional. Attempts to connect to the database from home also fails. Various other troubleshooting directions are followed and also meet in failure.</p>
<p>And then some scheduled jobs in our development and staging environments kick off and also report database timeouts. It&#8217;s getting increasingly unlikely that this is us, time to contact support.</p>
<p><strong>6.45 PM</strong>. Calling support leaves me in a hold queue that is experiencing &#8220;longer than normal call volume&#8221;. Maybe this isn&#8217;t just me? I check the service status page and everything is green. Still waiting on hold. I check twitter and don&#8217;t see any mentions. </p>
<p><strong>7:10 PM</strong>. Lets check the public forums&#8230;ah, there&#8217;s a few other people with this problem. I add my own personal story so we can help flesh out the picture of what&#8217;s going on. </p>
<p><strong>7:15 PM</strong>. 30 minutes into the hold queue and I just got transferred to a ringing phone. After seeing the forum post, I suspect I&#8217;ll end up getting a canned &#8220;We know there&#8217;s a problem, we don&#8217;t know what it is or when it will be fixed, thank you for all your money&#8221; speech. So I&#8217;m a little surprised when after two minutes of ringing the phone simply goes dead. </p>
<p>By now I&#8217;ve added a few tweets to twitter with the appropriate tags, started looking at the SLA information for the service, and generally just continue to waste my evening in front of the computer instead of spending time with my wife and two year old. </p>
<p>And time passes.</p>
<p><strong>8:10 PM</strong>. I&#8217;ve been refreshing the status dashboard every 10 minutes since I first opened it but this is the first change. Red notifications show up, along with hourly messages going back in time to 5:11 PM. I add a note to the forum and a tweet for anyone else waiting for some word from our service provider. The messages are fairly generic and innocuous, admitting that some customers may experience outages with given services and regions. We apologize for the inconvenience.</p>
<p>We couldn&#8217;t be bothered to provide an update for 3 hours, but we apologize for the inconvenience.</p>
<p>Your business has been down for three hours and there was no official announcement you could point your customers to, but we apologize for the inconvenience.</p>
<h2>Admit Your Service Outages?</h2>
<p>I would bet we have all worked with companies or products that go to great pains not to announce bugs or outages to their end users. After all, admitting an outage means that the people that didn&#8217;t get affected will know about it too, and that looks bad.</p>
<p>Maybe we&#8217;re afraid of upsetting users that weren&#8217;t online at the time, of losing customers, of warning off potential users, of providing inside information to our competitors, or getting negative press.</p>
<h3>Been There&#8230;</h3>
<p>I once worked with a manager that screened each outage email, broadcasting only the ones that he felt were important enough to be forwarded, which tended to be none of them. Our service levels improved amazingly in the short term. Unfortunately since we weren&#8217;t keeping our users informed, each outage took longer to correct as we also fielded calls from end users thinking it was just a problem with their system. Which meant our mean time to fix outages went down and affected more people. Which meant that the overall public consensus of our service level got poorer, especially as people realized we were simply not reporting our outages anymore. </p>
<p>We lost credibility. Our service levels were reduced to levels we had worked years to raise them from. The trust our end users extended to us was heavily impacted. </p>
<p>Before that slow slide back into the mud, we had originally climbed out by being open about our outages. Every outage had been announced, often before we had a fix identified, with follow-ups when information was available. Users trusted us more because they could see us jumping on problems, hear us being honest and open with them, and see the problems getting taken care of. We didn&#8217;t have to tell them how much things were improving, they saw it. </p>
<p>But we stopped admitting our outages, and for a short time we looked even better. Then we looked far, far worse.</p>
<h3>Pretending Doesn&#8217;t Make It So</h3>
<p>Hiding bad news to protect your image is a short term loan with major long term costs. Your statistics are broken, so justifying and performing root cause analysis is that much harder. You are limited in what you can ask or discuss with your customers, because each one has to be treated as a potential leak. Your support services are put under a lot of strain and probably built with a higher focus on cost reduction than quality of service.</p>
<p>In short, all of the energy you are spending to look awesome is actually moving you further away and unlikely to be fooling your end users.</p>
<h2>Back to Saturday Night</h2>
<p>Saturday night, a well known service provider had an outage that shut down our business for 3 hours and 31 minutes. </p>
<p>For 3 hours we were in the dark and then, when an update was provided, it was backdated to look like we had been kept in the loop the whole time. Countless hours were wasted as we and many other customers tried troubleshooting a problem that wasn&#8217;t in our systems. The support center was overloaded (or just not responding). And at the end of the night a degree of credibility and trust was thrown away.</p>
<p>Someone had an opportunity to shine, and instead chose to make a bad situation that much worse.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/itservicemanagement/hiding-outages-is-a-short/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
