<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>career &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/career/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The times they are a-changin’</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/the-times-they-are-a/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/the-times-they-are-a/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[element61]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intense school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mssqltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/10/the-times-they-are-a/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This blog post will not be about Bob Dylan, but rather about some professional changes/challenges I’ve been up to lately.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">This blog post will not be about Bob Dylan, but rather about some professional changes/challenges I’ve been up to lately.</p>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: justify;">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a title="http://www.element61.be/" href="http://www.element61.be/"><img style="float: left;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/timeschanging/e61_v8.png?mtime=1383041522" alt="" width="161" height="70" /></a></p>
<p>The most important one is my switch to a new employer. After almost 3 years being happily employed at Ordina Belgium, I’ll move to <a href="http://www.element61.be/">element61</a> in November. element61 is a Performance Management and Business Intelligence consultancy firm. From their website: “<em>element61 is the thought-leading Business Analytics, Performance Management and Financial Reporting consulting company in the Belgian marketplace. Today, element61 has brought together the most experienced team in Performance Management, BI &amp; data warehousing in Belgium. The company has grown in 6 years to about 36 senior consultants with -on average- 12 years of experience in PM &amp; BI, totaling over 425 man years of experience</em>”.</p>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">element61 encourages its employees to write articles – called Insights – for their website. There are really interesting pieces about various aspects of BI and PM, and they are not restricted to a single vendor. There are insights about SQL Server, but also about SAP, Cognos, Business Objects or about general topics such as data quality. You can find an overview </span><a style="text-align: justify;" href="http://www.element61.be/e/resourc.asp?ResourceTypeId=22">here</a><span style="text-align: justify;">. I’ll probably write some insights too in the future and I’ll let you know when one is published.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The main reason for my move is the extremely talented and experienced team of element61. I’ll definitely learn a lot from them in my time there and I look forward to joining the team.</p>
</div>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: justify;"><a title="http://resources.intenseschool.com/" href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/"><img style="float: left; margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/timeschanging/IntenseSchool_logo.gif?mtime=1383041520" alt="" width="204" height="33" /></a></p>
<p>The second change is that I have started writing technical articles for two websites. The technical content is still SQL Server of course, focused on business intelligence and Integration Services in particular. The first site is the resource page of <a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/">Intense School</a>. Intense School is a training provider, offering accelerated IT trainings (classroom, on-site and on-line) from different vendors, such as Cisco, Microsoft, Red Hat and so on. They were looking to expand their resource page on SQL Server, and that’s where I came into the picture. I have already written two articles for their site. The first is a two-part piece on how to implement slowly changing dimensions in SSIS, exploring the various possibilities and alternatives: <a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/four-methods-for-implementing-a-slowly-changing-dimension-in-integration-services-part-i/">part I</a> and <a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/four-methods-for-implementing-a-slowly-changing-dimension-in-integration-services-part-ii/">part II</a>. The second article is a collection of tips for starting SSIS developers: <a href="http://resources.intenseschool.com/5-tips-to-make-you-a-pro-ssis-developer/">5 tips to make you a pro SSIS developer</a>. For more information about the services offered by Intense School, you can visit <a href="http://www.intenseschool.com/">their website</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="image_block" style="text-align: justify;"><a title="www.mssqltips.com" href="http://www.mssqltips.com/"><img style="float: left; margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/users/koenverbeeck/timeschanging/mssqltips_logo.png?mtime=1383041521" alt="" width="105" height="70" /></a>The second site is a well-known resource hub for SQL Server related articles: <a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/">MSSQLTips.com</a>. Obviously the tips I will write will be about SQL Server. I’m joining an extraordinary team of writers and I’m proud to be a part of it. I already have on tip published: <a href="http://www.mssqltips.com/sqlservertip/3072/sql-server-integration-services-ssis-transactions-without-msdtc/">SQL Server Integration Services SSIS Transactions without MSDTC</a>. I’m currently working on a 3-part introductory to BIML, so keep your eye on their website.</div>
<p><span style="text-align: justify;">A lot of writing ahead, but don’t worry, I’ll still update this blog.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Cheers,<br /> Koen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/the-times-they-are-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quite a career change</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/quite-a-career-change/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/quite-a-career-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 08:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Axel Achten (axel8s)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product information management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2013/09/quite-a-career-change/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Long time since I posted something on this blog but I hope to pick up the pace again. Only the subjects of the post will slightly change.
Working for a large e-business integrator in Belgium]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Long time since I posted something on this blog but I hope to pick up the pace again. Only the subjects of the post will slightly change.<br />
Working for a large e-business integrator in Belgium can have some unexpected effects on your career. It all started almost a year ago with a simple sentence: &#8220;We want to extend our product portfolio with Product Information Management and we think you are the right person to help us with this.&#8221;<br />
Well, I was free to decide, continue with SQL Server like the 12 years before or close my eyes and jump into the dark.<br />
I gave it some thought, looked at the pros and cons and decided to go for it.</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/simonk/4794640288/in/photolist-8iFMvS-8K1sP8-9GAiNZ-bPx25B-8TfF2B-asUwcB-asXa7A-asUwxR-asUvwX-asX92Y-asX9gJ-asUwFP-8QHDjD-8QHDjx-aBfrCB-7XhCeU-asX9C5-asX8T9-98Tq5c-bFtGiz-cW9GVh-cW9E4U-cWHzvU-cWbw17-cWJTp1-cW9EoQ-cWJ9nS-cWbvKQ-d78EiG-d78EoG-cWbv5G-cWJZmA-cW9Feq-fkpmvK-8CR1Hi-bEetC3-bT9dGv-bT9dEx-bT9dBt-bEetxu-bEetvL-bEetz1-bT9duP-b7CwFT-b7CwyR-bT9diz-bEetiE-bT9dfP-bT9dsB-bEetm9-bT9dqZ/lightbox/"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Axel/CarreerChange.jpg?mtime=1378996829" width="500" height="374" /></a></div>
<h1>Why?</h1>
<p>After 12 years of explaining how you can prevent the unstoppable logfile growth, explaining the foreign key principles to senior developers, removing unused indexes&#8230; I found for myself I was still interested in SQL Server but not in the things I needed to do for the customers. So it was time for a new challenge and it was offered on a silver plate. So why not?<br />
To make sure there was a way back, I booked the exams to upgrade my SQL Server certifications to MCSE data platform so in case of&#8230; I could still return to the market with a valid certificate for some years.<br />
So I hope to share the journey of learning all about Product Information Management and a bit about E-commerce on this site.</p>
<p>See you soon</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/quite-a-career-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moving on</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/my-new-home-with-magenic/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/my-new-home-with-magenic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 11:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ted Krueger (onpnt)]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Professional Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/11/my-new-home-with-magenic/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After this week comes to an end, I will be moving to the Magenic family.  I say family because over the months of talking to them I quickly realized that the group at Magenic truly is a family.  Not only one that holds themselves together with a high level of expertise but one that openly draws off each others knowledge and skills.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image_block"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/moving-day.jpg" alt="" title="" width="468" height="330" /></div>
<p>The SQL Community is an important part to everything I do both in work and pleasure.  Over the last year, I&#8217;ve started to realize that the work aspect to my life could be pushed higher and at the same time, pushed more into a role that benefits the SQL Community.  It is always hard to disconnect yourself as a production DBA from the systems that you build and nurture from a failing service into an enterprise worthy service.  Even so, I&#8217;ve made the decision to part with those systems and my current employer to move into a role that will for one, be more challenging and second, a company that supports both the community and has great pride in the product and services they provide.</p>
<p>After this week comes to an end, I will be moving to the <a href="http://www.magenic.com/">Magenic</a> family.  I say family because over the months of talking to them I quickly realized that the group at Magenic truly is a family.  Not only one that holds themselves together with a high level of expertise but one that openly draws off each others knowledge and skills. </p>
<p>All job changes come with a certain amount of disconnect while the adjustments are made.  I hope this change will be quick so I can keep to my goals of helping the community from the forum, blog and speaking side of things.  I would like to thank everyone (and I mean everyone) in the community for the years of helping me push myself daily to be better.  I owe this change to all of you as much as anyone.</p>
<p>I look forward to the future and sharing everything it has with the community.</p>
<p>Personal thanks go out to my future new coworkers Aaron Lowe and Wendy Patrick.  I can’t wait to get the SQL Saturday in Chicago crew back together now in roles where we can take over the data architecture world!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/professionaldevelopment/my-new-home-with-magenic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
