<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>office &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/office/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>E-Books in epu, mobi and pdf for Microsoft Technologies available for download</title>
		<link>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/e-book-in-epu-mobi/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/e-book-in-epu-mobi/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 23:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mvc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pdf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sql server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2012/06/e-book-in-epu-mobi/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Microsoft Technet site has made available a bunch of ebooks in epub, mobi and pdf formats

At this moment there are 11 books available, here is the list 


ASP.NET	
Deploying an ASP.NET Web Application to a Hosting Provider using Visual Studio&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Microsoft Technet site has made available a bunch of e-books in epub, mobi and pdf formats</p>
<p>At this moment there are 11 books available, here is the list </p>
<p><strong><em>ASP.NET</em></strong><br />
Deploying an ASP.NET Web Application to a Hosting Provider using Visual Studio<br />
Getting Started with ASP.NET 4.5 Web Forms (Beta)<br />
Intro to ASP.NET MVC 4 with Visual Studio (Beta)</p>
<p><em><strong>Office</strong></em><br />
Configure Kerberos Authentication for SharePoint 2010 Products</p>
<p><em><strong>SQL Server</strong></em><br />
Master Data Services Capacity Guidelines<br />
Microsoft SQL Server AlwaysOn Solutions Guide for High Availability and Disaster Recovery<br />
Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services Multidimensional Performance and Operations Guide<br />
QuickStart: Learn DAX Basics in 30 Minutes<br />
SQL Server 2012 Transact-SQL DML Reference</p>
<p><strong><em>Windows Azure</em></strong><br />
Windows Azure Prescriptive Guidance<br />
Windows Azure Service Bus Reference</p>
<p>Some of these books are pretty short, the shortest one is 6 pages, there are also longer books, the longest one is 422 pages. This a good deal, now you can load these books on your mobile device and even if you don&#8217;t have connectivity, you will be able to pick up some new things that you will learn from these books</p>
<p>You can check out all these books here: http://social.technet.microsoft.com/wiki/contents/articles/11608.e-book-gallery-for-microsoft-technologies.aspx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/itprofessionals/book-review/e-book-in-epu-mobi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vulnerability in Microsoft Office Web Components control could allow remote code execution</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/vulnerability-in-microsoft-office-web-co/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/vulnerability-in-microsoft-office-web-co/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 12:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Operating Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/07/vulnerability-in-microsoft-office-web-co/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Vulnerability in Microsoft Office Web Components control could allow remote code execution Another critical problem that is currently being exploited in the wild (0 day attack). Microsoft is investigating a privately reported vulnerability in Microsoft Office Web Components. An attacker who successfully exploited this vulnerability could gain the same user rights as the local user. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vulnerability in Microsoft Office Web Components control could allow remote code execution</p>
<p>Another critical problem that is currently being exploited in the wild (0 day attack). Microsoft is investigating a privately reported vulnerability in Microsoft Office Web Components. An attacker who successfully exploited this vulnerability could gain the same user rights as the local user. When using Internet Explorer, code execution is remote and may not require any user intervention.<br />
We are aware of attacks attempting to exploit the vulnerability.</p>
<p>Below is a list of affected software, if you have the latest service pack on Office 2007 then you are safe</p>
<p><strong>Affected Software</strong><br />
Microsoft Office XP Service Pack 3<br />
Microsoft Office 2003 Service Pack 3<br />
Microsoft Office XP Web Components Service Pack 3<br />
Microsoft Office 2003 Web Components Service Pack 3<br />
Microsoft Office 2003 Web Components for the 2007 Microsoft Office system Service Pack 1<br />
Microsoft Internet Security and Acceleration Server 2004 Standard Edition Service Pack 3<br />
Microsoft Internet Security and Acceleration Server 2004 Enterprise Edition Service Pack 3<br />
Microsoft Internet Security and Acceleration Server 2006<br />
Internet Security and Acceleration Server 2006 Supportability Update<br />
Microsoft Internet Security and Acceleration Server 2006 Service Pack 1<br />
Microsoft Office Small Business Accounting 2006</p>
<p><strong>Non-Affected Software</strong><br />
Microsoft Office 2000 Service Pack 3<br />
2007 Microsoft Office Suite Service Pack 1 and 2007 Microsoft Office Suite Service Pack 2<br />
Microsoft Office Compatibility Pack for Word, Excel, and PowerPoint 2007 File Formats Service Pack 1 and Microsoft Office Compatibility Pack for Word, Excel, and PowerPoint 2007 File Formats Service Pack 2<br />
Microsoft Forefront Threat Management Gateway, Medium Business Edition<br />
Microsoft Internet Security and Acceleration Server 2000 Service Pack 2</p>
<p>You can use the workaround found in this link: http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/advisory/973472.mspx</p>
<p>You can also use the fix-it button found in this link: http://support.microsoft.com/kb/973472</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/vulnerability-in-microsoft-office-web-co/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
