<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>wpf &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/wpf/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Visual Studio 2010 and .NET Framework 4 Training Kit June 2010 Release Available</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-and-net-framework-4-t/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-and-net-framework-4-t/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 13:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[C#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VB.NET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.net framework 4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ado.net data services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[f#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parallel extensions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual basic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual studio 2010]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wcf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wwf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2010/06/visual-studio-2010-and-net-framework-4-t/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has made available for download the June 2010 Release of the Visual Studio 2010 and .NET Framework 4 Training Kit. The Visual Studio 2010 and .NET Framework 4 Training Kit includes presentations, hands-on labs, and demos. This content is designed to help you learn how to utilize the Visual Studio 2010 features and a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has made available for download the June 2010 Release of the Visual Studio 2010 and .NET Framework 4 Training Kit.</p>
<p>The Visual Studio 2010 and .NET Framework 4 Training Kit includes presentations, hands-on labs, and demos. This content is designed to help you learn how to utilize the Visual Studio 2010 features and a variety of framework technologies including:<br />
C# 4<br />
Visual Basic 10<br />
F#<br />
Parallel Extensions<br />
Windows Communication Foundation<br />
Windows Workflow<br />
Windows Presentation Foundation<br />
ASP.NET 4<br />
Windows 7<br />
Entity Framework<br />
ADO.NET Data Services<br />
Managed Extensibility Framework<br />
Visual Studio Team System</p>
<p>The size of the download file is 178.0 MB and you can download it here: http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=752CB725-969B-4732-A383-ED5740F02E93&amp;displaylang=en</p>
<p>Channel 9 also has a bunch of video available, you can find all 41 videos here: http://channel9.msdn.com/shows/10-4/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-and-net-framework-4-t/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual Studio 2010 Screenshots</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-screenshots/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-screenshots/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[f#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual studio 2010]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/05/visual-studio-2010-screenshots/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2010 has been made available to MSDN subscribers yesterday. I downloaded Visual Studio 2010 today and installed it on Windows 7 RC. I took some images so that you can see what it looks like

Here is what the setup screen looks like, noth&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Visual Studio 2010 has been made available to MSDN subscribers yesterday. I downloaded Visual Studio 2010 today and installed it on Windows 7 RC. I took some images so that you can see what it looks like</p>
<p>The new welcome screen in Visual Studio 2010</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20101.png?mtime=1357606093"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20101.png?mtime=1357606093" width="735" height="521" /></a></div>
<p>
In Visual Studio 2010 you can target frameworks 2.0, 3.0, 3.5 and 4.0</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20102.png?mtime=1357606111"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20102.png?mtime=1357606111" width="605" height="657" /></a></div>
<p>
The toolbox has changed in Visual Studio 2010. it looks a lot cleaner to me. Finally we have a toolbox which does not resemble the Visual Basic 4 toolbox anymore</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20103.png?mtime=1357606121"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20103.png?mtime=1357606121" width="864" height="643" /></a></div>
<p>
Finally here is what a WPF project looks like</p>
<div class="image_block"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20104.png?mtime=1357606132"><img alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/blogs/ITProfessionals/Denis/vs20104.png?mtime=1357606132" width="436" height="638" /></a></div>
<p></p>
<p>So what do you think, do you like the looks of Visual Studio 2010?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/visual-studio-2010-screenshots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kaxaml a lightweight XAML editor</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/kaxaml-a-lightweight-xaml-editor/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/kaxaml-a-lightweight-xaml-editor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 17:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design, Graphics and Styling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaxaml]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xaml]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/02/kaxaml-a-lightweight-xaml-editor/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kaxaml is a lightweight XAML editor that gives you a &#8220;split view&#8221; so you can see both your XAML and your rendered content (kind of like XamlPad but without the gigabyte of SDK). First watch the video on channel 9 to see what it looks like. Here is what is covered: Robby Ingebretsen came by [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kaxaml is a lightweight XAML editor that gives you a &#8220;split view&#8221; so you can see both your XAML and your rendered content (kind of like XamlPad but without the gigabyte of SDK).</p>
<p>First watch the video on channel 9 to see what it looks like. Here is what is covered:</p>
<blockquote><p>Robby Ingebretsen came by to explain what Kaxaml is and how it can be useful to you when developing XAML-based applications.  Not only does he introduce the tool, but he also touches on some of the lesser known features and add-ins that may be missed on an initial glance.</p>
<p>Robby also discusses the fact that he will be presenting two workshops at MIX09.  The first is Design Fundamentals for Developers and the second, with Jaime Rodriguez, Hiking Mt Avalon.</p></blockquote>
<p>You can watch the show here: http://channel9.msdn.com/shows/Continuum/Kaxaml/</p>
<p>The video runs for 18 minutes and 11 seconds</p>
<p>You can download Kaxaml here: http://www.kaxaml.com/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/webdesigngraphicsstyling/kaxaml-a-lightweight-xaml-editor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of MCTS Self-Paced Training Kit (Exam 70-502): Microsoft .NET Framework 3.5 Windows Presentation Foundation</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 15:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.net 3.5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows presentation foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Review of MCTS Self-Paced Training Kit (Exam 70-502): Microsoft .NET Framework 3.5 Windows Presentation Foundation Written by Matthew A. Stoecker This book has 524 pages The reason I read exam preparation books is to learn things about the product which you would otherwise learn the hard way, you might have introduced bugs because you didn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Review of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735625662?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=sql08-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creativeASIN=0735625662">MCTS Self-Paced Training Kit (Exam 70-502): Microsoft .NET Framework 3.5 Windows Presentation Foundation</a> </strong></p>
<p>Written by Matthew A. Stoecker<br />
This book has 524 pages</p>
<p>The reason I read exam preparation books is to learn things about the product which you would otherwise learn the hard way, you might have introduced bugs because you didn&#8217;t know why certain things worked the way they did. Taking the preparation exams in the book is also another good way to see if you have actually mastered the material inside the book. This book is organized in 10 chapters. If you have done Windows Forms programming then you will have no problem following the material in the book, it is written in a clear and concise matter and source code is in C# and VB. </p>
<p>Here is what is covered in each chapter.</p>
<p>Chapter one explains the different kinds of WPF apps that you can develop and when you should chose one over the other.<br />
Chapter two is about Evens, Event Handling, Commands and Application Settings.<br />
Chapter three is all about building the user interface.<br />
Chapter four is about content, this includes images and binary resources.<br />
Chapter five is about data binding including ADO.NET and XML.<br />
Chapter six is about data validation and conversion, this includes implementing IValueConverter.<br />
Chapter seven is all about Styles and Animation. This chapter is where the fun of WPF programming is. You will learn about using triggers, animations, styles and understanding Property Value Precedence.<br />
Chapter eighth is all about customizing the User Interface.<br />
Chapter nine deals with Resources, Localization and Documents.<br />
Chapter ten will teach you how to deploy and application including using a windows installer or ClickOnce</p>
<p>After you are done with this book you will be able to create a Windows Presentation Foundation application from start to finish including deployment. You will also learn that you can do things in code or in XAML and that the end result is the same. I highly recommend this book for any person who has done at least 6 months of Windows Forms. Windows Presentation Foundation is the natural evolution of Windows Forms and this book will help you master the cool stuff and let you know about pitfalls. You will learn that all your Windows Forms knowledge is still relevant, you will also learn that WPF is so much more than Windows Forms. The graphics features and multimedia integration alone will make you stay up until the early morning to create that cool app to show to your boss.</p>
<p>One thing I would recommend is to read this book twice, reading things the second time around will make it very clear why things are done a certain way</p>
<p>This book is a must if you want to pass the 70-502 exam or if you want to learn about Windows Presentation Foundation</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/review-of-mcts-self-paced-training-kit-e/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>WPF Performance Profiling Tools</title>
		<link>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/wpf-performance-profiling-tools/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/wpf-performance-profiling-tools/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 23:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.net 3.5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows presentation foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wpf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2008/09/wpf-performance-profiling-tools/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you have done windows forms development in the past and now you are using Windows Presentation Foundation, then you cannot help but notice that Windows Presentation Foundation uses more resources. This is why you need Performance Profiling Tools for WPF. Below is a list of 5 five performance profiling tools that are included in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you have done windows forms development in the past and now you are using Windows Presentation Foundation, then you cannot help but notice that Windows Presentation Foundation uses more resources.</p>
<p>This is why you need Performance Profiling Tools for WPF. Below is a list of 5 five performance profiling tools that are included in the Windows SDK tool, WPFPerf:<br />
<strong><br />
Perforator</strong><br />
Use for analyzing rendering behavior.</p>
<p><strong>Visual Profiler</strong><br />
Use for profiling the use of WPF services, such as layout and event handling, by elements in the visual tree.</p>
<p><strong>Working Set Analyzer</strong><br />
Use for analyzing the working set characteristics of your application.</p>
<p><strong>Event Trace</strong><br />
Use for analyzing events and generating event log files.</p>
<p><strong>ETW Trace Viewer</strong><br />
Record, display, and browse Event Tracing for Windows (ETW) log files in a WPF user-interface format. </p>
<p>To get more details about these tools visit this link: <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa969767.aspx">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa969767.aspx</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/desktopdev/mstech/wpf-performance-profiling-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
