<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>tableau &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/tableau/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook – Review</title>
		<link>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 11:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization cookbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After my review of Tableau Dashboard Cookbook, I read another book about Tableau, namely Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook by Ashutosh Nandeshwar. The book is published by Packt but I am relieved to say this time there were no significant editing issues. In fact it is quite well written and as far as I could tell [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">After my review of <a href="/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/">Tableau Dashboard Cookbook</a>, I read another book about Tableau, namely <a href="http://amzn.to/1RzPjkU">Tableau Data Visualization Cookbook</a> by Ashutosh Nandeshwar. The book is published by Packt but I am relieved to say this time there were no significant editing issues. In fact it is quite well written and as far as I could tell there were no spelling mistakes or typos (yeah those things can really bug me out when reading a book).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The book promises “Over 70 recipes for creating visual stories with your data using Tableau”. That sounds like a lot and it is, because the book (the actual content, not counting preface, indexes …) is about 150 pages long. In other words, a little over 2 pages per recipe. In fact, I actually counted them (I have apparently nothing better to do). There are 74 recipes spread out over 147 pages, so 1.986 pages per recipe. Those are not long recipes. Some other numbers: the shortest recipe is 2 bullet points. It’s about adding a wildcard filter on a worksheet, but it actually builds upon a previous recipe, so it doesn’t count. The following scatter plot (created with Tableau of course) gives an overview of the various lengths of the recipes encountered in the book:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2898" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png" alt="scatterplot" width="500" height="598" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot.png 573w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/scatterplot-250x300.png 250w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">There are quite a few very short recipes, which can easily be verified with a histogram:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2897" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png" alt="histogram" width="500" height="521" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram.png 725w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/histogram-288x300.png 288w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">As you can notice, the distribution is a little bit skewed to the left (sorry for the sarcasm). Recipes with a length of 6 or shorter make up over 50% of the book. More statistics can be deduced from this box and whisker plot:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2899" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png" alt="boxwhiskerplot" width="800" height="146" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot.png 973w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/08/boxwhiskerplot-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What is my point in all this (aside from me giving the opportunity to myself to exercise creating some charts in Tableau)? The point is that this book is short and the recipes are too basic. 74 recipes in 150 pages, clearly the choice for quantity over quality has been made. It would have been much better if the bulk of those recipes were bundled into a few recipes who were longer but also more complex and challenging. Now most of the recipes just scratch the surface of a feature and never go into any depth. They are the equivalent of a recipe for boiling potatoes:</p>
<ol style="text-align: justify">
<li>Peel potatoes.</li>
<li>Throw them in boiling water.</li>
<li>Wait for 10 to 20 minutes, depending on type of potatoes.</li>
<li>Bon appétit.</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: justify">Maybe in another chapter you get a recipe for cooking vegetables and in another for grilling meat, but you don’t get instructions to cook a lovely meal with all of the ingredients (and now I’m hungry…). There are three chapter dealing with almost the same basic stuff: creating visualizations with one measure, creating visualizations with two measures and finally creating visualizations with multiple measures. Those should be combined in one single chapter with just a couple of interesting recipes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Another issue is that the author sometimes doesn’t bother to give more information on how the resulting visualization should be interpreted (from time to time the resulting visualization looks nice, but is rubbish from a business perspective becomes it doesn’t really give useful insights). Anyway, this is just a detail. The author does include a lot of links to reference material however, which is certainly a big plus. He also gives some good advice about the different types of charts, for example what the downsides are of pie charts and stacked area charts and how to avoid them.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">The book is way too basic and this because of the overly simplistic recipes. Get this book only if you are an absolute beginner in Tableau and have never read anything about this tool or if you are an absolute novice in data visualizations tools. In my opinion, the <a href="/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/">Tableau Dashboard Cookbook</a> by Jen Stirrup offers considerable more depth (despite the editing issues) and you’ll learn more tricks than in this book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/datamgmt/tableau-data-visualization-cookbook-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tableau Dashboard Cookbook by Jen Stirrup</title>
		<link>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 08:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Koen Verbeeck]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataviz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tableau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DISCLAIMER I received this book through the O’Reilly blogger review program, which I already mentioned in the review of Thinking With Data. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself. TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">DISCLAIMER</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I received this book through the <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/reviews/">O’Reilly blogger review program</a>, which I already mentioned in the review of <a href="/index.php/datamgmt/thinking-with-data-by-max-shron/">Thinking With Data</a>. The actual publisher of the book is Packt Publishing, not O’Reilly itself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">TABLEAU DASHBOARD COOKBOOK</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">I guess most people who have been in contact with the SQL Server community have at least heard of Jen Stirrup (<a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/">blog</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/jenstirrup">twitter</a>): she currently holds the PASS board seat for Europe, she has spoken at dozens of different events and has won the PASSion award in 2012. I have watched her speak at the SQL Server Days in Belgium a few times before and this year she will deliver <a href="http://www.sqlserverdays.be/precon/#jen">a full precon about Power BI and R</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s say I was a little bit excited when I heard she wrote<a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781782177906.do"> a book about Tableau</a>. I had no experience whatsoever with Tableau, but I had seen some demos and visualizations so I was anxious to try out the product. I got myself the book and I downloaded the free trial of <a href="http://www.tableausoftware.com/products/desktop">Tableau Desktop 8.2</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><em>Note:</em> the trial is only 10 days, so if you want to finish the entire book in that time period, you better reserve some quality reading time for yourself.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2816" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover.gif" alt="tableau_dashboard_cookbook_cover" width="180" height="222" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Let’s start with the good stuff. Personally I loved this book and the main reason is because it is very hands-on: there are a lot of examples (or recipes if you follow the cookbook doctrine) that guide you step-by-step through the features of Tableau. For readers inexperienced with Tableau – such as myself – this is a great way to discover the product without being overwhelmed by its many features. Each recipe starts with a short introduction – not too long so it doesn’t get tedious – and then dives directly into the action. At the end there is a small recap of what you just did and how it works and there are optionally some pointers to further references. The book is limited on theory but overloaded with practicalities, which was very appealing to me. I felt I learned a great deal about Tableau by reading this book, but I also realized I just learned the basic functionalities of the product. That’s why this book may not be suited for already advanced users of Tableau; they may not find a lot of new information in this book.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">A small disadvantage is that this book is (in theory) already outdated because it deals with Tableau 8.1, while the 8.2 version has just been released. However, I didn’t experience much difficulties over this. The only obvious difference is the import of multiple files, where there is now a much more graphical and easier to use interface to join tables together.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Personally I found that this book is best read from front to back, as the recipes in a single chapter often depend on each other: you start with a blank worksheet and in each recipe you build on top of the other until you end with a working dashboard at the end of the chapter. Also, sometimes chapters depend on the finished dashboard of the previous chapter. This makes it a bit harder to just jump to a chapter in the book and do some recipes. Luckily you can download finished worksheets from the publishers’ website.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">What I found a little bit disappointing was the section in the final chapter about R, called <em>Wrapping up with R – dashboards as a tool</em>. I have been toying with the R language lately and I expected to see some cool stuff there. But there was only an introduction on how to install R with a package called Rserve and how to set-up a connection from within Tableau to Rserver. That’s it. No demonstration on how to actually use R with Tableau. I would have liked some more material over there, or maybe something in an addendum. An idea perhaps for a second edition? Anyway, this book is not about R but about Tableau <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify">Now on to the bad stuff. Quite early on in the book – somewhere in chapter 2 – it became very clear that this book was badly edited. There are no spelling or grammar mistakes – not that I know of – but sometimes screenshots are switched or even wrong. One time a recipe – which is essentially a bulleted list of action points – jumped to the end while skipping a few steps. Sometimes when following the recipe step-by-step, you achieve a different result than what is displayed in a screenshot. Most of the time you can work around those issues by using your mind a bit and by comparing with (hopefully correct) screenshots. It can get annoying after a while, but it didn’t stop me from reading the book (unlike some delicate little flowers who wrote some reviews on Amazon) because there is still very great content inside it. But you would think that with 4 reviewers, 3 proofreaders and 10 (!) editors mistakes like these would have been avoided. I have contacted the author and she told me that the mistakes have been reported and should appear on the Errata page.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">All in all, I recommend this book to people new to Tableau. They will definitely learn enough by this book to take their first steps with Tableau. A job well done by the author, but shame on you Packt Publishing for all those mistakes. Fire those editors please.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify">UPDATE: the author (Jen Stirup) has placed <a href="http://www.jenstirrup.com/2014/07/packt-tableau-dashboard-cookbook-errata.html">errata about chapter 2 on her blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/webdev/business-intelligence/tableau-dashboard-cookbook-by-jen-stirrup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
