<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>buffer overflow &#8211; LessthanDot</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/buffer-overflow/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Technical Community for IT Professionals</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 12:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Microsoft bans memcpy() to minimize buffer overflows</title>
		<link>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/microsoft-bans-memcpy-to-minimize-buffer/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/microsoft-bans-memcpy-to-minimize-buffer/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Application Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buffer overflow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/05/microsoft-bans-memcpy-to-minimize-buffer/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Microsoft announced that they have added memcpy() to their list of banned functions. The function memcpy() has been responsible for a bunch of security problems in Microsoft and third party products. The reason for this is that memcpy() is not safe and&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft announced that they have added <strong>memcpy()</strong> to their list of banned functions. The function memcpy() has been responsible for a bunch of security problems in Microsoft and third party products. The reason for this is that memcpy() is not safe and can cause a buffer overflow. So what is a buffer overflow anyway? Here is what wikipedia has on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffer_overflow">buffer overflow</a></p>
<blockquote><p>In computer security and programming, a buffer overflow, or buffer overrun, is an anomaly where a process stores data in a buffer outside the memory the programmer set aside for it. The extra data overwrites adjacent memory, which may contain other data, including program variables and program flow control data. This may result in erratic program behavior, including memory access errors, incorrect results, program termination (a crash), or a breach of system security.</p>
<p>Buffer overflows can be triggered by inputs that are designed to execute code, or alter the way the program operates. They are thus the basis of many software vulnerabilities and can be maliciously exploited. Bounds checking can prevent buffer overflows.</p>
<p>Programming languages commonly associated with buffer overflows include C and C++, which provide no built-in protection against accessing or overwriting data in any part of memory and do not automatically check that data written to an array (the built-in buffer type) is within the boundaries of that array.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here is a video of a UltraVNC v1.01 client buffer overflow by using Metasploit.<br />
<object width="425" height="344"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/Vyzvxtk2H_g&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/Vyzvxtk2H_g&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"  width="425" height="344"></embed></object></p>
<p>You can also check <a href="http://milw0rm.com/">milw0rm</a> where they list security vulnerabilities exploits, count the buffer overflow vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>Here is a nice one: <a href="http://milw0rm.com/exploits/8733">AOL IWinAmpActiveX Class (AmpX.dll 2.4.0.6) ConvertFile() remote overflow exploit (IE6/IE7)</a></p>
<p>So now that memcpy() is banned what should you use? You should use memcpy_s(). The function memcpy_s() takes one extra parameter: this extra parameter is the size of the destination buffer.</p>
<p>You can read more about this here: http://blogs.msdn.com/sdl/archive/2009/05/14/please-join-me-in-welcoming-memcpy-to-the-sdl-rogues-gallery.aspx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/enterprisedev/appserver/microsoft-bans-memcpy-to-minimize-buffer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do you use Metasploit to check if your servers are vulnerable?</title>
		<link>/index.php/sysadmins/os/do-you-use-metasploit-to-check-if-your-s/</link>
		<comments>/index.php/sysadmins/os/do-you-use-metasploit-to-check-if-your-s/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 12:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SQLDenis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Operating Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buffer overflow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hackers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metasploit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/2009/01/do-you-use-metasploit-to-check-if-your-s/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Do you use Metasploit to check if your servers are vulnerable? If not then you should take a look at it. What is Metasploit? The Metasploit Framework is a development platform for creating security tools and exploits. The framework is used by network security professionals to perform penetration tests, system administrators to verify patch installations, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you use Metasploit to check if your servers are vulnerable? If not then you should take a look at it. </p>
<p><strong>What is Metasploit?</strong><br />
The Metasploit Framework is a development platform for creating security tools and exploits. The framework is used by network security professionals to perform penetration tests, system administrators to verify patch installations, product vendors to perform regression testing, and security researchers world-wide. The framework is written in the Ruby programming language and includes components written in C and assembler.</p>
<p><strong>What does Metasploit do?</strong><br />
The framework consists of tools, libraries, modules, and user interfaces. The basic function of the framework is a module launcher, allowing the user to configure an exploit module and launch it at a target system. If the exploit succeeds, the payload is executed on the target and the user is provided with a shell to interact with the payload.</p>
<p>Here are some thing you can check with this</p>
<p><strong>Scanning for MD5-signed SSL Certificates</strong><br />
Allows the Metasploit framework to be used as a SSL certificate scanner. This provides a simple way to identify SSL certificates in use that were signed with the MD5 algorithm and need to re-issued</p>
<p><strong>Fuzzing Flash For Fun (ASNative)</strong><br />
The vulnerable function is exposed through the System.Product namespace but is also accessible by using the ASnative API directly. </p>
<p>The ASnative API is interesting because it offers a different way to call builtin functions, and the only way to call certain undocumented functions. ASnative functions are indexed in a two-dimensional array, with the first index being between 1 and 3000, while the second index is usually below 300. The &#8220;escape&#8221; function has an index value of (100,0)</p>
<p>Remember a H4x0r already is using Metasploit and other tools to penetrate and take over your servers by take advantage of buffer overflows and other vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>You can download Metasploit here: http://www.metasploit.com/framework/</p>
<p>Also check out <a href="http://carnal0wnage.blogspot.com/2008/11/oracle-pwnage-with-metasploit-oracle_17.html">Oracle Pwnage with the Metasploit Oracle Modules Part 2</a> and many more exploits on http://carnal0wnage.blogspot.com/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/sysadmins/os/do-you-use-metasploit-to-check-if-your-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
